<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en-US"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.10.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://nova.mkultra.monster/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://nova.mkultra.monster/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en-US" /><updated>2025-01-14T19:05:51-05:00</updated><id>https://nova.mkultra.monster/feed.xml</id><title type="html">cmdr-nova@internet:~$</title><subtitle>cmdr-nova&apos;s personal blog and home on the indie-web.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Don’t Just Ask AI to Stay Away, Block Them</title><link href="https://nova.mkultra.monster/tech/2025/01/14/don-t-just-ask-ai-to-stay-away-block-them.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Don’t Just Ask AI to Stay Away, Block Them" /><published>2025-01-14T11:18:00-05:00</published><updated>2025-01-14T11:18:00-05:00</updated><id>https://nova.mkultra.monster/tech/2025/01/14/don-t-just-ask-ai-to-stay-away-block-them</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://nova.mkultra.monster/tech/2025/01/14/don-t-just-ask-ai-to-stay-away-block-them.html"><![CDATA[<p>If you’ve been on the internet in the past year and a half to two years, you’re probably very familiar with company’s like OpenAI, where Sam Altman argues that <a href="https://futurism.com/the-byte/openai-copyrighted-material-parliament" target="_blank">his bots <em>must</em> steal in order for his company to be profitable</a>. And, you’re probably also <em>very</em> aware of the endless two-braincell-tech-dudes who post and write about how awesome it is to plagiarize and steal the work of artists to generate some quick, sloppy garbage for short-term gains. Well, if you’re like me, this <em>pisses you the frick off</em>, and in today’s post I’m going to help you completely block their grungy asses from accessing your website.</p>

<p>You may already have a robots.txt file, which provides the internets with a list of ai-gen slop-machines that you’d like to ask nicely, “Don’t crawl or scrape my site.” But, as we know, asking bots made by people and companies who don’t believe in the concept of consent, is like asking a serial killer not to kill. So, we’re not going to ask. We’re going to tell them to take their scraping, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2025/01/10/how-openais-bot-crushed-this-seven-person-companys-web-site-like-a-ddos-attack/" target="_blank">DDOS machines</a>, and make like a screen door on a battleship, and get outta here.</p>

<p>This is <em>very</em> important to do, especially if you’re an independent party who hosts a website, or, say, a <em>Mastodon instance</em>, on your own personal VPS, that you pay for. A service that probably jacks up prices based on overages related to traffic.</p>

<p>So, let’s take off our pants and jacket, and get to it.</p>

<p>There are a lot of complicated ways to do this, that require all kinds of know-how about Apache and Nginx and all sorts of stuff that’ll probably give you a migraine. So, we’re going to make this really simple.</p>

<p>We’re going to use an .htaccess file.</p>

<p>Normally, you could use this to block access to your entire website for everyone <em>but you</em>, which can be useful for testing purposes, or to hide what you’re working on, or what-have-you. But, instead of doing that, we’re going to make it so these bots simply <em>do not</em> access your website, <em>at all</em>. No asking. Just punching them in the face, and leaving them unconscious in a gutter.</p>

<p>I run my website on Jekyll, so I decided to make a ruby that compiles my .htaccess file based on a json file that contains a list of AI scrapers. Once I build and serve my site, it regenerates the .htaccess file, <em>every single time</em>, based on what’s written in crawlers.json. In this way, I can <em>easily</em> add to it in the future, as morally corrupt businesses and corporations roll out even <em>more</em> <a href="https://cee.illinois.edu/news/AIs-Challenging-Waters#:~:text=Data%20centers%20are%20growing%20like%20weeds%2C%20and%20they%20are%20thirsty&amp;text=For%20example%2C%20Google's%20hyperscale%20data,day%20over%20the%20past%20year." target="_blank">water guzzling</a>, <a href="https://www.unep.org/news-and-stories/story/ai-has-environmental-problem-heres-what-world-can-do-about" target="_blank">climate destroying</a> shit-machines.</p>

<p>You <em>could</em> simply copy/paste the .htaccess file, but before we do that, I want to show you how to make it so you can do what I’m doing, if you’re using Jekyll, or something similar.</p>

<p>First, make the ruby gem in your site’s root directory, and call it something like, “generate_htaccess.rb”:</p>

<div class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge"><div class="highlight"><pre class="highlight"><code>require 'json'

# Read the JSON file containing a list of crawlers, i.e., ai bots (the file doesn't *need* to be in assets/data/, that's just where I personally put it)
file_path = 'assets/data/crawlers.json'
crawlers = JSON.parse(File.read(file_path))['crawlers']

# Generate .htaccess
htaccess_content = &lt;&lt;~HTACCESS
  RewriteEngine On
  RewriteCond %{HTTP_USER_AGENT} (#{crawlers.join('|')}) [NC]
  RewriteRule ^ - [F]
HTACCESS

# Write .htaccess
File.open('.htaccess', 'w') do |file|
  file.write(htaccess_content)
end
# Show output in the terminal
puts ".htaccess file generated successfully."
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>Next, create your “crawlers.json” file in whichever directory you’d like. Mine is in /assets/data, but if you change this, you’ll have to edit the “file_path” in the ruby gem in order for this to work. Here’s my crawlers.json:</p>

<div class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge"><div class="highlight"><pre class="highlight"><code>{
    "crawlers": [
      "AI2Bot",
      "Ai2Bot-Dolma",
      "Amazonbot",
      "anthropic-ai",
      "Applebot",
      "Applebot-Extended",
      "Bytespider",
      "CCBot",
      "ChatGPT-User",
      "Claude-Web",
      "ClaudeBot",
      "cohere-ai",
      "cohere-training-data-crawler",
      "Diffbot",
      "DuckAssistBot",
      "FacebookBot",
      "FriendlyCrawler",
      "Google-Extended",
      "GoogleOther",
      "GoogleOther-Image",
      "GoogleOther-Video",
      "GPTBot",
      "iaskspider/2.0",
      "ICC-Crawler",
      "ImagesiftBot",
      "img2dataset",
      "ISSCyberRiskCrawler",
      "Kangaroo Bot",
      "Meta-ExternalAgent",
      "Meta-ExternalFetcher",
      "OAI-SearchBot",
      "omgili",
      "omgilibot",
      "PanguBot",
      "PerplexityBot",
      "PetalBot",
      "Scrapy",
      "SemrushBot",
      "Sidetrade indexer bot",
      "Timpibot",
      "VelenPublicWebCrawler",
      "Webzio-Extended",
      "YouBot"
    ]
  }
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>If you’ve been following any of my Python projects, this will look similar to ways that I list, for example, subreddits for my “bots” to pull images from, and then post them to Mastodon. I like these json lists. It makes things real simple-like.</p>

<p>I took this list, and other ideas on how to do this, from <a href="https://github.com/ai-robots-txt/ai.robots.txt?tab=readme-ov-file" target="_blank">this GitHub repository</a>. I am personally subscribed to their RSS feed so that I can stay up-to-date with slop that’s being rolled out by the likes of Meta and other terrible corporations.</p>

<p>Finally, when building my Jekyll site locally, I use a shell script that does all sorts of things for me, such as, indexing all of my posts for my search engine, generating post metadata so that random posts can be shown at the bottom of other posts, and so on, and so forth. For this, though, we don’t need all of that. So, make a “serve.sh” (in your site’s root directory) that looks like this:</p>

<div class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge"><div class="highlight"><pre class="highlight"><code>#!/bin/bash

# Generate .htaccess file
ruby generate_htaccess.rb

# Build
bundle exec jekyll build

# Serve
bundle exec jekyll serve --watch
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>Now, as you’re updating your site on the local machine, and updating the build in order to admire your changes, or confirm that things are working, it’ll build a new .htaccess file, <em>every time you run this script</em>, and it’ll use the list of AI bots you’ve already provided (crawlers.json). This way, you can update the crawlers any time you want, and whenever you build your site locally, .htaccess gets updated (you should note, that executing Ruby without Ruby being installed, will do nothing, and it is assumed, that because you’re running Jekyll, you <em>do</em> have it installed).</p>

<p>Once you commit the site to live, it’ll already be done and generated, and for all intents and purposes, <em>this should stop these greedy, power-hungry mother assheads from accessing your website</em>.</p>

<p>The generated file should look something like this:</p>

<div class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge"><div class="highlight"><pre class="highlight"><code>RewriteEngine On
RewriteCond %{HTTP_USER_AGENT} (AI2Bot|Ai2Bot-Dolma|Amazonbot|anthropic-ai|Applebot|Applebot-Extended|Bytespider|CCBot|ChatGPT-User|Claude-Web|ClaudeBot|cohere-ai|cohere-training-data-crawler|Diffbot|DuckAssistBot|FacebookBot|FriendlyCrawler|Google-Extended|GoogleOther|GoogleOther-Image|GoogleOther-Video|GPTBot|iaskspider/2.0|ICC-Crawler|ImagesiftBot|img2dataset|ISSCyberRiskCrawler|Kangaroo Bot|Meta-ExternalAgent|Meta-ExternalFetcher|OAI-SearchBot|omgili|omgilibot|PanguBot|PerplexityBot|PetalBot|Scrapy|SemrushBot|Sidetrade indexer bot|Timpibot|VelenPublicWebCrawler|Webzio-Extended|YouBot) [NC]
RewriteRule ^ - [F]
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>Now, this website and <a href="https://mkultra.monster" target="_blank">my Mastodon instance</a> are on the same domain, but they <em>are not</em> on the same server. So, what I did for my Mastodon instance was this:</p>

<div class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge"><div class="highlight"><pre class="highlight"><code>ssh root@your_mastodon_instance_ip

su - mastodon

cd live

cd public

nano .htaccess

# copy/paste the generated .htaccess into this file with ctrl+shift+v

ctrl+O

ctrl+X
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>Done.</p>

<p>The reason I’ve also included this on my Mastodon instance, is, partially, because I’ve noticed at least once a week, or every other week, there’s a <em>massive</em> spike of activity that causes my entire instance to go offline. And it <em>doesn’t come back up again</em>, until I force a power cycle, and then restart Mastodon streaming. I have some … <em>suspicions</em> that this is to do with sludge-scrapers, and so, <em>hopefully</em>, this does <em>something</em> for me.</p>

<p>And maybe also you.</p>

<p>But, there you have it. Block these sumbitches.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Tech" /><category term="blockai" /><category term="ai" /><category term="block" /><category term="htaccess" /><category term="robots" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[If you’ve been on the internet in the past year and a half to two years, you’re probably very familiar with company’s like OpenAI, where Sam Altman argues that his bots must steal in order for his company to be profitable. And, you’re probably also very aware of the endless two-braincell-tech-dudes who post and write about how awesome it is to plagiarize and steal the work of artists to generate some quick, sloppy garbage for short-term gains. Well, if you’re like me, this pisses you the frick off, and in today’s post I’m going to help you completely block their grungy asses from accessing your website.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Fediverse Comments Have Returned</title><link href="https://nova.mkultra.monster/fediverse/2025/01/13/fediverse-comments-have-returned.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Fediverse Comments Have Returned" /><published>2025-01-13T11:32:00-05:00</published><updated>2025-01-13T11:32:00-05:00</updated><id>https://nova.mkultra.monster/fediverse/2025/01/13/fediverse-comments-have-returned</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://nova.mkultra.monster/fediverse/2025/01/13/fediverse-comments-have-returned.html"><![CDATA[<p>A while back, last year now, I briefly launched a Sharkey instance, and replaced my managed-host Mastodon instance, and since my fediverse comments on this blog weren’t completely compatible, I removed them and replaced them with an embedded comment section that makes calls to my VPS in order to store them. This is <em>pretty</em> memory intensive on a 6 dollar VPS that I’m not interested in upgrading, just so that I can host a bajillion different proxy servers.</p>

<p>Now that I’ve been back to Mastodon, except, this time, hosting it myself, I figured, “Why not put the Fediverse comment sections back on each post?”</p>

<p>And so I have done that!</p>

<p>Now, you can continue seeing your replies to my blog posts on fedi, also show up here on my blog. It appears to work with other Mastodon instances, Wafrn, and <em>maybe</em> Sharkey/Misskey? Although, I’ve tested a Sharkey comment on a previous blog post, and it has not yet shown up. This could either be due to federation issues between my specific instance, with the Sharkey instance I posted from, <em>or</em> it could be due to slower federation. Meaning, it could show up sometime later. Not sure!</p>

<p>My <em>only</em> stipulation, is that I would <em>really</em> love if someone could help me figure out how to get a piece of JavaScript to automatically grab a post ID from the resulting Mastodon post that’s made once I make a <em>new</em> blog post (and then somehow also find a way to make it so that it inserts that post ID into the front matter of the corresponding post). I only <em>assume</em> this is possible, but it also sounds <em>extremely</em> complicated.</p>

<p>Unless I could use more server-side Python to accomplish this, altho, I would rather not run more proxy servers.</p>

<p>Either way, this is something that will be figured out … uh, eventually.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Fediverse" /><category term="fediverse" /><category term="mastodon" /><category term="wafrn" /><category term="sharkey" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[A while back, last year now, I briefly launched a Sharkey instance, and replaced my managed-host Mastodon instance, and since my fediverse comments on this blog weren’t completely compatible, I removed them and replaced them with an embedded comment section that makes calls to my VPS in order to store them. This is pretty memory intensive on a 6 dollar VPS that I’m not interested in upgrading, just so that I can host a bajillion different proxy servers.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The Backrooms: Tape 1</title><link href="https://nova.mkultra.monster/backrooms/2025/01/13/the-backrooms-tape-1.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Backrooms: Tape 1" /><published>2025-01-13T01:10:00-05:00</published><updated>2025-01-13T01:10:00-05:00</updated><id>https://nova.mkultra.monster/backrooms/2025/01/13/the-backrooms-tape-1</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://nova.mkultra.monster/backrooms/2025/01/13/the-backrooms-tape-1.html"><![CDATA[<p>So, there’s been a bit of a Kane Pixels drought, ever since <a href="https://youtu.be/acdYs9tPLko?si=lKMN9wQ8WRGbjgWn" target="_blank">Found Footage 3</a> was released, and if you haven’t watched that yet, <em>you need to</em>. I’m assuming the release of these shorts has been slower, due to the production of the full length feature film that was announced … quite some time ago, at this point. In conjunction with A24, Backrooms, or The Complex, the MOVIE, is set to release … uh, sometime before I die of old age, hopefully! But, until then, we have content to watch from other, smaller-time creators.</p>

<p>I’m <em>very</em> selective with the Backrooms content I’ll watch. The silly, slides-and-coconut-milk (or whatever it is?) backrooms-wiki creations are … we’ll just say, mostly <em>bad</em>. Turning Backrooms into a huge thing that tons of people are adding to without any consideration for <em>what’s</em> being added, really takes the actual fear and immersion completely away from the concept. Which is why I don’t consume that content.</p>

<p>I pretty much <em>only</em> watch Backrooms content that is either Kane Pixels, or works inspired by it.</p>

<p>And, even then, sometimes those videos are a little iffy. Sometimes the pacing of the camera-holder versus their footstep movement doesn’t match up well, at all. Sometimes the textures have bad lighting and it’s extremely obvious that they’re just recording in Blender, hence, breaking immersion. Other times, they’ll try to incorporate scenes with actual people in them, or the person who’s lost, themselves, and they’re <em>really</em> not great looking 3D models.</p>

<p>Kane is the masterclass, and there are some who follow the formula well.</p>

<p>Today, I discovered TheMrLeoniasty on Youtube, through his Tape 1 video, and it’s really something else. It’s not 100% perfect, some of the pacing is a little off, but it doesn’t try and take the usual formula that most everyone else does (think: howler / bacteria chase scenes that happen in every single video). It, instead, does something <em>entirely</em> different (although, I’m not sure yet how I feel about the PS2 boot screen).</p>

<p>It’s very slow paced, until the end. The end is absolutely something to behold, as a Backrooms enjoyer.</p>

<p>Watch.</p>

<iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/9Rk1WAR1iL0?si=DUpykixF-K5DA2Oy" title="YouTube video player" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Backrooms" /><category term="thebackrooms" /><category term="backrooms" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[So, there’s been a bit of a Kane Pixels drought, ever since Found Footage 3 was released, and if you haven’t watched that yet, you need to. I’m assuming the release of these shorts has been slower, due to the production of the full length feature film that was announced … quite some time ago, at this point. In conjunction with A24, Backrooms, or The Complex, the MOVIE, is set to release … uh, sometime before I die of old age, hopefully! But, until then, we have content to watch from other, smaller-time creators.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">When All Else Fails; Ramen</title><link href="https://nova.mkultra.monster/thoughts/2025/01/11/when-all-else-fails-ramen.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="When All Else Fails; Ramen" /><published>2025-01-11T22:35:00-05:00</published><updated>2025-01-11T22:35:00-05:00</updated><id>https://nova.mkultra.monster/thoughts/2025/01/11/when-all-else-fails-ramen</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://nova.mkultra.monster/thoughts/2025/01/11/when-all-else-fails-ramen.html"><![CDATA[<p>I get off of work, third day of my work week, whole body aching, staving off the pain with exactly three Ibuprofen and nothing else, and I log onto Second Life. Standing outside my static mansion on a hill that no one visits but me, because nobody else is allowed, I try to think of something interesting to write about. I <em>do</em> kind of tire of writing on negative topics, and topics I have to constantly cite with outbound links, screenshots, and facts. That stuff takes me such a long time to write. But today, I think I want to talk about ramen.</p>

<p><img src="/img/posts/ramen/Screenshot from 2025-01-11 22-35-02.png" /></p>

<p>It took me an enormous amount of time in my life to finally have an actual <em>good</em> bowl of ramen, that wasn’t some bouillon chicken mess in a styrofoam cup. And that was … about three years ago. From a restaurant that, unfortunately, shutdown. I think they were called, <em>Taste of Asia</em>. And, although, I’ve never had the delight of going to Japan, or Korea, or Indonesia, I can say that <em>if I did</em>, I would eat ramen, <em>first</em>.</p>

<p>I remember it like it was almost yesterday. I ordered a bowl of ramen through DoorDash, and it came in this giant plastic container, and it wasn’t just the noodles. It had all the garnish: the seaweed, the pork, the egg, the noodles, and the broth. For this, I had bought a pair of wooden chopsticks, just to feel like I was doing something authentic. And then I took the first bite.</p>

<p>It was like how I would imagine Gordon Ramsay feels when he takes a bite of Beef Wellington that’s done right. It was <em>amazing</em> (I am by no means comparing myself to Gordon Ramsay, I cannot cook, not like that). And it was at that moment that Top Ramen, and Maruchan became <em>dead to me</em>.</p>

<p>It was like, “Wow! Ramen is supposed … to be FLAVORFUL?!” And my god, it was.</p>

<p>Flash forward to today, and I have specific instant ramen brands that I like, and I <em>will not</em> eat anything else.</p>

<p>Those brands are Shin Black, Samyang Buldak, and Sapporo Ichiban.</p>

<p><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Nongshim-Premium-Instant-Vegetables-Microwaveable/dp/B00BEIKRBY?crid=2RE7NPU9EHR9K&amp;dib=eyJ2IjoiMSJ9.xHXapwCC-Pv1Rkl5NuAhr0c8kYwdRXFVhgSX-3UMw0Wnvc9qqQeRxHo7Os5h8UClrR95R2fnI59DCUvniIQ92ulpZNCh3gDHVS-XQcu7YgRoNxd-_DU4JTEKQvlF-znZx7qEpJOyey2WqvqmL8nqYSsGfpEBBZEPVnJjzicej_ObtMyjtjr4P8nlSscijr37CgwE79hgwNbwG06SKq77-KOi53SrAKlTv61lh5M15HuamGc8W2yCAWjCEs77oKA0Dp6atgNk01_BB71fBfjUpt0hRfDGzwi4pfS1VvDHLviVyWwmp32otbymQ9ApZHoxaRgMpuB8k1zVlF-JCBVzf9EQKh49UT3fxxbxodlmZnSEL1o00hLvn3AYoJTxgER2Bg4Os61GXeBN08gSxkk05zJ8DrDq5eIi5c9brGmIZ5t1VYe6j-IEpYTIFxVXbxqK.lcdRf5LTMCSCsoWYfPlylZYKYyhJLOodMyNpt1vj4Yo&amp;dib_tag=se&amp;keywords=shin%2Bblack%2Bramen&amp;qid=1736653783&amp;rdc=1&amp;sprefix=shin%2Bblack%2Bramen%2Caps%2C160&amp;sr=8-1&amp;th=1" target="_blank">Shin Black</a> is a very deep flavor, with a spicy kick to it, and it’s only “failing,” if you can call it that, is that they add no MSG to it. There are a lot of misconceptions about MSG, and although, it is <em>of course</em>, not healthy, it’s mostly fine.</p>

<p>My second favorite is <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Samyang-Chicken-Stir-Fried-Instant-Carbonara/dp/B0C85RZWP3?crid=131JM9EPLBZT8&amp;dib=eyJ2IjoiMSJ9.6A_Wx8Fgg5bqODsI4eTvqrnOGnYuDJutso-YGIlKV0s-sFrFLP5UYlj2Q157ri2xOEtloVA0pXoesaHFZIOJGnM6Qr9M5M85HMwI19KhZfcZXkQpyBAdY-jQF2o8VelyMl5jFmdPdaLXNc80P0u7-ur2ehMJd33qrE_w-Gq5VGluynQOpRJcvL-dlttRjmQUcA4G1TRW4R6-hZlZlQMcrK1HuVfiz_4HgragJ_0E2NkFOI8UlEpIzzhN-vnw8eapvY05aLJW5FWec81mK5cMUyw-yLrr8gDGU88ZGjDBZLg.MIN95VxYZgR_yZ4f6sLG8mY65sCrmJCVgldhPx1qc-4&amp;dib_tag=se&amp;keywords=buldak+ramen&amp;qid=1736653938&amp;sprefix=buldack+rame%2Caps%2C107&amp;sr=8-1" target="_blank">Samyang Buldak</a>, which <em>I think</em> went viral on Tik-Tok for some reason? But, I eat Buldak when I want to punish my stomach with flavor, and fire. You know, you gotta remind yourself that you’re <em>alive</em> sometimes, and the best way to do that, is to punch your stomach in the stomach with knives known as chili peppers.</p>

<p>My only downfall is that as I get older, I can’t handle intense spice as much as I used to, but I also partially blame the “one chip challenge” in damaging my stomach (because I’m pretty sure it did).</p>

<p>And then, at the top of my list, is <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Sapporo-Ichiban-Ramen-Noodles-Original/dp/B00N3K2I7C?crid=38KAYZH9AQS00&amp;dib=eyJ2IjoiMSJ9.q27X2atTczpdkfJHBSaPeKqPahqyU_Pjj15jmlHLcD0q3jXsg6MvZcPik47MPIk7qU_NElfaZ-cuOt2Zk0QbpjUMMKUP7oCKYiKKEqaONMH7TuIkKu7LzBkTT0pkJBm_FVMlQNbcWL5Hbu1F7Euz9n0KTfGfl5cYY_2tm2pYX2W-NnogOSV39jYWm3nhZl03egJXc6gdSbkiNUDNQhODxmNXrofOxT5qh_Dsycav_8hYn8UfnhoFMdqhXFVuBooCWb-anKczlJ8qxcRCLxFsnUeQIylv4cLSlp7ieuKvZ5nvvOqQc2g1rPZtZhD_ULES18ceF83Qkzzl0I4F-XeH2sL7E0qh9pb_bSy4APnhCw9dzs1zWCYCwZ5USa8mWzOQA0jtSsrmOUSJPP_-g_2bfcroWmNnuSD3PIhjSxx6mP9N6Vrt1N62U_qT9nRk_-A7.bKFf-8TaiM8U2_kL0nIb71K88IV6QX64sMXkZqnJ3gQ&amp;dib_tag=se&amp;keywords=sapporo%2Bichiban%2Bramen&amp;qid=1736654126&amp;rdc=1&amp;sprefix=sappora%2Bic%2Caps%2C115&amp;sr=8-1&amp;th=1" target="_blank">Sapporo Ichiban</a>. These noodles aren’t for committing crimes against yourself. It’s got a very rich flavor, it has the MSG, and it’s not punishing to your stomach. Sapporo is for when I’m on a day off from work, and I’m doing for myself a little bit of self care, and I want something easy, and also <em>good</em> to eat. This is my favorite instant noodle of all time.</p>

<p>But, there is a reason I eat all of this in moderation, and that’s because <em>they’re all absolutely filled to the brim with sodium</em>, and there is definitely value in understanding, that there can be too much of a good thing.</p>

<p>People who know me, know that I like to joke about pizza, but, pizza is only my second favorite food. Ramen is number one, and I don’t really speak about it. You wouldn’t know this unless you’ve just read this blog post.</p>

<p>Which brings me to what made me want to post this, and that is this video posted by someone I know on the fediverse, of multiple professional chefs critiquing instant ramen noodles. I recommend a watch!</p>

<blockquote class="mastodon-embed" data-embed-url="https://mastodon.social/@ManiacalV/113813166547141709/embed" style="background: #FCF8FF; border-radius: 8px; border: 1px solid #C9C4DA; margin: 0; max-width: 540px; min-width: 270px; overflow: hidden; padding: 0;"> <a href="https://mastodon.social/@ManiacalV/113813166547141709" target="_blank" style="align-items: center; color: #1C1A25; display: flex; flex-direction: column; font-family: system-ui, -apple-system, BlinkMacSystemFont, 'Segoe UI', Oxygen, Ubuntu, Cantarell, 'Fira Sans', 'Droid Sans', 'Helvetica Neue', Roboto, sans-serif; font-size: 14px; justify-content: center; letter-spacing: 0.25px; line-height: 20px; padding: 24px; text-decoration: none;"> <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" width="32" height="32" viewBox="0 0 79 75"><path d="M74.7135 16.6043C73.6199 8.54587 66.5351 2.19527 58.1366 0.964691C56.7196 0.756754 51.351 0 38.9148 0H38.822C26.3824 0 23.7135 0.756754 22.2966 0.964691C14.1319 2.16118 6.67571 7.86752 4.86669 16.0214C3.99657 20.0369 3.90371 24.4888 4.06535 28.5726C4.29578 34.4289 4.34049 40.275 4.877 46.1075C5.24791 49.9817 5.89495 53.8251 6.81328 57.6088C8.53288 64.5968 15.4938 70.4122 22.3138 72.7848C29.6155 75.259 37.468 75.6697 44.9919 73.971C45.8196 73.7801 46.6381 73.5586 47.4475 73.3063C49.2737 72.7302 51.4164 72.086 52.9915 70.9542C53.0131 70.9384 53.0308 70.9178 53.0433 70.8942C53.0558 70.8706 53.0628 70.8445 53.0637 70.8179V65.1661C53.0634 65.1412 53.0574 65.1167 53.0462 65.0944C53.035 65.0721 53.0189 65.0525 52.9992 65.0371C52.9794 65.0218 52.9564 65.011 52.9318 65.0056C52.9073 65.0002 52.8819 65.0003 52.8574 65.0059C48.0369 66.1472 43.0971 66.7193 38.141 66.7103C29.6118 66.7103 27.3178 62.6981 26.6609 61.0278C26.1329 59.5842 25.7976 58.0784 25.6636 56.5486C25.6622 56.5229 25.667 56.4973 25.6775 56.4738C25.688 56.4502 25.7039 56.4295 25.724 56.4132C25.7441 56.397 25.7678 56.3856 25.7931 56.3801C25.8185 56.3746 25.8448 56.3751 25.8699 56.3816C30.6101 57.5151 35.4693 58.0873 40.3455 58.086C41.5183 58.086 42.6876 58.086 43.8604 58.0553C48.7647 57.919 53.9339 57.6701 58.7591 56.7361C58.8794 56.7123 58.9998 56.6918 59.103 56.6611C66.7139 55.2124 73.9569 50.665 74.6929 39.1501C74.7204 38.6967 74.7892 34.4016 74.7892 33.9312C74.7926 32.3325 75.3085 22.5901 74.7135 16.6043ZM62.9996 45.3371H54.9966V25.9069C54.9966 21.8163 53.277 19.7302 49.7793 19.7302C45.9343 19.7302 44.0083 22.1981 44.0083 27.0727V37.7082H36.0534V27.0727C36.0534 22.1981 34.124 19.7302 30.279 19.7302C26.8019 19.7302 25.0651 21.8163 25.0617 25.9069V45.3371H17.0656V25.3172C17.0656 21.2266 18.1191 17.9769 20.2262 15.568C22.3998 13.1648 25.2509 11.9308 28.7898 11.9308C32.8859 11.9308 35.9812 13.492 38.0447 16.6111L40.036 19.9245L42.0308 16.6111C44.0943 13.492 47.1896 11.9308 51.2788 11.9308C54.8143 11.9308 57.6654 13.1648 59.8459 15.568C61.9529 17.9746 63.0065 21.2243 63.0065 25.3172L62.9996 45.3371Z" fill="currentColor" /></svg> <div style="color: #787588; margin-top: 16px;">Post by @ManiacalV@mastodon.social</div> <div style="font-weight: 500;">View on Mastodon</div> </a> </blockquote>
<script data-allowed-prefixes="https://mastodon.social/" async="" src="https://mastodon.social/embed.js"></script>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Thoughts" /><category term="thoughts" /><category term="secondlife" /><category term="ramen" /><category term="food" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[I get off of work, third day of my work week, whole body aching, staving off the pain with exactly three Ibuprofen and nothing else, and I log onto Second Life. Standing outside my static mansion on a hill that no one visits but me, because nobody else is allowed, I try to think of something interesting to write about. I do kind of tire of writing on negative topics, and topics I have to constantly cite with outbound links, screenshots, and facts. That stuff takes me such a long time to write. But today, I think I want to talk about ramen.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Second Life: No, You Don’t Get to Dictate What Creators Do</title><link href="https://nova.mkultra.monster/second-life/2025/01/09/second-life-no-you-don-t-get-to-dictate-what-creators-do.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Second Life: No, You Don’t Get to Dictate What Creators Do" /><published>2025-01-09T22:11:00-05:00</published><updated>2025-01-09T22:11:00-05:00</updated><id>https://nova.mkultra.monster/second-life/2025/01/09/second-life-no-you-don-t-get-to-dictate-what-creators-do</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://nova.mkultra.monster/second-life/2025/01/09/second-life-no-you-don-t-get-to-dictate-what-creators-do.html"><![CDATA[<p>In Second Life, anyone can be a creator, and make their creations available to the virtual world for purchase, and some have found major success with this. Others, it exists, maybe, as more of a hobby. For me, that’s mostly what it is, for now. But this all comes with a downside, because, like in the real world, the customer sometimes thinks they know best, and if you’ve ever worked retail, you know how very wrong that is.</p>

<p>I touched on this topic a little bit via Mastodon while I was on break at work, but I wanted to break it down in more detail, because this is a problem I see a lot of in Second Life. I’m not saying this is <em>every person in the virtual world who buys things</em>, but it is more or less, a pretty pervasive idea that I don’t think gets challenged enough. But, to break <em>that</em> down, basically, when people sell things in Second Life, you can sell it with permissions that allow a buyer to modify your content to their liking. You can <em>also</em> choose not to do this, in order to keep your work the way it is when it’s sold (especially if you want to sell different variations, which is, again, entirely up to the creator). Some people have a <em>very big problem</em> with the latter …</p>

<p><img src="/img/posts/sl-stores/IMG_8137.jpg" /></p>

<p>This is a screenshot of a Reddit post that got a lot of traction … a lot of people in agreement, and because Reddit is a place where dissenting opinions get buried and heckled, I felt it a good idea to write it all up here. So, let’s tear this apart, shall we?</p>

<blockquote>
As I'm customising my avatar more and getting more creative. I'm realising that there's no good reason for 99% of clothing to be non mod Perm (especially if it's a fatpack).
</blockquote>

<p>A lot of this language will probably be pretty alien to people who don’t peruse Second Life, so … “fatpack” is something creators make that contain all variations of a certain product, such as a shirt. We’ll go with that. So, a creator makes a black shirt, and a white shirt, and then maybe five other colors, and they sell them all individually. Then, what they’ll do, is they’ll make a pack that contains all of them together, along with, maybe, a couple bonuses for buying that pack, i.e., a “fatpack.”</p>

<p>I don’t see any real problem with this, but we’ll get into that when I’m done here.</p>

<p>This Redditor believes there’s “no good reason” for most clothing to not to be modifiable by the buyer. And I say, there is a good reason! If a creator <em>wants</em> to sell their virtual clothing in specific colors, patterns and textures, and not allow people to change this, that’s up to them! You are <em>not</em> the person running the store. You are not the person <em>creating</em> these things. And <em>most of it</em> is sold for prices <em>below</em> 2000 linden.</p>

<p>A fatpack will usually run anywhere between 600 to 1200 linden. And maybe you’re thinking, “Whoa, is that expensive?”</p>

<p>No.</p>

<p>Some people look at that pricing, <em>within</em> Second Life, and they’ll call it expensive. They always do. But why don’t we look at the actual exchange rate.</p>

<p><img src="/img/posts/sl-stores/Screenshot from 2025-01-09 22-29-48.png" /></p>

<p>So … for less than a value meal at McDonalds, or a cup of coffee at Starbucks, you can buy an entire set of clothing? For a little bit less than 5 dollars USD?</p>

<p>Another way to look at this, is that people are spending <em>hours</em> and <em>hours</em> on making clothing and accessories for people to buy, to customize their avatars, and to spice up their little virtual lives, <em>for almost nothing</em>. For less than a Fiverr gig. When, in the real world, if I were making you a custom 3D modeled product for a <em>game</em>, with complete textures, UV mapping, skeleton rigging, and weight painting … I would charge you <em>at least 500 dollars</em>.</p>

<p>Fortunately, we’re talking about Second Life, where all of that work is done behind-the-scenes, and people sell things at prices that are easily digestible to the masses, which, I think <em>is beyond fair.</em> It’s almost highway robbery.</p>

<blockquote>
Removing hidden faces, unliking and linking items is a must. Especially because you often start running against attachment limits.
</blockquote>

<p>We step into the next point of this user’s argument, in that, their perceived issue, is that clothing in link-sets should be able to be de-linked, because sometimes you run into an issue where your avatar has <em>too many attachments</em>, and you can’t wear something that you want. And, a linkset, is basically just <em>gluing</em> different items together so that they count more as one, but, even in doing that, they still cost server resources.</p>

<p>So you can only attach so many resources to your avatar until you hit that limit, you know, so that you don’t become a walking DDoS.</p>

<p>But … what’s the attachment limit in 2025, for a Second Life avatar?</p>

<p>Quoted directly from the <a href="https://wiki.secondlife.com/wiki/Limits#:~:text=general%20inworld%20experience.-,Avatar,and%20choosing%20Edit%20My%20Outfit." target="_blank">Second Life Wiki</a>, “Max. # of attachments - 38 combined HUD and body attachments.”</p>

<p>An outfit someone might wear, will usually consist of a top, a bottom, and maybe shoes. So we’re talking … three to four attachment points. But then, of course, you have to account for your body, whether the hands and feet are separate, your hair, maybe custom eyes, and even fingernails.</p>

<p>So what would that run you?</p>

<p>To be generous, we’ll just say … 15. Even though that’s more than what I’ve listed, we’ll go with 15, to be fair to the original quoted post.</p>

<p>You’ve <em>still got 23 additional attachment points</em>.</p>

<p>Now, some people like to wear HUDs, like body HUDs that make hiding texture faces on your body easier (although, I’m not sure why you would wear this at all times), or gaming HUDs, like a system that makes it so your avatar is a vampire, or sexual HUDs that make your virtual life a little more … spicy. And, of course, you probably walk around with the HUD for your head on, at least, <em>sometimes</em>, so that you can control your eye and mouth movements.</p>

<p>But … that’s like, maybe 3 to 5 more attachment points.</p>

<p>You’ve still got a lot to go.</p>

<p>I can’t remember if server weight is counted in addition to attachment points, but we’ll just say, <em>it is</em>, and some of these attachments are taking up multiple points. Odds are, you’ve still got room to put more stuff on your avatar.</p>

<p>My point here, is that, <em>in most cases</em>, this is a complete non-issue, and it’s an excuse being made in order to aid the original argument. That creator’s should do what non-creator’s say, or else. And maybe you’re thinking, “Wh … what do you mean by that?”</p>

<p>Just wait.</p>

<blockquote>
When you're new, you don't care and I think it's a bit cash grabby to sell non mod Items with shiny branding pages and stores.
<br /><br />
There are so many stores that are less shiny on the outside but their stuff is amazing and mod Perm.
</blockquote>

<p>I’m going to tackle both of these points together, because this is already pretty long. So. This kind of circles back to my point on pricing, and how <em>utterly entitled it is</em> to say that creators in Second Life are pushing out “cash grabs” when they decide they want to sell specific colors and designs, that you can’t rip out and replace with … whatever.</p>

<p>That sounds, not just entitled, but … and this is a little ironic, but <em>greedy</em>.</p>

<p>I’m not sure what being “new” has to do with this.</p>

<p>But then in their continued final point, basically, stores that aren’t flashy and less established are, apparently, more inclined to sell their products with the ability to tear things apart, and do with them whatever a customer pleases. And hey, that’s also fine! If someone wants to sell their products in a way that makes it so customers can do whatever they want, go ahead!</p>

<p>There is no wrong way to be a creator in Second Life, and you can do whatever you want, <em>because it is your work.</em></p>

<p>And now, we’re going to circle back to my comment that hinted at an ultimatum …</p>

<p><img src="/img/posts/sl-stores/Screenshot from 2025-01-09 22-56-08.png" /></p>

<p>So, and this is also a point I’ve seen come up elsewhere, in that, and I’m going to be blunt, these <em>entitled as all hell people</em>, are trying to say that if a creator sells their work in a way that you can’t modify it, this <em>incentivizes</em> people to steal. To use ToS breaking scripts to rip your work out of Second Life, and to then re-upload it so that anything they want to do with it, can be done, for <em>free</em>.</p>

<p>It’s no secret that there are unscrupulous, grifting, uncreative, jerks out there in the world. We know this, <em>especially now</em>, because of generative AI. But to say that creators should let you tear their work apart, or have it stolen … That’s just ridiculous. It’s <em>especially</em> ridiculous, when you realize that there <em>are</em> people stealing work in Second Life, that costs, <em>most of the time</em>, less than five dollars to have.</p>

<p>When I say, there are some petty, entitled people in Second Life, <strong>I mean it</strong>.</p>

<p><em>A large majority of work sold on the Second Life marketplace goes for less than even a dollar, sometimes 30 to 50 cents!</em></p>

<p>And there are people <em>threatening to steal the work of these creators</em>, because they want to color the shirt you made baby-puke green.</p>

<p>I have enjoyed running a store in Second Life for 10 years, and I’ll continue to do so, in exactly the way that I want, with complete disregard for what people like this think. Because they need hobbies. They need things to occupy themselves.</p>

<p>They remind me of the people who walk into Walmarts with shitty attitudes, who yell at staff about pricing, and about item availability, and then stomp their feet and whine like a baby.</p>

<p>Because that’s what they are.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Second-Life" /><category term="secondlife" /><category term="metaverse" /><category term="creators" /><category term="stores" /><category term="virtualworld" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[In Second Life, anyone can be a creator, and make their creations available to the virtual world for purchase, and some have found major success with this. Others, it exists, maybe, as more of a hobby. For me, that’s mostly what it is, for now. But this all comes with a downside, because, like in the real world, the customer sometimes thinks they know best, and if you’ve ever worked retail, you know how very wrong that is.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">MKMO (mkultra.monster) Now Blocks Federation with Threads, Once, and For All</title><link href="https://nova.mkultra.monster/social-media/2025/01/07/mkmo-mkultra-monster-now-blocks-federation-with-threads-once-and-for-all.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="MKMO (mkultra.monster) Now Blocks Federation with Threads, Once, and For All" /><published>2025-01-07T13:21:00-05:00</published><updated>2025-01-07T13:21:00-05:00</updated><id>https://nova.mkultra.monster/social-media/2025/01/07/mkmo-mkultra-monster-now-blocks-federation-with-threads-once-and-for-all</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://nova.mkultra.monster/social-media/2025/01/07/mkmo-mkultra-monster-now-blocks-federation-with-threads-once-and-for-all.html"><![CDATA[<p>As per <a class="pages-link" href="https://nova.mkultra.monster/social-media/2025/01/07/meta-to-end-fact-checking-to-become-twitter-2-or-3">my last post</a> this morning (in regard to Meta’s loosening of moderation, as if it wasn’t already loose enough), I, as the admin of <a href="https://mkultra.monster" target="_blank">mkultra.monster</a>, will be blocking federation with Threads. For a long period of time, I hadn’t been doing this, partially because I don’t like bandwagons, and also because there are <em>regular, decent</em> people on Threads that I personally wanted to see. But, now it’s a bit more than a lost cause, and the social network is nothing <em>but</em> a detriment to the open social web.</p>

<p>The people I liked seeing updates from will just have to move to Mastodon, or some other fediverse software.</p>

<p>But, the other reason I wanted to post this, is because there are a lot of people who trot out their reasoning, or why they’ve blocked them from the start. Whether it’s performative or not, I remained skeptical for a long period of time. Skeptical, because I have experience from within the fediverse of numerous people, moderators, and admins saying one thing, or that they <em>stand</em> for one thing, and then they do the opposite.</p>

<p>And this has made me <em>more</em> critical, <em>more</em> skeptical, and <em>more</em> distrusting of others.</p>

<p>Yes, I have spoken about this before, but since it’s been about a year or so (or more?) since this all happened, I want to <em>again</em> bring light to the actions of the administrator and moderation team behind the Mastodon instance … hackers.town.</p>

<p>It was some time around August 25th of 2023, that I was posting on my timeline over at HT about … I don’t know, something to do with how resilient my Macbook was. I was kind of stanning Apple real hard around that time, just because I enjoyed/liked their hardware. Never-the-less, a user by the name of 0xSH00T (who now, at least, appears to be banned and erased, over a <em>year</em> later) jumped in to make some vitriolic remarks about myself, my having posted on the timeline, and my choice in hardware.</p>

<p>It was a <em>stupid</em> thing to get angry about, and it was a <em>stupid</em> thing to troll someone over.</p>

<p>He escalated, <em>I</em> escalated, and I don’t claim to be of perfect cognitive or mental health. <em>I have my issues</em>, and I deal with them.</p>

<p>I told him, and I quote, “Go fuck yourself, eat a pile of dicks and delete your goddamn account.”</p>

<p>Yes, this is kind of … haha, ANGRY.</p>

<p>And I had every right to be.</p>

<p>In a direct message that no longer contains the originating message from the admin (@thegibson), I responded, “I’m here minding my own business mostly just talking to myself, and this person comes into my mentions swinging, I’m not tolerating any both sides-ing bullshit. Delete the instigator or I’m out.”</p>

<p>Because, he and his mod-team, very much <em>were</em> playing the “both sides” card. In response to a troll, who was, in fact, instigating a fight.</p>

<p>I didn’t really <em>want</em> to leave hackers.town (and I wouldn’t have, anyway, I just wanted the troll to, at minimum, be moderated). I was in a blood-haze, and kind of spiraling a bit. Just like when it happened on the instance over at deadinsi.de, where just about the same things had gone on, and the admin and moderator team had a lapse in judgment. That’s … that’s what we’ll call it, I guess.</p>

<p>I made an off-the-cuff post about PTSD, I told Gibson again something like, “either you ban this asshole, or you ban me” and rather than doing any real moderation work, I was, of course, banned.</p>

<p>This was not the outcome I <em>thought</em> would take place. At least not at the time.</p>

<p>Again, I was spiraling. I was in a much worse mental place than I am now.</p>

<p><em>Of course</em>, I shouldn’t have been banned. If someone is having a break in mental health, and spiraling out (crashing out, as the zoomers would say) over being harassed over and over, as a responsible administrator, or moderator, <em>you take action against the instigator, no matter the personal relationship you hold with them.</em></p>

<p>Over this <em>tiny</em>, insignificant instance of abuse, I lost <em>years</em> of my presence on the fediverse, <em>indefinitely</em>. There were never any talks or apologies once the dust had settled. There was never any further action taken, appeals never read, never looked at, never considered. And yet, for <em>whatever reason</em>, my account still stands, frozen in time (suspended, but viewable), and now linking to my account on my own instance … <em>where this type of thing will never happen</em>.</p>

<p>You cannot call yourself an instance, a server, that is tolerant, and forward-thinking, and “for the people,” if your personal relationships come first. Especially if those personal relationships are with instigative assholes who shouldn’t exist on your platform. This is going to sound really self-absorbed, but <em>I am a better administrator and moderator than anyone at hackers.town by 1000 miles,</em> and I will stand by that, into the future. Because I will never let this happen.</p>

<p>Even if my server is only ever myself, and one other person, trolls will never gain the upper-hand, because I will never make excuses for anyone who’s being a shit.</p>

<p>And that’s why, when people start posting on the federated timeline, about how bad you are if you don’t, or haven’t had Threads blocked, I have to stop and question: Is there an ulterior motive here? Should I <em>care</em> what any of these people think? What have they done in their positions that they likely haven’t answered for?</p>

<p>And, thankfully, in a lot of instances, none of this applies. They’re just thoughts … most of the time.</p>

<p>But there are people out there in the fediverse who are <em>just as bad</em> as the people you’d hope to escape by leaving Twitter, or Threads, and I think it’s important to realize that no place is perfect. The open social web, Mastodon, and ActivityPub is something I will continue to, and <em>always</em> support. But … it’s important to know that it’s not all just roses and candy.</p>

<p>Jerks, and people not fit to moderate, exist, <em>everywhere</em>.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Social-Media" /><category term="mastodon" /><category term="fediverse" /><category term="meta" /><category term="threads" /><category term="facebook" /><category term="instagram" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[As per my last post this morning (in regard to Meta’s loosening of moderation, as if it wasn’t already loose enough), I, as the admin of mkultra.monster, will be blocking federation with Threads. For a long period of time, I hadn’t been doing this, partially because I don’t like bandwagons, and also because there are regular, decent people on Threads that I personally wanted to see. But, now it’s a bit more than a lost cause, and the social network is nothing but a detriment to the open social web.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Meta to End Fact-Checking to Become Twitter 2, or 3?</title><link href="https://nova.mkultra.monster/social-media/2025/01/07/meta-to-end-fact-checking-to-become-twitter-2-or-3.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Meta to End Fact-Checking to Become Twitter 2, or 3?" /><published>2025-01-07T10:37:00-05:00</published><updated>2025-01-07T10:37:00-05:00</updated><id>https://nova.mkultra.monster/social-media/2025/01/07/meta-to-end-fact-checking-to-become-twitter-2-or-3</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://nova.mkultra.monster/social-media/2025/01/07/meta-to-end-fact-checking-to-become-twitter-2-or-3.html"><![CDATA[<p>We all (or most of us) remember when Musk took over Twitter. People got fired, the website became increasingly unstable, the algorithm got tweaked to be less “biased” toward fascist propaganda, lies, and hate, and then everyone left in droves. Then, in response to this, Meta launched Threads, a Twitter alternative. And it was actually <em>nice</em> … for a time. About a year ago. But then Trump got elected, and like billionaires do, Marky Knuckleburger decided that it was time to pander, by eliminating safe-guards against the exact same things that turned Twitter into 4chan 2.</p>

<div class="threads-container">
<blockquote class="text-post-media" data-text-post-permalink="https://www.threads.net/@zuck/post/DEhgZJYJu5D" data-text-post-version="0" id="ig-tp-DEhgZJYJu5D" style=" background:#FFF; border-width: 1px; border-style: solid; border-color: #00000026; border-radius: 16px; max-width:540px; margin: 1px; min-width:270px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);"> <a href="https://www.threads.net/@zuck/post/DEhgZJYJu5D" style=" background:#FFFFFF; line-height:0; padding:0 0; text-align:center; text-decoration:none; width:100%; font-family: -apple-system, BlinkMacSystemFont, sans-serif;" target="_blank"> <div style=" padding: 40px; display: flex; flex-direction: column; align-items: center;"><div style=" display:block; height:32px; width:32px; padding-bottom:20px;"> <svg aria-label="Threads" height="32px" role="img" viewBox="0 0 192 192" width="32px" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg"> <path d="M141.537 88.9883C140.71 88.5919 139.87 88.2104 139.019 87.8451C137.537 60.5382 122.616 44.905 97.5619 44.745C97.4484 44.7443 97.3355 44.7443 97.222 44.7443C82.2364 44.7443 69.7731 51.1409 62.102 62.7807L75.881 72.2328C81.6116 63.5383 90.6052 61.6848 97.2286 61.6848C97.3051 61.6848 97.3819 61.6848 97.4576 61.6855C105.707 61.7381 111.932 64.1366 115.961 68.814C118.893 72.2193 120.854 76.925 121.825 82.8638C114.511 81.6207 106.601 81.2385 98.145 81.7233C74.3247 83.0954 59.0111 96.9879 60.0396 116.292C60.5615 126.084 65.4397 134.508 73.775 140.011C80.8224 144.663 89.899 146.938 99.3323 146.423C111.79 145.74 121.563 140.987 128.381 132.296C133.559 125.696 136.834 117.143 138.28 106.366C144.217 109.949 148.617 114.664 151.047 120.332C155.179 129.967 155.42 145.8 142.501 158.708C131.182 170.016 117.576 174.908 97.0135 175.059C74.2042 174.89 56.9538 167.575 45.7381 153.317C35.2355 139.966 29.8077 120.682 29.6052 96C29.8077 71.3178 35.2355 52.0336 45.7381 38.6827C56.9538 24.4249 74.2039 17.11 97.0132 16.9405C119.988 17.1113 137.539 24.4614 149.184 38.788C154.894 45.8136 159.199 54.6488 162.037 64.9503L178.184 60.6422C174.744 47.9622 169.331 37.0357 161.965 27.974C147.036 9.60668 125.202 0.195148 97.0695 0H96.9569C68.8816 0.19447 47.2921 9.6418 32.7883 28.0793C19.8819 44.4864 13.2244 67.3157 13.0007 95.9325L13 96L13.0007 96.0675C13.2244 124.684 19.8819 147.514 32.7883 163.921C47.2921 182.358 68.8816 191.806 96.9569 192H97.0695C122.03 191.827 139.624 185.292 154.118 170.811C173.081 151.866 172.51 128.119 166.26 113.541C161.776 103.087 153.227 94.5962 141.537 88.9883ZM98.4405 129.507C88.0005 130.095 77.1544 125.409 76.6196 115.372C76.2232 107.93 81.9158 99.626 99.0812 98.6368C101.047 98.5234 102.976 98.468 104.871 98.468C111.106 98.468 116.939 99.0737 122.242 100.233C120.264 124.935 108.662 128.946 98.4405 129.507Z" /></svg></div><div style=" font-size: 15px; line-height: 21px; color: #000000; font-weight: 600; "> View on Threads</div></div></a></blockquote>
<script async="" src="https://www.threads.net/embed.js"></script>
</div>

<p>I’m not saying that community notes on Twitter have been a <em>bad thing</em>, because they’ve actually been pretty funny when its been used against liars and people who fabricate situations in order to embolden hate. But, it’s the context, and the reasons you have to look at. Mack Fucklenarg has never been genuine or progressively-inclined about anything he’s ever done. From building The Facebook, which was originally <a href="https://www.eviemagazine.com/post/before-facebook-zuckerberg-created-a-girl-rating-site-facemash" target="_blank">a website used to rate the “hotness” of girls in college</a>, to seemingly condemning the acts of the January 6th terrorists.</p>

<p><img src="/img/posts/meta-censors/jan6.jpg" /></p>

<p>This was, and you guessed it, manipulative pandering to the incoming administration.</p>

<p>Fark Bafflenard doesn’t have <em>any core beliefs</em>. Like all billionaires, he follows the money, and he follows his own interests in not wanting to be potentially arrested and imprisoned by the currently incoming administration. It is only a complete coincidence if your beliefs and your virtues <em>ever</em> line up with what Mark Zugzugsomethingneeddoing is currently doing, or saying.</p>

<p>Right now, those actions are lining up with the same criminals and potential mass shooters that Twitter harbors. And that’s a bad thing. A bad thing for people who enjoy posting within a civilized atmosphere that at least attempts to pretend that we’re living in 2025, and not 1825.</p>

<p>If, in 4 years, a straight-up communist is somehow elected, I’m almost entirely <em>sure</em> that Marky-Mark would make statements on how Meta and its properties will release control of its production means to its users.</p>

<p>It’s just as pathetic as Diamond-Mine Musk using memes from 15 years ago in an attempt to impress neo nazis who are in their 40s and 50s.</p>

<p>Men who go through life believing in nothing, who hold insurmountable amounts of power over mass amounts of people, will be the downfall of civilized society.</p>

<p>But, despite all of Meta’s mistakes, its family of apps hold more than <a href="https://variety.com/2024/digital/news/meta-q4-2023-earnings-record-revenue-monthly-users-1235894587/" target="_blank">3.98 billion users</a> (as of February 1st, 2024), and that’s a staggering amount of people. That’s about half of the entire world’s popu-frikken-lation. And while I’ve seen the usual round of people promising they’re moving to Bluesky (which is honestly not even much better of a platform), I don’t think there is <em>any way</em> in any shape or form, that you will <em>ever</em> convince half the world’s population to join Mastodon, or even the Twitter-carbon-copy, Bluesky.</p>

<p>Like with most things, the average user only cares about ease of use, and if you can sign up for Threads by already having an Instagram account, that eliminates the process of even just setting up an account. You’re already there! An advantage that Meta has over <em>all other platforms</em>. And this is why I think it is incredibly important that Mastodon, and other ActivityPub apps and projects, work toward simplifying the onboarding process even more than they already have.</p>

<p>It is imperative to get as many people off of propaganda platforms as humanly possible, because, the annoying people from 2017 Tumblr … were correct, after-all.</p>

<p><img src="/img/posts/meta-censors/propaganda.png" /></p>]]></content><author><name>𐕣 C M D R ░ NOVA 𐕣</name></author><category term="Social-Media" /><category term="meta" /><category term="threads" /><category term="facebook" /><category term="instagram" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[We all (or most of us) remember when Musk took over Twitter. People got fired, the website became increasingly unstable, the algorithm got tweaked to be less “biased” toward fascist propaganda, lies, and hate, and then everyone left in droves. Then, in response to this, Meta launched Threads, a Twitter alternative. And it was actually nice … for a time. About a year ago. But then Trump got elected, and like billionaires do, Marky Knuckleburger decided that it was time to pander, by eliminating safe-guards against the exact same things that turned Twitter into 4chan 2.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Second Life: [REVOSA] Has Moved!</title><link href="https://nova.mkultra.monster/second-life/2025/01/06/irsecond-life-revosa-has-moved.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Second Life: [REVOSA] Has Moved!" /><published>2025-01-06T13:18:00-05:00</published><updated>2025-01-06T13:18:00-05:00</updated><id>https://nova.mkultra.monster/second-life/2025/01/06/irsecond-life-revosa-has-moved</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://nova.mkultra.monster/second-life/2025/01/06/irsecond-life-revosa-has-moved.html"><![CDATA[<p>Keeping up with my finnicky tradition of always moving my store around in Second Life about once every six months (at this point), I’ve transferred land ownership back to the account that <em>actually runs the store</em>, and moved to a better parcel! This comes, after realizing I made a huge mistake with my finances in relation to Linden Labs, and being someone who uses <em>multiple accounts</em>. That’s a big oof on my part.</p>

<p>Still with all the same products, and room to add more, you can now find my Second Life store, in-world, <a href="http://maps.secondlife.com/secondlife/Necrotee/218/233/3551" target="_blank">here</a>.</p>

<p>I made this move, because I wasn’t too happy with the tiny amount of space I had in the old spot, and I was shuffling around expenses and found out … I’ve been paying Linden Labs for a large amount of land for probably <em>well over a year</em>, unknowingly. Being that, I somehow <em>forgot</em> that I was doing this. So, I moved everything around, found a new location, put the store online <em>in that new location</em>, and then turned off all transactions on my alt account.</p>

<p>Now … the only account paying for anything, <em>should be the account running the store!</em></p>

<p>Whew.</p>

<p>Anyway, on-wards and forwards into the new year!</p>]]></content><author><name>𐕣 C M D R ░ NOVA 𐕣</name></author><category term="Second-Life" /><category term="secondlife" /><category term="revosa" /><category term="metaverse" /><category term="virtualworld" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Keeping up with my finnicky tradition of always moving my store around in Second Life about once every six months (at this point), I’ve transferred land ownership back to the account that actually runs the store, and moved to a better parcel! This comes, after realizing I made a huge mistake with my finances in relation to Linden Labs, and being someone who uses multiple accounts. That’s a big oof on my part.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Ironic Use of AI Just Means You’re Not Funny</title><link href="https://nova.mkultra.monster/tech/2025/01/06/ironic-use-of-ai-just-means-you-re-not-funny.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Ironic Use of AI Just Means You’re Not Funny" /><published>2025-01-06T09:32:00-05:00</published><updated>2025-01-06T09:32:00-05:00</updated><id>https://nova.mkultra.monster/tech/2025/01/06/ironic-use-of-ai-just-means-you-re-not-funny</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://nova.mkultra.monster/tech/2025/01/06/ironic-use-of-ai-just-means-you-re-not-funny.html"><![CDATA[<p>We’ve all seen it at this point: Chronic shitposters (largely coming from Bluesky) using AI generated imagery to poke fun at the incoming administration, or <em>generative slop users themselves</em>. And, every single time, I imagine these people think they’re doing something productive, or revolutionary, or funny. But here’s the news flash: You’re not. If you wouldn’t use blockchain tech, or buy NFTs in 2022, then you shouldn’t be generating sludge as a joke, either.</p>

<p>Situations like this remind of me old Mastodon instances in the pre-2020 era of the fediverse, that were erected solely for “shitposting.” They start out funny, or mildly annoying (because, let’s face it, if the only thing you ever post is incoherent jokes, you become tiring after about a day), and usually mostly politically left-leaning. Then, the jokes get worse, and worse. And suddenly, the instance is being flooded with neo nazis and predators, because you decided that ironic fascist jokes weren’t over-the-line. And now you’re just no different than them.</p>

<p>I can just vaguely recall Mastodon instances that were shutdown within months of opening, such as bofa.lol, kazink, and so on. And shitposters.club, a currently active server that is instance-blocked by <em>most</em> instances across the fediverse. <em>All guilty of exactly the same things</em>.</p>

<p>Why do I bring up this comparison?</p>

<p>Partially, because I have a personal grudge against people whose entire personality is shitty jokes (see: the monumentally huge amount of harassment I’ve received on Bluesky for practically no reason at all, from people who have bad taste in humor and politics). But also, because this is an extremely predictable pipeline that <em>always leads to opening the door for undesirables (fascists, crypto-brained losers, sludge-enjoyers)</em>.</p>

<p>This isn’t even the only reason you shouldn’t do this, though! Making yourself indistinguishable from people who have no qualms with the destruction of human creativity, and art is, <em>bad enough</em>, but then you also have to take into account the harm you’re causing the <em>actual literal planet every single time you make a prompt</em>.</p>

<p>Quote from <a href="https://www.watertechnologies.com/blog/artificial-intelligence-using-ton-water-heres-how-be-more-resourceful" target="_blank">watertech.com</a>:</p>

<blockquote>
Artificial intelligence (AI) quickly went from a neat parlor trick to a business imperative. IBM reports that 82% of large enterprises have either deployed AI or are experimenting with doing so. Unlike other technology innovations like smartphones or WiFi networks, AI isn’t a one-time integration. The technology is constantly evolving with new models and capabilities.
<br />
<br />
Each time these AI tools are prompted, there’s a cost that few consider. Researchers believe that each string of prompts uses roughly 16 ounces of water at data centers that house these AI systems. Extrapolate AI use globally, and it’s clear how water systems are taxed. Microsoft’s latest environmental report shows its water consumption jumped 34% from 2021 to 2022, reaching nearly 1.7 billion gallons. Google reports its water consumption went up nearly 22% over the same period to a staggering 5.56 billion gallons, about 800 times as big as The Lincoln Memorial reflecting pool.
</blockquote>

<p>And that doesn’t even mention the carbon dioxide generated from the fossil-fuel powered electricity that we use, that <em>has already been melting the ice caps for about fifty to sixty years, or more</em>.</p>

<p>Some of these people might argue that you do the same amount of harm by charging your smartphone, or running a microwave. But, if that’s true (and those were just crude examples), why in the world would you feel it necessary to <em>double</em> the harm you’re doing by generating some uncanny-valley sludge in response to racist propaganda?</p>

<blockquote class="bluesky-embed" data-bluesky-uri="at://did:plc:pga3jfwjqmilx3od5hsjccty/app.bsky.feed.post/3lf23bad6g222" data-bluesky-cid="bafyreiexgtfgdwrtsr2bddhdk6eby3p3hnafe2qqr2tehhw5bvyyfy4ehm"><p lang="en">OK, it&#x27;s AI...but much truer than Haitians eating your dogs and cats!<br /><br /><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/did:plc:pga3jfwjqmilx3od5hsjccty/post/3lf23bad6g222?ref_src=embed">[image or embed]</a></p>&mdash; eugene (<a href="https://bsky.app/profile/did:plc:pga3jfwjqmilx3od5hsjccty?ref_src=embed">@eugene290390.bsky.social</a>) <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/did:plc:pga3jfwjqmilx3od5hsjccty/post/3lf23bad6g222?ref_src=embed">January 5, 2025 at 9:22 PM</a></blockquote>
<script async="" src="https://embed.bsky.app/static/embed.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>Oh, I see, it’s <em>funny</em>, because Donald Trump is just a drooling baby and Elon Musk is the actual sitting president. Ah.</p>

<p>And you couldn’t have dictated your little joke with <em>words</em>, and a little bit of stock footage? Or, remembered that Joe Biden is still currently in the White House (as of posting this)?</p>

<p>To give some closing perspective, here are some websites and communities that have been willingly (by their creators) destroyed by generative AI.</p>

<ul>
  <li>
    <p><a href="https://www.deviantart.com/tag/ai" target="_blank">DeviantArt</a>: Once a place for artists to share their work, and even sell it, now overrun by inauthentic slop.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p><a href="https://www.etsy.com/seller-handbook/article/1275449912004" target="_blank">Etsy</a>: Once a place for creatives to make money off of the things they make, and do, now a place where you can use algorithmically stolen work, that <em>can’t legally even be copyrighted</em> to make money off the backs of those <em>same exact people</em>.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p><a href="https://www.wired.com/story/nanowrimo-organizers-classist-and-ableist-to-condemn-ai/" target="_blank">NaNoWriMo</a>: Once a fun community event about writing for yourself a 50,000 word novel in the month of November, now fully endorses plagiarism bots. And this is a <em>special</em> case, because they <em>originally</em> called those who are against AI <em>ableist</em>, for not wanting plagiarism and creative theft in writing spaces. And then they doubled back and deleted that statement, and edited it to talk down to those critical of AI as if they’re our angry parents.</p>
  </li>
</ul>

<p>And that’s just to name a few. There are many more spaces and communities that either have already been destroyed by the continuing enshitification of anything good that’s left in the world, by big tech companies, or those that are currently being targeted. This is why <em>so many people</em> have been fleeing corporate social media. And the <em>last</em> thing you should do, is bring it with you, in the form of bad jokes and a vitriolic personality, <em>just to be ironic</em> on Bluesky, or even <em>Mastodon</em>.</p>

<p>Don’t be <em>that</em> douche.</p>]]></content><author><name>𐕣 C M D R ░ NOVA 𐕣</name></author><category term="Tech" /><category term="ai" /><category term="tech" /><category term="bluesky" /><category term="mastodon" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[We’ve all seen it at this point: Chronic shitposters (largely coming from Bluesky) using AI generated imagery to poke fun at the incoming administration, or generative slop users themselves. And, every single time, I imagine these people think they’re doing something productive, or revolutionary, or funny. But here’s the news flash: You’re not. If you wouldn’t use blockchain tech, or buy NFTs in 2022, then you shouldn’t be generating sludge as a joke, either.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Meta Experiments with Digital Blackface</title><link href="https://nova.mkultra.monster/social-media/2025/01/04/meta-experiments-with-digital-blackface.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Meta Experiments with Digital Blackface" /><published>2025-01-04T09:52:00-05:00</published><updated>2025-01-04T09:52:00-05:00</updated><id>https://nova.mkultra.monster/social-media/2025/01/04/meta-experiments-with-digital-blackface</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://nova.mkultra.monster/social-media/2025/01/04/meta-experiments-with-digital-blackface.html"><![CDATA[<p>So, last week, I wrote about <a href="/tech/2024/12/30/the-dead-internet-comes-to-life.html">Meta inadvertently planning to confirm the “Dead Internet Theory,”</a> with cringy fake people (AI bots), and how enthusiastic the Zuck was about all of this, despite there being no value, or any verifiable <em>reason</em> for it all to exist. And, almost <em>immediately</em> afterward, scores of people began planning their move away from Threads across the platform (post-2023 social media is just a game of digital hot potato). Other users scoured Instagram and Facebook to find a slew of 20 some bots … including a fake black woman pretending to have a family, and culture.</p>

<p><img src="/img/posts/meta-dead/liv.png" /></p>

<p>As it turns out, these weren’t actually the bots that Meta was planning to implement, rather, they were experiments from over a year ago that nobody noticed and/or completely ignored, until Mark started to bring attention to his next, biggest, worst decision. These profiles are now deleted, as complaints were made against the accounts … <em>because you couldn’t block them</em>, and due to major backlash, in-general.</p>

<p>Via <a href="https://www.404media.co/metas-ai-profiles-are-indistinguishable-from-terrible-spam-that-took-over-facebook/" target="_blank">404 Media</a>:</p>

<blockquote>
"There is confusion: the recent Financial Times article was about our vision for AI characters existing on our platforms over time, not announcing any new product," Sweeney said. "The accounts referenced are from a test we launched at Connect in 2023. These were managed by humans and were part of an early experiment we did with AI characters. We identified the bug that was impacting the ability for people to block those AIs and are removing those accounts to fix the issue.” 
</blockquote>

<p>But, the aforementioned “Liv” wasn’t Meta’s only experiment with making racist caricatures, as Threads user krenaep details, with a completely different, and also now deleted account, named “Jade.”</p>

<div class="threads-container">
<blockquote class="text-post-media" data-text-post-permalink="https://www.threads.net/@krenaep/post/DEYPd_qvd69" data-text-post-version="0" id="ig-tp-DEYPd_qvd69" style=" background:#FFF; border-width: 1px; border-style: solid; border-color: #00000026; border-radius: 16px; max-width:540px; margin: 1px; min-width:270px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);"> <a href="https://www.threads.net/@krenaep/post/DEYPd_qvd69" style=" background:#FFFFFF; line-height:0; padding:0 0; text-align:center; text-decoration:none; width:100%; font-family: -apple-system, BlinkMacSystemFont, sans-serif;" target="_blank"> <div style=" padding: 40px; display: flex; flex-direction: column; align-items: center;"><div style=" display:block; height:32px; width:32px; padding-bottom:20px;"> <svg aria-label="Threads" height="32px" role="img" viewBox="0 0 192 192" width="32px" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg"> <path d="M141.537 88.9883C140.71 88.5919 139.87 88.2104 139.019 87.8451C137.537 60.5382 122.616 44.905 97.5619 44.745C97.4484 44.7443 97.3355 44.7443 97.222 44.7443C82.2364 44.7443 69.7731 51.1409 62.102 62.7807L75.881 72.2328C81.6116 63.5383 90.6052 61.6848 97.2286 61.6848C97.3051 61.6848 97.3819 61.6848 97.4576 61.6855C105.707 61.7381 111.932 64.1366 115.961 68.814C118.893 72.2193 120.854 76.925 121.825 82.8638C114.511 81.6207 106.601 81.2385 98.145 81.7233C74.3247 83.0954 59.0111 96.9879 60.0396 116.292C60.5615 126.084 65.4397 134.508 73.775 140.011C80.8224 144.663 89.899 146.938 99.3323 146.423C111.79 145.74 121.563 140.987 128.381 132.296C133.559 125.696 136.834 117.143 138.28 106.366C144.217 109.949 148.617 114.664 151.047 120.332C155.179 129.967 155.42 145.8 142.501 158.708C131.182 170.016 117.576 174.908 97.0135 175.059C74.2042 174.89 56.9538 167.575 45.7381 153.317C35.2355 139.966 29.8077 120.682 29.6052 96C29.8077 71.3178 35.2355 52.0336 45.7381 38.6827C56.9538 24.4249 74.2039 17.11 97.0132 16.9405C119.988 17.1113 137.539 24.4614 149.184 38.788C154.894 45.8136 159.199 54.6488 162.037 64.9503L178.184 60.6422C174.744 47.9622 169.331 37.0357 161.965 27.974C147.036 9.60668 125.202 0.195148 97.0695 0H96.9569C68.8816 0.19447 47.2921 9.6418 32.7883 28.0793C19.8819 44.4864 13.2244 67.3157 13.0007 95.9325L13 96L13.0007 96.0675C13.2244 124.684 19.8819 147.514 32.7883 163.921C47.2921 182.358 68.8816 191.806 96.9569 192H97.0695C122.03 191.827 139.624 185.292 154.118 170.811C173.081 151.866 172.51 128.119 166.26 113.541C161.776 103.087 153.227 94.5962 141.537 88.9883ZM98.4405 129.507C88.0005 130.095 77.1544 125.409 76.6196 115.372C76.2232 107.93 81.9158 99.626 99.0812 98.6368C101.047 98.5234 102.976 98.468 104.871 98.468C111.106 98.468 116.939 99.0737 122.242 100.233C120.264 124.935 108.662 128.946 98.4405 129.507Z" /></svg></div><div style=" font-size: 15px; line-height: 21px; color: #000000; font-weight: 600; "> View on Threads</div></div></a></blockquote>
<script async="" src="https://www.threads.net/embed.js"></script>
</div>

<p>It seems these bots were completely willing to de-mask their creators, showing us that both of these accounts, and the others, were all constructed by a team of mostly white guys. Which, and I’m not a genius or anything, but, looks <em>real</em> bad, chief. But it <em>does</em> further the conversation as to <em>what exactly</em> the goal was, or <em>is</em> with these things. Some have said the the goal is to “drive engagement,” but, to what end, and how? You going to use AI to boost real human beings?</p>

<p>Or, you’re going to ask content creators to use your AI tools in order to develop caricatures of themselves that can interact with people <em>for them</em>, thereby discouraging human interaction on a social media platform. Because if there’s anything billionaires hate more than losing a single cent to paying their <em>goddamn taxes</em>, it’s regular, <em>real</em> human beings, who still have functioning frontal lobes. And the assumption, is, I guess, that <em>everyone else must be like this, too</em>.</p>

<p><img src="/img/posts/meta-dead/tools.png" /></p>

<p>In the age of tomfoolery, and fuckery, and generative slop that guzzles gallons of fresh water <em>every single time</em> you make a prompt, I think it’s important to <em>begin</em> the move away from corporate social media. If you can. Albeit, I do exist on Meta social media, and that’s entirely for my own reasons–I’m conflicted, and I have work that I’d like to reach more than a few handfuls of people with, because I don’t want to work retail for the rest of my natural life, until I’m replaced by an AI bot that will inevitably hallucinate that I was <em>never actually born</em>.</p>

<p>But, this is your regular reminder that user-owned social media exists, and you have full control over the things you see, and interact with online … even if Meta will never truly delete or relinquish your data, no matter <em>what</em> you do with your accounts. And if we can get people en-masse to move to the protocol mentioned below, then maybe even <em>more</em> people will feel like they don’t have to keep one foot in the digital hell, and the other in the place where they actually want to be.</p>

<p>Ways to join Mastodon:</p>

<ul>
  <li>
    <p>Check out <a href="https://mastodon.social" target="_blank">mastodon.social</a>, the flagship instance that has the <em>most</em> people on it. This is good for people who don’t want to bother looking through different servers and simply want to give the place a try.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Check out <a href="https://mkultra.monster" target="_blank">my instance</a>, and submit a join request (please type a legible reason for joining with your request, so that I can distinguish you from bots).</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Or, <a href="https://jointhefediverse.net/?lang=en-us" target="_blank">surf through numerous different ActivityPub instances</a> that span even more than just Mastodon.</p>
  </li>
</ul>]]></content><author><name>𐕣 C M D R ░ NOVA 𐕣</name></author><category term="Social-media" /><category term="meta" /><category term="threads" /><category term="instagram" /><category term="facebook" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[So, last week, I wrote about Meta inadvertently planning to confirm the “Dead Internet Theory,” with cringy fake people (AI bots), and how enthusiastic the Zuck was about all of this, despite there being no value, or any verifiable reason for it all to exist. And, almost immediately afterward, scores of people began planning their move away from Threads across the platform (post-2023 social media is just a game of digital hot potato). Other users scoured Instagram and Facebook to find a slew of 20 some bots … including a fake black woman pretending to have a family, and culture.]]></summary></entry></feed>