<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en-US"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.10.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://mkultra.monster/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://mkultra.monster/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en-US" /><updated>2025-03-30T14:00:08-04:00</updated><id>https://mkultra.monster/feed.xml</id><title type="html">cmdr-nova@internet:~$</title><subtitle>cmdr-nova&apos;s personal blog and home on the indie-web.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Retro Net Goes Deeper Than You Think</title><link href="https://mkultra.monster/social-media/2025/03/28/retro-net-goes-deeper-than-you-think.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Retro Net Goes Deeper Than You Think" /><published>2025-03-28T06:06:28-04:00</published><updated>2025-03-28T06:06:28-04:00</updated><id>https://mkultra.monster/social-media/2025/03/28/retro-net-goes-deeper-than-you-think</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://mkultra.monster/social-media/2025/03/28/retro-net-goes-deeper-than-you-think.html"><![CDATA[<p>Queue Inception bwam sound. If you’ve been following my little journey in hollowing out a piece of the internet that isn’t annoying, dominated by corporations, and their engagement tricks, you’ve likely seen me popping up this website, erecting a phpBB forum, and you’ve probably also noticed that people all over the place are making GeoCities-ish type websites for fun! Well, the revival of the old-net goes even deeper than that.</p>

<p>Ever since Meta turned on Facebook, things have gotten worse, and worse. MySpace got sold off and changed into something completely different (a janky website for bands???). AOL Instant Messenger went offline, <em>for good</em>. Twitter plopped into the ether, Tumblr became a replacement for LiveJournal, and then for a decade everyone only visited four websites.</p>

<p>That was … until people got tired of the algorithms, and the disingenuous content of people and corps who use social media to pump stats and shun actual social interaction.</p>

<p>Out came Mastodon on the ActivityPub network, and, although ActivityPub existed for <em>a long time</em> before Mastodon’s rise, I feel like <em>this</em> is exactly where people started rebuilding, for <em>real</em>.</p>

<p>You see, the internet is a lot like space. You can build a wall. You can put up a ton of interstellar checkpoints that flash a million ads in your face as you navigate around each system. But, as soon as people realize that space is not a two dimensional plane, and that they can just, fly in a different direction, things start to change.</p>

<p>AOL Instant Messenger, reborn!</p>

<p>Exactly a year ago today, the <a href="https://github.com/mk6i/retro-aim-server" target="_blank">Retro AIM Server</a> repo appeared on Github. A project that effectively open sourced the AOL Instant Messenger servers. In that, <em>you</em>, or <em>anyone</em>, can just host a server that people can use the <em>actual</em> old software to connect to.</p>

<p>But you don’t need to do all of that.</p>

<p>All you need to do is use the links in the repo to download AIM to your system of choice. I’m on Linux, so I had to use Wine to open it. No biggie.</p>

<p>Then, you need a server, right?</p>

<p>I gotchu.</p>

<p>All you’ve got to do is <a href="https://sso.chivanet.org" target="_blank">go here</a>, and create an account. Then, in the AIM section, create your username and password.</p>

<p>You’re done!</p>

<p>Open the original AIM client, follow the instructions from the repo that tell you where to put your connection info, and sign on!</p>

<p>You’re back, or, if you were born in the 2000s, you’re here for the first time!</p>

<p>The <em>only</em> issue, is this is not something that’s on a billion person network. So … having buddies will not be something you … <em>have</em>, right away. But, that’s okay, because you can have me as your first buddy. My AIM name is Atomleiche.</p>

<p>Just click the “+/- setup” button on the bottom right, then click “add buddy” and type in my username. Then confirm it. If I’m online, you’ll hear the sound of a door opening, and then you can just double-click me and send a message!</p>

<p>It’s that simple!</p>

<p>And this is how it worked back on the old-net. You added buddies, and then when they came online, it was time chat. Or not! Some people would just add me back in the day to expand their list, I think. Who knows. But I had a whole lot of buddies, who I’m sure have completely different lives now. Maybe none of them think about this stuff anymore. Maybe they do!</p>

<p>I don’t know.</p>

<p>But, I feel like this is still only the beginning.</p>]]></content><author><name>⸸ commander ░ nova ⸸ :~$</name></author><category term="Social-Media" /><category term="social-media" /><category term="webdev" /><category term="internet" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Queue Inception bwam sound. If you’ve been following my little journey in hollowing out a piece of the internet that isn’t annoying, dominated by corporations, and their engagement tricks, you’ve likely seen me popping up this website, erecting a phpBB forum, and you’ve probably also noticed that people all over the place are making GeoCities-ish type websites for fun! Well, the revival of the old-net goes even deeper than that.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">A Summary Of The Past Three Days</title><link href="https://mkultra.monster/updates/2025/03/26/a-summary-of-the-past-three-days.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A Summary Of The Past Three Days" /><published>2025-03-26T15:10:24-04:00</published><updated>2025-03-26T15:10:24-04:00</updated><id>https://mkultra.monster/updates/2025/03/26/a-summary-of-the-past-three-days</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://mkultra.monster/updates/2025/03/26/a-summary-of-the-past-three-days.html"><![CDATA[<p>I’m at this point again, where, I’m having trouble thinking of things I want to write about. Not because there’s <em>nothing</em> to write about, but more-so that everything I <em>could</em> write about is mostly negative. Negative, like me visiting the forum I’ve endorsed over and over again (Melonland), and speaking out against the pro-AI users and their bad ideas, and then subsequently being moderated by <em>Melooon themselves</em>, is … discouraging, to say the least.</p>

<p>Read more on that, <a href="https://labyrinth.zone/notice/AsSifF0crLJyf1gsbI" target="_blank">here</a>.</p>

<p>I’ve since, unfortunately, scrubbed all mention of Melonland from this website. Not going to support someone (and their projects) who thinks it’s bad form to say, “These people should be mocked and shunned.”</p>

<p>And then I go on Bluesky, and it’s just a continual waterfall of “Laurelai Bailey this, Laurelai Bailey that,” as it goes, because she keeps gaining influence on every new platform that crops up, and apparently there’s nothing anyone can do about it. Due-in-part to the fact that the newest generation of trans people <em>have no idea who she is</em>, or any idea at all about the numerous crimes she’s committed, starting from sexual assault, years-long efforts in gaslighting and manipulating people, all the way up to divulging information to the FBI, and working hand-in-hand with admitted neo nazis, and sexual predators.</p>

<p>But, instead of deep-diving into either of these topics, I just want to summarize the last three days, before I’m shoved back into offline work, and my time is taken up by all of that, plus sleeping and being exhausted for the following next three days.</p>

<p>So, as you know, I’ve launched a forum over at <a href="https://forum.mkultra.monster" target="_blank">forums.mkultra.monster</a>. And there are many potential topics to engage in. I’ll be subsequently adding different things to the forum, as I write, and do <em>stuff</em>, as a way to document and archive <em>what</em> I’m doing, and also to encourage users to join, and start up a conversation.</p>

<p>This <em>may</em> be the hard part, but I’m mostly happy that I finally decided to <em>just make the forum</em> I’ve been wanting to make, whether people will use it or not.</p>

<p>I also took a whole bunch of painstaking hours, and added custom thumbnail images <em>to every single</em> forum, so that each has their own little dash of flavor.</p>

<p>The only issue I’m working through now, is that e-mail authentication and sending for accounts, <em>does not work at all</em>. I’ve tried using SendGrid’s SMTP credentials, and even Google’s SMTP credentials.</p>

<p>So far, this has resulted in … <em>Nothing</em>.</p>

<p>In the meantime, you don’t <em>need</em> e-mail authentication to sign up, but, you <em>will</em> need to remember your password, since the only way to recover it is via e-mail. Which currently does not work.</p>

<p>I’ll be investigating via the official PHPBB forums to figure out why this is the one pain-point of putting together a forum.</p>

<p>Otherwise … that’s basically it! That’s how I’ve spent the past three days!</p>

<p>And, continual negative stuff aside, I hope that I’m able to continue building from here, in my quest to bring back and isolate parts of nineties internet culture that were thought to be dead long ago.</p>]]></content><author><name>⸸ commander ░ nova ⸸ :~$</name></author><category term="Updates" /><category term="thoughts" /><category term="updates" /><category term="webdev" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[I’m at this point again, where, I’m having trouble thinking of things I want to write about. Not because there’s nothing to write about, but more-so that everything I could write about is mostly negative. Negative, like me visiting the forum I’ve endorsed over and over again (Melonland), and speaking out against the pro-AI users and their bad ideas, and then subsequently being moderated by Melooon themselves, is … discouraging, to say the least.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Speaking Of Forums</title><link href="https://mkultra.monster/webdev/2025/03/25/speaking-of-forums.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Speaking Of Forums" /><published>2025-03-25T01:26:30-04:00</published><updated>2025-03-25T01:26:30-04:00</updated><id>https://mkultra.monster/webdev/2025/03/25/speaking-of-forums</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://mkultra.monster/webdev/2025/03/25/speaking-of-forums.html"><![CDATA[<p>Earlier last night, I wrote about how I don’t know, or don’t think that discussion forums can be saved. And, I thought about it for a while. How do I know something can’t be saved, if I haven’t tried to fix the problem myself? So, I launched my own old-school PHPBB forum!</p>

<p>Basically, at <a href="https://forum.mkultra.monster" target="_blank">MKULTRA Board</a>, I copy/pasted a <em>huge</em> part of <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20010401015509/http://animeboards.com:80/" target="_blank">the old anime forum</a> I used to be part of back in 1999-2001 (somewhere in that era), and then added my own things.</p>

<p>I did this, because I’ve missed it greatly. So much so, that, <em>years back</em>, I contacted the original owner and asked if he’d be willing to part with the database and software, so that it could be resurrected. Unfortunately, if I recall, he wasn’t too interested in doing that, or felt like it would be too much of a hassle, or cost too greatly.</p>

<p>I don’t know about that. I’m running the new forum on a 16 dollar VPS, and it’s pretty smooth!</p>

<p>Now, obviously, if, <em>for some reason</em>, it attracts thousands of people, then <em>yes</em>, it would require much more in hosting.</p>

<p>But, here’s <em>something</em>. Will you register and begin the discussion?</p>]]></content><author><name>⸸ commander ░ nova ⸸ :~$</name></author><category term="Webdev" /><category term="webdev" /><category term="community" /><category term="forums" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Earlier last night, I wrote about how I don’t know, or don’t think that discussion forums can be saved. And, I thought about it for a while. How do I know something can’t be saved, if I haven’t tried to fix the problem myself? So, I launched my own old-school PHPBB forum!]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Is It Too Late To Save Discussion Forums?</title><link href="https://mkultra.monster/web/2025/03/24/is-it-too-late-to-save-discussion-forums.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Is It Too Late To Save Discussion Forums?" /><published>2025-03-24T17:36:40-04:00</published><updated>2025-03-24T17:36:40-04:00</updated><id>https://mkultra.monster/web/2025/03/24/is-it-too-late-to-save-discussion-forums</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://mkultra.monster/web/2025/03/24/is-it-too-late-to-save-discussion-forums.html"><![CDATA[<p>I was reading this article from [a website] that will not be named, since they used and credited Midjourney for images in their article, and we don’t do that. As people who care about artists and the work they do, we don’t generate sludge, and then also credit the theft machines that are making sludge for us, okay? But anyway, the article was about how we need to <em>save</em> discussion forums, and that Reddit and Discord are killing them (a conversation that feels ten years too late). But, <em>is it</em> too late to talk about this?</p>

<p>I’ve personally gone on tangents on here a few times already about how nostalgic I am for the era of the internet when people were less accessible, not <em>always around</em>, and the web was something you explored. How discussion forums were the <em>main</em> place you gathered to form communities, and that these places <em>weren’t</em> a thing with millions of people, but more like hundreds, and rarely, <em>sometimes</em>, thousands.</p>

<p>I’ve also talked about how one of my favorite forums to visit, the mirror of forums of yore, is <a href="https://forum.melonland.net" target="_blank">Melonland</a> (mostly for retro webdevs and community around that topic).</p>

<p>You might say, “What do you mean they’re dying? We have Discourse for modern forum software!”</p>

<p>But, I don’t <em>like</em> Discourse all that much. It doesn’t <em>feel</em> like a forum. It feels like … I don’t know. Something <em>else</em>, entirely.</p>

<p>It feels like modern webdevs who are constantly trying to modernize <em>every single</em> web system that has ever existed, as if <em>something was wrong</em> with the way things were once presented to us, online. There was nothing wrong with PHPBB. We don’t need forums that look like a Slack meeting.</p>

<p><img src="/img/posts/save-forums/discourse.png" /></p>

<p>Just like there was <em>nothing wrong</em> with AOL Instant Messenger. AOL <em>totally</em> could have continued developing it, with its current UI, to run much the same way Discord does. That would’ve been neat, huh?</p>

<p>But then Discord <em>did</em> come along, and with instant messaging, they brought servers, and with servers, they also brought channels that you can setup as some bastardized rip of what a forum is. <em>Channels</em>, that you can <em>post</em> to, and have slower discussion.</p>

<p>It does and still feels needless and also pointless.</p>

<p>But then you have Reddit, which has been a mainstay for … so many years. I think it was open to the public around … 2005? So, right around the time that Facebook started replacing MySpace, Reddit was replacing forums with one gigantic “frontpage of the internet” where millions would eventually gather to talk about any and all topics.</p>

<p>Essentially, <em>erasing</em> the need or <em>drive</em> to setup a discussion forum on your own domain, on your own server, for specific topics. Why do that, when you’ve got Reddit, where you can just create a community centered around whatever topic you’re interested in?</p>

<p>And that’s the overwhelming problem with the modern internet, and its many developers. We’re always trying to smash as many things as possible into one <em>thing</em>, under <em>one</em> roof.</p>

<p>Centralization is the anti-thesis of the <em>internet</em>. We <em>shouldn’t</em> put <em>everything</em> into one place, because, as you, the reader, have probably <em>already seen</em>, that doing so is catastrophic, when places like Twitter get bought out.</p>

<p>Not that I don’t <em>like</em> Reddit and its alternative federated clone, Lemmy, which, for all intents and purposes, does a better job at splitting up hosting and data shards. But … I do find myself asking, “Where have all the normal PHPBB forums gone?”</p>

<p>It’s an internet tragedy that the anime forum (that I link to via WayBackMachine at the bottom of the homepage) that I was on as a 16 year old has been dead for five years. Gone. Deleted. Never to be seen again. And, because of the way the WayBackMachine works, there’s <em>no way</em> to extract my old thoughts, my old posts … who <em>I was</em> when I was 16, and put it somewhere that won’t die and be erased.</p>

<p>Decentralization, though, people treat this like it’s a <em>new</em> idea, even though this is just how the internet worked back then. People did their <em>own</em> thing, there were websites for every topic, every interest, and a million discussion forums to cover those topics and interests. But, to save them?</p>

<p>Unfortunately, I don’t see a way through any of this where old-style, or discussion forums, in-general, will end up “saved.” I don’t see this happening in the present day, where “decentralization” is a buzzword corporations and crypto-bros use in order to garner interest in their next pump and dump.</p>

<p>While mass amounts of people are <em>happy</em> to continue posting on Twitter, or to move their posting to Threads under Meta, one of the <em>largest</em> and <em>most evil</em> central platforms in the world.</p>

<p>In my opinion, the average Joe <em>doesn’t care</em> about this stuff. You might care about it. I care about it. But what do two people matter, to a mass of millions who log onto the next central billionaire owned platform to post about the next foozeball game, and then log off, without a thought or care in the world? Even while said platforms <a href="https://www.nbcnews.com/tech/social-media/meta-new-hate-speech-rules-allow-users-call-lgbtq-people-mentally-ill-rcna186700" target="_blank">are stripping them of their right to not be harassed or hate-crimed</a>.</p>

<p>It’s almost like there’s this thing that’s been happening the past decade, like, some kind of … net split?</p>

<p>The net is splitting, between the hangers-on who know things can be better, and actively are <em>trying</em> to make them that way, and the people who just want to thought-dump, without a care for where they do it. Like a digital Great Wall, or Cyberpunk 2077’s Black Wall, I think there will be an underground web where people speak, communicate, and build for a more humane digital future, and then there’ll be the billion dollar platforms where people post shit like, “Who up? Gotta be on that grind bro, get that bread! $$$” and then log off.</p>

<p>Which, is a shame. Because it will be those people who ask the question, “Well, what do I do now?” When they lose their presence, data, and online identity the next time one of these billionaires has a mid-life crisis.</p>

<p>“But Nova, this is really pessimistic and uncharitable to most people!”</p>

<p>Yup, look what “most people” have done to the world.</p>]]></content><author><name>⸸ commander ░ nova ⸸ :~$</name></author><category term="Web" /><category term="thoughts" /><category term="web" /><category term="community" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[I was reading this article from [a website] that will not be named, since they used and credited Midjourney for images in their article, and we don’t do that. As people who care about artists and the work they do, we don’t generate sludge, and then also credit the theft machines that are making sludge for us, okay? But anyway, the article was about how we need to save discussion forums, and that Reddit and Discord are killing them (a conversation that feels ten years too late). But, is it too late to talk about this?]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">You’ve Been Nicoled: A Fediverse User With Too Much Time On Her Hands, Or A Vengeful Stalker?</title><link href="https://mkultra.monster/social-media/2025/03/17/youve-been-nicoled.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="You’ve Been Nicoled: A Fediverse User With Too Much Time On Her Hands, Or A Vengeful Stalker?" /><published>2025-03-17T01:03:13-04:00</published><updated>2025-03-17T01:03:13-04:00</updated><id>https://mkultra.monster/social-media/2025/03/17/youve-been-nicoled</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://mkultra.monster/social-media/2025/03/17/youve-been-nicoled.html"><![CDATA[<p>If you’ve been on the fediverse for a while now, it’s very likely you’ve been “nicoled,” in that an account on a random instance, calling herself “Nicole the Fediverse Chick” has sent you a private message, talking about who she is, and where you can follow her. At first glance, you’ll notice that she’s creating <em>many</em> accounts, <em>everywhere</em>. And this is probably the result of a script running on a VPS somewhere that’s creating accounts, and then sending messages via a headless browser that watches the federated network of an instance.</p>

<p><img src="/img/posts/fediverse-chick/nicole.png" /></p>

<p>But … the question is, why?</p>

<p>Surely, someone couldn’t <em>possibly</em> think that spamming millions of people, nonstop, for two years or more, is going to gain them any amount of positive clout, or follower-ship.</p>

<p>Unless … unless you look at it through the eyes of a stalker who feels he’s been wronged by a woman, some way, or somehow, and in his attempt at revenge, he’s set out on one of the nastiest, and most dangerous doxxing efforts I’ve ever seen.</p>

<p>But … what would make you think this is an attempt a doxxing someone to a mass amount of people, out of some sick, twisted attempt at revenge?</p>

<p>Firstly, in some of the profiles created that send out these messages, there are … strangely enough, real-world addresses included. I’m not going to <em>post</em> those addresses here, but you have to ask yourself … why would someone include the address to where they work in a social media profile?</p>

<p>That’s strange.</p>

<p>And then there’s the fact that every single photo of her that exists on Mastodon, has some strange aura to it. As if … they’re all screenshots from video calls.</p>

<p>For example, look at this profile …</p>

<p><img src="/img/posts/fediverse-chick/nicole2.png" /></p>

<p>Not only do these look like screen-grabs from some kind of video call app, but <em>who in the world</em> structures a profile like this? Your selfie in the banner, and your selfie in the avatar?</p>

<p>In my opinion, more evidence showing that this is likely more than some scripted clout-grab.</p>

<p>Then, if you get extra sleuthy, you can attempt to reverse image search one of these photos, and do you know what kind of results you get?</p>

<p>Nothing.</p>

<p>At least, nothing outside of the Mastodon source that all of these images are posted to.</p>

<p>The <em>only</em> way this would be possible, is if these photos were never actually shot, and taken, and then uploaded somewhere. This would only be possible, if some dude were screenshotting your face in video-to-video calls, and saving them to his hdd in order to use later.</p>

<p>Such as, in an attempt to get some kind of revenge against you, by making an entire social network think that you’re some annoying person who thinks script-spamming thousands to millions of random people will get you follows. And, for all intents and purposes, that whole idea would work just fine … if all of the photos didn’t look like screengrabs, and if real world addresses weren’t included in some of the profiles.</p>

<p>There <em>is</em> one central profile this seems to be coming from, or, at least, an account that’s mentioned in <em>most</em> of the messages. And, maybe it’s just not been properly moderated, maybe nobody at friendica.world is paying attention to this account. But, <em>most</em> of the messages sent to people include mentioning the profile <a href="https://friendica.world/contact/1462572" target="_blank">@fediversechick@friendica.world</a>.</p>

<p>But, if you were hoping that this would answer any questions, <em>it doesn’t</em>. Although, I do now have an account on friendica.world!</p>

<p>This is about as far as my investigating has gotten. I know there are usually Discord and Matrix servers mentioned along with some, or all of these messages, but I’ve never joined them, because … <em>who</em> in the right mind would do that?</p>

<p>But, I’m not sure I believe that this is some random girl who can’t keep her scripts to herself.</p>]]></content><author><name>⸸ commander ░ nova ⸸ :~$</name></author><category term="Social-Media" /><category term="social-media" /><category term="fediverse" /><category term="scams" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[If you’ve been on the fediverse for a while now, it’s very likely you’ve been “nicoled,” in that an account on a random instance, calling herself “Nicole the Fediverse Chick” has sent you a private message, talking about who she is, and where you can follow her. At first glance, you’ll notice that she’s creating many accounts, everywhere. And this is probably the result of a script running on a VPS somewhere that’s creating accounts, and then sending messages via a headless browser that watches the federated network of an instance.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Today, I Have To Defend Bluesky</title><link href="https://mkultra.monster/social-media/2025/03/15/today-i-have-to-defend-bluesky.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Today, I Have To Defend Bluesky" /><published>2025-03-15T05:19:27-04:00</published><updated>2025-03-15T05:19:27-04:00</updated><id>https://mkultra.monster/social-media/2025/03/15/today-i-have-to-defend-bluesky</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://mkultra.monster/social-media/2025/03/15/today-i-have-to-defend-bluesky.html"><![CDATA[<p>I’m writing this, partially because, I need something to write about to take my mind off the pain of potentially having broken my toe at work, and because I’ve seen and kind of keep seeing people sharing this as a way to say, “Hey, Bluesky is about to start scraping its users data for profit in relation to AI companies.” And, I really do think it needs to be highlighted, that that’s not what any of this says.</p>

<p>In the below article …</p>

<div class="link-preview" data-url="https://techcrunch.com/2025/03/10/bluesky-is-weighing-a-proposal-that-gives-users-consent-over-how-their-data-is-used-for-ai/"></div>

<p>It reads:</p>

<blockquote>
The demand for AI training data means the new social network has to think about its AI policy, even though it doesn’t plan to train its own AI systems on users’ posts.
<br /><br />
However, the public nature of Bluesky’s social network has already allowed others to train their AI systems on users’ content, as was discovered last year when 404 Media came across a dataset built from 1 million Bluesky posts hosted on Hugging Face.
<br /><br />
Bluesky competitor X, meanwhile, is feeding users’ posts into sister company xAI to help train its AI chatbot Grok. Last fall, it changed its privacy policy to allow third parties to train their AI on users’ X posts, as well. The move, followed by the U.S. elections that elevated X owner Elon Musk’s status within the Trump administration, helped fuel another exodus of users from X to Bluesky.
<br /><br />
As a result, Bluesky’s open source, decentralized X alternative has grown to over 32 million users in just two years’ time.
<br /><br />
Speaking at SXSW, Graber explained that the company has engaged with partners to develop a framework for user consent over how they would want their data to be used — or not used — for generative AI.
<br /><br />
“We really believe in user choice,” Graber said, saying that users would be able to specify how they want their Bluesky content to be used.
<br /><br />
“It could be something similar to how websites specify whether they want to be scraped by search engines or not,” she continued.
<br /><br />
“Search engines can still scrape websites, whether or not you have this, because websites are open on the public internet. But in general, this robots.txt file gets respected by a lot of search engines,” she said. “So you need something to be widely adopted and to have users and companies and regulators to go with this framework. But I think it’s something that could work here.”
</blockquote>

<p>And while I don’t agree that Bluesky is <em>actually</em> decentralized, and I feel like, at the current moment, they’re really just using this as a buzzword, and I also don’t think it’s a great idea to put any faith in AI companies <em>actually</em> respecting a robots.txt, the part you should pay attention to, is …</p>

<blockquote>
However, the public nature of Bluesky’s social network has already allowed others to train their AI systems on users’ content, as was discovered last year when 404 Media came across a dataset built from 1 million Bluesky posts hosted on Hugging Face.
</blockquote>

<p>That a company <em>has already</em> scraped Bluesky, and that’s what this is about.</p>

<p>Bluesky wants to offer its users the ability to say whether or not they want this to happen. It doesn’t mean these companies will <em>respect</em> that, but <em>not even Mastodon</em> has a toggle in preferences that embeds a robots.txt file into <em>your profile</em>.</p>

<p><em>In fact,</em> there are <em>quite a few instances</em> across the Fediverse, whose rules completely ignore the existence of AI, don’t mention it at all, and even some actively protect users who <em>post</em>, or even <strong>sell</strong>, generated slop.</p>

<p>So, unfortunately, I think I do have to say here, that Bluesky might actually be ahead on this, in that they’ve somehow managed to think of this, <em>before</em> any working on Mastodon has.</p>

<p>But, back to my main point here, you <em>also</em> have to pay attention to that first line. Aha! You thought I forgot about that, didn’t you?</p>

<blockquote>
The demand for AI training data means the new social network has to think about its AI policy, even though it doesn’t plan to train its own AI systems on users’ posts.</blockquote>

<p>This is kind of interesting wording. One <em>might</em> assume that the people behind Bluesky <em>have</em> an AI system that they’re running. Or, you could take it to mean, <em>if</em> they develop a system, they don’t plan to use it to scrape your posts.</p>

<p>I guess you could take it either way, honestly.</p>

<p>All of that said, and this article sliced into bite-sized pieces, absolutely don’t get me wrong, people <em>definitely</em> have reason to be skeptical, and ask questions, as I do, <em>all of the time</em>. Social media has come crashing down all around us over the past five years. Many people have <em>lost</em> the basis of their livelihoods because of it. Some just picked a new place, and set up shop.</p>

<p>Heck, I <em>used to have</em> 3000+ followers on Twitter, and some of that (aside from Mastodon), was <em>the basis</em> for my ability to <em>actually sell music.</em> And I gave that up. I don’t mean that as a, “I sacrificed more than you,” but more as a like, “I understand your skepticism and fears.”</p>

<p>But I feel it’s <em>important</em> to get the facts straight, and even if you vehemently <em>hate</em> everything that Bluesky stands for, you should make sure that everything you say <em>accurately</em> represents and depicts who they are, and what they’re doing. It’s all about credibility. At least, if you want people to believe you.</p>

<p>For further clarification on all that’s going on here, you can <a href="https://github.com/bluesky-social/proposals/tree/main/0008-user-intents" target="_blank">read the actual proposal on Github</a> in order to dive deeper into what Bluesky is putting forth.</p>

<p>And I definitely want to reiterate, Mastodon has <em>a lot</em> of work to do in making itself <em>less</em> friendly to scrapers and AI scammers.</p>]]></content><author><name>⸸ commander ░ nova ⸸ :~$</name></author><category term="Social-Media" /><category term="social-media" /><category term="bluesky" /><category term="scrapers" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[I’m writing this, partially because, I need something to write about to take my mind off the pain of potentially having broken my toe at work, and because I’ve seen and kind of keep seeing people sharing this as a way to say, “Hey, Bluesky is about to start scraping its users data for profit in relation to AI companies.” And, I really do think it needs to be highlighted, that that’s not what any of this says.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Social Media Was Good For A While</title><link href="https://mkultra.monster/social-media/2025/03/13/social-media-was-good-for-a-while.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Social Media Was Good For A While" /><published>2025-03-13T05:56:26-04:00</published><updated>2025-03-13T05:56:26-04:00</updated><id>https://mkultra.monster/social-media/2025/03/13/social-media-was-good-for-a-while</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://mkultra.monster/social-media/2025/03/13/social-media-was-good-for-a-while.html"><![CDATA[<p>Yeah, I’m writing about something I’ve written about a few times now, but it echoes my feelings of getting older, and wishing we could take at least <em>parts</em> of the world back twenty five years or so. But, why? Would I, or anyone else, really actually enjoy interacting with an internet where they can’t just immediately connect with a thousand people and get some likes and shares? Am I being uncharitable in assuming this is all people care about anymore?</p>

<p>I feel like there was a turning point in the early 2000s, where we were kind of <em>forced</em> to say goodbye to everything that was good about the internet, and introduced to a monster. But, we didn’t <em>know</em> it was a monster. We went along with it, because it was <em>new</em>, and if you grew up in the 90s, new things were happening <em>constantly</em>. And you rolled with it.</p>

<blockquote class="mastodon-embed" data-embed-url="https://mastodon.social/@hhardy01/99739317870899852/embed" style="background: #FCF8FF; border-radius: 8px; border: 1px solid #C9C4DA; margin: 0; max-width: 540px; min-width: 270px; overflow: hidden; padding: 0;"> <a href="https://mastodon.social/@hhardy01/99739317870899852" target="_blank" style="align-items: center; color: #1C1A25; display: flex; flex-direction: column; font-family: system-ui, -apple-system, BlinkMacSystemFont, 'Segoe UI', Oxygen, Ubuntu, Cantarell, 'Fira Sans', 'Droid Sans', 'Helvetica Neue', Roboto, sans-serif; font-size: 14px; justify-content: center; letter-spacing: 0.25px; line-height: 20px; padding: 24px; text-decoration: none;"> <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" width="32" height="32" viewBox="0 0 79 75"><path d="M74.7135 16.6043C73.6199 8.54587 66.5351 2.19527 58.1366 0.964691C56.7196 0.756754 51.351 0 38.9148 0H38.822C26.3824 0 23.7135 0.756754 22.2966 0.964691C14.1319 2.16118 6.67571 7.86752 4.86669 16.0214C3.99657 20.0369 3.90371 24.4888 4.06535 28.5726C4.29578 34.4289 4.34049 40.275 4.877 46.1075C5.24791 49.9817 5.89495 53.8251 6.81328 57.6088C8.53288 64.5968 15.4938 70.4122 22.3138 72.7848C29.6155 75.259 37.468 75.6697 44.9919 73.971C45.8196 73.7801 46.6381 73.5586 47.4475 73.3063C49.2737 72.7302 51.4164 72.086 52.9915 70.9542C53.0131 70.9384 53.0308 70.9178 53.0433 70.8942C53.0558 70.8706 53.0628 70.8445 53.0637 70.8179V65.1661C53.0634 65.1412 53.0574 65.1167 53.0462 65.0944C53.035 65.0721 53.0189 65.0525 52.9992 65.0371C52.9794 65.0218 52.9564 65.011 52.9318 65.0056C52.9073 65.0002 52.8819 65.0003 52.8574 65.0059C48.0369 66.1472 43.0971 66.7193 38.141 66.7103C29.6118 66.7103 27.3178 62.6981 26.6609 61.0278C26.1329 59.5842 25.7976 58.0784 25.6636 56.5486C25.6622 56.5229 25.667 56.4973 25.6775 56.4738C25.688 56.4502 25.7039 56.4295 25.724 56.4132C25.7441 56.397 25.7678 56.3856 25.7931 56.3801C25.8185 56.3746 25.8448 56.3751 25.8699 56.3816C30.6101 57.5151 35.4693 58.0873 40.3455 58.086C41.5183 58.086 42.6876 58.086 43.8604 58.0553C48.7647 57.919 53.9339 57.6701 58.7591 56.7361C58.8794 56.7123 58.9998 56.6918 59.103 56.6611C66.7139 55.2124 73.9569 50.665 74.6929 39.1501C74.7204 38.6967 74.7892 34.4016 74.7892 33.9312C74.7926 32.3325 75.3085 22.5901 74.7135 16.6043ZM62.9996 45.3371H54.9966V25.9069C54.9966 21.8163 53.277 19.7302 49.7793 19.7302C45.9343 19.7302 44.0083 22.1981 44.0083 27.0727V37.7082H36.0534V27.0727C36.0534 22.1981 34.124 19.7302 30.279 19.7302C26.8019 19.7302 25.0651 21.8163 25.0617 25.9069V45.3371H17.0656V25.3172C17.0656 21.2266 18.1191 17.9769 20.2262 15.568C22.3998 13.1648 25.2509 11.9308 28.7898 11.9308C32.8859 11.9308 35.9812 13.492 38.0447 16.6111L40.036 19.9245L42.0308 16.6111C44.0943 13.492 47.1896 11.9308 51.2788 11.9308C54.8143 11.9308 57.6654 13.1648 59.8459 15.568C61.9529 17.9746 63.0065 21.2243 63.0065 25.3172L62.9996 45.3371Z" fill="currentColor" /></svg> <div style="color: #787588; margin-top: 16px;">Post by @hhardy01@mastodon.social</div> <div style="font-weight: 500;">View on Mastodon</div> </a> </blockquote>
<script data-allowed-prefixes="https://mastodon.social/" async="" src="https://mastodon.social/embed.js"></script>

<p>I’m talking about Facebook, and what would eventually become <em>Meta</em>. Google had its share in destroying the internet, too, but Facebook and Meta is where I believe the greatest evil lives. Albeit, at least Meta never had a “Don’t be evil” sign that they eventually took down, so that they could … be evil?</p>

<p>Never-the-less …</p>

<p>If you were on the internet in the 90s, you were <em>already</em> kind of a nerd. A digital tinkerer. A websurfer. So, you <em>probably</em> had some sort of website. Maybe something on Geocities, like we all know and love, and wish was still around. Thank garsh we have <a href="https://neocities.org" target="_blank">Neocities</a> as some form of continued interest in giving people a place to be themselves online.</p>

<p>But, it <em>totally</em> wasn’t exclusive to nerds. I very much remember a girl I had a crush on showing me her AOL instant messenger bio when I went to her place once, and then her Geocities that was plastered with her made-up Star Wars Twi’lek character.</p>

<p>… uh, alright, maybe <em>she was a nerd</em>.</p>

<p>But, the question: Would people actually be able to tolerate returning to an internet that was just websites?</p>

<p>I think so, if you ease them into it.</p>

<p>Back in the 90s, the only <em>real</em> way to “post” to people were through bulletin boards. You’d join an online community site full of topics of your interest, and post threads in order to speak to other people who shared your interests. It wasn’t like posting on Twitter. You had to wait, or, <em>sometimes</em>, never get a reply to things you were talking about. Which, sure, a lot of people can probably relate to that by today’s standards, like when you talk into the void on social media and nobody pays you any mind.</p>

<p>It wasn’t hundreds of thousands, or millions of people, though. It was like fifty people, or a hundred people. <em>That’s it</em>. There were <em>many</em> of these bulletin boards, and they were <em>all over the place</em>. Some exist today, even still, and people definitely still use them (I highly recommend <a href="https://forum.melonland.net" target="_blank">melonland</a> for getting a sense of what it was like).</p>

<p>But, that wasn’t the <em>only</em> way that you could connect with people.</p>

<p>If you had a Geocities, you could “join” communities, and put a webring on your site in order for visitors to travel around through sites with similar topics (you can see some new-age webrings right here on my own website). Sometimes, maybe you’d spark interest in getting to know someone who was running a site in the same “neighborhood” as you, so you’d jump into a Yahoo chatroom with twenty other people and have a real-time chat. Or, better yet, you’d simply <em>add them</em> on an instant messaging app (like AOL Instant Messenger), and talk! Like … back and forth, personally!</p>

<p><em>This</em> is what made the early internet so exciting.</p>

<p>You <em>didn’t</em> have immediate access to everyone, at all times.</p>

<p>Sometimes you would log on to mess with your site, and surf the net for a new desktop wallpaper, idling away time to see if some of your buddies logged on, and sometimes they wouldn’t!</p>

<p>But when they <em>would</em>, you had <em>so much more</em> to talk about, because you weren’t socially exhausting them, and <em>yourself</em>, by just <em>always</em> being in-touch.</p>

<p>It was … awesome.</p>

<p>Now, I know <em>some</em> of us might ask, “Okay, but what about people who have material need for fundraising? How would a return to the early internet accommodate something like that?”</p>

<p>To be honest, and completely frank, I <em>never</em> saw this on the early internet. But, that <em>may</em> be because, back in the 90s, the internet wasn’t really this place that people would log on and be like, “I need help, this is where I can get it.” People just didn’t make, or get a whole lot of money, at all, online, because that was an idea that had yet to take any shape.</p>

<p><em>Paypal didn’t exist</em>.</p>

<p>Setting up some kind of internet store wasn’t really something many people … <em>could do</em>.</p>

<p>I would imagine, though, you would probably want to post something like that on a personal website, and send it to your friends, and people who share your interests on forums (bulletin boards), and it’d probably have the same effect as blasting it out on Mastodon, or Bluesky.</p>

<p>Speaking of, does this mean I think we should be <em>rid</em> of Mastodon and Bluesky?</p>

<p>Not entirely, no. I think Mastodon is great, and Bluesky is … <em>okay</em>. It could be better. But <em>neither</em> of them have algorithms, and Facebook is to blame for the algorithmic hell that much of the internet <em>is</em>, today. Without algorithms, you kind of <em>are</em> just talking, which … in a way, <em>does</em> mirror the old net.</p>

<p>But, we need <em>more</em> of that. And now.</p>

<p>I’m not just talking about this as something we need immediately <em>just</em> because AI has fucked everything up. But, because, people, as a <em>whole</em>, have got to unlearn the antisocial ideals that Twitter and Facebook spent over a decade hammering into us.</p>

<p>And by that, I mean, eschewing all social sensibilities in interacting and connecting with people, in order to to post <em>bait</em>. Something that will get you <em>more likes</em>, <em>more follows</em>, <em>more fame</em>, etc, etc. It is an addiction, a sickness, and if you spend enough time surrounded by it, you might start thinking a majority of people don’t care about anyone but themselves and their own instant gratification.</p>

<p>This extends to Tik Tok, too. Where this behavior is so egregious, that people engineer videos <em>just to waste your time</em>, because pissing people off does <em>huge</em> numbers!</p>

<p>No.</p>

<p>We have to deconstruct all of that. We <em>must</em> return to something that encouraged discovery, and connection. Maybe even for the sake of the world, actually. I don’t know.</p>

<p>I just wish everything about being online didn’t seem <em>so bad</em>, <em>all of the time.</em></p>

<p>But that’s why I have this website.</p>]]></content><author><name>⸸ commander ░ nova ⸸ :~$</name></author><category term="Social-Media" /><category term="social-media" /><category term="webdev" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Yeah, I’m writing about something I’ve written about a few times now, but it echoes my feelings of getting older, and wishing we could take at least parts of the world back twenty five years or so. But, why? Would I, or anyone else, really actually enjoy interacting with an internet where they can’t just immediately connect with a thousand people and get some likes and shares? Am I being uncharitable in assuming this is all people care about anymore?]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">I Spent Two Days Playing World Of Warcraft</title><link href="https://mkultra.monster/gaming/2025/03/12/i-spent-two-days-playing-world-of-warcraft.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="I Spent Two Days Playing World Of Warcraft" /><published>2025-03-12T02:06:10-04:00</published><updated>2025-03-12T02:06:10-04:00</updated><id>https://mkultra.monster/gaming/2025/03/12/i-spent-two-days-playing-world-of-warcraft</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://mkultra.monster/gaming/2025/03/12/i-spent-two-days-playing-world-of-warcraft.html"><![CDATA[<p>You might look at the headline, “I spent two days playing World of Warcraft,” and go, “What is this, 2008?” And, honestly? I wish it was. But, the past it is not. Recently, I had a position change at work, and now I have to sleep during the day. But, an added bonus? I work longer days, and have more days off. So, I decided to take a sizeable chunk of that time off, and get back into the World of Warcraft. But, how long have I had characters in this game?</p>

<p><img src="/img/posts/wow-2025/mokk.png" /></p>

<p>This is one of the oldest characters on my account … Mokklerblitz, the Death Knight. I created this character <em>on the day</em> that Wrath of the Lich King launched, in the hours when the servers had come back online. I wish I could show you what this character looked like, <em>then</em>, rather than now, in War Within … but, keeping record of my screenshots in 2008 (or even 2004) wasn’t really something I did.</p>

<p>But, I spent a couple days (okay, maybe not two entire full days straight) grinding in WoW, in order to get my set of four main characters caught-up with War Within.</p>

<p><img src="/img/posts/wow-2025/camp.png" /></p>

<p>It’s been far too many years since I really went all out and <em>actually played</em> through an expansion in World of Warcraft. Which, is pretty <em>nuts</em>, because I’ve pre-ordered … <em>every single one of them.</em></p>

<p>I still have the Cataclysm special edition box sitting on a shelf here.</p>

<p>Anyway, I didn’t start playing World of Warcraft as a Death Knight in 2008. I started as a Night Elf Druid (which is now pictured above to the far left), and then I was bribed by friends at the time (with in-game gold) to join the Horde, and play there. Which I did. On a mage.</p>

<p>I don’t have that mage anymore.</p>

<p>I won’t say <em>why</em>, exactly, but let’s just say, this was before Battle.net accounts, and people sometimes swapped characters between each other.</p>

<p>Never-the-less, I <em>wish</em> I still had that character.</p>

<p>I feel, though, World of Warcraft has come a long way. There’s <em>so much content</em> that it’s kind of ridiculous if you somehow run out of things to do. <em>There’s so much to do</em> you could probably spend the next decade completing it, and then you’d have probably four more expansions to run.</p>

<p>What I miss, though, is something that not even the Classic servers can really capture. That’s partially, because, for <em>some reason</em>, they decided that part of Classic should just … run through <em>every single expansion</em> until it catches up with the Retail version.</p>

<p>I don’t think that was needed. I think we needed three servers for the first three expansions, and then they could’ve just stopped there.</p>

<p>But what do I know? Cataclysm, at least, didn’t need a “classic” edition on these servers. One of the <em>very reasons</em> I think people <em>even wanted</em> classic servers, was to <em>experience the game before Cataclysm vastly changed everything!</em></p>

<p>Sometimes I wish I could log in again for the first time in 2004, create a Night Elf, and die repeatedly, mesmerized as to what exactly was happening.</p>

<p>“Why am I a glowing ball? Where do I go? What the heck is this? I’m lost!” And then re-rez, and do it all over again.</p>

<p>No, my <em>favorite</em>, “I’m a noob and I don’t know what MMOs are” thing, was when I ran from Darnassus to Ironforge, on foot, at level one, because I wanted to see what it looked like. And then I found out that my graphics card couldn’t handle it, <em>so I ran to Walmart and bought a new one</em>.</p>

<p>That was back when Walmart still sold videocards, and when videocards didn’t cost as much as a used car due to crypto and AI grifters jacking up demand.</p>

<p>But I spent two days playing, and it felt like I was 19 years old again, in some points. I ignored most of the world. Ignored social media, ignored the constant onslaught of notifications from millions of different sources that demand your attention only to <em>waste it</em>, and I leveled the hell up. I just leveled up, dude.</p>

<p>Did this improve my dating life? Hell no. Date? Who dates in this economy?</p>

<p>Did I almost feel like things were normal for short stints over a two day period? Sort of. But … with a whole lot less friends.</p>

<p>On that note, got a guild? I’m looking for one on my Alliance Druid! The one I joined yesterday is <em>dead in the water</em>. Hit me up!</p>]]></content><author><name>⸸ commander ░ nova ⸸ :~$</name></author><category term="Gaming" /><category term="world-of-warcraft" /><category term="gaming" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[You might look at the headline, “I spent two days playing World of Warcraft,” and go, “What is this, 2008?” And, honestly? I wish it was. But, the past it is not. Recently, I had a position change at work, and now I have to sleep during the day. But, an added bonus? I work longer days, and have more days off. So, I decided to take a sizeable chunk of that time off, and get back into the World of Warcraft. But, how long have I had characters in this game?]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Ingest Your Bluesky Posts To Jekyll</title><link href="https://mkultra.monster/social-media/2025/03/09/ingest-your-bluesky-posts-to-jekyll.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Ingest Your Bluesky Posts To Jekyll" /><published>2025-03-09T17:21:03-04:00</published><updated>2025-03-09T17:21:03-04:00</updated><id>https://mkultra.monster/social-media/2025/03/09/ingest-your-bluesky-posts-to-jekyll</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://mkultra.monster/social-media/2025/03/09/ingest-your-bluesky-posts-to-jekyll.html"><![CDATA[<p>Recently, I figured out how to get the mastodon-markdown-archive script working, which is a great script, and you should check it out, <a href="https://git.garrido.io/gabriel/mastodon-markdown-archive#installation" target="_blank">here</a>. But! I wanted to do the same thing with Bluesky, in the case that Bluesky could be bought out by billionaires and destroyed in the same way that Twitter was. And, because I <em>lost</em> my entire decade-old Twitter account and all of its content, I also want to make sure that <em>never happens again</em>.</p>

<p>So, I’ve made a Ruby script that you can use on a Jekyll site to automatically import anything from your Bluesky RSS feed, directly into your website under a “_skeets” directory, which includes images as media, and excludes reposts, quote posts, and replies (or should!)</p>

<p>It is as follows:</p>

<div class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge"><div class="highlight"><pre class="highlight"><code>require 'rss'
require 'fileutils'
require 'jekyll'
require 'open-uri'
require 'nokogiri'

# Defining the RSS feed URL and where it should be located on your site
RSS_FEED_URL = 'https://bsky.app/profile/did:plc:zzofxcatgqb5wpkqetnng4wo/rss' # Don't use my feed URL, replace this with your own
OUTPUT_DIR = '_skeets'
MEDIA_DIR = 'assets/media'
LAST_IMPORTED_FILE = 'last_imported_guid.txt'

# Script creates directories if they don't already exist
FileUtils.mkdir_p(OUTPUT_DIR)
FileUtils.mkdir_p(MEDIA_DIR)

# Sanitize filenames, because bsky does it all weird and stuff
def sanitize_filename(filename)
  base = File.basename(filename, ".*")
  ext = File.extname(filename).gsub('@', '.')
  sanitized_base = base.gsub(/[^0-9A-Za-z.\-]/, '_').gsub(/_+/, '_')
  "#{sanitized_base}#{ext}"
end

# Convert URLs included in posts into an anchor that can be clicked
def convert_urls_to_links(content)
  content.gsub(/(https?:\/\/[^\s]+)(?![^&lt;]*&gt;)/, '&lt;a href="\1" target="_blank"&gt;\1&lt;/a&gt;')
end

# Download images as media, and update the content
def download_images_and_update_content(content, media_dir)
  content.gsub(/&lt;img src="(https?:\/\/[^\s]+)"[^&gt;]*&gt;/) do |match|
    image_url = $1
    image_filename = sanitize_filename(File.basename(image_url).gsub('@', '.'))
    image_path = "#{media_dir}/#{image_filename}"
    
    puts "Found image URL: #{image_url}"
    puts "Downloading image: #{image_url} to #{image_path}"
    
    begin
      # Download media
      URI.open(image_url) do |image|
        File.open(image_path, 'wb') do |file|
          file.write(image.read)
        end
      end
      puts "Successfully downloaded image: #{image_url}"
    rescue StandardError =&gt; e
      puts "Failed to download image: #{image_url}. Error: #{e.message}"
    end
    
    # Update the path to the image so that it displays correctly
    "&lt;img src=\"/#{image_path}\" alt=\"Image\"&gt;"
  end
end

# Fetch and parse post content in order to find images, because, by default, they aren't displayed in the RSS feed
def fetch_and_parse_skeet_content(url)
  begin
    html_content = URI.open(url).read
    document = Nokogiri::HTML(html_content)
    images = document.css('meta[property="og:image"]').map { |meta| meta['content'] }
    puts "Found images: #{images}" if images.any?
    images
  rescue StandardError =&gt; e
    puts "Failed to fetch or parse skeet content: #{url}. Error: #{e.message}"
    []
  end
end

# Read the last imported GUID from the created file
last_imported_guid = if File.exist?(LAST_IMPORTED_FILE)
                       File.read(LAST_IMPORTED_FILE).strip
                     else
                       nil
                     end

# Fetch and parse the RSS feed
begin
  rss_content = URI.open(RSS_FEED_URL).read
  rss = RSS::Parser.parse(rss_content, false)

  # Iterate through each item in the RSS feed
  rss.items.each do |item|
    puts "Processing item: #{item.title}"
    puts "Description: #{item.description}"
    
    break if item.guid.content == last_imported_guid

    # Exclude replies, reposts, and quote posts
    next if item.title&amp;.start_with?('Re:') || item.title&amp;.start_with?('RT:') || item.description.include?("[contains quote post or other embedded content]")

    # Sanitize the filename
    sanitized_filename = sanitize_filename(item.guid.content)
    filename = "#{OUTPUT_DIR}/#{sanitized_filename}.md"
    
    # Fetch and parse content to find images
    images = fetch_and_parse_skeet_content(item.link)
    images.each do |image_url|
      # Download image and update
      downloaded_image_tag = download_images_and_update_content("&lt;img src=\"#{image_url}\" alt=\"Image\"&gt;", MEDIA_DIR)
      item.description += downloaded_image_tag
    end

    # Create a Markdown file for each feed item with Jekyll front matter (customize this do be whatever you normally use)
    File.open(filename, 'w') do |file|
      file.write("---\n")
      file.write("layout: skeet\n")
      file.write("title: \"#{item.title || 'New Skeet'}\"\n")
      file.write("date: #{item.pubDate}\n")
      file.write("author: ⸸ commander ░ nova ⸸ :~$\n")
      file.write("collection: skeets\n")
      file.write("guid: #{item.guid.content}\n")
      file.write("avatar: /img/avatar/daemon.jpeg\n")
      file.write("bluesky: #{item.link}\n")
      file.write("---\n\n")
  
      # Convert URLs in the content to HTML anchors
      content = convert_urls_to_links(item.description)
      
      file.write("#{content}\n")
    end
  end

  # Update the last imported GUID
  File.write(LAST_IMPORTED_FILE, rss.items.first.guid.content) if rss.items.any?

  puts "Successfully converted RSS feed to Markdown files in #{OUTPUT_DIR}."

rescue StandardError =&gt; e
  puts "An error occurred: #{e.message}"
end
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>And there you have it. Using this Ruby alongside Jekyll, you can import everything you post to Bluesky as native “posts” on a Jekyll site, from just your Bluesky RSS feed! Now, this <em>isn’t</em> going to import your entire posting history thus far (that would be problematic, especially if you’ve got a large history), but, it’s a good starting point to making yourself billionaire proof.</p>

<p>I don’t fully believe, or <em>trust</em> that Bluesky can’t be corrupted by money and corporations, and that doesn’t have to even matter, if all of your content, and the essence of <em>you</em>, is hosted on <em>your own site</em>.</p>

<p>Obviously, other things, like <em>displaying</em> these on a Jekyll feed, are things you’ll need to configure. But it <em>should</em> be as easy as specifying …</p>

<div class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge"><div class="highlight"><pre class="highlight"><code>{% assign skeets_array = site.skeets %}
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>and then …</p>

<div class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge"><div class="highlight"><pre class="highlight"><code>  {% for item in paginated_array %}
    {% assign post_type = item.collection %}
        {% elsif post_type == "skeets" %}
      {% assign icon = "ph ph-butterfly" %}
      {% assign verb = "Skeeted" %}
      {% assign content = item.content %}
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>But, it <em>is</em> assumed that if you’re doing this, you <em>might</em> have some knowledge of how Jekyll and Liquid syntax works.</p>

<p>Either way, have fun turning your website into a compendium of everything you say and do!</p>]]></content><author><name>⸸ commander ░ nova ⸸ :~$</name></author><category term="social-media" /><category term="webdev" /><category term="social-media" /><category term="bluesky" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Recently, I figured out how to get the mastodon-markdown-archive script working, which is a great script, and you should check it out, here. But! I wanted to do the same thing with Bluesky, in the case that Bluesky could be bought out by billionaires and destroyed in the same way that Twitter was. And, because I lost my entire decade-old Twitter account and all of its content, I also want to make sure that never happens again.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">International Women’s Day: My Favorite Female Characters</title><link href="https://mkultra.monster/media/2025/03/08/international-womens-day-my-favorite-female-characters.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="International Women’s Day: My Favorite Female Characters" /><published>2025-03-08T12:33:34-05:00</published><updated>2025-03-08T12:33:34-05:00</updated><id>https://mkultra.monster/media/2025/03/08/international-womens-day-my-favorite-female-characters</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://mkultra.monster/media/2025/03/08/international-womens-day-my-favorite-female-characters.html"><![CDATA[<p>As you know, it’s International Women’s Day, and so, instead of writing continually about the dudes trying to steal the world’s creativity and ingenuity for their own profit, I wanted to write about my personal favorite female characters. Maybe you’re thinking, “Shouldn’t Women’s Day posts be about <em>real</em> women?” But, aha! I gotchu. Female characters are voiced by women!</p>

<p>This is in no particular order, and is not an exhaustive list. More-so, <em>just my top faves</em>, so, let’s go.</p>

<ul>
  <li>1: <strong>Commander Shepard, i.e., “FemShep”</strong></li>
</ul>

<p><img src="/img/posts/iwd-2025/femshep.png" /></p>

<p>People born in or after 2013 might not have the context or experience of knowing this character, or this series, and that’s a <em>real shame</em>. The Mass Effect series is the pinnacle of gaming, and came about during the <em>real</em> golden age. There <em>hasn’t</em> been anything quite as good, since the end of Mass Effect 3. Not even Cyberpunk 2077 fully hits all the right notes.</p>

<p>FemShep was a turning point, though. I remember thinking, all through the early 2000s, “Why, in <em>every</em> game except for World of Warcraft, am I forced to play as some fuckin’ dude?” And then I discovered (what is now) old school BioWare. And Dragon Age. And then Mass Effect. And so began a years-long obsession with the greatest gaming franchise ever made, that, <em>for some reason</em>, never saw a worthy continuation (yet).</p>

<p>FemShep was voiced by: <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jennifer_Hale" target="_blank">Jennifer Hale</a></p>

<ul>
  <li>2: <strong>Morrigan, the Witch of the Wilds</strong></li>
</ul>

<p><img src="/img/posts/iwd-2025/morrigan.png" /></p>

<p>Continuing on with BioWare classics, and ongoing stories that have created <em>a lot</em> of controversy in post-2020 society (see: incels, gamergate, fascism), we move on to another one of my faves. The arrogant, shrewd, selfish, and sometimes evil, Witch of the Wilds, i.e., Morrigan, of the Dragon Age series.</p>

<p>Long before BioWare mostly stripped Dragon Age of its more <em>extreme</em> dark fantasy themes, there was Dragon Age: Origins. A game where you made the choice to side with a demon on whether or not she could possess a child, or whether or not you wanted to slaughter an entire village, and so on and so forth. But then there was Morrigan, the first character in a game I was ever … infatuated with! And it was <em>the first game</em> I ever played where you could <em>romance</em> characters.</p>

<p>You know what this means, and you know what I did. Continuing my Dragon Age legacy in Veilguard, I am <em>definitely</em> curious as to where my son is. I’ve abandoned my boy!</p>

<p>Morrigan is a powerful character, and seemingly invincible woman, who <em>very much</em> shaped the direction of the Dragon Age series, and is one of my all-time favorites.</p>

<p>She was (and still is) voiced by: <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Claudia_Black" target="_blank">Claudia Black</a></p>

<ul>
  <li>3: <strong>Lara Croft</strong></li>
</ul>

<p><img src="/img/posts/iwd-2025/laracroft.png" /></p>

<p>My list of favorite female characters absolutely <em>would not</em> be complete without mention Lara Croft, of the ever-expanding Tomb Raider franchise (now owned by Embracer Group, the company that continues to kill dev studios). This one holds a special place in my heart, because I played Tomb Raider … <em>in the 90s</em>, when the <em>very first game</em>, was brand new. The gaming landscape in the 90s was much different than it is today, because a game with a leading female role was almost <em>completely unheard of</em>.</p>

<p>And then there was Tomb Raider.</p>

<p>A game, and character I spent numerous hours with, and then watched, and continued playing as the franchise evolved. I’m currently, and very slowly, making my way through Shadow of the Tomb Raider.</p>

<p>Lara Croft was originally voiced by: <a href="https://tombraider.fandom.com/wiki/Shelley_Blond" target="_blank">Shelley Blond</a>, and went on to be voiced by: <a href="https://tombraider.fandom.com/wiki/Judith_Gibbins" target="_blank">Judith Gibbons</a>, <a href="https://tombraider.fandom.com/wiki/Jonell_Elliott" target="_blank">Jonell Elliot</a>, <a href="https://tombraider.fandom.com/wiki/Keeley_Hawes" target="_blank">Keeley Hawes</a>, <a href="https://tombraider.fandom.com/wiki/Minnie_Driver" target="_blank">Minnie Driver</a>, and <a href="https://tombraider.fandom.com/wiki/Camilla_Luddington" target="_blank">Camilla Luddington</a>.</p>

<ul>
  <li>4: <strong>Kassandra, the Spartan Mercenary</strong></li>
</ul>

<p><img src="/img/posts/iwd-2025/kass.png" /></p>

<p>Now we do a bit of a time-jump to the far future, far from 1996, to 2019, and the first Assassin’s Creed game I <em>actually enjoyed</em>, and <em>am still playing</em>, despite there being a completely different sequel, and another slated to come out very soon (where, coincidentally, this character makes a return).</p>

<p>I am, of course, talking about Kassandra, the largely agreed upon canon hero of Assassin’s Creed: Odyssey, wherein you play a Spartan mercenary during the brick, slate, and robe-wearing era.</p>

<p>Kassandra, obviously, wasn’t the <em>first</em> example of a hugely badass woman in a lead role, but she is one of my all-time favorites, and I still enjoy, in 2025, running around descending on enemy camps, and knocking out entire fields of enemies just so that I can recruit them to staff my ship.</p>

<p>Not only is she a badass, but you can run around romancing other women, and I think that makes for one of the <em>very few</em> LGBTQ+ (using the acronym here, because, as you play, you can romance pretty much anyone you want) themed female lead roles in gaming. The others, of course, being FemShep, wherein you could totally romance Liara, which I <em>did</em>.</p>

<p>Kassandra is voiced by: <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Melissanthi_Mahut" target="_blank">Melissanthi Mahut</a></p>

<ul>
  <li>5: <strong>V, Valerie, of Cyberpunk 2077</strong></li>
</ul>

<p><img src="/img/posts/iwd-2025/v.png" /></p>

<p>Now we jump into the game I mentioned at the beginning of this post, for my final of the top five, Valerie. This one is <em>a little different</em>, because she can look and be <em>any way you choose</em>. But, V is definitely on my top faves, because, not only does she hold all the characteristics of the characters I’ve mentioned thus far, but her story is one of tragedy.</p>

<p>A story that takes place in the year 2077, where you’re thrust into an impossible situation, struggling with the visage and personality of an unreliable narrator, and a man, <em>inside of your own head</em>. Something that can be interpreted in … many different ways, in fiction analysis.</p>

<p>Suffice to say, the story <em>does not</em> have a happy ending. But, that’s how it goes in 2077.</p>

<p>Either way, Cyberpunk 2077 is <em>one of the best games</em> I have ever played, with one of the greatest characters I’ve ever inhabited in a virtual world. V is right up there with Lara Croft and FemShep, and hasn’t taken the top spot <em>only</em> because the Mass Effect series did things right, that I wish 2077 could, or <em>would have</em> done (like, for example, making room for your character to maybe … come back, in the sequel).</p>

<p>Valerie was voiced by: <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cherami_Leigh" target="_blank">Cherami Leigh</a></p>

<p>That’s it, though! That’s my top five! I <em>definitely</em> have many more favorite female characters, but if I had to choose to live on an island with five of my favorite characters, or choose only five characters in gaming that have been <em>utterly</em> life changing, these would be those characters.</p>

<p>Who are your top five female characters? Name a woman!</p>

<p><img src="/img/posts/iwd-2025/name-a-woman.png" /></p>]]></content><author><name>⸸ commander ░ nova ⸸ :~$</name></author><category term="Media" /><category term="international-womens-day" /><category term="gaming" /><category term="media" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[As you know, it’s International Women’s Day, and so, instead of writing continually about the dudes trying to steal the world’s creativity and ingenuity for their own profit, I wanted to write about my personal favorite female characters. Maybe you’re thinking, “Shouldn’t Women’s Day posts be about real women?” But, aha! I gotchu. Female characters are voiced by women!]]></summary></entry></feed>