<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en-US"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.10.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en-US" /><updated>2025-02-05T01:33:30-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">cmdr-nova@internet:~$</title><subtitle>cmdr-nova&apos;s personal blog and home on the indie-web.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Music Questions Challenge!</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/questions/2025/02/05/music-questions-challenge.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Music Questions Challenge!" /><published>2025-02-05T00:32:00-05:00</published><updated>2025-02-05T00:32:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/questions/2025/02/05/music-questions-challenge</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/questions/2025/02/05/music-questions-challenge.html"><![CDATA[<p>So, I was tagged by <a href="https://malici.ous.computer/@shellsharks" target="_blank">@shellsharks@malici.ous.computer</a> (you can visit the post on his own site that he references, <a href="https://shellsharks.com/music-questions-challenge" target="_blank">here</a>) on the Fedi to answer some questions about music! This is new to me, because, I was <em>mostly</em> unaware that there’s some kind of blog challenge thing that goes around every once in a while. But, that’s great! It gives me something to write about on days where I have no brain-space for things to write about.</p>

<p>The questions are as follows:</p>

<div class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge"><div class="highlight"><pre class="highlight"><code>1. What are five of your favorite ablums?
2. What are five of your favorite songs?
3. Favorite instrument(s)?
4. What song or album are you currently listening to?
5. Do you listen to the radio? If so, how often?
6. How often do you listen to music?
7. How often do you discover music? And how do you discover music?
8. What’s a song or album that you enjoy that you wish had more recognition?
9. What’s your favourite song of all time?
10. Has your taste in music evolved over the years?
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>Jumping right into the first question, <strong>“What are five of your favorite albums?”</strong></p>

<p>I think I’d have to think back through all of my years being alive, because I’ve become a creature of repetition in the recent past. But, here’s the list.</p>

<p>1: <a href="https://album.link/us/i/311283715" target="_blank">Sevendust - Home</a></p>

<p>This is the <em>very first album</em> I ever bought as a teenager, and will remain one of my favorites.</p>

<p>2: <a href="https://album.link/us/i/302196508" target="_blank">Orgy - Candyass</a></p>

<p>From the years before I fell heavily into KoRn, this album was gifted to me at the age of 16 when I began living in what I still believe to be the most haunted house I’ve ever inhabited. My first dive into industrial numetal.</p>

<p>3: <a href="https://album.link/us/i/967389561" target="_blank">KoRn - Life is Peachy</a></p>

<p><em>I. Don’t. Know. Your. Fuckin’. Name. So. What. Let’s.</em></p>

<p><em>Fuck.</em></p>

<p>I loved this album so much that I learned how to do the scatman bullshit Jonathan Davis does at the beginning of this album.</p>

<p>4: <a href="https://album.link/us/i/1443851273" target="_blank">Deadsy - Commencement</a></p>

<p>Following in the foot-steps of my beginning years of a numetal obsession, comes Deadsy, with another album that I liked quite a lot.</p>

<p>5: <a href="https://album.link/us/i/1532029367" target="_blank">Rammstein - Herzeleid</a></p>

<p>Rammstein is special to me, because I had no idea they existed until German class in the sixth grade, when the fifty-some-odd year old teacher rolled a TV into the classroom and put on Du Hast. Never-the-less, I fell in love with Herzeleid.</p>

<p>6: <a href="https://album.link/us/i/927731469" target="_blank">Slipknot - Slipknot</a></p>

<p>In the eleventh grade I turned into a very mad teenager, which followed Slipknot’s self-titled album that was purchased for me after I begged about three times.</p>

<p>7: <a href="https://album.link/us/i/1440837096" target="_blank">Nine Inch Nails - The Downward Spiral</a></p>

<p>This is actually the second album I ever owned, which accompanied my more angsty, depressed teenage self. I became obsessed with Nine Inch Nails around the same time Quake 3 was one of the biggest games on PC.</p>

<p>8: <a href="https://album.link/us/i/302301243" target="_blank">Static-X - Wisconsin Death Trip</a></p>

<p>An album for back when I was like 17 and had so much more energy than I do now. I saw Wayne Static up close and personal at Crocodile Rock out here in Pennsylvania, years before he passed away. I have one of his guitar picks.</p>

<p>9: <a href="https://album.link/us/i/1474185287" target="_blank">TOOL - Undertow</a></p>

<p>Probably one of the best albums ever made, and one of my favorite progressive rock albums ever. The ending is especially chilling, and I love it. I used to listen to this album a lot while I was playing Tomb Raider in the nineties.</p>

<p>10: <a href="https://album.link/us/i/1440738173" target="_blank">Marilyn Manson - Mechanical Animals</a></p>

<p>Back before it was revealed that Manson was kind of a giant asshole with all kinds of things wrong with him, this was on repeat pretty much all of the time, when I wasn’t listening to KoRn and Nine Inch Nails. It brings back all the memories of sitting in front of Aol Instant Messenger talking to my three internet girlfriends and posting incessantly on animeboards.com.</p>

<p>“But Nova, the question said <strong>FIVE</strong> favorite albums.”</p>

<p>Oh yeah? Who said I follow rules?</p>

<p>Next question: <strong>What are five of your favorite songs?</strong></p>

<p>1: <a href="https://song.link/us/i/1572930403" target="_blank">Power Glove - Brain Jack</a></p>

<p>Jumping directly into my more recent listening habits, and retro-synth obsession, Brain Jack is like an anthem to a cybernetic lifestyle I wish I was living.</p>

<p>2: <a href="https://song.link/us/i/926187670" target="_blank">Slipknot - Psychosocial</a></p>

<p>No, I didn’t stop listening to Slipknot after their self-titled album. I actually never stopped.</p>

<p>3: <a href="https://song.link/us/i/1434900919" target="_blank">Nine Inch Nails - The Perfect Drug</a></p>

<p>Yes, one of my favorite NIN songs isn’t even on an album. But I was so addicted to it in my teen years that it can’t <em>not</em> be on this list.</p>

<p>4: <a href="https://song.link/us/i/1474185654" target="_blank">TOOL - Schism</a></p>

<p>Another one of the greatest songs ever made by the best progressive rock band in the world, I’ve listened to this every year <em>since it came out</em>.</p>

<p>5: <a href="https://song.link/us/i/914145878" target="_blank">Dance with the Dead - Dressed to Kill</a></p>

<p>How could I end this list without jumping back to the present. <em>I love this track</em>. I listen to it constantly, and have done so, for years.</p>

<p>Anyway, let’s get into question number three … <strong>Favorite instrument(s)?</strong></p>

<p>My favorite instrument is probably really cliche, but I’m pretty fond of the guitar. I used to have one, and I used to also play it. But I lost that thing. It was a Gibson Warlock. If I still had it today, who knows, maybe I’d be in a full-fledged band???</p>

<p>Fourth question: <strong>What song or album are you currently listening to?</strong></p>

<p><a href="https://song.link/us/i/1500836562" target="_blank">A Cruel Angel’s Thesis</a></p>

<p>Question numero cinco: <strong>Do you listen to the radio? If so, how often?</strong></p>

<p>I <em>used</em> to listen to the radio way back, maybe fifteen some years ago. That was before I caved to streaming, and before I started buying albums on Bandcamp to put on my almost equally as old iPod. I think radio has a place in today’s society, but it’s so commercial I find literally almost no reason to even touch it in 2025.</p>

<p>Question 666: <strong>How often do you listen to music?</strong></p>

<p>I listen to music as often as I can. If I were allowed to wear my Airpods at work, I’d probably be listening while I work. And while I listen to a lot of true crime podcasts while I drive, I still manage to make time for music in my daily life.</p>

<p>Number 7: <strong>How often do you discover music? And how do you discover music?</strong></p>

<p>I don’t discover new music as often as I should. I have this problem where I’ll like something, or an entire genre, and that’s the only thing I’ll listen to. <em>For years</em>. But I’ve gotten better about it. I <em>make</em> myself go onto Bandcamp and look through genres I like, and here and there I’ll drop some money on an album, especially if I’ve never heard of the artist before.</p>

<p>The eighth question goes, <strong>“What’s a song or album that you enjoy that you wish had more recognition?”</strong></p>

<p>I think Orgy doesn’t get enough recognition in industrial numetal, pretty much <em>at all</em>. They’ve been around since the 90s, and <em>they’re still doing live music</em>, but they’re nowhere near as big as KoRn or Nine Inch Nails, and that’s a shame. They should have <em>way more albums</em> and should still be talked about. I don’t really understand why they’ve been an under-the-radar band since the early 2000s.</p>

<p>Second to last question, <strong>What’s your favourite song of all time?</strong></p>

<p>Oh fuck that’s easy, <a href="https://song.link/us/i/201268495" target="_blank">System of a Down - B.Y.O.B.</a></p>

<p>And, the final question: <strong>Has your taste in music evolved over the years?</strong></p>

<p>I think it’s mostly stayed the same, but in a lot of evolved ways. I started out with numetal, then industrial, then metal, then numetal again, then industrial metal, then electronic, then synthwave, then darksynth / industrial, and then back to numetal again. Because I miss the 90s.</p>

<p>Music has been pretty important to me all of my life, even as I made my own albums and darksynth weirdness in FL Studio. I have a lot of memories and feelings locked into albums and songs that I kind of refuse to listen to, even twenty years later. It’s like a memory-bomb that sits in a plastic case somewhere in my room.</p>

<p>But, I think a life without music, is a weird life. What you doin’? Staring at a blank wall? Psh.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Questions" /><category term="questions" /><category term="music" /><category term="challenge" /><category term="indieweb" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[So, I was tagged by @shellsharks@malici.ous.computer (you can visit the post on his own site that he references, here) on the Fedi to answer some questions about music! This is new to me, because, I was mostly unaware that there’s some kind of blog challenge thing that goes around every once in a while. But, that’s great! It gives me something to write about on days where I have no brain-space for things to write about.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Brain Too Thought For Sleep</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/thoughts/2025/02/03/brain-too-thought-for-sleep.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Brain Too Thought For Sleep" /><published>2025-02-03T22:46:00-05:00</published><updated>2025-02-03T22:46:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/thoughts/2025/02/03/brain-too-thought-for-sleep</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/thoughts/2025/02/03/brain-too-thought-for-sleep.html"><![CDATA[<p>I haven’t written anything on here in a few days, not since I wrote up nine guides for budding web developers, and then promptly returned to work to be exhausted and run through the grinder of the grind. And, with one day left til my “weekend,” I got a little bit more to go. But I don’t really like to talk about my offline job in social places online. I mean, it’s my job. Yes, some day I would either like to promote upward until I don’t have to worry about anything anymore, <em>or</em> find a career in web development, but that’s besides the point.</p>

<p>I just get tired.</p>

<p>And it’s hard to think.</p>

<p>Yeah, it’s tax time. Worst time of the year, when single people with lots of bills and a day job get pennies back from the IRS, and then charges from the local bureau because fuck you, that’s why.</p>

<p>I find a lot of the time, if I don’t stop to write, and if I don’t stop to think about the things around me, and how life’s going, I tend to … <em>lose</em> myself. I lose track of where I am and where I’m headed. I get stuck in a brain-fog where I feel like I’m an outsider watching myself move through the motions of the everyday monotony. Some people might call that, uh, dissociation.</p>

<p>Not sure why I’d be dissociating, but hey, whatever.</p>

<p>Here’s a picture of my cat.</p>

<p><img src="/img/steve/IMG_8256.jpg" /></p>

<p>Today I was thinking to myself, “I can use my time while I’m at work to low-key try to think of ideas on how I can use my website to turn out some kind of income.” But then I got distracted by being at work, and by being busy, and I came up with no ideas on how to do that. And, no, I am not going to start stuffing ad-sense into this site.</p>

<p>I don’t want Google’s haphazard ad-malware painted all over this castle of web design that I’ve spent almost a year building. It’d be like putting brussels sprouts on pizza. Why the hell would you do that?</p>

<p>Anyway, my neck hurts. These are my night-time thoughts for the third of February.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Thoughts" /><category term="thoughts" /><category term="blogging" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[I haven’t written anything on here in a few days, not since I wrote up nine guides for budding web developers, and then promptly returned to work to be exhausted and run through the grinder of the grind. And, with one day left til my “weekend,” I got a little bit more to go. But I don’t really like to talk about my offline job in social places online. I mean, it’s my job. Yes, some day I would either like to promote upward until I don’t have to worry about anything anymore, or find a career in web development, but that’s besides the point.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Nine Guides Complete, More To Come</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/webdev/2025/02/01/nine-guides-complete-more-to-come.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Nine Guides Complete, More To Come" /><published>2025-02-01T16:25:00-05:00</published><updated>2025-02-01T16:25:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/webdev/2025/02/01/nine-guides-complete-more-to-come</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/webdev/2025/02/01/nine-guides-complete-more-to-come.html"><![CDATA[<p>In my last post on here, I mentioned that I had started writing web development guides, but got interrupted by work, and tiredness. Well, do I have news for you. Today, I had off of work, and after having some caffeine and breakfast this morning, I spent about eight hours writing through nine different guides, from getting started with ultra-basic HTML, to constructing JavaScript that makes updating links while having many pages, <em>way easy</em>, to getting setup on Neocities.</p>

<p>If you’ve never made a website before, or are interested in learning things, I’m confidence <a class="page-link" href="/pages/webdev/">these guides</a> will do <em>something</em> for you, in the very least.</p>

<p>And, although it’s shown on the guide page itself, <a href="/webdev/basics/examples/index10.html" target="_blank">here’s the finished website</a> you’ll be making alongside the guides.</p>

<p>This took … a lot of time to write, and there are some things that could be more technically explained, but I think I’ve at least done <em>enough</em> that someone new to web development can <em>at least</em> get started. If even you just copy and paste what I’ve written in order to hack around and mess with stuff. I mean. That’s fine too!</p>

<p>Either way, enjoy. I’m going to go take a break.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Webdev" /><category term="webdev" /><category term="tutorials" /><category term="socialmedia" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[In my last post on here, I mentioned that I had started writing web development guides, but got interrupted by work, and tiredness. Well, do I have news for you. Today, I had off of work, and after having some caffeine and breakfast this morning, I spent about eight hours writing through nine different guides, from getting started with ultra-basic HTML, to constructing JavaScript that makes updating links while having many pages, way easy, to getting setup on Neocities.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Tutorials and Post Archiving</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/webdev/2025/01/31/tutorials-and-post-archiving.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Tutorials and Post Archiving" /><published>2025-01-31T22:16:00-05:00</published><updated>2025-01-31T22:16:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/webdev/2025/01/31/tutorials-and-post-archiving</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/webdev/2025/01/31/tutorials-and-post-archiving.html"><![CDATA[<p>I meant to write about this earlier, but I guess I’ll do that now as I wait for The Sims 1 and 2 Legacy Editions to download (which, I’ve had to reinstall on my SSD so that they’ll load???) But, a few days ago (before I migrated to another instance), I saw someone basically, kind of, sort of, complaining that making a website is like this unattainable act, or practice, and that this is why most people just post on short-form media. My initial reaction was to be like, “What the hell are you talking about?” But, I realize, that things I find extremely simple, like writing HTML, or signing up on a fediverse instance, are actually really complicated for some.</p>

<p>So, in the same way I wrote guides for getting setup on Mastodon, I’m writing guides on <a class="page-link" href="/pages/webdev/">how to build a website from scratch, for beginners</a>!</p>

<p>I’ve merely <em>started</em> it, at this point. Partially because, my offline job sort of interrupted the flow of me making this, but also because I’m now home, and tired, and don’t feel much like writing more, at the moment. But, what I plan to do with this, is have full guides on getting <em>something</em> running, for people who <em>at least</em> have an interest in <em>reading</em> things, and figuring out how to do this, on their own. I understand that <em>even that</em> is asking too much, for some people.</p>

<p>Regardless, though, for the people who want to do these things, I wanted to help make it just a little simpler.</p>

<p>Alongside that, <a href="https://malici.ous.computer/@shellsharks" target="_blank">@shellsharks</a> on fedi (short for fediverse) has been a huge source of inspiration, and ideas, and is the person to thank, or <em>blame</em>, for my entirely renewed interest in building, maintaining, and writing on my own website. In that same vein, he’s also the idea-maker behind syndicating your own posts from social media (that you want to showcase for more than the 30 seconds they appear to others on the timeline) directly to your website.</p>

<p>Now, it’s not <em>real</em> syndication, in a sense that a post automatically appears on your site. It’s more like, manually backing up a post, and then linking to it. Which is fine!</p>

<p>I actually wanted to do this long ago, but my idea for going about it, was to somehow make it so that I could create a post <em>on my website</em>, and have it post to ActivityPub, in the way you might make a normal post <em>on Mastodon</em>, rather than a full blog post. So, in other words, I was trying to make my website <em>be</em> the compose box for Mastodon (or some other such ActivityPub client). Uh … this was kind of a really nuts idea, that I’m sure is possible in like a month of nonstop coding and hacking, but ultimately? Nah.</p>

<p>Instead, I’ve decided to do <a class="page-link" href="/pages/notes/">this</a>. A page where I just type in posts I want to showcase, and then hit “save.”</p>

<p>Easy peasy.</p>

<p><em>Now</em>, to figure out why Sims 1 and 2 Legacy Editions won’t run properly without being installed on an SSD.</p>

<p>Last time I checked, at least one of them functioned perfectly on a 486.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Webdev" /><category term="webdev" /><category term="tutorials" /><category term="socialmedia" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[I meant to write about this earlier, but I guess I’ll do that now as I wait for The Sims 1 and 2 Legacy Editions to download (which, I’ve had to reinstall on my SSD so that they’ll load???) But, a few days ago (before I migrated to another instance), I saw someone basically, kind of, sort of, complaining that making a website is like this unattainable act, or practice, and that this is why most people just post on short-form media. My initial reaction was to be like, “What the hell are you talking about?” But, I realize, that things I find extremely simple, like writing HTML, or signing up on a fediverse instance, are actually really complicated for some.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Migrating Across the Fediverse: Nova Edition</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/socialmedia/2025/01/29/migrating-across-the-fediverse-nova-edition.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Migrating Across the Fediverse: Nova Edition" /><published>2025-01-29T13:24:00-05:00</published><updated>2025-01-29T13:24:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/socialmedia/2025/01/29/migrating-across-the-fediverse-nova-edition</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/socialmedia/2025/01/29/migrating-across-the-fediverse-nova-edition.html"><![CDATA[<p>So, last night I was poking around in my VPS billing reports, and I was going over some things. Basically, I have <em>plenty</em> of bandwidth for the mass of incoming media across the fediverse on my Mastodon instance … <em>but</em>, all the things I have running, in order to keep it operating smoothly, are costing me nearly 70-80 USD a month, <strong>and</strong> my instance is beginning to experience slow-down. This is not good. If I felt more secure in my current job, and wanted to keep spending that much, maybe this wouldn’t be an issue. But, for now, it kinda is. Therefore, I’m migrating away from hosting my own instance, for now.</p>

<p>As of now, and as my account migrates in this exact moment, I’ve moved over to labyrinth.zone, on the account <a href="https://labyrinth.zone/daemon_nova" target="_blank">@daemon_nova</a>.</p>

<p>The good news is, I’m still able to maintain a feed of my posts on this site, and <em>also</em> fediverse comments beneath my posts (although, once I shut-off the instance, old ones will obviously be broken). The down-side, is that I haven’t quite work out some of the kinks, because comments from <em>myself</em> show up as unidentified in the “instance” field of a comment.</p>

<p>Since I’m not sure how to extract a user ID number from Akkoma, this will just have to be like that for now.</p>

<p>The feed, on the other-hand, was just a quick simple RSS feed hack that took me 10 minutes to setup.</p>

<p>But, the bad news is, since I’m not sure you can setup API keys on an Akkoma account, I’ll have to share my posts <em>manually</em>, for now. Which is kinda okay? It’s an alright trade-off for saving myself 70 USD a month.</p>

<p>Plus, copy / pasting isn’t that hard. I only automated this because I can be overwhelmed sometimes.</p>

<p>Either way, the migration process was <em>sort of</em> smooth. I think I briefly nearly crashed the instance (my bad) due to the amount of follows I have. And, if you’re following me, and notice that I’m not, it’s not because I unfollowed you! It’s because the Mastodon &gt; Akkoma follow transfer didn’t go through 100%, so I unfortunately will have to refollow some people, <em>as I notice them</em>.</p>

<p>Thanks for coming along in my fediverse journey. We’ll see where it goes from here! I’m mainly doing this, <em>also</em>, because I wanted to focus more on maintaining my website, rather than doing that, <em>plus</em> being the full-time admin of my own Mastodon instance.</p>

<p>So, I think things will only get cooler from here, especially as mkultra.monster will now direct to this website.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="SocialMedia" /><category term="fediverse" /><category term="akkoma" /><category term="migration" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[So, last night I was poking around in my VPS billing reports, and I was going over some things. Basically, I have plenty of bandwidth for the mass of incoming media across the fediverse on my Mastodon instance … but, all the things I have running, in order to keep it operating smoothly, are costing me nearly 70-80 USD a month, and my instance is beginning to experience slow-down. This is not good. If I felt more secure in my current job, and wanted to keep spending that much, maybe this wouldn’t be an issue. But, for now, it kinda is. Therefore, I’m migrating away from hosting my own instance, for now.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Sims 4: New Template &amp;amp; Resurrection of the VampHouse Challenge</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/gaming/2025/01/28/sims-4-new-template-resurrection-of-the-vamphouse-challenge.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Sims 4: New Template &amp;amp; Resurrection of the VampHouse Challenge" /><published>2025-01-28T16:07:00-05:00</published><updated>2025-01-28T16:07:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/gaming/2025/01/28/sims-4-new-template-resurrection-of-the-vamphouse-challenge</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/gaming/2025/01/28/sims-4-new-template-resurrection-of-the-vamphouse-challenge.html"><![CDATA[<p>So, I was thinking today, “Hey, my old website used to have a section dedicated to The Sims 4 where I hosted a downloadable version of my game template.” And, after some consideration, I decided to put it back! Although, as of posting this, EA released an update to Sims 4 that <em>somehow</em> completely broke their servers, and now you can’t launch the game … at all. Which means, I can’t finish editing my new 2025 Sims 4 world template. Thanks EA! But, that’s not the only thing I’ve added to the site.</p>

<p>The template <a href="/pages/thesims/">will be here</a>, once they fix what they broke.</p>

<p>But, back in 2019, I was <em>really</em> into doing Sims 4 challenges. I was still out-of-work, so I spent most of the time that I wasn’t working on personal projects, playing The Sims 4.</p>

<p>I enjoyed the Legacy Challenge the most, because it involved starting with <em>nothing</em>, and then building up a massive family legacy over numerous generations of sims. I could never really make it past the first generation, though, because, like in all of my save files, I find it hard to let go of the originals. Never-the-less, I thought it would be cool to make <em>my own</em> version of the Legacy Challenge.</p>

<p>So, I wrote something, and hosted it on Google Sheets, so that people could connect to and read it. And then some years passed, and it vanished, along with the website where I originally posted it. And, for the longest time, I thought it was just gone, completely.</p>

<p>But, much like my Second Life guide, <em>nothing is ever gone, forever</em>.</p>

<p>Now, if you navigate to the right (or from the pop-out menu at the top, if you’re on mobile), you’ll find my original VampHouse Challenge recovered and preserved on its own page, <a href="/sims4/vamphouse">right here</a> on my website!</p>

<p>My head hurts a little bit right now, so I haven’t jumped into re-reading the whole thing, but, basically, it’s a challenge that revolves around the idea of the original save file I had way, <em>way</em> back, when I first started playing The Sims 4. I had my own sim, and I moved her into a house. Eventually, she got married and had a child to another sim. Then, someone who will not be named (cause she’s a jerk), from Mastodon, bought me the Vampire pack, and, well, I <em>had</em> to play with it, right?</p>

<p>So I made a new sim, a vampire, and I moved her in down the street from the family I started.</p>

<p>I became <em>so engrossed</em> with this sim, that I ended up moving her into my main house.</p>

<p>And then, one thing led to another, and the vampire, and my original main sim, became romantically involved, and then had a huge family of children. This grew into a massive household, and sims that branched out across the 4 different worlds that there were in the game, at the time. Which, after digging up the save file, and incorporating aspects of it into a world template, I thought, “This should be a challenge people can do themselves.”</p>

<p>So now it is.</p>

<p>If you feel up to it, and partake in this years-old challenge, upload the family you create to the Sims 4 gallery, and use the hashtag #vamphousechallenge. Maybe I’ll check them out, and maybe I’ll use them in my own world!</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Gaming" /><category term="gamingnews" /><category term="sims4" /><category term="gaming" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[So, I was thinking today, “Hey, my old website used to have a section dedicated to The Sims 4 where I hosted a downloadable version of my game template.” And, after some consideration, I decided to put it back! Although, as of posting this, EA released an update to Sims 4 that somehow completely broke their servers, and now you can’t launch the game … at all. Which means, I can’t finish editing my new 2025 Sims 4 world template. Thanks EA! But, that’s not the only thing I’ve added to the site.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Nvidia Will Have To Go Back To Selling Videocards At Normal Human Prices</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/tech/2025/01/27/nvidia-will-have-to-go-back-to-selling-videocards-at-normal-human-prices.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Nvidia Will Have To Go Back To Selling Videocards At Normal Human Prices" /><published>2025-01-27T22:37:00-05:00</published><updated>2025-01-27T22:37:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/tech/2025/01/27/nvidia-will-have-to-go-back-to-selling-videocards-at-normal-human-prices</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/tech/2025/01/27/nvidia-will-have-to-go-back-to-selling-videocards-at-normal-human-prices.html"><![CDATA[<p>It’s been a hell of a week. Work has been busy. I’ve been tentatively trying to get back to finding new work as a web developer, because that’s the career I should’ve been in twenty some odd years ago, and by golly gee whiz, I’m going to get it. But that’s not why I’m writing you today, Mr. Internet. I’m writing, because the AI bubble is having a giant shit, and it’s popping, and Nvidia is tanking. Thank the all mighty Flying Spaghetti Monster, and Venus’ molten atmosphere: AI might be finished, or, at least, seriously diminished to the point that it’s no longer a fad that annoying bastards on public social media timelines spam you about all day.</p>

<p><img src="/img/posts/nvidia/07fbb834c5ac2bb1.png" /></p>

<p>Drink it in. Greedy, unoriginal, plagiarism loving fucks, are having themselves a cry. And the juice couldn’t be more delicious.</p>

<p>Why’s this happening, though?</p>

<p>China, somehow, someway, <a href="https://www.cbsnews.com/news/what-is-deepseek-ai-china-stock-nvidia-nvda-asml/" target="_blank">figured out how to do AI for pocket change</a>, compared to what American billionaires are spending, and that’s <em>hilarious</em>. And I can only hope this takes a chunk out of Meta, out of Twitter, and most importantly, out of Sam Altman’s mega-grift of stealing the entire internet to power his wrong-answer machine.</p>

<p>Albeit, AI should go away, <em>completely</em>. But if I have to settle for China doing it slightly better, and crashing the entire stock market. Well. I’ll take it.</p>

<p>Thanks, China.</p>

<p>As I dump year old malt liquor into my Dr. Pepper, I sit and reflect on two years of bullshit. Dudes with no imagination telling you, “This is inevitable.” And corporations ignoring your consent in order to use everything you’ve ever typed, online, to fuel these things: Potentially becoming worthless e-waste.</p>

<p>Man, that’s the JUICE.</p>

<p>Anyway, I’m gonna go run around in Pandora for 14 hours while I have time to myself.</p>

<iframe title="Avatar: Frontiers of Pandora | Escape to Pandora" width="560" height="315" src="https://video.infosec.exchange/videos/embed/47b127f3-2965-40d2-a5ad-705a16de5b90" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="" sandbox="allow-same-origin allow-scripts allow-popups allow-forms"></iframe>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Tech" /><category term="ai" /><category term="tech" /><category term="nvidia" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[It’s been a hell of a week. Work has been busy. I’ve been tentatively trying to get back to finding new work as a web developer, because that’s the career I should’ve been in twenty some odd years ago, and by golly gee whiz, I’m going to get it. But that’s not why I’m writing you today, Mr. Internet. I’m writing, because the AI bubble is having a giant shit, and it’s popping, and Nvidia is tanking. Thank the all mighty Flying Spaghetti Monster, and Venus’ molten atmosphere: AI might be finished, or, at least, seriously diminished to the point that it’s no longer a fad that annoying bastards on public social media timelines spam you about all day.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">There is No Snow in Alaska; But AI Must Continue</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/tech/2025/01/26/there-is-no-snow-in-alaska-but-ai-must-continue.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="There is No Snow in Alaska; But AI Must Continue" /><published>2025-01-26T03:48:00-05:00</published><updated>2025-01-26T03:48:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/tech/2025/01/26/there-is-no-snow-in-alaska-but-ai-must-continue</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/tech/2025/01/26/there-is-no-snow-in-alaska-but-ai-must-continue.html"><![CDATA[<p>It’s a pretty widely known fact, at this point, that the development and continued use of AI is <a href="https://www.unep.org/news-and-stories/story/ai-has-environmental-problem-heres-what-world-can-do-about" target="_blank">killing the planet</a>. It’s killing the planet at an even more accelerated rate than the world’s richest people and their corporations were, already. And yet, you can log onto Twitter (if you dare), Threads, Bluesky, and even Mastodon, and see tech-hype-brained, uncritical idiots (for lack of a better term), celebrating the thought of the expansion of LLMs to the point where we’re now apparently even talking of wasting the potential of Linux-based operating systems on our phones, on its continued development and use.</p>

<blockquote class="mastodon-embed" data-embed-url="https://mastodon.social/@one_with_linux/113891469603965665/embed" style="background: #FCF8FF; border-radius: 8px; border: 1px solid #C9C4DA; margin: 0; max-width: 540px; min-width: 270px; overflow: hidden; padding: 0;"> <a href="https://mastodon.social/@one_with_linux/113891469603965665" target="_blank" style="align-items: center; color: #1C1A25; display: flex; flex-direction: column; font-family: system-ui, -apple-system, BlinkMacSystemFont, 'Segoe UI', Oxygen, Ubuntu, Cantarell, 'Fira Sans', 'Droid Sans', 'Helvetica Neue', Roboto, sans-serif; font-size: 14px; justify-content: center; letter-spacing: 0.25px; line-height: 20px; padding: 24px; text-decoration: none;"> <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" width="32" height="32" viewBox="0 0 79 75"><path d="M74.7135 16.6043C73.6199 8.54587 66.5351 2.19527 58.1366 0.964691C56.7196 0.756754 51.351 0 38.9148 0H38.822C26.3824 0 23.7135 0.756754 22.2966 0.964691C14.1319 2.16118 6.67571 7.86752 4.86669 16.0214C3.99657 20.0369 3.90371 24.4888 4.06535 28.5726C4.29578 34.4289 4.34049 40.275 4.877 46.1075C5.24791 49.9817 5.89495 53.8251 6.81328 57.6088C8.53288 64.5968 15.4938 70.4122 22.3138 72.7848C29.6155 75.259 37.468 75.6697 44.9919 73.971C45.8196 73.7801 46.6381 73.5586 47.4475 73.3063C49.2737 72.7302 51.4164 72.086 52.9915 70.9542C53.0131 70.9384 53.0308 70.9178 53.0433 70.8942C53.0558 70.8706 53.0628 70.8445 53.0637 70.8179V65.1661C53.0634 65.1412 53.0574 65.1167 53.0462 65.0944C53.035 65.0721 53.0189 65.0525 52.9992 65.0371C52.9794 65.0218 52.9564 65.011 52.9318 65.0056C52.9073 65.0002 52.8819 65.0003 52.8574 65.0059C48.0369 66.1472 43.0971 66.7193 38.141 66.7103C29.6118 66.7103 27.3178 62.6981 26.6609 61.0278C26.1329 59.5842 25.7976 58.0784 25.6636 56.5486C25.6622 56.5229 25.667 56.4973 25.6775 56.4738C25.688 56.4502 25.7039 56.4295 25.724 56.4132C25.7441 56.397 25.7678 56.3856 25.7931 56.3801C25.8185 56.3746 25.8448 56.3751 25.8699 56.3816C30.6101 57.5151 35.4693 58.0873 40.3455 58.086C41.5183 58.086 42.6876 58.086 43.8604 58.0553C48.7647 57.919 53.9339 57.6701 58.7591 56.7361C58.8794 56.7123 58.9998 56.6918 59.103 56.6611C66.7139 55.2124 73.9569 50.665 74.6929 39.1501C74.7204 38.6967 74.7892 34.4016 74.7892 33.9312C74.7926 32.3325 75.3085 22.5901 74.7135 16.6043ZM62.9996 45.3371H54.9966V25.9069C54.9966 21.8163 53.277 19.7302 49.7793 19.7302C45.9343 19.7302 44.0083 22.1981 44.0083 27.0727V37.7082H36.0534V27.0727C36.0534 22.1981 34.124 19.7302 30.279 19.7302C26.8019 19.7302 25.0651 21.8163 25.0617 25.9069V45.3371H17.0656V25.3172C17.0656 21.2266 18.1191 17.9769 20.2262 15.568C22.3998 13.1648 25.2509 11.9308 28.7898 11.9308C32.8859 11.9308 35.9812 13.492 38.0447 16.6111L40.036 19.9245L42.0308 16.6111C44.0943 13.492 47.1896 11.9308 51.2788 11.9308C54.8143 11.9308 57.6654 13.1648 59.8459 15.568C61.9529 17.9746 63.0065 21.2243 63.0065 25.3172L62.9996 45.3371Z" fill="currentColor" /></svg> <div style="color: #787588; margin-top: 16px;">Post by @one_with_linux@mastodon.social</div> <div style="font-weight: 500;">View on Mastodon</div> </a> </blockquote>
<script data-allowed-prefixes="https://mastodon.social/" async="" src="https://mastodon.social/embed.js"></script>

<p>“Who made <em>you</em> the arbiter of what people do with their own hardware?!” An apologist of planet-crushing autocorrect, might ask.</p>

<p>To which I say, “Me, asshole. Just me.”</p>

<p>When I moved to Linux, it was partially because of Microsoft and their bad decisions in regard to booting anyone with slightly out-of-date processors to the curb (welcome to Windows 10, say goodbye to security updates). The other half of it, was the eventual announcement of their “AI powered” <a href="/linux/2024/11/11/ten-months-without-windows.html">privacy invasion software</a>, labeled “Recall.” You know, along with the ads, the popups, and the <em>other</em> AI garbage, embedded directly into your desktop.</p>

<p>I moved to Linux, because, you can do pretty much whatever you want with the software, and it is <em>extremely secure</em>, and privacy focused.</p>

<p>Unfortunately, people with no imagination, and no respect for themselves, the environment, or the Linux operating system, have decided that “anything” can also mean, developing and/or using water-guzzling, ice-cap melting, plagiarism machines.</p>

<p>And when I think of Linux, but on a phone, I think: Security, privacy, endless customization, and how cool it would be if we still had snow on Christmas in Pennsylvania.</p>

<p>When these fartbags think of Linux, but on a phone, they think: Of how great it would be if the entire human population were wiped out by 2042.</p>

<blockquote class="mastodon-embed" data-embed-url="https://alaskan.social/@Ghostsheetz/113892118620430992/embed" style="background: #FCF8FF; border-radius: 8px; border: 1px solid #C9C4DA; margin: 0; max-width: 540px; min-width: 270px; overflow: hidden; padding: 0;"> <a href="https://alaskan.social/@Ghostsheetz/113892118620430992" target="_blank" style="align-items: center; color: #1C1A25; display: flex; flex-direction: column; font-family: system-ui, -apple-system, BlinkMacSystemFont, 'Segoe UI', Oxygen, Ubuntu, Cantarell, 'Fira Sans', 'Droid Sans', 'Helvetica Neue', Roboto, sans-serif; font-size: 14px; justify-content: center; letter-spacing: 0.25px; line-height: 20px; padding: 24px; text-decoration: none;"> <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" width="32" height="32" viewBox="0 0 79 75"><path d="M74.7135 16.6043C73.6199 8.54587 66.5351 2.19527 58.1366 0.964691C56.7196 0.756754 51.351 0 38.9148 0H38.822C26.3824 0 23.7135 0.756754 22.2966 0.964691C14.1319 2.16118 6.67571 7.86752 4.86669 16.0214C3.99657 20.0369 3.90371 24.4888 4.06535 28.5726C4.29578 34.4289 4.34049 40.275 4.877 46.1075C5.24791 49.9817 5.89495 53.8251 6.81328 57.6088C8.53288 64.5968 15.4938 70.4122 22.3138 72.7848C29.6155 75.259 37.468 75.6697 44.9919 73.971C45.8196 73.7801 46.6381 73.5586 47.4475 73.3063C49.2737 72.7302 51.4164 72.086 52.9915 70.9542C53.0131 70.9384 53.0308 70.9178 53.0433 70.8942C53.0558 70.8706 53.0628 70.8445 53.0637 70.8179V65.1661C53.0634 65.1412 53.0574 65.1167 53.0462 65.0944C53.035 65.0721 53.0189 65.0525 52.9992 65.0371C52.9794 65.0218 52.9564 65.011 52.9318 65.0056C52.9073 65.0002 52.8819 65.0003 52.8574 65.0059C48.0369 66.1472 43.0971 66.7193 38.141 66.7103C29.6118 66.7103 27.3178 62.6981 26.6609 61.0278C26.1329 59.5842 25.7976 58.0784 25.6636 56.5486C25.6622 56.5229 25.667 56.4973 25.6775 56.4738C25.688 56.4502 25.7039 56.4295 25.724 56.4132C25.7441 56.397 25.7678 56.3856 25.7931 56.3801C25.8185 56.3746 25.8448 56.3751 25.8699 56.3816C30.6101 57.5151 35.4693 58.0873 40.3455 58.086C41.5183 58.086 42.6876 58.086 43.8604 58.0553C48.7647 57.919 53.9339 57.6701 58.7591 56.7361C58.8794 56.7123 58.9998 56.6918 59.103 56.6611C66.7139 55.2124 73.9569 50.665 74.6929 39.1501C74.7204 38.6967 74.7892 34.4016 74.7892 33.9312C74.7926 32.3325 75.3085 22.5901 74.7135 16.6043ZM62.9996 45.3371H54.9966V25.9069C54.9966 21.8163 53.277 19.7302 49.7793 19.7302C45.9343 19.7302 44.0083 22.1981 44.0083 27.0727V37.7082H36.0534V27.0727C36.0534 22.1981 34.124 19.7302 30.279 19.7302C26.8019 19.7302 25.0651 21.8163 25.0617 25.9069V45.3371H17.0656V25.3172C17.0656 21.2266 18.1191 17.9769 20.2262 15.568C22.3998 13.1648 25.2509 11.9308 28.7898 11.9308C32.8859 11.9308 35.9812 13.492 38.0447 16.6111L40.036 19.9245L42.0308 16.6111C44.0943 13.492 47.1896 11.9308 51.2788 11.9308C54.8143 11.9308 57.6654 13.1648 59.8459 15.568C61.9529 17.9746 63.0065 21.2243 63.0065 25.3172L62.9996 45.3371Z" fill="currentColor" /></svg> <div style="color: #787588; margin-top: 16px;">Post by @Ghostsheetz@alaskan.social</div> <div style="font-weight: 500;">View on Mastodon</div> </a> </blockquote>
<script data-allowed-prefixes="https://alaskan.social/" async="" src="https://alaskan.social/embed.js"></script>

<p>As an iPhone user, I’ve already had AI shoved in my face–Just as much as I have in using Microsoft products that I’m forced to interface with at my job, or the endless droves of creatively bankrupt drones on corporate social media who post slop, ad infinitum, and for the pleasure of no one but themselves.</p>

<p>And maybe you’re thinking, “Pfft, so you’re almost 40, I bet you’re just yelling angrily at a cloud, afraid to embrace new things!”</p>

<p>No, see. <em>I have used AI,</em> and even <em>without</em> the extreme environmental impact, it sucks nards and ass.</p>

<p><img src="/img/posts/nosnow/Screenshot from 2025-01-26 17-12-33.png" /></p>

<p>AI has a massive propensity to simply <em>guess</em> things if it doesn’t immediately know the answer. Which, in the least, is a bunch of crap. You mean to tell me you think Jupiter is closer to Saturn than it is to Earth? Are you serious?</p>

<p>And, at worst, it’s an efficient propaganda machine that could easily fuel misinformation campaigns.</p>

<p>These trillion dollar companies have scraped the entire internet, and the creativity of real human beings, in order to … <em>give you incorrect information</em>.</p>

<p>And yet, these tech bros will talk to you and say things like, “It’s inevitable dude, may as well jump on board!”</p>

<p><img src="/img/posts/nosnow/Screenshot from 2025-01-26 04-27-03.png" /></p>

<p>Yeah, AI is inevitable. Inevitable to either aid and abet Elon Musk and Mark Zuckerberg in killing everyone on the planet, or popping like a saturated bubble in the same way NFTs did.</p>

<p>Either way, if you’re using Linux to interface with a plagiarism bot, please just go back to Windows. Windows was <em>built for you</em>. You can revel in your contribution to the destruction of our home <em>without</em> tainting the Linux operating system for something you’re going to be embarrassed about if you happen to live long enough to retire.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Tech" /><category term="ai" /><category term="linux" /><category term="climatechange" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[It’s a pretty widely known fact, at this point, that the development and continued use of AI is killing the planet. It’s killing the planet at an even more accelerated rate than the world’s richest people and their corporations were, already. And yet, you can log onto Twitter (if you dare), Threads, Bluesky, and even Mastodon, and see tech-hype-brained, uncritical idiots (for lack of a better term), celebrating the thought of the expansion of LLMs to the point where we’re now apparently even talking of wasting the potential of Linux-based operating systems on our phones, on its continued development and use.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Sleeper Hits: Games With No Ad Revenue</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/gaming/2025/01/24/sleeper-hits-games-with-no-ad-revenue.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Sleeper Hits: Games With No Ad Revenue" /><published>2025-01-24T21:43:00-05:00</published><updated>2025-01-24T21:43:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/gaming/2025/01/24/sleeper-hits-games-with-no-ad-revenue</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/gaming/2025/01/24/sleeper-hits-games-with-no-ad-revenue.html"><![CDATA[<p>Today, I wanted to write about some games that I enjoy that also appear to have no advertising, <em>ever</em>, for one reason or another. Either the studio just doesn’t spend any money on ads, or they have no money to spend. In the past, I firmly believe this has been the reason games like Wildstar were eventually shutdown. You probably heard of that MMO, and also probably its demise, but had you seen any advertisements for or about it years after its launch? Probably not. Or, with how Second Life has been running for over 20 years, and there are virtually no and/or never any advertising campaigns about it. Yet, somehow, it thrives based on word-of-mouth, <em>alone</em>.</p>

<p>If you’ve read my blog here and there over the past year, you might remember when I wrote about the game POOLS, which I believed to be a liminal horror walking simulator that stands as an allegory to abuse. Or, any of the other <em>more traditional</em> Backrooms related games, that come, go, and never get talked about.</p>

<p>One of them, being, <em>The Complex: Expedition</em>.</p>

<p><img src="/img/posts/sleepers/Screenshot from 2025-01-24 21-48-57.png" /></p>

<p>If you’re familiar with the Kane Pixels’ Youtube series of Backrooms content, diving into this game will feel like the same territory. And, although, it’s <em>not</em> directly based on Kane’s work, it is very much obviously inspired by it.</p>

<p><img src="/img/posts/sleepers/Screenshot from 2025-01-24 22-09-05.png" /></p>

<p>In an almost frighteningly real looking excursion into the Backrooms, as one of the hazmat-suit-wearing researchers, you crawl beneath a crevice, and while <em>within the complex itself</em>, you slip through a null zone and sink further into it. Effectively cutting you off from your team. Hence begins your expedition, a personal walk around the actual Backrooms.</p>

<p>Another game that I’ve been enjoying lately, along with a few others from the publisher and studios that are currently undergoing a possible acquisition, i.e., <a href="https://www.euronews.com/business/2025/01/10/ubisoft-appoints-advisors-to-explore-strategic-options-for-a-potential-buyout" target="_blank">Ubisoft</a>, is Avatar: Frontiers of Pandora.</p>

<p><img src="/img/posts/sleepers/Screenshot from 2025-01-24 22-19-10.png" /></p>

<p>Firstly, it’s really no surprise that Ubisoft is about to be bought out by a larger company (like Tencent), after one of their executives fumbled its customer relations so <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/ubisoft-exec-says-gamers-need-to-get-comfortable-not-owning-their-games-for-subscriptions-to-take-off" target="_blank">disturbingly badly</a>.</p>

<p>But, as we all know, studios within a publishing house don’t really always reflect the opinions of out-of-touch stock-jockeys.</p>

<p>So, we enter the world of Pandora, not through the eyes of one of the humans attempting to colonize and exploit the planet, and not even through the eyes of one of the human freedom fighters, but through a native of the planet itself. Which is really cool.</p>

<p>Think: Farcry meets Avatar.</p>

<p>You’ve got a massively expansive world to explore, places to liberate from human exploitation, and a crafting system that involves foraging and looting in a way that fits well within the nature-bound lifestyle of the Na’vi.</p>

<p><img src="/img/posts/sleepers/Screenshot from 2025-01-24 20-28-21.png" /></p>

<p>And, like the previous game I mentioned, AFOP has next to none, or <em>absolutely</em> no advertising, whatsoever. Which is <em>especially</em> strange, since it appears to have multiple expansions. Not to mention, the backing of three movies that cost more than potentially buying the city of New York for your personal amusement.</p>

<p>Third on my list, is a Call of Duty clone by Ukrainian developers, Alfa Bravo Inc, that is originally a mobile game, but <em>entirely functional on Linux</em>, with zero intrusive kernel-level anti-cheat.</p>

<p><img src="/img/posts/sleepers/Screenshot from 2025-01-24 22-26-52.png" /></p>

<p>The game plays like a slightly fumbly-ish Call of Duty Modern Warfare, except it’s not being replaced every 6 months with another 200 gig iteration. In fact, the game only takes up around about a single gigabyte of storage.</p>

<p>“WHAT?!” You say.</p>

<p>Yes.</p>

<p><img src="/img/posts/sleepers/20250124223011_1.jpg" /></p>

<p>It’s great for blowing off some steam, and especially for scratching that itch you may be missing having abandoned Windows. Which, <em>you should</em>, because <em>fuck</em> Microsoft.</p>

<p>When I say “fumbly,” though, I mean, it could do with a bit more polish in the area of character movement. It doesn’t feel <em>as tight</em> as it would in Call of Duty. You sometimes feel like a piece of jello bouncing around. But, other than that, it’s great! And it’s not at all like its polar opposite, which also works on Linux, Counterstrike.</p>

<p>Personally, I’ve had so much time in CS:GO, that it’s virtually uninteresting to me in 2025. I was playing that game in … frikken, uh, 2002 (the original CS, obviously)?</p>

<p>And, like the others, you’ve probably never heard of this game before.</p>

<p>But that’s just three of the sleepers I wanted to mention. Honestly, this post could go on and on for hours about numerous games that I think are really cool, that nobody ever talks about, that you never even see on milquetoast social media adverts (I don’t even really look at that stuff anymore, anyway). I could write detailed information on Sacred 2 Gold, an <em>extremely old</em> action RPG, Grim Dawn, another ARPG, or even, something way out of left field, Quake Champions!</p>

<p>Although … Quake Champions is kind of a … lukewarm re-imagining of the classic arena shooter, that I honestly think is not that popular, solely because they tried to reinvent something that didn’t need reinventing, with … hero classes.</p>

<p>But anyway, I’m not writing this post to talk about why I think Quake Champions is never talked about or even mentioned, <em>anywhere</em>.</p>

<p>No matter if you’re a fan of liminal horror, Farcry, or shooters, I’m sure everyone reading this will find something they enjoy about at least <em>one</em> of the three titles I’ve mentioned.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Gaming" /><category term="gamingnews" /><category term="gaming" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today, I wanted to write about some games that I enjoy that also appear to have no advertising, ever, for one reason or another. Either the studio just doesn’t spend any money on ads, or they have no money to spend. In the past, I firmly believe this has been the reason games like Wildstar were eventually shutdown. You probably heard of that MMO, and also probably its demise, but had you seen any advertisements for or about it years after its launch? Probably not. Or, with how Second Life has been running for over 20 years, and there are virtually no and/or never any advertising campaigns about it. Yet, somehow, it thrives based on word-of-mouth, alone.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Fun Things To Do in Your Linux Terminal</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/linux/2025/01/21/fun-things-to-do-in-your-linux-terminal.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Fun Things To Do in Your Linux Terminal" /><published>2025-01-21T17:17:00-05:00</published><updated>2025-01-21T17:17:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/linux/2025/01/21/fun-things-to-do-in-your-linux-terminal</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/linux/2025/01/21/fun-things-to-do-in-your-linux-terminal.html"><![CDATA[<p>I’m still sort of sick, but also actively participating in going to work (because I don’t have sick time to use right now), but! I wanted to write something on the blog here, despite being tired, and stuffy, and having pains in my body, and so I thought, “What about neat things you can do in your Linux terminal that some might not be aware of?” I know, yes. This is a very nerdy thing to think about, or even do, and I’m sure the Windows-holdouts are giving this paragraph the stink-eye. Never-you-mind them, though. Let’s open up that terminal.</p>

<p>First, let’s do a ‘sudo apt install cowsay’, and then once it’s finished, type in something like,</p>

<div class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge"><div class="highlight"><pre class="highlight"><code>cowsay 'At the stripted club, jorkin my peanits'
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>And enjoy the result:</p>

<p><img src="/img/posts/funlinux/Screenshot from 2025-01-21 17-21-32.png" /></p>

<p>Or, maybe you want to generate some quick ascii text for your blog header, or social profile? Easy peasy, dude. First, make sure you have figlet installed, by typing, ‘sudo apt install figlet’, and then go ahead and do something like this:</p>

<div class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge"><div class="highlight"><pre class="highlight"><code>figlet cmdr nova
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>Example result:</p>

<p><img src="/img/posts/funlinux/Screenshot from 2025-01-21 17-28-34.png" /></p>

<p>Our next little easter-egg-ish thing (depending on whether it’s already installed on your system or not) is more just kind of neat. Just in case, since not all systems will have this, type in ‘sudo apt install sl’, and then run this:</p>

<div class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge"><div class="highlight"><pre class="highlight"><code>sl
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>(No, it won’t delete your entire hdd)</p>

<p>Or, maybe you want to do something a little more complicated, but fun, nonetheless. If you’re a 90s baby, or even a mid-80s baby, this will suddenly feel like, <em>maybe</em>, you’re being warped back in time a bit. Type ‘sudo apt install sudoku’ into your terminal, and then run it with:</p>

<div class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge"><div class="highlight"><pre class="highlight"><code>sudoku
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>And enjoy:</p>

<p><img src="/img/posts/funlinux/Screenshot from 2025-01-21 17-33-11.png" /></p>

<p>Perhaps you want something a bit more complex, so let’s install NetHack, and become a Wizard!</p>

<div class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge"><div class="highlight"><pre class="highlight"><code>sudo apt install nethack-console
</code></pre></div></div>
<p>and then run:</p>
<div class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge"><div class="highlight"><pre class="highlight"><code>nethack
</code></pre></div></div>

<p><img src="/img/posts/funlinux/Screenshot from 2025-01-21 17-40-45.png" /></p>

<p>But, maybe this is too complicated, and you’re looking for something … a bit more straight-forward, and maybe even <em>retro</em>? I got you.</p>

<p>Do this:</p>
<div class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge"><div class="highlight"><pre class="highlight"><code>sudo apt install colossal-cave-adventure
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>And then, in any terminal, just type in ‘adventure.’</p>

<p><img src="/img/posts/funlinux/Screenshot from 2025-01-21 18-35-10.png" /></p>

<p>Okay, so, obviously, we went a little bit further here than just playing with random little quirky things in a Linux terminal, but I wanted to showcase how, even if you don’t want to install Steam, even if you mainly use your Linux computer for work, or productivity, and there really aren’t any games, or fun things on it … you can just <em>do</em> things, in the Terminal, and this is just the beginning.</p>

<p>An entire era of lost art, and a type of gaming, living freely in your Linux terminal, rather than a DOS machine from 1985.</p>

<p>One thing I <em>do</em> remember from those times, is a text adventure Twilight Zone game, and I would <em>very much</em> like to find it again, or, to be more specific, <em>find it</em>, and then load it up in the terminal and play it that way. I’m pretty sure it’s easily available on DOSbox somewhere. But, you know, I have a terminal. Let me play it like that. The way it was <em>meant to be played</em>. If you’ve done this, or can point me in the right direction: Let me know!</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Linux" /><category term="linux" /><category term="terminal" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[I’m still sort of sick, but also actively participating in going to work (because I don’t have sick time to use right now), but! I wanted to write something on the blog here, despite being tired, and stuffy, and having pains in my body, and so I thought, “What about neat things you can do in your Linux terminal that some might not be aware of?” I know, yes. This is a very nerdy thing to think about, or even do, and I’m sure the Windows-holdouts are giving this paragraph the stink-eye. Never-you-mind them, though. Let’s open up that terminal.]]></summary></entry></feed>