<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en-US"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.10.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en-US" /><updated>2025-02-25T11:23:54-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">cmdr-nova@internet:~$</title><subtitle>cmdr-nova&apos;s personal blog and home on the indie-web.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Make The Move To RSS</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/tech/2025/02/24/make-the-move-to-rss.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Make The Move To RSS" /><published>2025-02-24T19:19:25-05:00</published><updated>2025-02-24T19:19:25-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/tech/2025/02/24/make-the-move-to-rss</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/tech/2025/02/24/make-the-move-to-rss.html"><![CDATA[<p>It’s been a while since I’ve written some kind of long-form post on my site. At least, since I introduced writing Notes and Logs on here, in a quick and simple way to just <em>post something</em> without worrying about it sounding coherent and planned. It’s only going to continue, from here, though, when I figure out how I can do this <em>easily</em> from my phone. But, I’m not writing this to talk about how much I like shotgunning random crap into the world via my own website. I wanted to talk about RSS.</p>

<p>Sure, I could talk about Bluesky again, and how, no matter how much I try and enjoy or like the app, the feed keeps working <em>against</em> my interest and attention.</p>

<p>I could talk about how I’m entering day five of my offline job, five days after having one day off that I had after three days of work. A nine day stretch where I’ve had little rest, and hardly any sleep.</p>

<p>But, no! It’s RSS time.</p>

<p>So, what <em>is</em> RSS?</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>RSS (RDF Site Summary or Really Simple Syndication)[2] is a web feed[3] that allows users and applications to access updates to websites in a standardized, computer-readable format. Subscribing to RSS feeds can allow a user to keep track of many different websites in a single news aggregator, which constantly monitors sites for new content, removing the need for the user to manually check them. News aggregators (or “RSS readers”) can be built into a browser, installed on a desktop computer, or installed on a mobile device.[4]</p>
</blockquote>

<p><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/RSS" target="_blank"><i>via Wikipedia.</i></a></p>

<p>RSS is something that “came out” a little over 25 years ago, now, in 1999, when Netscape was still a browser you could use. Fun fact! Did you know the corporate bloodsuckers destroying Mozilla own Netscape, and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mozilla_Application_Suite#History_and_development" target="_blank">it’s called Firefox</a>?</p>

<p>Ever since its beginnings, it’s always just been this plain text thing that you can plug into a reader, and use to keep tabs on your favorite subjects, or people’s blogs. And that’s what it <em>remains</em>, today. But, as social media eats itself alive, and the options grow fewer (aside from ActivityPub and <em>maybe</em> Bluesky), RSS becomes <em>very important</em>, once again.</p>

<p>Fun fact, number two! Did you know that Youtube channels have RSS feeds? Did you know that you can subvert all of Google’s ads no matter <em>what they do</em>, by simply using <a href="https://freetubeapp.io" target="_blank">FreeTube</a>, an app that pulls from Youtube RSS feeds?</p>

<p>I’ve talked before about how you should have a website. How all of your data should <em>belong to you</em>, and not some billionaire jerk-ass who can and <em>will</em> delete everything you’ve ever done in the snap of a finger, just because. And I’ve <em>even</em> written guides on how to build one yourself.</p>

<p>But, what do you do <em>after</em> that? Well, … you setup an RSS feed, of course.</p>

<p>And it’s really simple, and maybe I’ll write a guide on how to do that, if whatever you’re using for your site doesn’t already provide you with one. You just setup an XML that reads your posts from a directory and then shoots them out into the digital universe.</p>

<p>I mean, okay. It’s a <em>little</em> more complicated than that. But! A lot of prebuilt blogging software <em>already</em> has this built-in. Wordpress has it. Ghost has it. Heck, I think Jekyll has a plugin, or a feature <em>built-in</em> to the software that generates one <em>for you</em>, but I made one myself. Because I’m not <em>just</em> sharing posts. And also, there’s some kind of weird timezone discrepancy I still haven’t figured out, that’s causing all kinds of issues.</p>

<p>You can see my RSS feed <a href="https://mkultra.monster/rss_feed.xml" target="_blank">here</a>, and, depending on what you’re using to view my site, it <em>might</em> show up as plain text versions of everything I post, <em>or</em>, it’ll look like a jumble of code with some words. Which is fine! Just plug the URL into a reader, or even your e-mail client (if it allows it), and voila!</p>

<p>Fun fact, number three! Did you know the <a href="https://vivaldi.com" target="_blank">Vivaldi browser</a> has a reader built-in? And it’ll just automatically convert all of that weird code into a feed cloud that looks <em>a lot</em> like the Tumblr feeds of old (you know, that page you get when you’re viewing all of someone’s posts at once).</p>

<p>Say hello to long-form posts, without all the styling you have on your website (a great way for people to keep up with what you’re writing and saying, without having to go all the way to your site, itself), in a simple-to-read interface.</p>

<p>The thing is, you don’t <em>have</em> to keep it confined to <em>just</em> long-form blog posts, though. You can, essentially, use it as a mailing list. You can use it as a one-way social feed of your thoughts, to readers. You can use it to share pictures of your cat with <em>anyone who subscribes to your feed</em>.</p>

<p>Bro.</p>

<p>Welcome to social media, 1999.</p>

<p>At the end of the day, if you don’t want to do <em>any of this</em>, I would <em>at least</em> recommend finding a nice home on a solid server via Mastodon, or some-such ActivityPub app. But, if you want to get into the <em>really</em> hardcore nerd shit, definitely start using an RSS feed. And plug it <em>everywhere</em>. It’s like … a podcast, of your THOUGHTS! IT’S TELEPATHY!</p>

<p>For real though, as the infrastructure of everything crumbles and corporations destroy all that’s left that’s good in the world, you should have a contingency. Even if it means speaking to the internet the way that we used to, before Google destroyed everything.</p>]]></content><author><name>⸸ commander ░ nova ⸸ :~$</name></author><category term="Tech" /><category term="tech" /><category term="rss" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[It’s been a while since I’ve written some kind of long-form post on my site. At least, since I introduced writing Notes and Logs on here, in a quick and simple way to just post something without worrying about it sounding coherent and planned. It’s only going to continue, from here, though, when I figure out how I can do this easily from my phone. But, I’m not writing this to talk about how much I like shotgunning random crap into the world via my own website. I wanted to talk about RSS.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The Digital Social Downfall</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/social-media/2025/02/21/the-digital-social-downfall.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Digital Social Downfall" /><published>2025-02-21T19:25:00-05:00</published><updated>2025-02-21T19:25:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/social-media/2025/02/21/the-digital-social-downfall</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/social-media/2025/02/21/the-digital-social-downfall.html"><![CDATA[<p>I see, sometimes, people talking about how they don’t really use any specific social media app as reinforcement of anything they do, or share, in regard to work, or art, and that if they <em>did</em> … if that was their <em>main mode</em> of deriving support, money, and so on, and so forth: They’d be screwed. And, well, yeah. That’s exactly correct. For all intents and purposes, if you’re just online to chat, and make friends with random people, that’s cool. You can do that in any space you choose, and you <em>should</em>. That’s the way the internet used to be.</p>

<p>For people like me, I use the internet for this reason as well, even though I’m … <em>terrible</em> at making friends in my near 40s, as a closeted trans woman, who spends most of my life, nowadays, hiding <em>everything about myself</em> in public spaces, and just … surviving.</p>

<p>The other half of me is online, <em>still online</em>, attempting to share the things I do: The music, the writing, the art, the things I make in Second Life (even though I haven’t been paying much creative attention to that as of late), and it’s <em>rough</em>.</p>

<p>You’ve got places like Reddit that have this toxic mindset built-in, where the only people allowed to share their work, are people who have already made it big. Otherwise, you’re breaking the rules.</p>

<p>You’ve got Bluesky, where gaining traction with <em>anything</em> is like playing the lottery, and, like post-2020 social media everywhere, if you don’t employ manipulative engagement tactics, you’re gonna have a bad time.</p>

<p>You’ve got Threads, which is exactly the same, except they’ve got <a href="https://www.splcenter.org/resources/stories/meta-policy-updates-could-encourage-hate-threaten-democracy/" target="_blank">bigotry coded into their Terms of Service</a>.</p>

<p>And then you have Mastodon/ActivityPub (and other associated apps), where talking and chatting is highly encouraged, but building takes time. <em>A lot of time</em>. And some people <em>don’t even take kindly to those who are trying to build some kind of audience on the platform/s</em>. Which, is a shame. ActivityPub is probably one of the greatest things to happen to the internet. That it’s been partially colonized by the privileged who don’t or haven’t scraped by, or <em>needed</em> a helping hand, or even just <em>support for their work</em>, is a little bit of a minor tragedy.</p>

<p>But, it hasn’t suddenly become <em>more</em> hostile to creatives, online, though. It’s <em>always been that way</em>. It’s just <em>worse</em>, now. <em>Especially</em> with the rise of algorithmic theft from the un-creative, who seek to profit off of artificially generated slop, derived from people who <em>do</em> work.</p>

<p>Long ago, though, there was Twitter. The <em>real</em> Twitter. And, sure, the place was <em>always</em> toxic. This idealistic pretend idea that people have in their heads, that Twitter used to be some kind of amazing social utopia … are living in a fantasy world.</p>

<p>But!</p>

<p>Twitter was instrumental in my album <a href="https://eyeshadow2600fm.bandcamp.com/album/ride-eternal" target="_blank">Ride Eternal</a> becoming a bestseller (before the calamity of twitter-synthwave dudes having a meltdown over transness in “their” “scene”), and, apart from Mastodon (I have had a lot of random support via ActivityPub, sporadically, throughout the years), I made <em>a lot</em> of progress for my work on the platform. The loss of Twitter wasn’t just a loss of some central “community square” online, it was a loss in an audience of thousands of people I, and others, had connections to.</p>

<p>It’s all gone.</p>

<p>And, now, what are we left with? To sift and jump back and forth between different spaces, <em>hoping</em> that something <em>sticks</em> hard enough that you can stop jumping back … and forth.</p>

<p>For many, this hasn’t happened.</p>

<p>For me, that is why my website is now my own personal social platform. My most important thoughts, my writing, my announcements, my little shitposts, or random things I want to say: They come here, <em>first</em>, and then they go to the other places.</p>

<p>To me, this is <em>the only</em> answer to the loss of some central idea of a community square where you really <em>could</em> reach thousands of people who might be interested in what you do.</p>

<p>I will <em>never</em> put my work, my thoughts, and my words, solely into the hands of corporate overlords, <em>ever again</em>.</p>

<p>My website cannot be <em>taken</em> from me, it can’t be lost forever, it can’t be deleted by some CEO who didn’t like what I had to say, it can’t be mobbed and silenced by evil little shitheads with ulterior motives and fears over the marginalized occupying spaces in their industries.</p>

<p>As long as I have a PC, thumb drives, portable hard drives, a laptop, a <em>phone</em>, my website sticks around, no matter what happens to the server it’s hosted on.</p>

<p>And that’s <em>awesome</em>.</p>

<p>Even if the government becomes <em>fully</em> 1984, and blocks out all sorts of content at the ISP level, I’ll just take my website to TOR.</p>

<p>That’s why you should <em>own your content</em>.</p>

<p>You <em>should</em> post on these platforms, and try and see what sticks. But your most important posts, well, they should be on a website. <em>Your</em> website. In 2025, this is the <em>only answer</em> to the destruction of the digital social landscape, and you owe it to yourself to <em>at least</em> spin something up on a template builder, if <em>anything</em> (although I do encourage learning at least the basics of HTML).</p>

<p>It’s rough out there on the world wide web, and it’s <em>never</em> been harder for creatives to find their people, and their audience. But, it <em>can be done</em>. The first step, is to <em>own your content</em>.</p>

<p>Now, <em>of course</em>, some select few people might see this sort of idea as “nerd shit.” And they’re free to think that way. I remember back in middle and high school, when “nerd” was a legitimate insult that inspired all kinds of bullying. And, I’m thankful, that the internet is <em>not</em> high school, and that people who are mentally <em>stuck</em> there, <em>probably</em> won’t be a real big part of the future digital social landscape.</p>]]></content><author><name>⸸ commander ░ nova ⸸ :~$</name></author><category term="Social-Media" /><category term="socialmedia" /><category term="creators" /><category term="webdev" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[I see, sometimes, people talking about how they don’t really use any specific social media app as reinforcement of anything they do, or share, in regard to work, or art, and that if they did … if that was their main mode of deriving support, money, and so on, and so forth: They’d be screwed. And, well, yeah. That’s exactly correct. For all intents and purposes, if you’re just online to chat, and make friends with random people, that’s cool. You can do that in any space you choose, and you should. That’s the way the internet used to be.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Kingdom Come: I Keep Messing Up</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/gaming/2025/02/20/kingdom-come-i-keep-messing-up.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Kingdom Come: I Keep Messing Up" /><published>2025-02-20T22:28:00-05:00</published><updated>2025-02-20T22:28:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/gaming/2025/02/20/kingdom-come-i-keep-messing-up</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/gaming/2025/02/20/kingdom-come-i-keep-messing-up.html"><![CDATA[<p>I’ve been spending a couple of days sprucing up my site, adding things to the feed, making it more like … a <em>social media</em> feed, and then I got myself a copy of Kingdom Come: Deliverance 2. Now, I played a little bit of the first one, but that was years back, and I got confused or stuck around the beginning, so I didn’t really pick it up again. At the time, it was a game I never really saw anyone talk about, so I didn’t really assume much of it.</p>

<p>That was, until the second one released.</p>

<p>Long story short, I have it. I played through … the beginning.</p>

<p>Not to spoil too much, I <em>eventually</em> made it to the point where the game drops you off into the world, and pushes you in the direction of doing <em>whatever the heck it was you want to do.</em></p>

<p>Oh boy.</p>

<p>I got let out of the pillory (yes, you get arrested, for reasons), and my buddy, the stuck-up dude, well, he abandoned me. I’m not sure if this was a consequence of your own actions, or if it’s meant to happen. So, I’m just going to assume that this is <em>supposed</em> to happen.</p>

<p>A lady stops you and helps you out a little, mentions something about finding work.</p>

<p>See, I’m someone who comes from games like Skyrim and Baldur’s Gate. I’m pretty familiar with finding quests in RPGs.</p>

<p>Haha.</p>

<p>I think I spent about ten minutes running around trying to figure out who would pay me to do things, until I ran into someone’s house and saw a bowl of food. I figured, “Hey, nobody’s here, and I need to eat!” So <em>I did</em>.</p>

<p>Upon immediately turning around, there’s a guy staring at me, and you can probably guess what happened next.</p>

<p>I was back in the pillories.</p>

<p>Another day later, I’m notified that if I commit another crime, I’ll be marked by an executioner or something, and that my character is fed up.</p>

<p>I put my clothes back on and head back into town again, hoping that maybe <em>this time</em> I’ll find some work. I wander around for a bit, and almost get hit with multiple trespassing charges.</p>

<p>It’s at this point that I’m getting kind of tired with my bumbling self almost, or completely breaking the law. I ran all the way out of town into the woods, and fell asleep in some abandoned camp under a bunch of trees. Finally, I was fully healed, and eating an apple out of my pocket.</p>

<p>Yeah. I had food in my pockets that I forgot about.</p>

<p>But now it was night time and pitch black. I’m warned about carrying a torch, in that, it’s a crime if I don’t have one. Another crime!</p>

<p>So I ran. I ran and ran directly into more woods, until I stumbled upon another small village. Nobody’s around. Perfect chance to … steal a horse! Which, was pretty easy, but I’m assuming that because it was dark, nobody saw me!</p>

<p>I decided for myself that my quest was to find my dog, so I road off into the dark again. Fell off the horse a few times, got back on. Eventually, after fumbling with my map and not being able to see where I’m going, I make it to where my dog is supposed to be, and I’m stopped by some guy.</p>

<p>I killed that guy, and took all his money.</p>

<p>Then I found 125 moneys in a pot under another tree by a rock.</p>

<p>With my dog still missing, I figured I’d run around the lake and at least see if … I can find anymore dead bodies with loot.</p>

<p>No such luck.</p>

<p>I run into a pack of wild dogs, and after about three minutes of flailing my sword around, I am dead.</p>

<p>And back at the village that I ran away from.</p>

<p>The game is pretty cool so far! I’ve definitely been experiencing some sort of deliverance, that’s for sure. Delivering my own self into pillories and death.</p>

<p>We’ll see how it goes next time I load it up.</p>]]></content><author><name>⸸ commander ░ nova ⸸ :~$</name></author><category term="Gaming" /><category term="gaming" /><category term="kingdom-come" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[I’ve been spending a couple of days sprucing up my site, adding things to the feed, making it more like … a social media feed, and then I got myself a copy of Kingdom Come: Deliverance 2. Now, I played a little bit of the first one, but that was years back, and I got confused or stuck around the beginning, so I didn’t really pick it up again. At the time, it was a game I never really saw anyone talk about, so I didn’t really assume much of it.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Writing Prompt: Describe Your Dream Home</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/writingprompt/2025/02/17/writing-prompt-describe-your-dream-home.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Writing Prompt: Describe Your Dream Home" /><published>2025-02-17T18:59:00-05:00</published><updated>2025-02-17T18:59:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/writingprompt/2025/02/17/writing-prompt-describe-your-dream-home</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/writingprompt/2025/02/17/writing-prompt-describe-your-dream-home.html"><![CDATA[<p>Today, I’m taking a prompt from the old Jetpack app that I’ve had installed on my phone ever since I still ran a Wordpress blog. It’s a pretty useless app, now, but there are at least some ideas for things to write about. Although, I’m <em>almost certain</em> there are probably easier ways to get daily writing prompts in order to fuel my need to write things. Never-the-less, today’s prompt is all about just … describing your dream home. As a millennial, this is a pipe-dream. A far-away thing that will likely never happen. But, if I could <em>somehow</em> have a home, that I own, what would it be, really?</p>

<p>There is, <em>of course</em>, the old haunted house I lived in when I was sixteen, that I’ve always thought would be <em>really cool</em> to buy, and then renovate, and take care of. But, it’s not really my <em>dream</em> home. It’s more like, a link to the past that I could actively live inside of, as if that would provide some level of comfort as the past, and the way things used to be, gets further and further away from me.</p>

<p>It would make me think of things like, hanging out the window in my room late at night smoking a cigarette. Sitting in front of my hand-me-down 486 choosing a cool anime wallpaper for my desktop. My highschool girlfriend picking me up for school in her jalopy of a car, and the one time I accidentally sleepily dialed 911 when I was trying to call her (to ask how far away she was).</p>

<p><em>That was one hell of a morning, having an ambulance outside wondering what the shit was happening, and my Dad outside, just as confused.</em></p>

<p>Maybe … maybe, it wouldn’t be <em>that</em> great of an idea to live in a place that makes me think of things, and the ways I was, that will never be, ever again. I learned that a couple of months ago when I wrote to that aforementioned highschool ex-girlfriend, and sort of poured out my feelings and thoughts as to why I couldn’t be just some side-thing, like she wanted, twenty years after abandoning what I thought would be the rest of my life, at the time.</p>

<p>She didn’t answer.</p>

<p>And that’s probably for the best.</p>

<p>So, if we’re talking a <em>real</em> dream home, I think I’d go out somewhere, maybe in the midwest, far away from the bustle of <em>other people</em>. I’d go out into the woods and drop down maybe two shipping containers, and I’d have them conditioned for living. There’d be water nearby, so that I could fish whenever I want, and I’d have a studio for gaming and working on all the things that I do on a daily basis. The outside would be covered in camouflage nets and black paint, and the inside would be a sort of … rustic gothic.</p>

<p>Sword collections, a battle-axe over a side table. Another shelf on the opposite side of the living area showcasing all the little game and anime figures I’ve collected over the years. In the center, a gigantic flat-screen television and whatever the latest and best console is.</p>

<p>The kitchen would be a wood-burning stove with ventilation connected to the outside, but there’d also be a modern fridge with temperature display and voice-activated features. But all the smart tech in my home would be running on a reverse proxy that redirects their tracking software to some other location.</p>

<p>The bathroom would have one of those rich-person walk-in showers that you just kind of, stand in while water falls on top of you in kind of an open concept where the sink and toilet are just kinda, right there, <em>also</em>.</p>

<p>But, there’d be a more private bathroom tucked at the back of the master, and <em>only</em> bedroom. Of course, the bed itself would be made out of top-of-the-line memory foam and down-feather sheets or whatever, and there’d be a gigantic glass window in the ceiling that looks out into the stars at night.</p>

<p>Maybe it’d be smart, so I could dim it, or blend it with the ceiling during the day.</p>

<p>There would be a security system surrounding the property, and all of this would be connected to a secondary PC in my studio, with alarms, and footage that’s all saved to my home server, that’d be tucked away in a large walk-in closet. A home server that also has built-in custom water-cooling, and the best of the best technology. That all runs on Linux, <em>of course</em>.</p>

<p>The front door, and the <em>only</em> door, would be reinforced steel, along with the paneling on the outside. Indestructible and impervious to most things, including bullets, and maybe even a grenade.</p>

<p>Then, the best kept secret of my home, would be the bunker beneath all of it, filled with perishables, water, and whatever amenities one might need in the event that <em>something</em> happens. Zombies, nukes, the Night of the Walking Entitled Rich People, whatever. I’ll be ready.</p>

<p>I wouldn’t have a car. I wouldn’t need it. There’d be a secure mailing box at the edge of the woods where my actual address would be, and I’d just order whatever I need, at all times. Imagine ordering a burger on Doordash and you’re like, “Just drop it off at the big huge box on the side of the road.”</p>

<p>And maybe … <em>that</em> could be a dream home. A dream home that’s also future-proof, and ready for disaster.</p>

<p>Maybe it sounds like a prepper’s dream, and that’s kinda funny, cause I’m not really a doomsday prepper. But, if I <em>had the money</em>, maybe I <strong>would</strong> be. Who knows!</p>]]></content><author><name>⸸ commander ░ nova ⸸ :~$</name></author><category term="WritingPrompt" /><category term="writing-prompt" /><category term="thoughts" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today, I’m taking a prompt from the old Jetpack app that I’ve had installed on my phone ever since I still ran a Wordpress blog. It’s a pretty useless app, now, but there are at least some ideas for things to write about. Although, I’m almost certain there are probably easier ways to get daily writing prompts in order to fuel my need to write things. Never-the-less, today’s prompt is all about just … describing your dream home. As a millennial, this is a pipe-dream. A far-away thing that will likely never happen. But, if I could somehow have a home, that I own, what would it be, really?]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Linux: Play Windows 95 Chime On Startup</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/linux/2025/02/16/linux-play-windows-95-chime-on-startup.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Linux: Play Windows 95 Chime On Startup" /><published>2025-02-16T19:59:00-05:00</published><updated>2025-02-16T19:59:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/linux/2025/02/16/linux-play-windows-95-chime-on-startup</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/linux/2025/02/16/linux-play-windows-95-chime-on-startup.html"><![CDATA[<p>Maybe you’re like me, and you’re edging close to 40, grasping for anything in the past, or <em>from the past</em>, that might spark memories of when things were less … enshitified. Not to say that software and technology in the 90s were perfect. But, it was a different time. So, short of installing a Windows 95 partition on your PC, how can you make its iconic startup sound play on-boot, and <em>on</em> Linux?</p>

<p>Easy.</p>

<p>Download the chime, <a href="/files/win_95.mp3" target="_blank">here</a>, first, and save it somewhere like, maybe, your “Music” folder.</p>

<p>Now, open your terminal and install MPV.</p>

<div class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge"><div class="highlight"><pre class="highlight"><code>sudo apt install mpv
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>Once you’re done doing that, you’re going to want to make a new shell script.</p>

<p>So, do this:</p>

<div class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge"><div class="highlight"><pre class="highlight"><code>nano startup.sh
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>And then, in the text editor (I use Nano, but you can use whatever you want), type this:</p>

<div class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge"><div class="highlight"><pre class="highlight"><code>#!/bin/bash
cd /home/$User(whatever your username is)/Music
mpv win_95.mp3
exit
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>Now, hit CTRL + O to save and then CTRL + X to exit.</p>

<p>Finally, type in:</p>

<div class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge"><div class="highlight"><pre class="highlight"><code>chmod +x startup.sh
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>Your computer is <em>almost</em> ready to play the Windows 95 chime whenever you startup your PC. But, we’re not quite there, yet!</p>

<p>Now, I’m on Pop!_OS, and your way of accessing this <em>may</em> be different, but you’re going to want to open “Startup Application Preferences.” If, for some reason, this <em>isn’t</em> installed, you can do that.</p>

<div class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge"><div class="highlight"><pre class="highlight"><code>sudo apt-get install gnome-startup-applications
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>To open it, at least on <em>my</em> machine, I just hit the Super key (Windows key), and type “Startup,” and then I click the result once it’s shown in the Applications menu.</p>

<p>Now, click “Add” in the window, and give the startup application a name, like, “Win95” or something. Click the “Browse” button and find your shell script, and select it. Once you’ve done that, just click “Add,” and you’re done!</p>

<p>Restart that beautiful PC, and listen.</p>

<p>This tutorial brought to you by: A yearning for the old internet.</p>]]></content><author><name>⸸ commander ░ nova ⸸ :~$</name></author><category term="Linux" /><category term="linux" /><category term="modding" /><category term="startup" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Maybe you’re like me, and you’re edging close to 40, grasping for anything in the past, or from the past, that might spark memories of when things were less … enshitified. Not to say that software and technology in the 90s were perfect. But, it was a different time. So, short of installing a Windows 95 partition on your PC, how can you make its iconic startup sound play on-boot, and on Linux?]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Dexter: Is Harry Morgan The Villain?</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/dexter/2025/02/15/dexter-is-harry-morgan-the-villain.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Dexter: Is Harry Morgan The Villain?" /><published>2025-02-15T20:12:00-05:00</published><updated>2025-02-15T20:12:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/dexter/2025/02/15/dexter-is-harry-morgan-the-villain</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/dexter/2025/02/15/dexter-is-harry-morgan-the-villain.html"><![CDATA[<p>So, this is it! Dexter: Original Sin season 1 is over!  After watching the final episode, and confirming to myself that Dexter hasn’t been this good since <em>at least</em> season four of the original show, I think there’s one <em>real</em> question that needs to be answered: Is Dexter’s foster father, Harry Morgan, the <em>main</em> villain? In order to answer that question, we have to look at this through the same kind of window in which we viewed the plot of Breaking Bad.</p>

<p>And, we need to keep in mind the title of the newest show, “Original Sin.” <em>Who’s sin?</em> Dexter’s? Or, more directly, Harry’s?</p>

<p><img src="/img/posts/dexter-harry/Screenshot from 2025-02-15 20-13-52.png" /></p>

<p>In a society where healthcare is for-profit, and, <em>sometimes</em>, a life or death situation, is it bad to become a criminal in order to pay for your cancer treatment?</p>

<p>Obviously, I wouldn’t blame someone for robbing a bank, or selling drugs in order to pay for treatment that could save their lives. It’s the <em>actions</em> that Walter White takes, and the things that he does, that <em>make</em> him the antagonist.</p>

<p>Walter White was a product of his own selfishness and violent desire.</p>

<p>But, Dexter … Dexter is a <em>completely different</em> beast, as a character.</p>

<p>In a <em>corrupt</em> and unjust society, where killers and predators walk free, is it <em>bad</em> to kill them <em>yourself?</em></p>

<p>This question is something I’ve thought about ever since I started watching the OG Dexter series in 2008. <em>Everyone</em> says that what Dexter does in the show is <em>bad</em>, but, is it? Is it <em>really</em>?</p>

<p>As a fictional character, he, for sure, goes off the rails a bit and his “code” slips. There are ways in which he becomes and <em>acts</em> like just a normal, everyday serial killer (and we’ll explore further down if this is part of his <em>own</em> inclinations, or sins of the father). But, for the most part, his actions in both of these shows are things that are shown to have <em>saved</em> lives. So, I guess it circles back to the real world line of thinking that a lot of liberals hold, in that if you enact evil against evil, <em>you are evil</em>.</p>

<p>Which … I don’t believe.</p>

<p>If you punch a Nazi in the face, you don’t <em>become</em> a Nazi. This isn’t the Marvel universe. We don’t have some magical transference of energy that occurs when you hit someone hard enough.</p>

<p>If Dexter kills a child predator who buries his victims under a shed, he doesn’t somehow <em>become</em> a child predator. Unlike Walter White, Dexter doesn’t unconsciously “absorb” pieces of his victims into his <em>own</em> personality.</p>

<p>Dexter does what Dexter does. He uses police resources to investigate killers, collects evidence, and then dumps them in the ocean. And then he goes home with a splotch of blood on a slide, and eats a sandwich.</p>

<p><img src="/img/posts/dexter-harry/Screenshot from 2025-02-15 20-30-06.png" /></p>

<p>But, we can’t really piece together a full canvas out of these things, unless we also look at the person who <em>made</em> Dexter.</p>

<p>The man who sees himself as a <em>hero</em>, who <em>saved</em> Dexter from becoming something much more along the lines of a monster, like his own brother, Brian Moser. I am, obviously, talking about the character, Harry Morgan.</p>

<p>Walter White and Harry Morgan are more alike than Walter and Dexter.</p>

<p>Both operate out of selfishness, out of a need for vengeance, for their own twisted version of justice, and both are men of tragedy, who see themselves <em>outside</em> of social norms out of a sense of immense pride, immense, inflated egos. Where a regular person would concede, that if they don’t do their job properly, as a cop, killers might get away. Or, in Walter’s respect, a normal person would just take help from their rich friends in order to pay for cancer treatment.</p>

<p>And, in <em>both</em> shows, these men are framed in a way that make the audience sympathize with them, which, in turn, makes it <em>harder</em> to see that the person you’re empathizing with is actually committing some pretty heinous crimes. Because, if there’s any way to get groups of people to excuse bad things, it’s to appeal to their sympathy, and put them in the shoes of those who do bad things.</p>

<p>Because most people are capable of empathy.</p>

<p>Harry is a man who adopted a child from the scene of a murder, of a woman with whom he had an affair, and then molded someone he <em>believed</em> to have inclinations toward murder, into his own “arm of the law.” In order to enact justice against those who escape it.</p>

<p>In his own way, Harry is just another killer. He just can’t pull the trigger himself. In his own selfishness, he creates the anti-monster, out of a child who, and I can’t stress this enough, <em>may not have even ended up that way, as an adult</em>.</p>

<p>That’s right. There is <em>nothing</em> in any of the shows that currently exist that suggest Dexter would have <em>definitely</em> become a stone-cold, regular serial killer. Sure, he committed small-time acts of violence as a child, and through prodding from his foster father, he grew to believe that he had “urges” that needed to be “satisfied.”</p>

<p>When you’re a child, your parents <em>create you</em>. Everything you know, do, and believe, is a product of how you were raised. Harry Morgan <em>knew</em> that, as a very young child, witnessing murder <em>could</em> lead someone to <em>become</em> antisocial, a “psychopath” later in life, and therefore <em>more</em> inclined to <em>be</em> a predator (the idea that someone can be <em>diagnosed</em> as a psychopath, and then also be considered inclined toward murder and violence is definitely something of a topic of contention, but this post isn’t about that). He didn’t <em>know</em> for sure that this is what would happen to Dexter. And yet, he <em>imprinted</em> this idea upon him.</p>

<p>Dexter is a victim of his own upbringing.</p>

<p>Harry Morgan is a man of tragedy. He’s a man who lost his first son to an accidental drowning. He lost the woman he had an affair with, and then he lost his <em>actual wife</em> to sickness. He’s a man who failed to be a <em>good</em> officer of the law on numerous occasions (if such a thing <em>can</em> exist), and it is through that failure, that Dexter was born.</p>

<p>Now, I’m not saying for sure that either Dexter or Harry are definitively <em>good</em> people. These ideas of “good” and “bad” in this sense are meaningless.</p>

<p>But Harry is only two steps from fitting within the moral code he gave his own son, so that he could be an ethical, and unseen, serial killer.</p>

<p>Think of Harry the same way you think of Jigsaw. Jigsaw isn’t a <em>traditional</em> killer. He never pulled a single trigger, or used any knives. He never <em>directly</em> ended anyone’s lives, himself. Jigsaw created the machinations that would do the killing <em>for him</em>, the same way Harry Morgan <em>created</em> a weapon that could kill, undetected, and <em>above the law</em>, without ever having to pull a trigger, himself. Jigsaw’s bear trap is to Harry Morgan what Dexter, <em>is.</em></p>

<p>Jigsaw is a villain.</p>

<p>Harry Morgan … is a villain.</p>

<p>The next question is, “Can a villain have good intentions?”</p>

<p>Or, “What <em>is</em> a villain?”</p>]]></content><author><name>⸸ commander ░ nova ⸸ :~$</name></author><category term="Dexter" /><category term="dexter" /><category term="tv" /><category term="media" /><category term="fiction" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[So, this is it! Dexter: Original Sin season 1 is over! After watching the final episode, and confirming to myself that Dexter hasn’t been this good since at least season four of the original show, I think there’s one real question that needs to be answered: Is Dexter’s foster father, Harry Morgan, the main villain? In order to answer that question, we have to look at this through the same kind of window in which we viewed the plot of Breaking Bad.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The HTML Element Quiz!</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/quiz/2025/02/14/the-html-element-quiz.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The HTML Element Quiz!" /><published>2025-02-14T15:12:00-05:00</published><updated>2025-02-14T15:12:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/quiz/2025/02/14/the-html-element-quiz</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/quiz/2025/02/14/the-html-element-quiz.html"><![CDATA[<p>Today I was looking for things to write about while I push through the main story quests in Zenless Zone Zero. Which, might I add, has like, 400 million lines of dialogue to move through in-between all the latter half of the game’s action. But, it was suggested to me via <a href="https://shellsharks.social/@shellsharks" target="_blank">@shellsharks</a> that I take the, “Which HTML element are you quit?” (you can <a href="https://jamesg.blog/2025/02/13/html-quiz" target="_blank">find that here</a>)</p>

<p>And, it turns out, I am the “canvas” element.</p>

<p><img src="/img/posts/htmlelement/Screenshot from 2025-02-14 15-11-38.png" /></p>

<p>Which element are you?</p>]]></content><author><name>⸸ commander ░ nova ⸸ :~$</name></author><category term="Quiz" /><category term="quiz" /><category term="html" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today I was looking for things to write about while I push through the main story quests in Zenless Zone Zero. Which, might I add, has like, 400 million lines of dialogue to move through in-between all the latter half of the game’s action. But, it was suggested to me via @shellsharks that I take the, “Which HTML element are you quit?” (you can find that here)]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">GameDevs Working Against Linux Users For Reasons</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/linux/2025/02/13/gamedevs-working-against-linux-users-for-reasons.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="GameDevs Working Against Linux Users For Reasons" /><published>2025-02-13T11:08:00-05:00</published><updated>2025-02-13T11:08:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/linux/2025/02/13/gamedevs-working-against-linux-users-for-reasons</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/linux/2025/02/13/gamedevs-working-against-linux-users-for-reasons.html"><![CDATA[<p>If you recently abandoned, or maybe even <em>never</em> used Windows, you might be like me, in that, you don’t get to play the likes of Fortnite, or especially games like Valorant, and Call of Duty. Maybe for some, this is a net positive, or you just don’t care either way. For me, I feel like I have enough to fill my time that missing Call of Duty and Valorant isn’t all that much of a thought. But, these things aside, some of the studios behind these games deploy an especially egregious type of anti-cheat via the kernel.</p>

<p>If you ask me, using the kernel as a method of stopping cheaters should be illegal. I mean, just look at this thread over on <a href="https://linustechtips.com/topic/1592979-whats-the-worst-that-can-happen-with-kernel-level-anti-cheat-in-games-if-one-already-took-these-following-steps/" target="_blank">Linus Tech Tips</a> where users are talking about how safe it is to <em>have</em> this kind of thing invading your PC, and what you can do to protect your data. Some suggest going so far as to having <em>nothing but your games</em> on said PC.</p>

<p>That is … <em>fuckin’ nuts</em>.</p>

<p>No gamedev studio should have that much control, whether it <em>actually</em> stops cheaters, or not (and whether it’s really all that effective is legitimately up-in-the-air).</p>

<p>But … it happens anyway. Do we blame the cheaters? Partially. But, we <em>also</em> have to blame the studio and the developers, or, maybe even the publishers, too. And maybe even a little bit of the blame should go to streaming platforms, and sweaty streamers, who have solidified this <em>idea</em> that you can get rich streaming Fortnite and Call of Duty. An idea that has inadvertently skyrocketed the seriousness of online competitive gaming.</p>

<p>Do you remember back in 1999 when the worst that happened to cheaters in Quake 2 was that they’d just get a permaban from a server? Pepperidge Farm remembers. And do you know how those cheaters were detected?</p>

<p>… the admins of a server would just actually watch footage and make the decision themselves.</p>

<p>A wild got-dang concept.</p>

<p>All of these things combined, though, have created an atmosphere where cheating must be stopped, <strong>has to be stopped</strong>, <em>at all costs</em>, even if it disadvantages you, the player, who’s just trying to chill, and have a good time. Because there’s no elementary school lesson more ingrained in our society, than punishing everyone for the actions of a few.</p>

<p>You can see an example of this, where a studio didn’t even deploy kernel level measures. They just <em>dropped support</em> for Steam’s Proton, and booted <em>all</em> Linux users from their player-base in a move to “stop cheaters”. Yep, I’m talking about <a href="https://www.indiatodaygaming.com/news/story/respawn-cuts-linux-support-for-apex-legends-in-bold-move-to-stop-cheaters-5684" target="_blank">Apex Legends</a>. Because, it’s not like anyone on Windows is using software hacks and cheats, it’s those <em>pesky Linux users</em>. It’s gotta be, what, with their custom window managers and desktop environments! Argh!</p>

<p>I just love when a studio decides to punish millions of potential customers and players, because someone who’s bad at games uses the same operating system as the rest of them.</p>

<p>I guess we’ll just ignore the fact that Windows is a hot-bed of spyware, bloat, and also cheats and scammers!</p>

<p>Anyway, this pretty much brings me to why I’m even writing this today.</p>

<p>I didn’t even know, until now, that FromSoftware was releasing another title, but now I do.</p>

<p><a href="https://en.bandainamcoent.eu/elden-ring/elden-ring-nightreign" target="_blank">Elden Ring NightReign</a> comes out on May 30th, as some kind of … standalone Elden Ring co-op title. I don’t really understand the need for this, because, why not just have it be an expansion to the <em>actual</em> Elden Ring? But, apparently, they redesigned the mechanics … or something.</p>

<p>That’s not what I really want to write about.</p>

<p>The issue, is that ERNR will, <em>allegedly</em>, be deploying … <a href="https://www.gamingonlinux.com/2025/02/elden-ring-nightreign-launches-in-may-will-have-kernel-level-anti-cheat/" target="_blank">kernel level anti-cheat</a>.</p>

<p>You’re probably thinking, “Why the FUCK do they need something like that, in a <em>co-op game</em>?”</p>

<p>Your guess is as good as mine, dude.</p>

<p>I mean, cheaters <em>are</em> a little rampant in Souls-like FromSoftware games. Corrupting files, becoming invincible, and so on, and so forth. And FromSoft has sort of a track record of questionable bans, where anyone who even so much as <em>accidentally</em> joins a session with a cheater, <em>could end up being banned, themselves</em>.</p>

<p>So … we’re just going to have to deal with this new title, and maybe even possibly <em>future</em> FromSoftware titles utilizing a method of anti-cheat that, again, <em>should be illegal</em> … because, we just can’t figure out how to make our games hacker proof, without tampering with every single user’s system, violating their privacy, making their data vulnerable, and also effectively barring Linux and Steam Deck users from playing our game.</p>

<p>Okay.</p>

<p>Seems logical.</p>

<p>Seems like I just won’t buy anymore FromSoftware games, huh. Just like I’ll never load up Apex Legends again, and Call of Duty is a distant memory that I’ll only touch if its on a console.</p>

<p>Maybe ten years down the line when we have a government interested in regulations, we can see something being done about this. Or, maybe Microsoft, as much as I <em>hate</em> them, <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/7/26/24206719/microsoft-windows-changes-crowdstrike-kernel-driver" target="_blank">will solve the problem themselves</a>.</p>]]></content><author><name>⸸ commander ░ nova ⸸ :~$</name></author><category term="Linux" /><category term="gaming" /><category term="linux" /><category term="anticheat" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[If you recently abandoned, or maybe even never used Windows, you might be like me, in that, you don’t get to play the likes of Fortnite, or especially games like Valorant, and Call of Duty. Maybe for some, this is a net positive, or you just don’t care either way. For me, I feel like I have enough to fill my time that missing Call of Duty and Valorant isn’t all that much of a thought. But, these things aside, some of the studios behind these games deploy an especially egregious type of anti-cheat via the kernel.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Tumblr Trying To Squeeze Into ActivityPub</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/tumblr/2025/02/12/tumblr-trying-to-squeeze-into-activitypub.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Tumblr Trying To Squeeze Into ActivityPub" /><published>2025-02-12T11:34:00-05:00</published><updated>2025-02-12T11:34:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/tumblr/2025/02/12/tumblr-trying-to-squeeze-into-activitypub</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/tumblr/2025/02/12/tumblr-trying-to-squeeze-into-activitypub.html"><![CDATA[<p>At the news that <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2025/02/11/tumblr-to-join-the-fediverse-after-wordpress-migration-completes/" target="_blank">Tumblr will be “joining” ActivityPub</a> after its migration to Wordpress completes, I have some thoughts. Maybe eight or nine years ago, I would’ve thought, “Oh cool! Now it’ll be easier to see some of my favorite creators and artists on the federated timeline!” And then things would have been pretty neat, simply adding cool stuff to an already growing platform. But, that’s not how I feel about it anymore.</p>

<p>Earlier, at the end of last year, Tumblr terminated my account without notice, without an e-mail, and without <em>responding</em> to my multiple e-mails, <em>for months</em>, over what I can only presume to be a cartoon gif of Super Mario Brothers character Luigi, holding a cartoon gun, shooting cartoon billionaires. Maybe they thought it was in bad taste. I thought it was in amazing and awesome taste, and you can’t change my mind. Never-the-less, it is <em>extremely unprofessional</em> to just delete someone’s account on your platform without at least specifying exactly <em>why</em> in an e-mail, and <em>if</em> there are any steps to eventually recover your account.</p>

<p>That was <em>years</em> of content, and even things I <em>paid for</em>, <strong>gone</strong>. Without a single word. The domain <em>I owned</em> through Wordpress, zapped out of existence!</p>

<p>But, these are only just <em>personal</em> grievances. There is … so much more.</p>

<p>In 2018, Tumblr wiped out NSFW content, which was said to be <em>mostly</em> about eliminating CSAM from their platform. Which, you know, <em>makes sense</em>. But, painting with such a broad brush had adverse side-effects, like <a href="https://www.eff.org/tossedout/tumblr-ban-adult-content" target="_blank">pushing LGBTQ+ users even further to the margins</a>, or <em>off of the platform entirely.</em></p>

<p>“But Nova, all they have to do is stop posting porn!”</p>

<p>It <em>wasn’t</em> just about porn. It was about sex positivity, sharing yourself, and your journey, in all of its facets, uncensored. A grown adult <em>should be allowed</em> to express themselves, as they see fit, on a platform, where there are safeguards <em>already in-place</em> to designate someone’s account 18+.</p>

<p>And I’m <em>sure</em> most people who were on Twitter in 2018 and 2019, back in the <em>supposed</em> golden days, remember Tumblr fandoms absolutely invading their timelines with the kind of niche, meaningless discourse you <em>would only ever see on Tumblr.</em> This was met with mixed feelings.</p>

<p>Then, in 2019, Automattic, the team behind Wordpress.com, <a href="https://wptavern.com/automattic-acquires-tumblr-plans-to-rebuild-the-backend-powered-by-wordpress" target="_blank">acquired Tumblr</a> from Yahoo for 3 million dollars USD. Which, is kind of hilarious, considering that <a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2022/09/15/how-tumblr-went-from-1-billion-yahoo-payday-to-3-million-fire-sale.html" target="_blank">Yahoo purchased Tumblr in 2013 for 1 billion USD</a>. But that’s beside the point. Automattic acquiring Tumblr was also a thing of mixed feelings, and ultimately, I don’t think people cared all that much, at the time, that Tumblr was now connected to Wordpress. I mean, <em>most people</em> were still correctly under the assumption that Tumblr was a <em>heavily</em> censored platform.</p>

<p>That’s not the end of the story, though. In 2024, Matt Mullenweg, the CEO of Automattic, began his tirade against <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/25/wordpress-org-bans-wp-engine-blocks-it-from-accessing-its-resources/" target="_blank">unaffiliated Wordpress companies</a>, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2025/01/11/matt-mullenweg-deactivates-wordpress-accounts-of-contributors-planning-a-fork/" target="_blank">and open source WP tech</a>.  Or, maybe you remember when Matt himself was fighting with a trans woman over moderation policy on Tumblr (because, people still use Tumblr, after-all), and then banned her for a mostly harmless post that read that she hopes the CEO “dies a forever painful death involving a car covered in hammers that explodes more than a few times and hammers go flying everywhere.” This, was, of course, in response to Tumblr/Automattic’s <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2024/02/22/tumblr-ceo-publicly-spars-with-trans-user-over-account-ban-revealing-private-account-names-in-the-process/" target="_blank">refusal to properly moderate transphobic content</a>.</p>

<p>The latter is, in my opinion, the failure of big-tech-talking-head’s ability to “read the room,” or detect when something is a <em>shitpost</em>, and not serious in the slightest. And definitely not a <em>threat of violence</em>. But, that’s a problem with most CEOs and billionaires. They’re so disconnected from reality and other people, that <em>everything</em> goes over their heads. Like exploding hammers.</p>

<p>And now, since you have the full story, you <em>know</em> why Tumblr shouldn’t be part of ActivityPub. Unless Matt is forced to step-down, and unless Tumblr <em>drastically</em> changes their moderation policy, they should be treated exactly the same way Meta is being treated on the fediverse–By instance blocking them <em>completely</em>.</p>]]></content><author><name>⸸ commander ░ nova ⸸ :~$</name></author><category term="Tumblr" /><category term="socialmedia" /><category term="tumblr" /><category term="activitypub" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[At the news that Tumblr will be “joining” ActivityPub after its migration to Wordpress completes, I have some thoughts. Maybe eight or nine years ago, I would’ve thought, “Oh cool! Now it’ll be easier to see some of my favorite creators and artists on the federated timeline!” And then things would have been pretty neat, simply adding cool stuff to an already growing platform. But, that’s not how I feel about it anymore.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The Breaking Point</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/thoughts/2025/02/10/the-breaking-point.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Breaking Point" /><published>2025-02-10T22:21:00-05:00</published><updated>2025-02-10T22:21:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/thoughts/2025/02/10/the-breaking-point</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/thoughts/2025/02/10/the-breaking-point.html"><![CDATA[<p>Not to be too personal, and with names censored due to this being the internet, but I think I might be <em>ready</em> to be done working for the company that I’m at. I told myself in January, that something had to change. Something big needed to change, or happen, because my life feels like it’s going in circles, and nothing’s ever really getting to where I need, or <em>want</em> it to be. And now, I’m kind of at this crossroads.</p>

<p>An intersection where I just suck it up, and work in a position I’ve literally never been interested in, just because it’s two extra dollars an hour, and risk hating it, not doing well <em>at all</em>, and possibly even maybe lose my job <em>because of that</em>, or … I do something I haven’t done in years.</p>

<p>I leave.</p>

<p>I take a risk, and I start working for myself.</p>

<p>Ever since the era of covid began, gig-jobs have erupted, and <em>never</em> gone away. I firmly believe it’s likely the future that people will just do work assigned to them through apps, at their own pace, with their own set hours and schedule.</p>

<p>Of course, my ultimate goal is to just be a web developer.</p>

<p>But, since it seems to be <em>extremely hard to find a career where I can get a shoe-in</em>, I’m looking at gig work as my next step.</p>

<p>Most corporations with zero-skill entry won’t pay you much, and it takes <em>years</em> before you’re making <em>just enough</em> to get by.</p>

<p>But I’m tired of making <em>just enough</em> to <em>hardly</em> get by, what with, massive amounts of debt, and all. Why keep doing that, keep making money at a set rate that can’t change, with restricted over-time that you <em>can’t have</em> at all times, whenever you want …</p>

<p>When I can download an app, jump in my car, and go make money <em>whenever the hell I want</em>?</p>

<p>Is it a risk? Yeah, probably.</p>

<p>I still haven’t yet decided if I’m going to make this jump.</p>

<p>My body, though, I feel, is at a breaking point, where it just can’t do this anymore.</p>

<p>I can’t be pushed into a position I didn’t ask for. I can’t keep running around on my feet for eight to ten hours a day and still have energy to … <em>have a life</em>. I’m relatively healthy. Quite a bit older than I was the last time I tried to do things for myself, and yet, it’s like they say. It’s never too late to make a change, right?</p>]]></content><author><name>⸸ commander ░ nova ⸸ :~$</name></author><category term="Thoughts" /><category term="thoughts" /><category term="life" /><category term="work" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Not to be too personal, and with names censored due to this being the internet, but I think I might be ready to be done working for the company that I’m at. I told myself in January, that something had to change. Something big needed to change, or happen, because my life feels like it’s going in circles, and nothing’s ever really getting to where I need, or want it to be. And now, I’m kind of at this crossroads.]]></summary></entry></feed>