<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en-US"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.10.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en-US" /><updated>2025-02-09T01:20:49-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">cmdr-nova@internet:~$</title><subtitle>cmdr-nova&apos;s personal blog and home on the indie-web.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Directions For Life</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/image/2025/02/09/directions-for-life.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Directions For Life" /><published>2025-02-09T01:19:00-05:00</published><updated>2025-02-09T01:19:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/image/2025/02/09/directions-for-life</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/image/2025/02/09/directions-for-life.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="/img/posts/inspo-backrooms/backrooms_onestep.png" /></p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Image" /><category term="image" /><category term="backrooms" /><category term="inspiration" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Dexter: Original Sin Is A Redemption</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/dexter/2025/02/08/dexter-original-sin-is-a-redemption.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Dexter: Original Sin Is A Redemption" /><published>2025-02-08T23:39:00-05:00</published><updated>2025-02-08T23:39:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/dexter/2025/02/08/dexter-original-sin-is-a-redemption</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/dexter/2025/02/08/dexter-original-sin-is-a-redemption.html"><![CDATA[<p>I’ve written about Dexter before. The lackluster ending to the original series, and the only <em>very slightly</em> better, but still lackluster ending to the redo in New Blood that the writer’s attempted. Gonna go full-on spoilers here: The OG series was <em>fine</em>, even after the fourth season, until the writers killed off Deb with a blood clot. The OG series was <em>fine</em>, until they had Dexter ride off into a hurricane, and then reappear as a lumberjack in upstate New York.</p>

<p>New Blood was <em>awesome</em> … until they had his son shoot him in the chest with a hunting rifle and leave him to die in the woods, driving off into Manhattan while the credits rolled.</p>

<p>It was artistic. I get it, I got it.</p>

<p>But, up until Original Sin started airing, I’ve always wondered, “Do the writers actually <em>know</em> what the viewers want to see? Are they just spit-balling ideas where Dexter is never known as the serial killer he is, for shits and giggles?”</p>

<p>The thing is, though, is that while Dexter <em>should</em> see the justice system, and that his old cop friends from Miami <em>should</em> find out what he was <em>really</em> doing … in this day and age, it’s really hard to sell it to an audience, that a guy who killed murderers, rapists, and pedophiles, that he was <em>somehow</em> a <em>bad</em> guy. The world is a <em>much different place</em> than it was in 2008.</p>

<p>But … the act of putting his real identity in front of people he knew for years, was something that <em>should have been done</em> in the original series. It’s <em>what everyone was waiting for</em>.</p>

<p>It would have been akin to the moment in Breaking Bad that his entire family finds out what Walter’s been doing with his free time.</p>

<p>It’s that <em>mask-off</em> moment that really would have made the show. But the writer’s didn’t do that. For some reason … they didn’t <em>want</em> to do that. They <em>wanted</em> him to get away, and keep going. And, I think, that’s also probably mostly what the audience <em>also</em> wanted. But, his identity as a killer of killers <em>cannot</em>, in a fictional 21st century, feasibly <em>remain</em> a secret. And it was exactly what should have happened, shortly after his sister found out that he was murdering people.</p>

<p>I don’t want to say that the show jumped the shark, because it’s still <em>a pretty good show</em>, especially in its freshman years.</p>

<p>Flash-forward and its 2025, the whole entire world has pretty much forgotten about Dexter and the two times they did the ending to his story, and somehow also just didn’t get it right. Both times.</p>

<p>Now, here we are, watching a narrated long-cut flashback sequence of his life as a 20 year old (or 19?) in the 90s just as he’s hired by Miami Metro.</p>

<p>I didn’t think it was a good idea, at first. I thought, “This is gonna be pointless. We already know everything that happens.” But, as a matter of fact, you <strong>don’t</strong> know everything that happens.</p>

<p>Aside from the fact that Original Sin starts with a flash-forward of Dexter surviving the gun shot from New Blood, it opens up a plethora of <em>brand new things</em> you’ve never seen before. Gun fights, screw-ups, relationships, and … Dexter <em>literally</em> taping the captain of the homicide unit to a kill table.</p>

<p>And it’s all done in a way that <em>actually</em> and <em>finally</em> feels like the writers have <em>figured it out</em>. Like the light-bulb flashed on in their heads, and they went, “Oh hey, you know what? I just realized what we should be doing with this character and this story.” And then they did it.</p>

<p>Now, I’m not saying Dexter’s identity is revealed to anyone in the prequel series. That wouldn’t make sense. But I think I can see where this is finally going. I mean, you got a <em>tease</em> of it at the end of New Blood, and then no resolution <em>whatsoever</em>, because they tentatively <em>killed Dexter off</em>.</p>

<p>But, after watching through 9 episodes out of 10 of Original Sin, so far, I think it was a good idea to go, “No, wait. He isn’t dead.”</p>

<p>Here’s hoping they get the ending right, this time.</p>

<p>As far as their plans to release a Trinity Killer side-series … uh, you know, I’m not really sure we need that. But hey, whatever floats the writer’s boats at this point.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Dexter" /><category term="dexter" /><category term="media" /><category term="television" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[I’ve written about Dexter before. The lackluster ending to the original series, and the only very slightly better, but still lackluster ending to the redo in New Blood that the writer’s attempted. Gonna go full-on spoilers here: The OG series was fine, even after the fourth season, until the writers killed off Deb with a blood clot. The OG series was fine, until they had Dexter ride off into a hurricane, and then reappear as a lumberjack in upstate New York.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Be Social In Second Life?</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/secondlife/2025/02/07/be-social-in-second-life.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Be Social In Second Life?" /><published>2025-02-07T22:27:00-05:00</published><updated>2025-02-07T22:27:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/secondlife/2025/02/07/be-social-in-second-life</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/secondlife/2025/02/07/be-social-in-second-life.html"><![CDATA[<p>I was writing a post this morning about mobile games and whether or not they’ve reach the glass ceiling of actually being worthy of the title “game,” but then I went to work, and twelve hours later … I don’t really feel like writing about that! I mean, it’s in the drafts, so maybe I’ll continue it. But, I actually kind of want to write about Second Life. As in, I don’t really know if it’s really my thing anymore?</p>

<p>I mean, I still run a store, and I think it’ll be there regardless, until the servers shut down. But, way back in the day, like 2016 or so, I had little virtual-world-friend-groups, and I always had people to talk to. It was <em>easy</em> to meet and make friends. Nowadays? I dunno. I meet someone through Thundr (the Second Life dating/friend app), we talk for about a minute, maybe meet up outside of the app …</p>

<p>And then that’s it. You never hear from them again.</p>

<p>I don’t know if it’s just me being older, and less tolerant of going through the process of meeting someone, doing smalltalk, getting to know them, and then finding out they suck, or they wanted something out of me that I can’t give, or so on and so forth.</p>

<p>But even just with <em>friends</em>. I have a long list of people on my Second Life friend list, and <em>none of them have messaged me in well over a year</em>. Some of them, for <em>years</em>.</p>

<p>There’s this strange phenomenon in SL, where people kind of treat time differently? Like, you’ve got a friend and you speak everyday, but then suddenly you have a bad week, or a busy couple of days, and you just *don’t talk.”</p>

<p>And then they’re gone.</p>

<p>As if you were missing for years, and they forgot about you.</p>

<p>It’s <strong>weird</strong>.</p>

<p>I dunno, I just had to rant a little bit about that. Because when I’m logged into Second Life I spend most of my time just hanging out in my house on the hill, and then logging off. Maybe it <strong>is</strong> a “me” problem.</p>

<p><img src="/img/posts/socialsl/Screenshot from 2025-02-07 22-33-53.png" /></p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="SecondLife" /><category term="secondlife" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[I was writing a post this morning about mobile games and whether or not they’ve reach the glass ceiling of actually being worthy of the title “game,” but then I went to work, and twelve hours later … I don’t really feel like writing about that! I mean, it’s in the drafts, so maybe I’ll continue it. But, I actually kind of want to write about Second Life. As in, I don’t really know if it’s really my thing anymore?]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The Sims 2</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/thesims2/2025/02/06/the-sims-2.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Sims 2" /><published>2025-02-06T22:13:00-05:00</published><updated>2025-02-06T22:13:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/thesims2/2025/02/06/the-sims-2</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/thesims2/2025/02/06/the-sims-2.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="/img/posts/thesims2/Screenshot from 2025-02-06 22-08-15.png" /></p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="TheSims2" /><category term="thesims2" /><category term="image" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Re: You Can’t Post Your Way Out of Fascism</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/socialmedia/2025/02/06/re-you-can-t-post-your-way-out-of-fascism.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Re: You Can’t Post Your Way Out of Fascism" /><published>2025-02-06T11:11:00-05:00</published><updated>2025-02-06T11:11:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/socialmedia/2025/02/06/re-you-can-t-post-your-way-out-of-fascism</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/socialmedia/2025/02/06/re-you-can-t-post-your-way-out-of-fascism.html"><![CDATA[<p>This post is in response to <a href="https://www.404media.co/you-cant-post-your-way-out-of-fascism/" target="_blank">a post made by Janus Rose over at 404 Media</a>. A website I mostly respect, and like to see every so often. But, when writers and journalists start talking about social media, and opposition to fascism, you have to take into account their own view of the world, and the internet, in order to begin to dissect what they’re saying. Like many, a lot of people know social media as the corporate algorithm farms that Twitter, Threads, and Instagram <em>are</em>, and it’s through this lens that I believe, “You Can’t Post Your Way Out of Fascism,” was written.</p>

<p>Never-the-less, I’d like to dissect it.</p>

<blockquote>
If there’s one thing I’d hoped people had learned going into the next four years of Donald Trump as president, it’s that spending lots of time online posting about what people in power are saying and doing is not going to accomplish anything. If anything, it’s exactly what they want.
<br /><br />
Trump’s second presidential term has arrived amidst a new golden age for internet grifters, propagandists, and bad-faith hucksters of all stripes. The contours of this era of untruth have been flashing like neon signs for the past decade, constantly enticing us to engage with its impenetrable nonsense. Whether it’s gaslighting everyone who saw Elon Musk give two Nazi salutes <a href="https://apnews.com/article/musk-gesture-salute-antisemitism-0070dae53c7a73397b104ae645877535" target="_blank">during the inauguration</a> or blaming the Los Angeles wildfires <a href="https://www.politico.com/news/2025/01/15/republicans-dei-la-fires-00198551" target="_blank">on the racist dog whistle of “DEI,</a>” lies and absurdities now regularly flood our senses, having long outpaced the media’s capacity to filter them.
</blockquote>

<p>This is kind of what I mean, when I say, that I believe the author’s personal experience with social media and being online, is exclusive to that of the aforementioned platforms. Those that use algorithms to harness endless attention and views. That is, after-all, how all of this works, and how misinformation and propaganda spreads. Taking all of that into account, it’s perfectly reasonable to think, or say, that “you can’t post your way out of fascism.”</p>

<p>But, a piece of the puzzle is missing, like it always is.</p>

<blockquote>
Many of my journalist colleagues have attempted to beat back the tide under banners like “fighting disinformation” and “accountability.” While these efforts are admirable, the past few years have changed my own internal calculus. Thinkers like <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/quotes/7870768-never-believe-that-anti-semites-are-completely-unaware-of-the-absurdity" target="_blank">Jean-Paul Sartre</a> and <a href="https://www.openculture.com/2022/02/hannah-arendt-explains-how-propaganda-uses-lies.html" target="_blank">Hannah Arendt</a> warned us that the point of this deluge is not to persuade, but to overwhelm and paralyze our capacity to act. More recently, researchers have found that the viral outrage disseminated on social media in response to these ridiculous claims actually <a href="https://par.nsf.gov/servlets/purl/10095997" target="_blank">reduces the effectiveness of collective action</a>. The result is a media environment that keeps us in a state of debilitating fear and anger, endlessly reacting to our oppressors instead of organizing against them. 
<br /><br />
To that end, the age of corporate social media has been a roaring success.
<br /><br />
“The reality is you are oxygenating the things these people are saying even as you purport to debunk them,” Katherine Cross, a sociologist and author of Log Off: Why Posting and Politics (Almost) Never Mix, told 404 Media. “Whether it’s [New York Times columnist] Ross Douthat providing a <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2025/01/11/opinion/columnists/o-canada-come-join-us.html" target="_blank">sane-washing gloss on Trump’s mania</a> or people on social media vehemently disagreeing and dunking on it, they’re legitimizing it as part of the discourse.”
</blockquote>

<p>Okay, so we cement the idea now, that the author is specifically referring to corporate social media, because, and unfortunately, this is a lot of people’s experience with being online. And, you probably <em>already know</em>, my answer to every single bit of this, is ActivityPub, and <a class="page-link" href="/pages/webdev/">building your own website</a>. But wait! I want to talk about the rest of this.</p>

<p>This second set of paragraphs continues to diverge into the idea of an algorithm controlling everything, wherein it keeps you in a constant, circular state of never-ending doom. And, for all intents and purposes, that is why most social media is bad!</p>

<p>But, also, these arguments that have been presented so far, that purport themselves to be socially-more-aware-than-thou, like always, <em>are completely ignoring disabled people</em>, whose, for some, entire lives <em>are online</em>. Which, obviously, specifically restricts them to only being able to take action via social media. And when you continue to frame the idea of social media around this faux pas that Twitter and Threads <em>are the only choices</em>, you’re doing yourself, and disabled people, a <em>huge disservice.</em></p>

<blockquote>
Cross’ book contains a meticulous catalog of social media sins which many people who follow and care about current events are probably guilty of—myself very much included. She documents how tech platforms encourage us, through their design affordances, to post and seethe and doomscroll into the void, always reacting and never acting.
<br /><br />
But perhaps the greatest of these sins is convincing ourselves that posting is a form of political activism, when it is at best a coping mechanism—an individualist solution to problems that can only be solved by collective action. This, says Cross, is the primary way tech platforms atomize and alienate us, creating “a solipsism that says you are the main protagonist in a sea of NPCs.”
<br /><br />
“Everything on social media is designed to make you think like that,” said Cross. “It’s all about you—your feed, your network, your friends.”
</blockquote>

<p>Now we get into the slightly-more-offensive bits of this article, where we continue to go on and on about the dangers of algorithms, continue to spout off about “collective action,” as if we don’t all live in a system that aggressively encourages individualism to the point that, if you don’t first deconstruct yourself of this ideal, none of this matters <em>at all</em>. <em>That</em> is why people go online in places like Twitter and Threads, and speak to others, the world, and the void, as if they’re the “main character” in a sea of NPCs.</p>

<p>Because we live in a system, that literally conditions you <em>to think that way.</em> We live in a system that <em>celebrates</em> narcissistic behavior.</p>

<p>Tech platforms harnessing that, are part of the disease, but not the main cause of it.</p>

<blockquote>
In the days since the inauguration, I’ve watched people on Bluesky and Instagram fall into these same old traps. My timeline is full of reactive hot takes and gotchas by people who still seem to think they can quote-dunk their way out of fascism—or who know they can’t, but simply can’t resist taking the bait. The media is more than willing to work up their appetites. Legacy news outlets cynically chase clicks (and ad dollars) by disseminating whatever sensational nonsense those in power are spewing. 
<br /><br />
This in turn fuels yet another round of online outrage, edgy takes, and screenshots exposing the “hypocrisy” of people who never cared about being seen as hypocrites, because that’s not the point. Even violent fantasies about putting billionaires to the guillotine are rendered inept in these online spaces—just another pressure release valve to harmlessly dissipate our rage instead of compelling ourselves to organize and act.
<br /><br />
This is the opposite of what media, social or otherwise, is supposed to do. Of course it’s important to stay informed, and journalists can still provide the valuable information we need to take action. But this process has been short-circuited by tech platforms and a media environment built around seeking reaction for its own sake. Many Twitter refugees made a good choice in migrating from Musk’s X to Bluesky, carving out a new online space that is inhospitable to bigoted debate bros and time-wasting trolls. But in their enemies’ absence, many of these Left-leaning posters have just reverted to dunking on each other, preferring the catharsis of sectarian conflict over the hard work of organizing. 
</blockquote>

<p>Now we’re finally mentioning Bluesky, and this is a point I want to touch on, because Bluesky is, unfortunately, just about as bad as <em>the other platforms.</em> You can see that in the author’s writing here. Janus <em>knows</em> that Bluesky is just another setup for the fascist oligarchs, but that’s about as far as the thought process goes.</p>

<p>First of all, a lot of people go online to vent. That’s just how it is. In 2025, most of our friends and most of our social interactions <em>are online</em>, so, it would make sense that if something is stressing us out, we’re probably going to express that in whatever space we happen to inhabit. That’s not the problem, or <em>a</em> problem.</p>

<p>Left-leaning people dunking on each other and generally creating an atmosphere of harassment and abuse is absolutely something that I’ve experienced multiple times on Bluesky, but that’s because this type of behavior is a symptom of Twitter, coming from people who <em>refuse</em> to deconstruct their behavior, and their own ideas about the people around them, and how they should be treated. But, this just goes back to what was previously mentioned about systems we live in, and the narcissism it encourages.</p>

<p>But, I’d like to address one other piece of this snippet, in that it’s apparently believed that our enemies are “absent” from Bluesky, or that Bluesky makes itself inhospitable to bigots.</p>

<p>That’s not true. If you haven’t been living under a rock, you’re probably already aware of <a href="https://www.advocate.com/business/bluesky-jesse-singal" target="_blank">the Jesse Singal disaster</a>, from <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2024/12/13/bluesky-is-at-a-crossroads-as-users-petition-to-ban-jesse-singal-over-anti-trans-views-harassment/?guccounter=1" target="_blank">multiple sources that wrote about it</a>.</p>

<p>And this is entirely the biggest problem with Bluesky: Is that <em>it is a centralized platform</em> (not decentralized even in the slightest), with VC investors skyrocketing into hundreds of millions of dollars in backing funds … And this is <em>partially why</em> its moderators would hesitate to silence bigotry and violence–Because its backers, such as Blockchain Capital, are <em>part of the abusive manosphere people are trying to escape by joining Bluesky</em>.</p>

<p>But we’re wondering why the platform kinda sorta seems to be no better than the Bad Places?</p>

<p>“But, but, on Mastodon, or other ActivityPub things, there’s just NERDS.”</p>

<p>Hold on, I’ll address you in a minute.</p>

<blockquote>
Under this status quo, everything becomes a myopic contest of who can best exploit peoples’ anxieties to command their attention and energy. If we don’t learn how to extract ourselves from this loop, none of the information we gain will manifest as tangible action—and the people in charge prefer it that way.
<br /><br />
It’s no surprise that tech billionaires like Musk, Jeff Bezos, and Mark Zuckerberg have rushed to kiss the ring of the twice-ascendent Trump. The marriage of big tech and Trumpworld should make clear that Silicon Valley and authoritarians share the same goal: to crush dissent by keeping their would-be opponents spinning on an endless hamster wheel of reactive anger. And just like in the classic 1983 thriller WarGames, the only winning move is not to play.
<br /><br />
That can be a tough pill to swallow when the internet is our main window into the world, and that world seems to be rapidly falling apart. We gaze into our phone-portals, paralyzed by the trance of the doomscroll, reacting and swiping from one news article and hot take to another. Authoritarians issue frightening proclamations that may or may not be legally enforceable, seizing our attention and energy and ensuring that the process will repeat, ad infinitum.
<br /><br />
So what is the alternative? If we log off, what exactly are we supposed to do instead? How are we supposed to get information without constantly raising our antennae into the noxious cumulonimbus cloud of social media?
<br /><br />
It isn’t quite as simple as “touch grass,” but it also sort of is.
</blockquote>

<p>I’m starting to blockquote mass amounts of text here, because this article is much longer than it needs to be, and mostly because the author keeps talking about the same thing, over, and over again.</p>

<p>The world that the author paints here is something that I can’t really relate to. I don’t log on to read bad news and doomscroll forever. Of course, I <em>do</em> read about what’s going on in the world, but as an active participant in ActivityPub, I curate my feeds and my timelines to be <em>mostly absent</em> of the constant deluge of panic-politics.</p>

<p>I <em>used</em> to be part of the techno-fascism complex’s algorithm, but then I started having panic attacks and issues with anxiety. So, I stopped.</p>

<p>The author asks, “What is the alternative?”</p>

<p>I mean, telling people to “touch grass” is exactly the mindset of the toxic, abusive people who quote-dunk on a daily basis in left-leaning spaces against <em>other</em> left-leaning people, thinking that this changes things, or has any social impact at all, outside of onlookers deciding that you’re a gigantic asshole.</p>

<p>But, I mean, you <em>should</em> go outside. It’s good for you.</p>

<p>But: With a Vengeance, the <em>alternative</em>, if you feel like you <em>want</em> to be on social media, and you <em>need</em> a space to express yourself, and your thoughts, has <em>always been</em> … ActivityPub.</p>

<p>“It’s hard” isn’t a valid excuse. “There’s just nerds there” isn’t a valid excuse. “There’s abusive people there,” is just a reflection of an issue with <em>all social media</em>. Bastards go everywhere, and it’s up to your admins, moderators, and also <strong>yourself</strong> to curate your environment, and timelines to be absent of the garbage.</p>

<p>That’s just how it is.</p>

<p>And, also, “I can’t find anyone but nerds on Mastodon!”</p>

<p>Hey, maybe, think for a second here: If yourself, and your friends, and the thousands of people who all believe the same exact things, don’t like the current population on ActivityPub, or <em>what you perceive the population to be</em>, how can we fix this?</p>

<p>Oh … by … joining? And participating?</p>

<p>Well, shit.</p>

<p>ActivityPub is maintained by the people, for the people. By volunteers, by donations. No corporations, no billionaires, no algorithm, no technological mechanisms for abuse.</p>

<p>Just people.</p>

<p>But, I’ve said all of this before, over, and over.</p>

<p>So, let’s continue.</p>

<blockquote>
Trusted information networks have existed since long before the internet and mass media. These networks are in every town and city, and at their core are real relationships between neighbors—not their online, parasocial simulacra. 
<br /><br />
Here in New York City, in the week since the inauguration, I’ve seen large groups mobilize to <a href="https://abc7ny.com/post/nyc-immigration-ice-agents-arrest-hundreds-migrants-sanctuary-cities-including-new-york/15835897/" target="_blank">defend migrants from anticipated ICE raids</a> and provide warm food and winter clothes for the unhoused after <a href="https://www.msn.com/en-us/news/us/nyc-to-close-13-more-migrant-shelters-by-june-2025/ar-BB1rfS3Y" target="_blank">the city closed shelters</a> and abandoned people in sub-freezing temperatures. Similar efforts are underway in Chicago, where <a href="https://www.chicagotribune.com/2025/01/27/chicago-ice-raids-what-to-know/" target="_blank">ICE reportedly arrested more than 100 people</a>,  and in other cities where ICE has planned or attempted raids, with volunteers assigned to keep watch over key locations where migrants are most vulnerable. 
<br /><br />
A few weeks earlier, residents created <a href="https://itsgoingdown.org/report-from-los-angeles-mutual-aid-hubs-fires/" target="_blank">ad-hoc mutual aid distros in Los Angeles</a> to provide food and essentials for those displaced by the wildfires. The coordinated efforts gave Angelenos a lifeline during the crisis, cutting through the <a href="https://www.reuters.com/fact-check/video-shows-people-evacuating-home-not-looting-amid-la-fires-2025-01-13/" target="_blank">false claims</a> spreading on social media about looting and out-of-state <a href="https://www.thereflector.com/stories/no-out-of-state-fire-vehicles-turned-away-from-california-due-to-emissions-testing,373975" target="_blank">fire trucks being stopped</a> for “emissions testing.” Many mutual aid groups in Los Angeles have not just been helping people affected by the fires but have also focused on distributing information about how to learn about and resist ICE raids in Los Angeles. It is no surprise that some of the <a href="https://abc7.com/post/dozens-march-101-freeway-downtown-los-angeles-during-protest-deportations/15857649/" target="_blank">largest and most coordinated protests</a> in the early days of Trump’s term have happened in Los Angeles, where thousands of anti-ICE protesters shut down the 101 highway and several streets in downtown Los Angeles Sunday. 
</blockquote>

<p>I’m just going to say it: I believe the author thinks that if you’re posting online, you’re not able to be out there doing these things. But, I guarantee, most of the people responsible for all of the action referenced here, <em>are probably also participants in social media</em>. And they’re probably also <em>not posting about the actions they’re taking</em>, because that can be dangerous when you live beneath authoritarian rule.</p>

<p>I’m going to side-track for a second, because it’s important to know, that <em>if you are organizing</em> these kinds of efforts, it is <em>extremely important</em> not to speak about it online. Furthermore, if you <em>have to</em>, you should only be using encrypted channels. No, that doesn’t mean Telegram or Whatsapp, obviously.</p>

<p>But, the author <em>does</em> address this …</p>

<blockquote>
Some of these efforts were coordinated online over Discord and secure messaging apps, but all of them arose from existing networks of neighbors and community organizers, some of whom have been organizing for decades.
<br /><br />
“For most people, social media gives you this sense that unless you care about everything, you care about nothing. You must try to swallow the world while it’s on fire,” said Cross. “But <a href="https://pmc.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/articles/PMC6502424/" target="_blank">we didn’t evolve</a> to be able to absorb this much info. It makes you devalue the work you can do in your community.”
<br /><br />
It’s not that social media is fundamentally evil or bereft of any good qualities. Some of my best post-Twitter moments have been spent goofing around with mutuals on Bluesky, or waxing romantic about the joys of human creativity and art-making in an increasingly AI-infested world. But when it comes to addressing the problems we face, no amount of posting or passive info consumption is going to substitute the hard, unsexy work of organizing.
</blockquote>

<p>You should <em>absolutely not</em> be using Discord to organize protests and protective actions against natural disasters. What the heck. DON’T DO THIS. Discord is run by some of the most incompetent people in tech I’ve ever witnessed. Ever. And I come from the nineties, in an age where it was still believed to be a scary thing to put your full name in your aol instant messenger bio, when tech was not only <em>not developed</em>, but entirely missing, for these sorts of things.</p>

<p>But, again, here we are, writing as if disabled people don’t exist, and positioning those who post things online, and those who are out and about in the world <em>doing things</em>, are mutually exclusive concepts.</p>

<p>A logical problem that I personally think stems from spending too much time on Tumblr in 2014.</p>

<blockquote>
It’s a lesson the Extremely Online Left still hasn’t fully learned, failing where its political enemies succeed. Reactionary right-wing groups like the homophobic and transphobic Moms for Liberty—which seeks to ban books from LGBTQ and BIPOC authors under the guise of “parental rights”—have claimed political victories by seizing power one public school board and small town at a time. Other reactionaries have similarly managed to take their pet grievances about diversity and wokeness to the national level by moving from online outrage to on-the-ground community organizing. 
<br /><br />
You can d­iscourse and quote-dunk and fact-check until you’re blue in the face, but at a certain point, you have to stop and decide what truth you believe in. The internet has conditioned us to constantly seek new information, as if becoming a sponge of bad news will eventually yield the final piece of a puzzle. But there is also such a thing as having enough information. As the internet continues to enshittify, maybe what we really need is to start trusting each other and our own collective sense of what is true and good.
<br /><br />
We don’t need any more irony-poisoned hot takes or cathartic, irreverent snark. We need to collectively decide what kind of world we actually do want, and what we’re willing to do to achieve it.
</blockquote>

<p>Right off the bat, we’re deciding to end our article on the evils of algorithms, and corporate social media where we omit the <em>real alternative</em>, and also disabled people, by using exactly the same language that left-leaning quote-dunk harassers use, on a daily basis.</p>

<p>“Extremely Online Left.”</p>

<p>Maybe I’m only speaking from personal experience, but <em>every single person</em> I’ve ever witnessed online using this phrase, has been someone so insufferable that simply <em>being</em> in their digital presence has given me flashbacks to routine abuse piled upon me by jerks online, who didn’t appreciate a trans woman existing in their spaces.</p>

<p>“The internet has conditioned us to constantly seek new information, as if becoming a sponge of bad news will eventually yield the final piece of the puzzle.”</p>

<p>I wish, when people wrote like this, they didn’t just assume that everyone does exactly the same things.</p>

<p>Like I said, I don’t go online to soak up panic-politics, or doomscroll, or to allow an algorithm to dictate what I see, and what I think, and what I do.</p>

<p>But it’s strange, a little further down, to use the phrase, “enshitify” while you constantly prop up a platform that is in immediate danger of enshitification. A phrase <a href="https://www.communication-generation.com/enshitification/" target="_blank">coined by Cory Doctorow</a>, who is <a href="https://mamot.fr/@pluralistic" target="_blank">one of the largest accounts on Mastodon</a>.</p>

<p>And then signing off with, “We don’t need any more irony-poisoned hot takes or cathartic, irreverent snark. We need to collectively decide what kind of world we actually do want, and what we’re willing to do to achieve it.”</p>

<p>I say, we <em>do</em> need irony-poisoned hot takes or cathartic, irreverent snark. Because, and I can’t stress this enough: Posting things online and organizing offline, <strong>are not mutually exclusive concepts</strong>. People can do two things at once.</p>

<p>My conclusion, is that this article is written by someone whose world-view and experience is confined to that of algorithmic hell, who has either <em>never heard</em> of ActivityPub, or is in league with the same journalists who’ve written off the platform for the past decade … for no verifiable reason.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, millions of people populate ActivityPub. Millions of people share, and grow, and express themselves, and organize, and so on, and so forth, all over Mastodon, Pleroma, Misskey, Akkoma, Lemmy, and Pixelfed, day-in-and-day-out, all without the influence of abusive people, algorithms, or billionaires.</p>

<p>Imagine that.</p>

<p>The thing we <em>really</em> need to stop doing, is writing this holier-than-thou trash that positions one person over another based on how much they’ve done, or <em>want to do</em>, while continually erasing those <em>who can’t</em>, positioning them as less important, or less impactful. Or, at worst, <em>contributors</em> and collaborators to the evils we identify.</p>

<p>You <em>don’t have to be</em> on Twitter, Threads, or Bluesky. You don’t have to subject yourself to enshitification, or a platform that <em>will</em> enshitify. You <em>can</em> log off and go do what you think needs to be done. But, you can also stop erasing millions of people that aren’t convenient to your fragile narrative.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Socialmedia" /><category term="socialmedia" /><category term="oligarchy" /><category term="bluesky" /><category term="mastodon" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[This post is in response to a post made by Janus Rose over at 404 Media. A website I mostly respect, and like to see every so often. But, when writers and journalists start talking about social media, and opposition to fascism, you have to take into account their own view of the world, and the internet, in order to begin to dissect what they’re saying. Like many, a lot of people know social media as the corporate algorithm farms that Twitter, Threads, and Instagram are, and it’s through this lens that I believe, “You Can’t Post Your Way Out of Fascism,” was written.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The Time To Leave Reddit Was Two Years Ago</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/socialmedia/2025/02/05/the-time-to-leave-reddit-was-two-years-ago.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Time To Leave Reddit Was Two Years Ago" /><published>2025-02-05T09:27:00-05:00</published><updated>2025-02-05T09:27:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/socialmedia/2025/02/05/the-time-to-leave-reddit-was-two-years-ago</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/socialmedia/2025/02/05/the-time-to-leave-reddit-was-two-years-ago.html"><![CDATA[<p>Two years ago, <a href="https://zuplo.com/blog/2024/10/01/reddit-api-guide" target="_blank">Reddit decided to follow in the footsteps of Twitter (and Elon Musk)</a>, and restricted access to its API, allowing usage <em>mostly</em> only to those who paid for it (aside from small personal-use projects). This is what ended up spawning the ActivityPub alternative to Reddit, <a href="https://join-lemmy.org/" target="_blank">Lemmy</a>. But, this was only the beginning of the wider and rapid enshitification of <em>all</em> corporate-controlled social media.</p>

<p>What we have today, <em>is much worse</em>.</p>

<p>Twitter has become a bull-horn of fascism and oligarchy, Threads has <a href="https://www.wired.com/story/meta-immigration-gender-policies-change/" target="_blank">altered its ToS in order to encourage bullying marginalized people</a>, and <a href="https://mastodon.online/@mastodonmigration/113801236486095587" target="_blank">Bluesky is owned by crypto-bros</a>.</p>

<p>Before we go any further, there has never been a better time than now to get over your fear of choosing a server on Mastodon, or <a href="https://jointhefediverse.net/?lang=en-us" target="_blank">any other associated ActivityPub software</a>.</p>

<p>But now, as recently as <em>today</em>, Reddit has begun nuking its communities that are critical of Elon Musk, communities it deems “un-moderated”, such as NSFW communities, and specifically trans related communities. This is really no surprise, because it’s just Reddit being Reddit. Taking ideas from larger social media platforms that it thinks’ll win it points with investors, and then following through entirely regardless of whether these decisions are actually beneficial to maintaining a website and healthy communities. As if corporate-controlled social media owners give any <em>shits</em> about community.</p>

<p>Hours after doing so, though, an admin stepped-in to declare all of this a glitch. But, with everything going on in this country, especially related to the trans community, <em>I don’t believe him</em>.</p>

<p><a href="https://old.reddit.com/r/SubredditDrama/comments/1ii6qa1/rporn_rrule34_are_banned_tissue_paper_sales/" target="_blank">See the post for yourself</a>, and you can decide what you think of the situation.</p>

<p>But, in the notion of being critical of colossal assholes, as Elon Musk stages a coup against the federal government, with <a href="https://fortune.com/2025/02/03/elon-musk-19-24-year-old-aides-take-control-6-trillion-government-payment-system-social-security-medicare/" target="_blank">a bunch of literal children, no-less</a>, there has never been a better time to be critical of the world’s most unintelligent billionaire. Just like there has never been a better time to <em>finally</em> concede that you are not safe on corporate social media.</p>

<p>I realize that this may not even be a good idea to post, while my website is being pushed <em>through</em> Github (which is owned by Microsoft) <em>to</em> Neocities, but I’m not worried. I have contingencies in place for this sort of thing, if bad situations should arise.</p>

<p>The fact of the matter is, though, is that <em>even if</em> Reddit <em>isn’t</em> beginning a years-long purge of marginalized communities, and especially those that are critical of billionaires, from its website, <em>you should still leave</em>. Just like you should have left Twitter 4 years ago. I am absolutely flabbergasted when I log onto Akkoma / Mastodon, and see people continuing to make their first posts on the Fediverse like, “I finally left Twitter.”</p>

<p>You <em>just</em> left? <em>Today?</em> Have you been living under a ROCK?</p>

<p>Unless your online presence is that of a bland influencer who has no original ideas, who only logs on to ask an inane question to an audience of none, <em>you should leave any piece of media that is in the hands of someone with enough money to buy a planet.</em></p>

<p>The internet began as a collection of disjointed websites where nobody had the ability to wield money and power over others, and it is there that it will return.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Socialmedia" /><category term="reddit" /><category term="socialmedia" /><category term="oligarchy" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Two years ago, Reddit decided to follow in the footsteps of Twitter (and Elon Musk), and restricted access to its API, allowing usage mostly only to those who paid for it (aside from small personal-use projects). This is what ended up spawning the ActivityPub alternative to Reddit, Lemmy. But, this was only the beginning of the wider and rapid enshitification of all corporate-controlled social media.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Music Questions Challenge!</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/questions/2025/02/05/music-questions-challenge.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Music Questions Challenge!" /><published>2025-02-05T00:32:00-05:00</published><updated>2025-02-05T00:32:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/questions/2025/02/05/music-questions-challenge</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/questions/2025/02/05/music-questions-challenge.html"><![CDATA[<p>So, I was tagged by <a href="https://malici.ous.computer/@shellsharks" target="_blank">@shellsharks@malici.ous.computer</a> (you can visit the post on his own site that he references, <a href="https://shellsharks.com/music-questions-challenge" target="_blank">here</a>) on the Fedi to answer some questions about music! This is new to me, because, I was <em>mostly</em> unaware that there’s some kind of blog challenge thing that goes around every once in a while. But, that’s great! It gives me something to write about on days where I have no brain-space for things to write about.</p>

<p>The questions are as follows:</p>

<div class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge"><div class="highlight"><pre class="highlight"><code>1. What are five of your favorite ablums?
2. What are five of your favorite songs?
3. Favorite instrument(s)?
4. What song or album are you currently listening to?
5. Do you listen to the radio? If so, how often?
6. How often do you listen to music?
7. How often do you discover music? And how do you discover music?
8. What’s a song or album that you enjoy that you wish had more recognition?
9. What’s your favourite song of all time?
10. Has your taste in music evolved over the years?
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>Jumping right into the first question, <strong>“What are five of your favorite albums?”</strong></p>

<p>I think I’d have to think back through all of my years being alive, because I’ve become a creature of repetition in the recent past. But, here’s the list.</p>

<p>1: <a href="https://album.link/us/i/311283715" target="_blank">Sevendust - Home</a></p>

<p>This is the <em>very first album</em> I ever bought as a teenager, and will remain one of my favorites.</p>

<p>2: <a href="https://album.link/us/i/302196508" target="_blank">Orgy - Candyass</a></p>

<p>From the years before I fell heavily into KoRn, this album was gifted to me at the age of 16 when I began living in what I still believe to be the most haunted house I’ve ever inhabited. My first dive into industrial numetal.</p>

<p>3: <a href="https://album.link/us/i/967389561" target="_blank">KoRn - Life is Peachy</a></p>

<p><em>I. Don’t. Know. Your. Fuckin’. Name. So. What. Let’s.</em></p>

<p><em>Fuck.</em></p>

<p>I loved this album so much that I learned how to do the scatman bullshit Jonathan Davis does at the beginning of this album.</p>

<p>4: <a href="https://album.link/us/i/1443851273" target="_blank">Deadsy - Commencement</a></p>

<p>Following in the foot-steps of my beginning years of a numetal obsession, comes Deadsy, with another album that I liked quite a lot.</p>

<p>5: <a href="https://album.link/us/i/1532029367" target="_blank">Rammstein - Herzeleid</a></p>

<p>Rammstein is special to me, because I had no idea they existed until German class in the sixth grade, when the fifty-some-odd year old teacher rolled a TV into the classroom and put on Du Hast. Never-the-less, I fell in love with Herzeleid.</p>

<p>6: <a href="https://album.link/us/i/927731469" target="_blank">Slipknot - Slipknot</a></p>

<p>In the eleventh grade I turned into a very mad teenager, which followed Slipknot’s self-titled album that was purchased for me after I begged about three times.</p>

<p>7: <a href="https://album.link/us/i/1440837096" target="_blank">Nine Inch Nails - The Downward Spiral</a></p>

<p>This is actually the second album I ever owned, which accompanied my more angsty, depressed teenage self. I became obsessed with Nine Inch Nails around the same time Quake 3 was one of the biggest games on PC.</p>

<p>8: <a href="https://album.link/us/i/302301243" target="_blank">Static-X - Wisconsin Death Trip</a></p>

<p>An album for back when I was like 17 and had so much more energy than I do now. I saw Wayne Static up close and personal at Crocodile Rock out here in Pennsylvania, years before he passed away. I have one of his guitar picks.</p>

<p>9: <a href="https://album.link/us/i/1474185287" target="_blank">TOOL - Undertow</a></p>

<p>Probably one of the best albums ever made, and one of my favorite progressive rock albums ever. The ending is especially chilling, and I love it. I used to listen to this album a lot while I was playing Tomb Raider in the nineties.</p>

<p>10: <a href="https://album.link/us/i/1440738173" target="_blank">Marilyn Manson - Mechanical Animals</a></p>

<p>Back before it was revealed that Manson was kind of a giant asshole with all kinds of things wrong with him, this was on repeat pretty much all of the time, when I wasn’t listening to KoRn and Nine Inch Nails. It brings back all the memories of sitting in front of Aol Instant Messenger talking to my three internet girlfriends and posting incessantly on animeboards.com.</p>

<p>“But Nova, the question said <strong>FIVE</strong> favorite albums.”</p>

<p>Oh yeah? Who said I follow rules?</p>

<p>Next question: <strong>What are five of your favorite songs?</strong></p>

<p>1: <a href="https://song.link/us/i/1572930403" target="_blank">Power Glove - Brain Jack</a></p>

<p>Jumping directly into my more recent listening habits, and retro-synth obsession, Brain Jack is like an anthem to a cybernetic lifestyle I wish I was living.</p>

<p>2: <a href="https://song.link/us/i/926187670" target="_blank">Slipknot - Psychosocial</a></p>

<p>No, I didn’t stop listening to Slipknot after their self-titled album. I actually never stopped.</p>

<p>3: <a href="https://song.link/us/i/1434900919" target="_blank">Nine Inch Nails - The Perfect Drug</a></p>

<p>Yes, one of my favorite NIN songs isn’t even on an album. But I was so addicted to it in my teen years that it can’t <em>not</em> be on this list.</p>

<p>4: <a href="https://song.link/us/i/1474185654" target="_blank">TOOL - Schism</a></p>

<p>Another one of the greatest songs ever made by the best progressive rock band in the world, I’ve listened to this every year <em>since it came out</em>.</p>

<p>5: <a href="https://song.link/us/i/914145878" target="_blank">Dance with the Dead - Dressed to Kill</a></p>

<p>How could I end this list without jumping back to the present. <em>I love this track</em>. I listen to it constantly, and have done so, for years.</p>

<p>Anyway, let’s get into question number three … <strong>Favorite instrument(s)?</strong></p>

<p>My favorite instrument is probably really cliche, but I’m pretty fond of the guitar. I used to have one, and I used to also play it. But I lost that thing. It was a Gibson Warlock. If I still had it today, who knows, maybe I’d be in a full-fledged band???</p>

<p>Fourth question: <strong>What song or album are you currently listening to?</strong></p>

<p><a href="https://song.link/us/i/1500836562" target="_blank">A Cruel Angel’s Thesis</a></p>

<p>Question numero cinco: <strong>Do you listen to the radio? If so, how often?</strong></p>

<p>I <em>used</em> to listen to the radio way back, maybe fifteen some years ago. That was before I caved to streaming, and before I started buying albums on Bandcamp to put on my almost equally as old iPod. I think radio has a place in today’s society, but it’s so commercial I find literally almost no reason to even touch it in 2025.</p>

<p>Question 666: <strong>How often do you listen to music?</strong></p>

<p>I listen to music as often as I can. If I were allowed to wear my Airpods at work, I’d probably be listening while I work. And while I listen to a lot of true crime podcasts while I drive, I still manage to make time for music in my daily life.</p>

<p>Number 7: <strong>How often do you discover music? And how do you discover music?</strong></p>

<p>I don’t discover new music as often as I should. I have this problem where I’ll like something, or an entire genre, and that’s the only thing I’ll listen to. <em>For years</em>. But I’ve gotten better about it. I <em>make</em> myself go onto Bandcamp and look through genres I like, and here and there I’ll drop some money on an album, especially if I’ve never heard of the artist before.</p>

<p>The eighth question goes, <strong>“What’s a song or album that you enjoy that you wish had more recognition?”</strong></p>

<p>I think Orgy doesn’t get enough recognition in industrial numetal, pretty much <em>at all</em>. They’ve been around since the 90s, and <em>they’re still doing live music</em>, but they’re nowhere near as big as KoRn or Nine Inch Nails, and that’s a shame. They should have <em>way more albums</em> and should still be talked about. I don’t really understand why they’ve been an under-the-radar band since the early 2000s.</p>

<p>Second to last question, <strong>What’s your favourite song of all time?</strong></p>

<p>Oh fuck that’s easy, <a href="https://song.link/us/i/201268495" target="_blank">System of a Down - B.Y.O.B.</a></p>

<p>And, the final question: <strong>Has your taste in music evolved over the years?</strong></p>

<p>I think it’s mostly stayed the same, but in a lot of evolved ways. I started out with numetal, then industrial, then metal, then numetal again, then industrial metal, then electronic, then synthwave, then darksynth / industrial, and then back to numetal again. Because I miss the 90s.</p>

<p>Music has been pretty important to me all of my life, even as I made my own albums and darksynth weirdness in FL Studio. I have a lot of memories and feelings locked into albums and songs that I kind of refuse to listen to, even twenty years later. It’s like a memory-bomb that sits in a plastic case somewhere in my room.</p>

<p>But, I think a life without music, is a weird life. What you doin’? Staring at a blank wall? Psh.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Questions" /><category term="questions" /><category term="music" /><category term="challenge" /><category term="indieweb" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[So, I was tagged by @shellsharks@malici.ous.computer (you can visit the post on his own site that he references, here) on the Fedi to answer some questions about music! This is new to me, because, I was mostly unaware that there’s some kind of blog challenge thing that goes around every once in a while. But, that’s great! It gives me something to write about on days where I have no brain-space for things to write about.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Brain Too Thought For Sleep</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/thoughts/2025/02/03/brain-too-thought-for-sleep.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Brain Too Thought For Sleep" /><published>2025-02-03T22:46:00-05:00</published><updated>2025-02-03T22:46:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/thoughts/2025/02/03/brain-too-thought-for-sleep</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/thoughts/2025/02/03/brain-too-thought-for-sleep.html"><![CDATA[<p>I haven’t written anything on here in a few days, not since I wrote up nine guides for budding web developers, and then promptly returned to work to be exhausted and run through the grinder of the grind. And, with one day left til my “weekend,” I got a little bit more to go. But I don’t really like to talk about my offline job in social places online. I mean, it’s my job. Yes, some day I would either like to promote upward until I don’t have to worry about anything anymore, <em>or</em> find a career in web development, but that’s besides the point.</p>

<p>I just get tired.</p>

<p>And it’s hard to think.</p>

<p>Yeah, it’s tax time. Worst time of the year, when single people with lots of bills and a day job get pennies back from the IRS, and then charges from the local bureau because fuck you, that’s why.</p>

<p>I find a lot of the time, if I don’t stop to write, and if I don’t stop to think about the things around me, and how life’s going, I tend to … <em>lose</em> myself. I lose track of where I am and where I’m headed. I get stuck in a brain-fog where I feel like I’m an outsider watching myself move through the motions of the everyday monotony. Some people might call that, uh, dissociation.</p>

<p>Not sure why I’d be dissociating, but hey, whatever.</p>

<p>Here’s a picture of my cat.</p>

<p><img src="/img/steve/IMG_8256.jpg" /></p>

<p>Today I was thinking to myself, “I can use my time while I’m at work to low-key try to think of ideas on how I can use my website to turn out some kind of income.” But then I got distracted by being at work, and by being busy, and I came up with no ideas on how to do that. And, no, I am not going to start stuffing ad-sense into this site.</p>

<p>I don’t want Google’s haphazard ad-malware painted all over this castle of web design that I’ve spent almost a year building. It’d be like putting brussels sprouts on pizza. Why the hell would you do that?</p>

<p>Anyway, my neck hurts. These are my night-time thoughts for the third of February.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Thoughts" /><category term="thoughts" /><category term="blogging" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[I haven’t written anything on here in a few days, not since I wrote up nine guides for budding web developers, and then promptly returned to work to be exhausted and run through the grinder of the grind. And, with one day left til my “weekend,” I got a little bit more to go. But I don’t really like to talk about my offline job in social places online. I mean, it’s my job. Yes, some day I would either like to promote upward until I don’t have to worry about anything anymore, or find a career in web development, but that’s besides the point.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Nine Guides Complete, More To Come</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/webdev/2025/02/01/nine-guides-complete-more-to-come.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Nine Guides Complete, More To Come" /><published>2025-02-01T16:25:00-05:00</published><updated>2025-02-01T16:25:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/webdev/2025/02/01/nine-guides-complete-more-to-come</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/webdev/2025/02/01/nine-guides-complete-more-to-come.html"><![CDATA[<p>In my last post on here, I mentioned that I had started writing web development guides, but got interrupted by work, and tiredness. Well, do I have news for you. Today, I had off of work, and after having some caffeine and breakfast this morning, I spent about eight hours writing through nine different guides, from getting started with ultra-basic HTML, to constructing JavaScript that makes updating links while having many pages, <em>way easy</em>, to getting setup on Neocities.</p>

<p>If you’ve never made a website before, or are interested in learning things, I’m confidence <a class="page-link" href="/pages/webdev/">these guides</a> will do <em>something</em> for you, in the very least.</p>

<p>And, although it’s shown on the guide page itself, <a href="/webdev/basics/examples/index10.html" target="_blank">here’s the finished website</a> you’ll be making alongside the guides.</p>

<p>This took … a lot of time to write, and there are some things that could be more technically explained, but I think I’ve at least done <em>enough</em> that someone new to web development can <em>at least</em> get started. If even you just copy and paste what I’ve written in order to hack around and mess with stuff. I mean. That’s fine too!</p>

<p>Either way, enjoy. I’m going to go take a break.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Webdev" /><category term="webdev" /><category term="tutorials" /><category term="socialmedia" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[In my last post on here, I mentioned that I had started writing web development guides, but got interrupted by work, and tiredness. Well, do I have news for you. Today, I had off of work, and after having some caffeine and breakfast this morning, I spent about eight hours writing through nine different guides, from getting started with ultra-basic HTML, to constructing JavaScript that makes updating links while having many pages, way easy, to getting setup on Neocities.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Tutorials and Post Archiving</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/webdev/2025/01/31/tutorials-and-post-archiving.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Tutorials and Post Archiving" /><published>2025-01-31T22:16:00-05:00</published><updated>2025-01-31T22:16:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/webdev/2025/01/31/tutorials-and-post-archiving</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/webdev/2025/01/31/tutorials-and-post-archiving.html"><![CDATA[<p>I meant to write about this earlier, but I guess I’ll do that now as I wait for The Sims 1 and 2 Legacy Editions to download (which, I’ve had to reinstall on my SSD so that they’ll load???) But, a few days ago (before I migrated to another instance), I saw someone basically, kind of, sort of, complaining that making a website is like this unattainable act, or practice, and that this is why most people just post on short-form media. My initial reaction was to be like, “What the hell are you talking about?” But, I realize, that things I find extremely simple, like writing HTML, or signing up on a fediverse instance, are actually really complicated for some.</p>

<p>So, in the same way I wrote guides for getting setup on Mastodon, I’m writing guides on <a class="page-link" href="/pages/webdev/">how to build a website from scratch, for beginners</a>!</p>

<p>I’ve merely <em>started</em> it, at this point. Partially because, my offline job sort of interrupted the flow of me making this, but also because I’m now home, and tired, and don’t feel much like writing more, at the moment. But, what I plan to do with this, is have full guides on getting <em>something</em> running, for people who <em>at least</em> have an interest in <em>reading</em> things, and figuring out how to do this, on their own. I understand that <em>even that</em> is asking too much, for some people.</p>

<p>Regardless, though, for the people who want to do these things, I wanted to help make it just a little simpler.</p>

<p>Alongside that, <a href="https://malici.ous.computer/@shellsharks" target="_blank">@shellsharks</a> on fedi (short for fediverse) has been a huge source of inspiration, and ideas, and is the person to thank, or <em>blame</em>, for my entirely renewed interest in building, maintaining, and writing on my own website. In that same vein, he’s also the idea-maker behind syndicating your own posts from social media (that you want to showcase for more than the 30 seconds they appear to others on the timeline) directly to your website.</p>

<p>Now, it’s not <em>real</em> syndication, in a sense that a post automatically appears on your site. It’s more like, manually backing up a post, and then linking to it. Which is fine!</p>

<p>I actually wanted to do this long ago, but my idea for going about it, was to somehow make it so that I could create a post <em>on my website</em>, and have it post to ActivityPub, in the way you might make a normal post <em>on Mastodon</em>, rather than a full blog post. So, in other words, I was trying to make my website <em>be</em> the compose box for Mastodon (or some other such ActivityPub client). Uh … this was kind of a really nuts idea, that I’m sure is possible in like a month of nonstop coding and hacking, but ultimately? Nah.</p>

<p>Instead, I’ve decided to do <a class="page-link" href="/pages/notes/">this</a>. A page where I just type in posts I want to showcase, and then hit “save.”</p>

<p>Easy peasy.</p>

<p><em>Now</em>, to figure out why Sims 1 and 2 Legacy Editions won’t run properly without being installed on an SSD.</p>

<p>Last time I checked, at least one of them functioned perfectly on a 486.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Webdev" /><category term="webdev" /><category term="tutorials" /><category term="socialmedia" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[I meant to write about this earlier, but I guess I’ll do that now as I wait for The Sims 1 and 2 Legacy Editions to download (which, I’ve had to reinstall on my SSD so that they’ll load???) But, a few days ago (before I migrated to another instance), I saw someone basically, kind of, sort of, complaining that making a website is like this unattainable act, or practice, and that this is why most people just post on short-form media. My initial reaction was to be like, “What the hell are you talking about?” But, I realize, that things I find extremely simple, like writing HTML, or signing up on a fediverse instance, are actually really complicated for some.]]></summary></entry></feed>