<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en-US"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.10.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://nova.mkultra.monster/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://nova.mkultra.monster/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en-US" /><updated>2025-01-19T12:30:37-05:00</updated><id>https://nova.mkultra.monster/feed.xml</id><title type="html">cmdr-nova@internet:~$</title><subtitle>cmdr-nova&apos;s personal blog and home on the indie-web.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Tik Tok, Popular Sludge Content Platform: Banned</title><link href="https://nova.mkultra.monster/social-media/2025/01/19/tik-tok-popular-sludge-content-platform-banned.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Tik Tok, Popular Sludge Content Platform: Banned" /><published>2025-01-19T11:48:00-05:00</published><updated>2025-01-19T11:48:00-05:00</updated><id>https://nova.mkultra.monster/social-media/2025/01/19/tik-tok-popular-sludge-content-platform-banned</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://nova.mkultra.monster/social-media/2025/01/19/tik-tok-popular-sludge-content-platform-banned.html"><![CDATA[<p>Yes, yes. It is absolutely a travesty and a violation of the first amendment for the government to ban a platform that the public uses to speak, and express themselves. Does that mean it was a perfect, and good platform? No. Just like Facebook, Instagram, Threads, and Twitter, there are, or have been, surface-level good things, with extremely very not good things just centimeters beneath the surface. From sludge that’s made to maintain a viewer’s attention for as long as possible, to manipulative content that pushes falsehoods and lies for engagement, to ByteDance’s own AI crawler that’s been scraping the entire internet for use in their image and video filters, <em>for years</em>. You definitely should not shed any tears.</p>

<p>“But what about the content creators who were making thousands of dollars off of engagement bait? The NPC actors making millions of dollars in a year?!” You might ask, and I’ll begrudgingly respond: I’m sure Instagram will welcome them with open arms.</p>

<p>You see, there <em>were</em> good things about Tik Tok, and I know it’s probably not gone forever, but I personally feel like the platform has been a net negative for the human population, overall, and I also realize that this makes it sound like I <em>agree</em> with the government. I do not.</p>

<p>I do not believe that the Chinese government gives two flying ballsacks what a random American person is doing on an app where people shovel food in their mouths and try not to puke, in hopes they get forty five million views and a 5000 dollar paycheck. I feel like, if the president and corporations don’t want our information being sold to China, they should first <em>stop</em> allowing Elon Musk and Mark Zuckerberg to do so.</p>

<p>With that out of the way, <em>fuck Tik Tok</em>.</p>

<p>From <a href="https://www.haproxy.com/blog/nearly-90-of-our-ai-crawler-traffic-is-from-tiktok-parent-bytedance-lessons-learned" target="_blank">an article</a> written in October 2024,</p>

<blockquote>
This month, Fortune.com reported that TikTok’s web scraper — known as Bytespider — is aggressively sucking up content to fuel generative AI models. We noticed the same thing when looking at bot management analytics produced by HAProxy Edge — our global network that we ourselves use to serve traffic for haproxy.com. Some of the numbers we are seeing are fairly shocking, so let’s review the traffic sources and where they originate.
</blockquote>

<p>Out of the slew of bots I have to block on both my website, and also my Mastodon instance, I’m praying that their bot gets shutdown. Just so that I can count on one less DDOS scraper violating my consent.</p>

<p>But, I’m also aware that Tik Tok is a staple of generation Z social networking. Like, it’s their monument, or whatever. It is to Gen Z, what MySpace is to Millennials. And while MySpace had the superficial “top 8” and spam in your inbox, I don’t recall an algorithm that <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2023/apr/04/how-tiktoks-algorithm-exploits-the-vulnerability-of-children" target="_blank">intentionally exploited children</a> in order to promote addiction.</p>

<p>This also has a lot to do with parents not properly reviewing what their kids are doing online, whether it be scrolling sludge for 6 hours, or screaming at adults in Call of Duty. I can’t really speak <em>too badly</em> about parents in this day and age though, because I’m sure <em>many</em> millennials were doing things online that they shouldn’t have been doing, as well.</p>

<p>Never-the-less, there is a bit of an influx of people from Tik Tok, to Mastodon, and ActivityPub, which is surprising. I’m not sure what characteristics of written social media Tik Tok users would enjoy. Either way, there’s always <a href="https://pixelfed.org/how-to-join" target="_blank">Pixelfed</a> and the upcoming <a href="https://loops.video" target="_blank">Loops.video</a> to replace predatory algorithm apps, and I hope they take off just the same way these scummy corporate apps have.</p>

<p>At the end of the day, remember: Tik Tok, Threads, Twitter, Instagram, and even Bluesky: These apps and websites can be banned. All of them. But you can’t ban ActivityPub, not unless you’re going to expend billions in resources to track down thousands to hundreds of thousands of apps and servers.</p>

<p>Welcome to the future.</p>

<p>(My thoughts throughout this blog post may seem disjointed and frayed, and that’s because I’m at home with the flu, and a fever right now)</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Social-Media" /><category term="tiktokban" /><category term="socialmedia" /><category term="tik tok" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Yes, yes. It is absolutely a travesty and a violation of the first amendment for the government to ban a platform that the public uses to speak, and express themselves. Does that mean it was a perfect, and good platform? No. Just like Facebook, Instagram, Threads, and Twitter, there are, or have been, surface-level good things, with extremely very not good things just centimeters beneath the surface. From sludge that’s made to maintain a viewer’s attention for as long as possible, to manipulative content that pushes falsehoods and lies for engagement, to ByteDance’s own AI crawler that’s been scraping the entire internet for use in their image and video filters, for years. You definitely should not shed any tears.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">MKULTRA GAMING NEWS: Brought to You By Python</title><link href="https://nova.mkultra.monster/development/2025/01/17/mkultra-gaming-news-brought-to-you-by-python.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="MKULTRA GAMING NEWS: Brought to You By Python" /><published>2025-01-17T09:04:00-05:00</published><updated>2025-01-17T09:04:00-05:00</updated><id>https://nova.mkultra.monster/development/2025/01/17/mkultra-gaming-news-brought-to-you-by-python</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://nova.mkultra.monster/development/2025/01/17/mkultra-gaming-news-brought-to-you-by-python.html"><![CDATA[<p>Today, I’m feeling a bit under-the-weather. I’ve got the aches, the pains, and the coughing fits. Never-the-less, I wanted to do something, <em>regardless</em>, and I thought to myself, “You know, there are a few gaming news related bots on the fediverse, and most of them kinda suck, because they have no regard for people’s timelines.” In that, I mean, a lot of bots I’ve seen will pump a handful of rounds of feed items into a shotgun, and blast them all over your timeline in extremely short time spans. This sucks, because attempting to read your timeline while a bot spams it, is annoying! So, I solved the problem.</p>

<p>What sparked me wanting to do this, was me, suddenly remembering how I asked one of the gaming news bot curators if he could … you know, put some kind of limit or interval on posts that his bot shares, or curate it in a way that it doesn’t share the same news ten times in five minutes.</p>

<p>I remember him saying something like, “Well, I don’t know how to do that.”</p>

<p>Being me, and knowing how to use a cronjob, I did it myself, with my own Python code, and my own bot. You can follow that bot <a href="https://mkultra.monster/@mkultra_gaming" target="_blank">here</a>, from my Mastodon instance.</p>

<p>Here’s how it’s done.</p>

<div class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge"><div class="highlight"><pre class="highlight"><code>import feedparser
import random
from mastodon import Mastodon
import time

# List of RSS feed URLs
rss_feeds = [
    'https://www.polygon.com/rss/index.xml',
    'https://www.dualshockers.com/feed/',
    'https://kotaku.com/rss',
    'https://www.vg247.com/feed/',
    'https://toucharcade.com/feed/',
    'https://www.gamespot.com/feeds/mashup',
    'https://www.ign.com/rss/articles/feed?tags=games',
    'https://www.gematsu.com/feed',
    'https://www.destructoid.com/feed/',
    'https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/feed',
    'https://www.siliconera.com/feed/',
    'https://nichegamer.com/feed/',
    'https://massivelyop.com/feed/',
    'https://www.gamingonlinux.com/article_rss.php',
    'https://www.tabletopgamingnews.com/feed/'
]

# Grab the latest item from a feed, and use retry logic, just in case a feed is dead
def get_latest_item(feed_url, retries=3):
    for attempt in range(retries):
        try:
            feed = feedparser.parse(feed_url)
            if feed.entries:
                return feed.entries[0]
        except Exception as e:
            print(f"Error fetching {feed_url}: {e}")
            if attempt &lt; retries - 1:
                time.sleep(2)  # Wait before retrying
            else:
                return None
    return None

# Look at all feeds
latest_items = []
for feed in rss_feeds:
    item = get_latest_item(feed)
    if item:
        latest_items.append(item)

# Select one at random
if latest_items:
    selected_item = random.choice(latest_items)

    # Custom text
    custom_text = "The latest gaming news! Brought to you and personally curated by cmdr_nova:\n\n"

    # Mastodon credentials
    mastodon = Mastodon(
        access_token='an_access_token_from_mastodon',
        api_base_url='https://mkultra.monster'
    )

    # Post that shit, bro!
    status = f"{custom_text}[{selected_item.title}]\n\n{selected_item.link}"
    mastodon.toot(status)
else:
    print("No items to share.")
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>Here are your requirements:</p>

<div class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge"><div class="highlight"><pre class="highlight"><code>feedparser==6.0.10
Mastodon.py==1.5.1
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>And here’s a cronjob using a shell script so that it can activate an environment, execute the script, and then close the environment.</p>

<p>Shell script:</p>
<div class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge"><div class="highlight"><pre class="highlight"><code>#!/bin/bash
cd folder_location_of_script
source environment_name/bin/activate
python3 mkultra-gaming.py
deactivate
</code></pre></div></div>
<p>Cronjob:</p>
<div class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge"><div class="highlight"><pre class="highlight"><code>0 * * * * folder_location_of_script/gaming.sh
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>And you’re good to go! This shares once an hour, from a feed, at random, and has retry logic just in case a feed doesn’t work, or blocks scripts, or whatever.</p>

<p>Voila.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Development" /><category term="gamingnews" /><category term="programming" /><category term="bots" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today, I’m feeling a bit under-the-weather. I’ve got the aches, the pains, and the coughing fits. Never-the-less, I wanted to do something, regardless, and I thought to myself, “You know, there are a few gaming news related bots on the fediverse, and most of them kinda suck, because they have no regard for people’s timelines.” In that, I mean, a lot of bots I’ve seen will pump a handful of rounds of feed items into a shotgun, and blast them all over your timeline in extremely short time spans. This sucks, because attempting to read your timeline while a bot spams it, is annoying! So, I solved the problem.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">So, It’s Been Over 20 Years</title><link href="https://nova.mkultra.monster/thoughts/2025/01/16/so-it-s-been-over-20-years.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="So, It’s Been Over 20 Years" /><published>2025-01-16T22:30:00-05:00</published><updated>2025-01-16T22:30:00-05:00</updated><id>https://nova.mkultra.monster/thoughts/2025/01/16/so-it-s-been-over-20-years</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://nova.mkultra.monster/thoughts/2025/01/16/so-it-s-been-over-20-years.html"><![CDATA[<p>It’s not a secret that I turn 40 in May. Not a secret, because I can’t stop talking about how conflicted and melancholy this makes me feel. It forces me to look back into the past, twenty some years ago when life was completely different. When things were simpler, and I was simultaneously more comfortable, and less worried, but angsty, and angry all of the time. Back when I lived in a most definitely haunted house, that still stands to this day. That I’ve promised to myself, that if ever I can afford to buy a house: That’s the one I’ll buy.</p>

<p>Thinking back 23 to 24 years ago, the memories in my head feel like … like something from another dimension. Something that wraps me in a lukewarm blanket of black and white, in the midst of Fall, and the silence of my bedroom where I once slept. Where I smoked cigarettes out the side-window, and sat at my 486 computer and waited for hours, <em>everyday</em>, for my internet girlfriends to log on AOL Instant Messenger. Where I spent most of my time trying to decide on the coolest anime wallpaper for my desktop, or prattling on and on about meaningless things on the message board, <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20030207160624/http://animeboards.com/" target="_blank">animeboards.com</a>. Where I decorated my room with goth and death inspired candles, and incense, and listened to KoRn and Marilyn Manson for hours and hours on infinite repeat.</p>

<p>The distant past feels like a place I could visit, if only I tried hard enough.</p>

<p>Yesterday, I pulled up my ex-girlfriend from the end of my high school years, on Facebook, and I sent her a semi-heartfelt message. I spoke about the reasons I broke up with her in 2004, what I really thought the future might’ve been months before I made that decision, in that time and period. And the things I didn’t express, such as how I wish I would’ve made different decisions. Wish I would’ve had my head on straight.</p>

<p>I miss it all.</p>

<p>I miss having all that energy. I miss not knowing what the future might be. I miss playing The Sims and torturing the Goth family while I renovated their house to be a castle of death.</p>

<p>I miss all the stupid things I said and did that ultimately ended up being experiences I would never forget.</p>

<p>I miss all the friends I had, and even the girl who only dated me for a week, in high school, only to ditch me for some other dude in a matter of minutes.</p>

<p>I miss not feeling like my entire life is bound to be owned by a corporation, where I’ll do nothing but work and pay bills until the end of days.</p>

<p>But I think about all of these things and how, you know? I don’t <em>have</em> to be totally confined, a loner, a shut-in. I could get back out there, and do <em>new</em> things, make new memories, and <em>new</em> experiences. The problem is, I don’t know where to start anymore. Don’t know where to go, what to do.</p>

<p>I do know, that something’s gotta change. In the immediate future.</p>

<p>Because your whole life can’t just be a cascade of thoughts that all start with, “You know, I miss …”</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Thoughts" /><category term="blogging" /><category term="thoughts" /><category term="aging" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[It’s not a secret that I turn 40 in May. Not a secret, because I can’t stop talking about how conflicted and melancholy this makes me feel. It forces me to look back into the past, twenty some years ago when life was completely different. When things were simpler, and I was simultaneously more comfortable, and less worried, but angsty, and angry all of the time. Back when I lived in a most definitely haunted house, that still stands to this day. That I’ve promised to myself, that if ever I can afford to buy a house: That’s the one I’ll buy.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">To Build A Website, and Remain Invested</title><link href="https://nova.mkultra.monster/webdev/2025/01/15/to-build-a-website-and-remain-invested.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="To Build A Website, and Remain Invested" /><published>2025-01-15T23:49:00-05:00</published><updated>2025-01-15T23:49:00-05:00</updated><id>https://nova.mkultra.monster/webdev/2025/01/15/to-build-a-website-and-remain-invested</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://nova.mkultra.monster/webdev/2025/01/15/to-build-a-website-and-remain-invested.html"><![CDATA[<p>I was surfing the <a href="https://forum.melonland.net" target="_blank">MelonLand forums</a>, looking for interesting topics to read, or even reply to, and then I noticed one I had once replied to late last year, where a user was asking how to stay invested in their own website. And I posted in reply, where I talked about how I was extending my website to make calls to a VPS in order to utilize Python to make it less “static.” But, that’s not really <em>the best</em> way to stay invested in maintaining your own personal website. You should stay invested, because, at the end of it all, and everything, and the oligarch-tech-complex that looms overhead, <em>it could end up being the only place where you’re able to speak.</em></p>

<p>Sure, your provider, be it Github Pages, or some VPS maintainer, they could just … pull the rug and offline your site in the blink of an eye. But, guess what! You’re smart. You build your website on your local machine, and then upload it to your server. So, you didn’t lose anything. You won’t <em>lose anything, ever</em>.</p>

<p>Think about how Twitter was overtaken, and maybe you said goodbye, and you deleted your account. A decade of your internet history, wiped clean from the internet. Think about going to Threads, and finding out Zuck is <em>even more of an asshole than you thought he was,</em> and so you left. Now you’ve joined Bluesky, or Mastodon. On Bluesky, what if some control-freak crypto-company buys the app, and then wipes your data? Or, something to that effect? What if you’re on Mastodon, and you take a break from social media, and then return, and the server you were on is gone?</p>

<p>Well, so’s your data, and your internet history, and all the work you’ve done.</p>

<p>This is not a criticism of ActivityPub, by the way. Maintaining community owned social media comes with some risks, and you should be prepared, <em>by having the bulk of your work, and words, and thoughts</em>, on a website of your own.</p>

<p>It doesn’t have to be flashy. It doesn’t have to look like it was developed by some 50-years-of-experience web developer. It just has to be <em>yours</em>.</p>

<p>Build, <em>something</em>, and then start jotting down your thoughts. Put up <a href="https://slashpages.net" target="_blank">slashpages</a>, and share your work, share your interests, share, <em>yourself</em>. And when you’re done doing all of that, <em>keep on writing.</em> Make new posts, put them in their own pages, share those pages to Mastodon, or Bluesky, or, wherever you are.</p>

<p>Speak your mind, and say whatever-the-fuck you want, because if you own the slate, it cannot be smashed by adult toddlers who want to take away everyone’s toys.</p>

<p>You want to know <em>how</em> to stay invested in maintaining your own website?</p>

<p><strong>Make your website the central communication and sharing platform, that’s all about you, that you own.</strong></p>

<p>You do that, and you’ll never stop messing with it.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Webdev" /><category term="webdev" /><category term="indieweb" /><category term="webmaster" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[I was surfing the MelonLand forums, looking for interesting topics to read, or even reply to, and then I noticed one I had once replied to late last year, where a user was asking how to stay invested in their own website. And I posted in reply, where I talked about how I was extending my website to make calls to a VPS in order to utilize Python to make it less “static.” But, that’s not really the best way to stay invested in maintaining your own personal website. You should stay invested, because, at the end of it all, and everything, and the oligarch-tech-complex that looms overhead, it could end up being the only place where you’re able to speak.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Ode to My Terminated Tumblr Blog</title><link href="https://nova.mkultra.monster/thoughts/2025/01/14/ode-to-my-terminated-tumblr-blog.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Ode to My Terminated Tumblr Blog" /><published>2025-01-14T21:34:00-05:00</published><updated>2025-01-14T21:34:00-05:00</updated><id>https://nova.mkultra.monster/thoughts/2025/01/14/ode-to-my-terminated-tumblr-blog</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://nova.mkultra.monster/thoughts/2025/01/14/ode-to-my-terminated-tumblr-blog.html"><![CDATA[<p>Twas a month before Christmas, and all through the web, not a creature was stirring, not even a pleb. When all of a sudden, and out of the blue, my blog was deleted, like a silent <em>fuck you</em>. No e-mail, no support, no response, and no word–They took all my work, and left but a turd. And time, that would pass, I sit and I think, “Damn … that sucks ass.”</p>

<p>And all over the net, complaints you can find, of blogs deleted, and reasons confined. On Reddit, on Twitter, on Mastodon, too; I hope Matt Mullenweg has trouble takin’ a poo.</p>

<p>If an alternative you seek, go on, take a peak, <a href="https://app.wafrn.net" target="_blank">Wafrn is here</a>, so don’t shed a tear. For me, for you, for your buddy John, too, come one, come all, sign the frick up, get away from Tumblr, cause they fuckin’ suck.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Thoughts" /><category term="tumblr" /><category term="thoughts" /><category term="banned" /><category term="ode" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Twas a month before Christmas, and all through the web, not a creature was stirring, not even a pleb. When all of a sudden, and out of the blue, my blog was deleted, like a silent fuck you. No e-mail, no support, no response, and no word–They took all my work, and left but a turd. And time, that would pass, I sit and I think, “Damn … that sucks ass.”]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Eternal: Through Time and Space, Forever</title><link href="https://nova.mkultra.monster/gaming/2025/01/14/eternal-through-time-and-space-forever.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Eternal: Through Time and Space, Forever" /><published>2025-01-14T19:30:00-05:00</published><updated>2025-01-14T19:30:00-05:00</updated><id>https://nova.mkultra.monster/gaming/2025/01/14/eternal-through-time-and-space-forever</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://nova.mkultra.monster/gaming/2025/01/14/eternal-through-time-and-space-forever.html"><![CDATA[<p>Months, and months, and months ago, I started making a really simple space flight game that I wanted to be like Elite. And then I found out that making a game exactly like Elite is actually extremely hard, and takes a very long time (I work a full time job that pretty much puts me to sleep the second I walk in the door at home, which leaves me with hardly any time to mess with code). I put the Python version of ETERNAL down, and let it roast, seemingly, <em>forever</em>. But then, I, more recently, thought, “What if it was just a simple space thing you do in JavaScript, and you put it in your website?”</p>

<p>So I did that.</p>

<p>You can try out ETERNAL, <a href="/eternal/eternal.html" target="_blank">here</a>. It’s … a little janky? The power consumption needs work, the refueling is kind of just like, “Okay here’s more fuel.” And on mobile, it works fine! Except … the power consumption appears to only sporadically work.</p>

<p>Never-the-less, you can try it out, and also listen to soma.fm while you play.</p>

<p>There is no end-goal, there are no objectives.</p>

<p>The only point is to fly through infinite space while enjoying some music. Maybe we can call it, a self-care space exploration game, in JavaScript.</p>

<iframe title="ETERNAL: A little JavaScript game I made" width="560" height="315" src="https://video.infosec.exchange/videos/embed/61ea56c5-75e9-489c-aa47-99e67c521efe" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="" sandbox="allow-same-origin allow-scripts allow-popups allow-forms"></iframe>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Gaming" /><category term="javascript-game" /><category term="java" /><category term="gaming" /><category term="space" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Months, and months, and months ago, I started making a really simple space flight game that I wanted to be like Elite. And then I found out that making a game exactly like Elite is actually extremely hard, and takes a very long time (I work a full time job that pretty much puts me to sleep the second I walk in the door at home, which leaves me with hardly any time to mess with code). I put the Python version of ETERNAL down, and let it roast, seemingly, forever. But then, I, more recently, thought, “What if it was just a simple space thing you do in JavaScript, and you put it in your website?”]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Don’t Just Ask AI to Stay Away, Block Them</title><link href="https://nova.mkultra.monster/tech/2025/01/14/don-t-just-ask-ai-to-stay-away-block-them.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Don’t Just Ask AI to Stay Away, Block Them" /><published>2025-01-14T11:18:00-05:00</published><updated>2025-01-14T11:18:00-05:00</updated><id>https://nova.mkultra.monster/tech/2025/01/14/don-t-just-ask-ai-to-stay-away-block-them</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://nova.mkultra.monster/tech/2025/01/14/don-t-just-ask-ai-to-stay-away-block-them.html"><![CDATA[<p>If you’ve been on the internet in the past year and a half to two years, you’re probably very familiar with company’s like OpenAI, where Sam Altman argues that <a href="https://futurism.com/the-byte/openai-copyrighted-material-parliament" target="_blank">his bots <em>must</em> steal in order for his company to be profitable</a>. And, you’re probably also <em>very</em> aware of the endless two-braincell-tech-dudes who post and write about how awesome it is to plagiarize and steal the work of artists to generate some quick, sloppy garbage for short-term gains. Well, if you’re like me, this <em>pisses you the frick off</em>, and in today’s post I’m going to help you completely block their grungy asses from accessing your website.</p>

<p>You may already have a robots.txt file, which provides the internets with a list of ai-gen slop-machines that you’d like to ask nicely, “Don’t crawl or scrape my site.” But, as we know, asking bots made by people and companies who don’t believe in the concept of consent, is like asking a serial killer not to kill. So, we’re not going to ask. We’re going to tell them to take their scraping, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2025/01/10/how-openais-bot-crushed-this-seven-person-companys-web-site-like-a-ddos-attack/" target="_blank">DDOS machines</a>, and make like a screen door on a battleship, and get outta here.</p>

<p>This is <em>very</em> important to do, especially if you’re an independent party who hosts a website, or, say, a <em>Mastodon instance</em>, on your own personal VPS, that you pay for. A service that probably jacks up prices based on overages related to traffic.</p>

<p>So, let’s take off our pants and jacket, and get to it.</p>

<p>There are a lot of complicated ways to do this, that require all kinds of know-how about Apache and Nginx and all sorts of stuff that’ll probably give you a migraine. So, we’re going to make this really simple.</p>

<p>We’re going to use an .htaccess file.</p>

<p>Normally, you could use this to block access to your entire website for everyone <em>but you</em>, which can be useful for testing purposes, or to hide what you’re working on, or what-have-you. But, instead of doing that, we’re going to make it so these bots simply <em>do not</em> access your website, <em>at all</em>. No asking. Just punching them in the face, and leaving them unconscious in a gutter.</p>

<p>I run my website on Jekyll, so I decided to make a ruby that compiles my .htaccess file based on a json file that contains a list of AI scrapers. Once I build and serve my site, it regenerates the .htaccess file, <em>every single time</em>, based on what’s written in crawlers.json. In this way, I can <em>easily</em> add to it in the future, as morally corrupt businesses and corporations roll out even <em>more</em> <a href="https://cee.illinois.edu/news/AIs-Challenging-Waters#:~:text=Data%20centers%20are%20growing%20like%20weeds%2C%20and%20they%20are%20thirsty&amp;text=For%20example%2C%20Google's%20hyperscale%20data,day%20over%20the%20past%20year." target="_blank">water guzzling</a>, <a href="https://www.unep.org/news-and-stories/story/ai-has-environmental-problem-heres-what-world-can-do-about" target="_blank">climate destroying</a> shit-machines.</p>

<p>You <em>could</em> simply copy/paste the .htaccess file, but before we do that, I want to show you how to make it so you can do what I’m doing, if you’re using Jekyll, or something similar.</p>

<p>First, make the ruby gem in your site’s root directory, and call it something like, “generate_htaccess.rb”:</p>

<div class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge"><div class="highlight"><pre class="highlight"><code>require 'json'

# Read the JSON file containing a list of crawlers, i.e., ai bots (the file doesn't *need* to be in assets/data/, that's just where I personally put it)
file_path = 'assets/data/crawlers.json'
crawlers = JSON.parse(File.read(file_path))['crawlers']

# Generate .htaccess
htaccess_content = &lt;&lt;~HTACCESS
  RewriteEngine On
  RewriteCond %{HTTP_USER_AGENT} (#{crawlers.join('|')}) [NC]
  RewriteRule ^ - [F]
HTACCESS

# Write .htaccess
File.open('.htaccess', 'w') do |file|
  file.write(htaccess_content)
end
# Show output in the terminal
puts ".htaccess file generated successfully."
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>Next, create your “crawlers.json” file in whichever directory you’d like. Mine is in /assets/data, but if you change this, you’ll have to edit the “file_path” in the ruby gem in order for this to work. Here’s my crawlers.json:</p>

<div class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge"><div class="highlight"><pre class="highlight"><code>{
    "crawlers": [
      "AI2Bot",
      "Ai2Bot-Dolma",
      "Amazonbot",
      "anthropic-ai",
      "Applebot",
      "Applebot-Extended",
      "Bytespider",
      "CCBot",
      "ChatGPT-User",
      "Claude-Web",
      "ClaudeBot",
      "cohere-ai",
      "cohere-training-data-crawler",
      "Diffbot",
      "DuckAssistBot",
      "FacebookBot",
      "FriendlyCrawler",
      "Google-Extended",
      "GoogleOther",
      "GoogleOther-Image",
      "GoogleOther-Video",
      "GPTBot",
      "iaskspider/2.0",
      "ICC-Crawler",
      "ImagesiftBot",
      "img2dataset",
      "ISSCyberRiskCrawler",
      "Kangaroo Bot",
      "Meta-ExternalAgent",
      "Meta-ExternalFetcher",
      "OAI-SearchBot",
      "omgili",
      "omgilibot",
      "PanguBot",
      "PerplexityBot",
      "PetalBot",
      "Scrapy",
      "SemrushBot",
      "Sidetrade indexer bot",
      "Timpibot",
      "VelenPublicWebCrawler",
      "Webzio-Extended",
      "YouBot"
    ]
  }
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>If you’ve been following any of my Python projects, this will look similar to ways that I list, for example, subreddits for my “bots” to pull images from, and then post them to Mastodon. I like these json lists. It makes things real simple-like.</p>

<p>I took this list, and other ideas on how to do this, from <a href="https://github.com/ai-robots-txt/ai.robots.txt?tab=readme-ov-file" target="_blank">this GitHub repository</a>. I am personally subscribed to their RSS feed so that I can stay up-to-date with slop that’s being rolled out by the likes of Meta and other terrible corporations.</p>

<p>Finally, when building my Jekyll site locally, I use a shell script that does all sorts of things for me, such as, indexing all of my posts for my search engine, generating post metadata so that random posts can be shown at the bottom of other posts, and so on, and so forth. For this, though, we don’t need all of that. So, make a “serve.sh” (in your site’s root directory) that looks like this:</p>

<div class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge"><div class="highlight"><pre class="highlight"><code>#!/bin/bash

# Generate .htaccess file
ruby generate_htaccess.rb

# Build
bundle exec jekyll build

# Serve
bundle exec jekyll serve --watch
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>Now, as you’re updating your site on the local machine, and updating the build in order to admire your changes, or confirm that things are working, it’ll build a new .htaccess file, <em>every time you run this script</em>, and it’ll use the list of AI bots you’ve already provided (crawlers.json). This way, you can update the crawlers any time you want, and whenever you build your site locally, .htaccess gets updated (you should note, that executing Ruby without Ruby being installed, will do nothing, and it is assumed, that because you’re running Jekyll, you <em>do</em> have it installed).</p>

<p>Once you commit the site to live, it’ll already be done and generated, and for all intents and purposes, <em>this should stop these greedy, power-hungry mother assheads from accessing your website</em>.</p>

<p>The generated file should look something like this:</p>

<div class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge"><div class="highlight"><pre class="highlight"><code>RewriteEngine On
RewriteCond %{HTTP_USER_AGENT} (AI2Bot|Ai2Bot-Dolma|Amazonbot|anthropic-ai|Applebot|Applebot-Extended|Bytespider|CCBot|ChatGPT-User|Claude-Web|ClaudeBot|cohere-ai|cohere-training-data-crawler|Diffbot|DuckAssistBot|FacebookBot|FriendlyCrawler|Google-Extended|GoogleOther|GoogleOther-Image|GoogleOther-Video|GPTBot|iaskspider/2.0|ICC-Crawler|ImagesiftBot|img2dataset|ISSCyberRiskCrawler|Kangaroo Bot|Meta-ExternalAgent|Meta-ExternalFetcher|OAI-SearchBot|omgili|omgilibot|PanguBot|PerplexityBot|PetalBot|Scrapy|SemrushBot|Sidetrade indexer bot|Timpibot|VelenPublicWebCrawler|Webzio-Extended|YouBot) [NC]
RewriteRule ^ - [F]
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>Now, this website and <a href="https://mkultra.monster" target="_blank">my Mastodon instance</a> are on the same domain, but they <em>are not</em> on the same server. So, what I did for my Mastodon instance was this:</p>

<div class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge"><div class="highlight"><pre class="highlight"><code>ssh root@your_mastodon_instance_ip

su - mastodon

cd live

cd public

nano .htaccess

# copy/paste the generated .htaccess into this file with ctrl+shift+v

ctrl+O

ctrl+X
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>Done.</p>

<p>The reason I’ve also included this on my Mastodon instance, is, partially, because I’ve noticed at least once a week, or every other week, there’s a <em>massive</em> spike of activity that causes my entire instance to go offline. And it <em>doesn’t come back up again</em>, until I force a power cycle, and then restart Mastodon streaming. I have some … <em>suspicions</em> that this is to do with sludge-scrapers, and so, <em>hopefully</em>, this does <em>something</em> for me.</p>

<p>And maybe also you.</p>

<p>But, there you have it. Block these sumbitches.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Tech" /><category term="blockai" /><category term="ai" /><category term="block" /><category term="htaccess" /><category term="robots" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[If you’ve been on the internet in the past year and a half to two years, you’re probably very familiar with company’s like OpenAI, where Sam Altman argues that his bots must steal in order for his company to be profitable. And, you’re probably also very aware of the endless two-braincell-tech-dudes who post and write about how awesome it is to plagiarize and steal the work of artists to generate some quick, sloppy garbage for short-term gains. Well, if you’re like me, this pisses you the frick off, and in today’s post I’m going to help you completely block their grungy asses from accessing your website.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Fediverse Comments Have Returned</title><link href="https://nova.mkultra.monster/fediverse/2025/01/13/fediverse-comments-have-returned.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Fediverse Comments Have Returned" /><published>2025-01-13T11:32:00-05:00</published><updated>2025-01-13T11:32:00-05:00</updated><id>https://nova.mkultra.monster/fediverse/2025/01/13/fediverse-comments-have-returned</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://nova.mkultra.monster/fediverse/2025/01/13/fediverse-comments-have-returned.html"><![CDATA[<p>A while back, last year now, I briefly launched a Sharkey instance, and replaced my managed-host Mastodon instance, and since my fediverse comments on this blog weren’t completely compatible, I removed them and replaced them with an embedded comment section that makes calls to my VPS in order to store them. This is <em>pretty</em> memory intensive on a 6 dollar VPS that I’m not interested in upgrading, just so that I can host a bajillion different proxy servers.</p>

<p>Now that I’ve been back to Mastodon, except, this time, hosting it myself, I figured, “Why not put the Fediverse comment sections back on each post?”</p>

<p>And so I have done that!</p>

<p>Now, you can continue seeing your replies to my blog posts on fedi, also show up here on my blog. It appears to work with other Mastodon instances, Wafrn, and <em>maybe</em> Sharkey/Misskey? Although, I’ve tested a Sharkey comment on a previous blog post, and it has not yet shown up. This could either be due to federation issues between my specific instance, with the Sharkey instance I posted from, <em>or</em> it could be due to slower federation. Meaning, it could show up sometime later. Not sure!</p>

<p>My <em>only</em> stipulation, is that I would <em>really</em> love if someone could help me figure out how to get a piece of JavaScript to automatically grab a post ID from the resulting Mastodon post that’s made once I make a <em>new</em> blog post (and then somehow also find a way to make it so that it inserts that post ID into the front matter of the corresponding post). I only <em>assume</em> this is possible, but it also sounds <em>extremely</em> complicated.</p>

<p>Unless I could use more server-side Python to accomplish this, altho, I would rather not run more proxy servers.</p>

<p>Either way, this is something that will be figured out … uh, eventually.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Fediverse" /><category term="fediverse" /><category term="mastodon" /><category term="wafrn" /><category term="sharkey" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[A while back, last year now, I briefly launched a Sharkey instance, and replaced my managed-host Mastodon instance, and since my fediverse comments on this blog weren’t completely compatible, I removed them and replaced them with an embedded comment section that makes calls to my VPS in order to store them. This is pretty memory intensive on a 6 dollar VPS that I’m not interested in upgrading, just so that I can host a bajillion different proxy servers.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The Backrooms: Tape 1</title><link href="https://nova.mkultra.monster/backrooms/2025/01/13/the-backrooms-tape-1.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Backrooms: Tape 1" /><published>2025-01-13T01:10:00-05:00</published><updated>2025-01-13T01:10:00-05:00</updated><id>https://nova.mkultra.monster/backrooms/2025/01/13/the-backrooms-tape-1</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://nova.mkultra.monster/backrooms/2025/01/13/the-backrooms-tape-1.html"><![CDATA[<p>So, there’s been a bit of a Kane Pixels drought, ever since <a href="https://youtu.be/acdYs9tPLko?si=lKMN9wQ8WRGbjgWn" target="_blank">Found Footage 3</a> was released, and if you haven’t watched that yet, <em>you need to</em>. I’m assuming the release of these shorts has been slower, due to the production of the full length feature film that was announced … quite some time ago, at this point. In conjunction with A24, Backrooms, or The Complex, the MOVIE, is set to release … uh, sometime before I die of old age, hopefully! But, until then, we have content to watch from other, smaller-time creators.</p>

<p>I’m <em>very</em> selective with the Backrooms content I’ll watch. The silly, slides-and-coconut-milk (or whatever it is?) backrooms-wiki creations are … we’ll just say, mostly <em>bad</em>. Turning Backrooms into a huge thing that tons of people are adding to without any consideration for <em>what’s</em> being added, really takes the actual fear and immersion completely away from the concept. Which is why I don’t consume that content.</p>

<p>I pretty much <em>only</em> watch Backrooms content that is either Kane Pixels, or works inspired by it.</p>

<p>And, even then, sometimes those videos are a little iffy. Sometimes the pacing of the camera-holder versus their footstep movement doesn’t match up well, at all. Sometimes the textures have bad lighting and it’s extremely obvious that they’re just recording in Blender, hence, breaking immersion. Other times, they’ll try to incorporate scenes with actual people in them, or the person who’s lost, themselves, and they’re <em>really</em> not great looking 3D models.</p>

<p>Kane is the masterclass, and there are some who follow the formula well.</p>

<p>Today, I discovered TheMrLeoniasty on Youtube, through his Tape 1 video, and it’s really something else. It’s not 100% perfect, some of the pacing is a little off, but it doesn’t try and take the usual formula that most everyone else does (think: howler / bacteria chase scenes that happen in every single video). It, instead, does something <em>entirely</em> different (although, I’m not sure yet how I feel about the PS2 boot screen).</p>

<p>It’s very slow paced, until the end. The end is absolutely something to behold, as a Backrooms enjoyer.</p>

<p>Watch.</p>

<iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/9Rk1WAR1iL0?si=DUpykixF-K5DA2Oy" title="YouTube video player" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Backrooms" /><category term="thebackrooms" /><category term="backrooms" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[So, there’s been a bit of a Kane Pixels drought, ever since Found Footage 3 was released, and if you haven’t watched that yet, you need to. I’m assuming the release of these shorts has been slower, due to the production of the full length feature film that was announced … quite some time ago, at this point. In conjunction with A24, Backrooms, or The Complex, the MOVIE, is set to release … uh, sometime before I die of old age, hopefully! But, until then, we have content to watch from other, smaller-time creators.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">When All Else Fails; Ramen</title><link href="https://nova.mkultra.monster/thoughts/2025/01/11/when-all-else-fails-ramen.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="When All Else Fails; Ramen" /><published>2025-01-11T22:35:00-05:00</published><updated>2025-01-11T22:35:00-05:00</updated><id>https://nova.mkultra.monster/thoughts/2025/01/11/when-all-else-fails-ramen</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://nova.mkultra.monster/thoughts/2025/01/11/when-all-else-fails-ramen.html"><![CDATA[<p>I get off of work, third day of my work week, whole body aching, staving off the pain with exactly three Ibuprofen and nothing else, and I log onto Second Life. Standing outside my static mansion on a hill that no one visits but me, because nobody else is allowed, I try to think of something interesting to write about. I <em>do</em> kind of tire of writing on negative topics, and topics I have to constantly cite with outbound links, screenshots, and facts. That stuff takes me such a long time to write. But today, I think I want to talk about ramen.</p>

<p><img src="/img/posts/ramen/Screenshot from 2025-01-11 22-35-02.png" /></p>

<p>It took me an enormous amount of time in my life to finally have an actual <em>good</em> bowl of ramen, that wasn’t some bouillon chicken mess in a styrofoam cup. And that was … about three years ago. From a restaurant that, unfortunately, shutdown. I think they were called, <em>Taste of Asia</em>. And, although, I’ve never had the delight of going to Japan, or Korea, or Indonesia, I can say that <em>if I did</em>, I would eat ramen, <em>first</em>.</p>

<p>I remember it like it was almost yesterday. I ordered a bowl of ramen through DoorDash, and it came in this giant plastic container, and it wasn’t just the noodles. It had all the garnish: the seaweed, the pork, the egg, the noodles, and the broth. For this, I had bought a pair of wooden chopsticks, just to feel like I was doing something authentic. And then I took the first bite.</p>

<p>It was like how I would imagine Gordon Ramsay feels when he takes a bite of Beef Wellington that’s done right. It was <em>amazing</em> (I am by no means comparing myself to Gordon Ramsay, I cannot cook, not like that). And it was at that moment that Top Ramen, and Maruchan became <em>dead to me</em>.</p>

<p>It was like, “Wow! Ramen is supposed … to be FLAVORFUL?!” And my god, it was.</p>

<p>Flash forward to today, and I have specific instant ramen brands that I like, and I <em>will not</em> eat anything else.</p>

<p>Those brands are Shin Black, Samyang Buldak, and Sapporo Ichiban.</p>

<p><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Nongshim-Premium-Instant-Vegetables-Microwaveable/dp/B00BEIKRBY?crid=2RE7NPU9EHR9K&amp;dib=eyJ2IjoiMSJ9.xHXapwCC-Pv1Rkl5NuAhr0c8kYwdRXFVhgSX-3UMw0Wnvc9qqQeRxHo7Os5h8UClrR95R2fnI59DCUvniIQ92ulpZNCh3gDHVS-XQcu7YgRoNxd-_DU4JTEKQvlF-znZx7qEpJOyey2WqvqmL8nqYSsGfpEBBZEPVnJjzicej_ObtMyjtjr4P8nlSscijr37CgwE79hgwNbwG06SKq77-KOi53SrAKlTv61lh5M15HuamGc8W2yCAWjCEs77oKA0Dp6atgNk01_BB71fBfjUpt0hRfDGzwi4pfS1VvDHLviVyWwmp32otbymQ9ApZHoxaRgMpuB8k1zVlF-JCBVzf9EQKh49UT3fxxbxodlmZnSEL1o00hLvn3AYoJTxgER2Bg4Os61GXeBN08gSxkk05zJ8DrDq5eIi5c9brGmIZ5t1VYe6j-IEpYTIFxVXbxqK.lcdRf5LTMCSCsoWYfPlylZYKYyhJLOodMyNpt1vj4Yo&amp;dib_tag=se&amp;keywords=shin%2Bblack%2Bramen&amp;qid=1736653783&amp;rdc=1&amp;sprefix=shin%2Bblack%2Bramen%2Caps%2C160&amp;sr=8-1&amp;th=1" target="_blank">Shin Black</a> is a very deep flavor, with a spicy kick to it, and it’s only “failing,” if you can call it that, is that they add no MSG to it. There are a lot of misconceptions about MSG, and although, it is <em>of course</em>, not healthy, it’s mostly fine.</p>

<p>My second favorite is <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Samyang-Chicken-Stir-Fried-Instant-Carbonara/dp/B0C85RZWP3?crid=131JM9EPLBZT8&amp;dib=eyJ2IjoiMSJ9.6A_Wx8Fgg5bqODsI4eTvqrnOGnYuDJutso-YGIlKV0s-sFrFLP5UYlj2Q157ri2xOEtloVA0pXoesaHFZIOJGnM6Qr9M5M85HMwI19KhZfcZXkQpyBAdY-jQF2o8VelyMl5jFmdPdaLXNc80P0u7-ur2ehMJd33qrE_w-Gq5VGluynQOpRJcvL-dlttRjmQUcA4G1TRW4R6-hZlZlQMcrK1HuVfiz_4HgragJ_0E2NkFOI8UlEpIzzhN-vnw8eapvY05aLJW5FWec81mK5cMUyw-yLrr8gDGU88ZGjDBZLg.MIN95VxYZgR_yZ4f6sLG8mY65sCrmJCVgldhPx1qc-4&amp;dib_tag=se&amp;keywords=buldak+ramen&amp;qid=1736653938&amp;sprefix=buldack+rame%2Caps%2C107&amp;sr=8-1" target="_blank">Samyang Buldak</a>, which <em>I think</em> went viral on Tik-Tok for some reason? But, I eat Buldak when I want to punish my stomach with flavor, and fire. You know, you gotta remind yourself that you’re <em>alive</em> sometimes, and the best way to do that, is to punch your stomach in the stomach with knives known as chili peppers.</p>

<p>My only downfall is that as I get older, I can’t handle intense spice as much as I used to, but I also partially blame the “one chip challenge” in damaging my stomach (because I’m pretty sure it did).</p>

<p>And then, at the top of my list, is <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Sapporo-Ichiban-Ramen-Noodles-Original/dp/B00N3K2I7C?crid=38KAYZH9AQS00&amp;dib=eyJ2IjoiMSJ9.q27X2atTczpdkfJHBSaPeKqPahqyU_Pjj15jmlHLcD0q3jXsg6MvZcPik47MPIk7qU_NElfaZ-cuOt2Zk0QbpjUMMKUP7oCKYiKKEqaONMH7TuIkKu7LzBkTT0pkJBm_FVMlQNbcWL5Hbu1F7Euz9n0KTfGfl5cYY_2tm2pYX2W-NnogOSV39jYWm3nhZl03egJXc6gdSbkiNUDNQhODxmNXrofOxT5qh_Dsycav_8hYn8UfnhoFMdqhXFVuBooCWb-anKczlJ8qxcRCLxFsnUeQIylv4cLSlp7ieuKvZ5nvvOqQc2g1rPZtZhD_ULES18ceF83Qkzzl0I4F-XeH2sL7E0qh9pb_bSy4APnhCw9dzs1zWCYCwZ5USa8mWzOQA0jtSsrmOUSJPP_-g_2bfcroWmNnuSD3PIhjSxx6mP9N6Vrt1N62U_qT9nRk_-A7.bKFf-8TaiM8U2_kL0nIb71K88IV6QX64sMXkZqnJ3gQ&amp;dib_tag=se&amp;keywords=sapporo%2Bichiban%2Bramen&amp;qid=1736654126&amp;rdc=1&amp;sprefix=sappora%2Bic%2Caps%2C115&amp;sr=8-1&amp;th=1" target="_blank">Sapporo Ichiban</a>. These noodles aren’t for committing crimes against yourself. It’s got a very rich flavor, it has the MSG, and it’s not punishing to your stomach. Sapporo is for when I’m on a day off from work, and I’m doing for myself a little bit of self care, and I want something easy, and also <em>good</em> to eat. This is my favorite instant noodle of all time.</p>

<p>But, there is a reason I eat all of this in moderation, and that’s because <em>they’re all absolutely filled to the brim with sodium</em>, and there is definitely value in understanding, that there can be too much of a good thing.</p>

<p>People who know me, know that I like to joke about pizza, but, pizza is only my second favorite food. Ramen is number one, and I don’t really speak about it. You wouldn’t know this unless you’ve just read this blog post.</p>

<p>Which brings me to what made me want to post this, and that is this video posted by someone I know on the fediverse, of multiple professional chefs critiquing instant ramen noodles. I recommend a watch!</p>

<blockquote class="mastodon-embed" data-embed-url="https://mastodon.social/@ManiacalV/113813166547141709/embed" style="background: #FCF8FF; border-radius: 8px; border: 1px solid #C9C4DA; margin: 0; max-width: 540px; min-width: 270px; overflow: hidden; padding: 0;"> <a href="https://mastodon.social/@ManiacalV/113813166547141709" target="_blank" style="align-items: center; color: #1C1A25; display: flex; flex-direction: column; font-family: system-ui, -apple-system, BlinkMacSystemFont, 'Segoe UI', Oxygen, Ubuntu, Cantarell, 'Fira Sans', 'Droid Sans', 'Helvetica Neue', Roboto, sans-serif; font-size: 14px; justify-content: center; letter-spacing: 0.25px; line-height: 20px; padding: 24px; text-decoration: none;"> <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" width="32" height="32" viewBox="0 0 79 75"><path d="M74.7135 16.6043C73.6199 8.54587 66.5351 2.19527 58.1366 0.964691C56.7196 0.756754 51.351 0 38.9148 0H38.822C26.3824 0 23.7135 0.756754 22.2966 0.964691C14.1319 2.16118 6.67571 7.86752 4.86669 16.0214C3.99657 20.0369 3.90371 24.4888 4.06535 28.5726C4.29578 34.4289 4.34049 40.275 4.877 46.1075C5.24791 49.9817 5.89495 53.8251 6.81328 57.6088C8.53288 64.5968 15.4938 70.4122 22.3138 72.7848C29.6155 75.259 37.468 75.6697 44.9919 73.971C45.8196 73.7801 46.6381 73.5586 47.4475 73.3063C49.2737 72.7302 51.4164 72.086 52.9915 70.9542C53.0131 70.9384 53.0308 70.9178 53.0433 70.8942C53.0558 70.8706 53.0628 70.8445 53.0637 70.8179V65.1661C53.0634 65.1412 53.0574 65.1167 53.0462 65.0944C53.035 65.0721 53.0189 65.0525 52.9992 65.0371C52.9794 65.0218 52.9564 65.011 52.9318 65.0056C52.9073 65.0002 52.8819 65.0003 52.8574 65.0059C48.0369 66.1472 43.0971 66.7193 38.141 66.7103C29.6118 66.7103 27.3178 62.6981 26.6609 61.0278C26.1329 59.5842 25.7976 58.0784 25.6636 56.5486C25.6622 56.5229 25.667 56.4973 25.6775 56.4738C25.688 56.4502 25.7039 56.4295 25.724 56.4132C25.7441 56.397 25.7678 56.3856 25.7931 56.3801C25.8185 56.3746 25.8448 56.3751 25.8699 56.3816C30.6101 57.5151 35.4693 58.0873 40.3455 58.086C41.5183 58.086 42.6876 58.086 43.8604 58.0553C48.7647 57.919 53.9339 57.6701 58.7591 56.7361C58.8794 56.7123 58.9998 56.6918 59.103 56.6611C66.7139 55.2124 73.9569 50.665 74.6929 39.1501C74.7204 38.6967 74.7892 34.4016 74.7892 33.9312C74.7926 32.3325 75.3085 22.5901 74.7135 16.6043ZM62.9996 45.3371H54.9966V25.9069C54.9966 21.8163 53.277 19.7302 49.7793 19.7302C45.9343 19.7302 44.0083 22.1981 44.0083 27.0727V37.7082H36.0534V27.0727C36.0534 22.1981 34.124 19.7302 30.279 19.7302C26.8019 19.7302 25.0651 21.8163 25.0617 25.9069V45.3371H17.0656V25.3172C17.0656 21.2266 18.1191 17.9769 20.2262 15.568C22.3998 13.1648 25.2509 11.9308 28.7898 11.9308C32.8859 11.9308 35.9812 13.492 38.0447 16.6111L40.036 19.9245L42.0308 16.6111C44.0943 13.492 47.1896 11.9308 51.2788 11.9308C54.8143 11.9308 57.6654 13.1648 59.8459 15.568C61.9529 17.9746 63.0065 21.2243 63.0065 25.3172L62.9996 45.3371Z" fill="currentColor" /></svg> <div style="color: #787588; margin-top: 16px;">Post by @ManiacalV@mastodon.social</div> <div style="font-weight: 500;">View on Mastodon</div> </a> </blockquote>
<script data-allowed-prefixes="https://mastodon.social/" async="" src="https://mastodon.social/embed.js"></script>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Thoughts" /><category term="thoughts" /><category term="secondlife" /><category term="ramen" /><category term="food" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[I get off of work, third day of my work week, whole body aching, staving off the pain with exactly three Ibuprofen and nothing else, and I log onto Second Life. Standing outside my static mansion on a hill that no one visits but me, because nobody else is allowed, I try to think of something interesting to write about. I do kind of tire of writing on negative topics, and topics I have to constantly cite with outbound links, screenshots, and facts. That stuff takes me such a long time to write. But today, I think I want to talk about ramen.]]></summary></entry></feed>