<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en-US"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.10.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://mkultra.monster/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://mkultra.monster/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en-US" /><updated>2025-05-14T14:00:09-04:00</updated><id>https://mkultra.monster/feed.xml</id><title type="html">cmdr-nova@internet:~$</title><subtitle>cmdr-nova&apos;s personal blog and home on the indie-web.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Early Minecraft, And Why Notch Was Erased</title><link href="https://mkultra.monster/gaming/2025/05/12/notchminecraft.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Early Minecraft, And Why Notch Was Erased" /><published>2025-05-12T18:55:29-04:00</published><updated>2025-05-12T18:55:29-04:00</updated><id>https://mkultra.monster/gaming/2025/05/12/notchminecraft</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://mkultra.monster/gaming/2025/05/12/notchminecraft.html"><![CDATA[<p>So, for the past month I’ve been on a really long Minecraft kick of setting up a new world that I started building on my Bedrock realm, flip-flopping between Java and Bedrock, because I can’t really decide which one is better suited to host a “forever world,” and basically just doing <em>everything</em>. But, as you do, when you’re deep-diving into a resurrected interest, you watch Youtube videos, right? Well, something I discovered, is that people are trying really hard, especially on Youtube, to sanitize Notch. Maybe you’re like, 19, and you didn’t see what it is that nefarious types would <em>want</em> to sanitize, so … let’s have a history lesson.</p>

<p>Back around the years of 2010 and 2011, Notch was pretty much a normal guy, from what I remember. He wrote the code, pushed out updates, and eventually brought us a functioning game called Minecraft. At first it was only building and breaking blocks. Then came the monsters.</p>

<p>And, like his work in Minecraft to do with hostile entities, Notch revealed himself to be the biggest monster of all.</p>

<p><img src="/img/posts/notchcraft/shot.png" /></p>

<p>But, he didn’t go from a simple developer of a game, to suddenly posting in exactly the same manner that a hat-wearing Neo Nazi does on present-day Twitter …</p>

<p><img src="/img/posts/notchcraft/white.png" /></p>

<p>Basically, as detailed in this … <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=OGEgT_qgikY" target="_blank">pretty milquetoast video</a> that <em>hardly</em> touches on the problems with the things he said, the man got tired of people yelling at him on Twitter about changes being made to Minecraft. So, like you do, he sold all of his shares to Microsoft for a billion dollars, and then bought a nice house. And, because hoarding wealth and sitting alone in a mansion ranting about how lonely it is to be incredibly rich doesn’t make you a very likeable person, he sunk into the depths of the Nether.</p>

<p>And started posting on Twitter like this:</p>

<p><img src="/img/posts/notchcraft/privilege.png" /></p>

<p>Much of the internet was up-in-arms about all of this back when this happened, and, you can probably guess by now, since I’m writing this, that in 2025, this is a faint, if even hardly remembered thing that happened. Where, now, in the present day, you can go on Youtube and see people who are hardly adults talking about how great Minecraft would be if Notch had never sold off his shares. Or continuing to share and build monuments to the man in their worlds in order to share with their Youtube communities.</p>

<p>It could be a factor of Gen-Z kids largely having been groomed by the hateful right in those same years that Notch lost his mind, or it could just simply be that the old adage of, “The internet lasts forever,” continues to be completely untrue. Especially if another billionaire wipes out most of the website you spoke your garbage upon.</p>

<p>But, I just wanted to put this out there, so that there is at least <em>some kind</em> of present day <strong>thing</strong> re-representing the past that is so often forgotten and swept aside in order to sanitize and make excuses for people who don’t deserve it.</p>]]></content><author><name>⸸ commander ░ nova ⸸ :~$</name></author><category term="Gaming" /><category term="gaming" /><category term="politics" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[So, for the past month I’ve been on a really long Minecraft kick of setting up a new world that I started building on my Bedrock realm, flip-flopping between Java and Bedrock, because I can’t really decide which one is better suited to host a “forever world,” and basically just doing everything. But, as you do, when you’re deep-diving into a resurrected interest, you watch Youtube videos, right? Well, something I discovered, is that people are trying really hard, especially on Youtube, to sanitize Notch. Maybe you’re like, 19, and you didn’t see what it is that nefarious types would want to sanitize, so … let’s have a history lesson.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">SoundCloud Bites The Dust: AI Edition</title><link href="https://mkultra.monster/tech/2025/05/09/soundcloud-sludge.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="SoundCloud Bites The Dust: AI Edition" /><published>2025-05-09T05:53:07-04:00</published><updated>2025-05-09T05:53:07-04:00</updated><id>https://mkultra.monster/tech/2025/05/09/soundcloud-sludge</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://mkultra.monster/tech/2025/05/09/soundcloud-sludge.html"><![CDATA[<p>So, the past couple years have been pretty much just a non-stop horror show, as each platform and app you use goes head-first into slop factory hype, and integrates some needless AI feature that violates your consent. I personally feel we mostly have out-of-touch CEOs and investors to blame for this, but I like to think a company can also just say, “No,” whenever they want (prove me right). Today is no different, and this time it’s SoundCloud.</p>

<p>Via <a href="https://soundcloud.com/terms-of-use#changes-to-terms-of-use" target="_blank">SoundCloud’s updated Terms of Service</a>, and, you <em>should</em> be reading these things from anything you sign up for in 2025, they now specify that your work can be used to train and inform “artificial intelligence.”</p>

<p>Great!</p>

<p>More ways to remove income and livelihood from artists and funnel money into the pockets of greedy shitheads who’ve never had a creative thought in their lives.</p>

<blockquote>
You explicitly agree that your Content may be used to inform, train, develop or serve as input to artificial intelligence or machine intelligence technologies or services as part of and for providing the services.
</blockquote>

<p>As a courtesy to providing you a platform to be spammed by bots and have the company beg you to pay them to upload <em>more</em> of your music, they’ll be taking that music for slop training, as well. Enjoy!</p>

<p>I think not.</p>

<p>I’ve deleted my account, and you should too.</p>

<p>Sooner, rather than later, the only websites I use for any of my work are going to be <em>this</em> website, and my account on Akkoma or Wafrn. Maybe that’s what these rich pieces of garbage want. They want everyone on the fringes, and they <em>want</em> chatbots to advertise to each other, endlessly.</p>

<p>I mean, I guess maybe there’s also Bluesky, but I’ve got nothing but questionable and bad experiences with that site, and let’s not forget that their money is <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/blockchaincapital.com/post/3l7biuedaop2g" target="_blank">controlled by crypto bros</a>.</p>

<p>I can’t wait to wake up tomorrow and find out which way another company my words or work live on have decided to waste precious drinking water for brain-dead prompts by people who are addicted to a 15 second serotonin buzz.</p>]]></content><author><name>⸸ commander ░ nova ⸸ :~$</name></author><category term="Tech" /><category term="tech" /><category term="ai" /><category term="soundcloud" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[So, the past couple years have been pretty much just a non-stop horror show, as each platform and app you use goes head-first into slop factory hype, and integrates some needless AI feature that violates your consent. I personally feel we mostly have out-of-touch CEOs and investors to blame for this, but I like to think a company can also just say, “No,” whenever they want (prove me right). Today is no different, and this time it’s SoundCloud.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">How Minecraft Helped Me Re-Contextualize Life</title><link href="https://mkultra.monster/thoughts/2025/05/06/minecraft-and-life.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How Minecraft Helped Me Re-Contextualize Life" /><published>2025-05-06T18:37:53-04:00</published><updated>2025-05-06T18:37:53-04:00</updated><id>https://mkultra.monster/thoughts/2025/05/06/minecraft-and-life</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://mkultra.monster/thoughts/2025/05/06/minecraft-and-life.html"><![CDATA[<p>This year has been pretty lukewarm, at least in my personal life. Only real big change was a shift-switch in my job. Everything else? Pretty much just sort of, stagnant, but not really in a negative light. Oh, and there’s me having an ongoing existential crisis over turning forty at the end of May. A spiral that I didn’t think would end, with no answers anywhere, and search results for help only giving more of the same. Jane Doe says, “I woke up this morning and cried for hours on my 40th birthday.” And John McGuy says, “One moment I was twenty years old, barely figuring things out, and now I’m 40, with just the same amount of things barely figured out.”</p>

<p>So, searching for answers on ways to feel better, about <em>anything</em>, seemed mostly fruitless.</p>

<p>That was, until I killed the Ender Dragon in Minecraft (again).</p>

<p>It wasn’t so much the <em>act</em> of beating the original “final boss” in Minecraft, or the resulting loot. It was also the second time I did it! But, I had to do it a second time, because I was interrupted the first time I did this during what I’m actually talking about: The end credits poem.</p>

<p>I’ve posted it <a href="https://forum.mkultra.monster/viewtopic.php?t=48&amp;sid=5cd61952d56ba1db33b9ccbebed9d438" target="_blank">here</a>, on my forum.</p>

<p>Up until you get to this point, Minecraft is just a game about breaking blocks and building stuff, while weird monsters try to grief you at any chance they get, and almost nothing more. That is, until you get to the credits, and then this little “story” of sorts completely changes how you view the game, and the world your character lives within.</p>

<p>But how does this affect actual real life?</p>

<p>For the first five months of 2025 so far, I’ve been feeling like a whole lot of everything just doesn’t matter. I’ve been questioning what it is I’m even working toward, and what the point of all that even is, when the end is … not only coming quicker and quicker as each year goes by, but the single thing that would, and <em>will</em> simply erase all of that. That, once you reach the end of the real, what’s the point?</p>

<p>What’s the point? I keep asking.</p>

<p>And then I stopped and actually read this little endgame poem in Minecraft. It’s probably more a byproduct of the original game, before Microsoft added the studio to their monopoly, and introduced the semi-bastardized Pocket Edition rebrand.</p>

<p>It’s about the universe, and the lives we live. That we’re not all completely separate, or individual. That, when you get right down to it, if you look back far enough in time, we all come from exactly the same point of a singularity. And, in that light, none of us are all that different. We’re all children of the beginning. We’ve existed for eons, billions and billions of years, and although we take this shape in one life, we’ll take on new forms in another.</p>

<p>You aren’t just some meaningless, random <em>thing</em> that’s been spat out onto the surface of a burning rock. But, you <em>are</em> the universe, a piece of it, looking in on itself, trying to <em>understand</em> itself.</p>

<p>And, I just think that gives a lot of meaning to things. It means that you aren’t unimportant, that there is a point to everything. That everything you do, think, and feel <em>matters</em>. Because all of that is an expression of something bigger, something greater, something that is almost incomprehensible to wrap your mind around.</p>

<p>I think, if you contextualize it all like that, it makes getting older a little more tolerable. Because, I’m not one to buy into religion. I don’t think I have the capacity to think or believe that there’s a person in the skies watching us.</p>

<p>But, the universe. That is something you can actually see and experience with your own two eyes.</p>

<p>With that, though, I’ll leave you with my first ever screenshot in Minecraft, from 2010.</p>

<p><img src="/img/posts/minecraft-life/2010.png" /></p>]]></content><author><name>⸸ commander ░ nova ⸸ :~$</name></author><category term="Thoughts" /><category term="thoughts" /><category term="gaming" /><category term="life" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[This year has been pretty lukewarm, at least in my personal life. Only real big change was a shift-switch in my job. Everything else? Pretty much just sort of, stagnant, but not really in a negative light. Oh, and there’s me having an ongoing existential crisis over turning forty at the end of May. A spiral that I didn’t think would end, with no answers anywhere, and search results for help only giving more of the same. Jane Doe says, “I woke up this morning and cried for hours on my 40th birthday.” And John McGuy says, “One moment I was twenty years old, barely figuring things out, and now I’m 40, with just the same amount of things barely figured out.”]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">BQC: Pointless Facts About Me</title><link href="https://mkultra.monster/challenge/2025/05/03/bqc2.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="BQC: Pointless Facts About Me" /><published>2025-05-03T08:22:27-04:00</published><updated>2025-05-03T08:22:27-04:00</updated><id>https://mkultra.monster/challenge/2025/05/03/bqc2</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://mkultra.monster/challenge/2025/05/03/bqc2.html"><![CDATA[<p>I was tagged and/or challenged to answer some basic pointless questions as a blog challenge via <a href="https://shellsharks.com/bqc-ten-pointless-facts" target="_blank">ShellSharks</a>, and before I pass out and sleep for my “friday” at work, I think I’ll go ahead and answer them! Especially since, I haven’t written here much due to the fact that a lot of my free time has just been filled with me decompressing, uh … pretty much always.</p>

<ul>
  <li>1: Do you floss your teeth?</li>
</ul>

<p>I don’t, despite brushing and mouthwashing multiple times a day. This is something I should do, but I procrastinate, and have been doing so for … a long time. I should do that, though!</p>

<ul>
  <li>2: Tea, coffee, or water?</li>
</ul>

<p>I can’t really remember the last time I had traditional tea. I think it was back three years ago when I was sick and needed an “at home” remedy while I was at work. Suffice to say, it kind of helped? But, if I was given the choice between the three, I’d probably have to choose coffee. As long as it’s <em>good</em>. If it’s like, sludge you get at work that’s five hours old and reheated? I’ll just take the water.</p>

<ul>
  <li>3: Footwear preference?</li>
</ul>

<p>If I’m out and about? Sneakers. Approaching 40, I’ll always probably just wear some variant of sneakers, or on the rare occasion, these hundred some dollar leather boots I got that I’ve worn one time. Now, if I’m at home, I don’t wear shoes. Wearing shoes, in my head, is associated with doing things, working, being out and not relaxing. And, usually, if I’m at home, I’m relaxing.</p>

<ul>
  <li>4: Favourite dessert?</li>
</ul>

<p>I haven’t had a dessert in the traditional sense in a really long time, but if someone asked me, “What’ll it be?” I’d have to think. I like sweet stuff, but not so much anymore. I’m usually craving something spicy, or salty. But, I think what I’d actually prefer is just a simple vanilla milkshake. You can call a milkshake a dessert, right?</p>

<ul>
  <li>5: The first thing you do when you wake up?</li>
</ul>

<p>Aside from stumbling out of bed and forcing my alarms to turn off? I immediately chug some water, and then pause whatever Youtube’s algorithm has decided my subconscious brain was going to listen to while I was passed out.</p>

<ul>
  <li>6: Age you’d like to stick at?</li>
</ul>

<p>Considering I’m about to hit 40, and having energy nonstop like a caffeine fiend who never stops moving, I think if it were possible I’d rewind and make myself at least 27 again. When I was 27 I was old enough to think things through and not put myself in-danger for fun, and I had enough energy at all times to just be constantly doing things. Not like now. I come home from work, I sit down on the couch and browse the internet, turn on a game, or a video, and somewhere in-between all of that I end up passed out for an hour, then awake again, and then asleep again for another eight hours. It’s a cycle that steals a lot of time away from me.</p>

<ul>
  <li>7: How many hats do you own?</li>
</ul>

<p>Zero. I’ve always been really particular about my hair, and I’m not even sure why. But anything that I’d have to put on my head and risk messing the hair is a no-go for me.</p>

<ul>
  <li>8: Describe the last photo you took?</li>
</ul>

<p>The last thing I snapped a photo of was my cat standing on the edge of the bathtub staring at me while I walked into the bathroom, as if he were asking for a shower. Even though he hates water. Aside from the water he splashes his face in from the sink when he begs for sips from the faucet.</p>

<ul>
  <li>9: Worst TV show?</li>
</ul>

<p>Another thing that’s kind of difficult for me. I don’t really watch a whole lot of TV anymore. Once Breaking Bad ended, I think that was right on the cusp of everything, and I mean <em>everything</em>, switching over to streaming. Once that happened, I kind of dropped off and only watched things I <em>knew</em> I would enjoy, and nothing else. You know, aside from Youtube. Which I pretty much use as a replacement for television nowadays.</p>

<p>But, garsh, uh … I have to agree with ShellSharks here, Big Bang Theory was absolutely terrible when it was on television in 2011. I’d rather watch paint dry inside of my eyelids.</p>

<ul>
  <li>10: As a child, what was your aspiration for adulthood?</li>
</ul>

<p>As a kid, I wanted to go to space, I wanted to be an artist, and for a short stint, I wanted to be a cop. I only became one of these things.</p>]]></content><author><name>⸸ commander ░ nova ⸸ :~$</name></author><category term="Challenge" /><category term="thoughts" /><category term="challenge" /><category term="questions" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[I was tagged and/or challenged to answer some basic pointless questions as a blog challenge via ShellSharks, and before I pass out and sleep for my “friday” at work, I think I’ll go ahead and answer them! Especially since, I haven’t written here much due to the fact that a lot of my free time has just been filled with me decompressing, uh … pretty much always.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Fosstodon: The Neutral Problem</title><link href="https://mkultra.monster/social-media/2025/04/28/fashtodon.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Fosstodon: The Neutral Problem" /><published>2025-04-28T08:04:26-04:00</published><updated>2025-04-28T08:04:26-04:00</updated><id>https://mkultra.monster/social-media/2025/04/28/fashtodon</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://mkultra.monster/social-media/2025/04/28/fashtodon.html"><![CDATA[<p>So, I was kind of debating writing this, because it’s not a very happy, or good topic. But, also, it’s a topic that’s scattered all over the Fediverse in about a million threads with no clear beginning, or even an end. To cut straight to the matter: Another Mastodon instance where some dudes knock on and on about being “neutral” politically so as to not cause upsets, and to create a “welcoming” environment for everyone, have probably killed their instance.</p>

<p>It all started days ago, when it was discovered that one of the moderators behind Fosstodon was <em>also</em> moderating a subreddit, where he expressed numerous anti-LGBTQ+ and anti-immigration views. People were <em>quick</em> to jump and call him fascist, <strong>and they were correct to do so.</strong></p>

<p>But it didn’t stop there.</p>

<p>I had to go searching Mastodon for a little bit so that I could make a list of less than five major things I feel should shine the clearest light on all of this behavior. There’s <em>a lot</em> to it, but I honestly don’t feel like you need a dissertation of a couple hundred posts to get the gist of what happened. So, let’s get started.</p>

<p>First, the Fosstodon/Reddit moderator in-question here, was a user named “Carrotcypher,” and, since having the lid flipped on who he is as a person, went through and scrubbed his username from posts he made on Reddit, and has since stepped down and <em>entirely deleted his Mastodon account</em>.</p>

<p>You can read a more concise account of these things, <a href="https://mastodon.social/@lo__/114370692797365997" target="_blank">here</a>.</p>

<p>And, <em>just in case</em> the post goes missing, or something happens wherein it’s no longer accessible, here’s what it says:</p>

<blockquote>
One of the #Fosstodon moderators, Carrotcypher, has a history of hostility and intolerance towards minorities that does not align with Fosstodon's stated values.

Here is the moderator defending the #deportation of #MahmoudKhalil

<a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/politics/comments/1j90vv6/comment/mhb8gtw/" target="_blank">https://www.reddit.com/r/politics/comments/1j90vv6/comment/mhb8gtw/</a>

Here's the moderator endorsing a law that unclosets #transgender children

<a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/privacy/comments/16nr11q/comment/k1gaxxi/?context=1" target="_blank">https://www.reddit.com/r/privacy/comments/16nr11q/comment/k1gaxxi/?context=1</a>

Here's the moderator censoring discussion of surveillance of #LGBT people in a #privacy community

<a href="https://lemm.ee/post/60365167" target="_blank">https://lemm.ee/post/60365167</a>
</blockquote>

<p>But, how did the admins of Fosstodon respond to people’s absolutely <em>rightful</em> criticism of this, and their questions in regard to … <em>who recruited this guy</em>?</p>

<p>Well, first, there’s Mike, and I found a couple of posts that I think paint a pretty clear picture of how he feels about this, and what he’s willing to cover for:</p>

<p>Firstly, we have <a href="https://fosstodon.org/@mike/114394345053697948" target="_blank">this post</a>, where, at the end of a semi-long thread where Mike makes excuses about how he feels that since these bigoted decisions were made elsewhere, it has no tangible consequences to Fosstodon, or it’s admin and moderation team (which is categorically ridiculous to say, and think).</p>

<p>And, because I fully believe this will all cease to exist at some point, maybe even likely in the near future, here’s how he ended his thread of excuses:</p>

<p><img src="/img/posts/fosstodon/mike1.png" /></p>

<p>I also want to include <a href="https://fosstodon.org/@mike/114399880044272760" target="_blank">this post</a>:</p>

<p><img src="/img/posts/fosstodon/mike2.png" /></p>

<p>Where Mike argues that these are simply, you know, <em>conservative</em> views, not a problem. They just want to have a diverse team of people with all sorts of ideas so as to not create a bubble, or whatever fascist-apologists say in order to make it easier for evil people to exist.</p>

<p>This is all a symptom of a larger problem with men in the tech and foss community in-general, wherein they adopt the position of neutrality in order to foster what they believe to be a “welcoming” environment, which holds the door open for suit-wearing Nazis who want to exterminate marginalized people.</p>

<p>You can see an example of this problem in the <em>other</em> admin’s (Kev’s) blog post, <a href="https://kevquirk.com/blog/my-thoughts-on-the-fosstodon-drama" target="_blank">here</a>.</p>

<p>You’ll notice, the post says a whole lot of <em>nothing</em>. His post is mostly a lot of bla-bla-bla, “people called us names,” “I’m leaving,” “Fosstodon might close.” And then, after all of that, we get to the important part of his post:</p>

<blockquote>
The last point I'll make is this - the fedi is supposed to be a friendly, welcoming online space, right? But the fact is, it isn't. It's just like everywhere else online - the vocal minority are just as loud, and just as obnoxious as everywhere else.

I'd like to say it's been a fun 8 years, but it hasn't. I was fun for the first 3 years or so. After that, it's been pretty much shit, to varying degrees, the entire time. ✌🏻
</blockquote>

<p>In all the neutrality these people try to keep, these last two paragraphs show you the <em>real</em> feelings behind that false-face, and fake grin.</p>

<p>“the fedi is supposed to be a friendly, welcoming online space, right? … the vocal minority are just as loud, and just as obnoxious as everywhere else.”</p>

<p>Really big red flag here. Huge red flag.</p>

<p>Remember, this <em>entire thing</em> happened because of a moderator <em>these people recruited</em>, who then expressed fascist views via other forms of communication. Kev, are you saying that the Fediverse should be <em>welcoming</em> to these types of people (don’t they already have a choke-hold over Twitter)? Is that what you wanted to get off your chest? Is that the “friendly” space you think you’re creating? A space where hateful men can silence and erase the voices of transgender people, and those who would speak up for immigrants who are being shuttled off to who the hell knows where?</p>

<p>Are the hundreds, or maybe even thousands of people criticizing you two, the vocal minority? I mean, it is just <em>you two guys</em> defending these decisions, against numerous instances who are now blocking you from federation, <em>entirely</em>. Is that how you would define a minority?</p>

<p>Is it, Kev?</p>

<p>But, this is the big problem. This is what keeps “normies” away from the Fediverse. It’s not the LGBTQ+ people, it’s not the immigrants trying to establish a voice for themselves online, it’s the “politically neutral” tech-obsessed foss-bros who are so insulated from harm and hatred, that they can’t tell the difference between a guy who would ship you off to prison for being gay, and someone who thinks everyone should have equal rights.</p>

<p>I’ll say it until I’m blue in the face, the Fediverse needs to excise people like this as hard as they have this past week, from ActivityPub, <em>entirely</em>. Over and over again. Until they return to Twitter, and we never have to look at their shitty little profile pictures, ever again.</p>]]></content><author><name>⸸ commander ░ nova ⸸ :~$</name></author><category term="Social-Media" /><category term="social-media" /><category term="mastodon" /><category term="activitypub" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[So, I was kind of debating writing this, because it’s not a very happy, or good topic. But, also, it’s a topic that’s scattered all over the Fediverse in about a million threads with no clear beginning, or even an end. To cut straight to the matter: Another Mastodon instance where some dudes knock on and on about being “neutral” politically so as to not cause upsets, and to create a “welcoming” environment for everyone, have probably killed their instance.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Does The Fediverse Need Influencers To Survive?</title><link href="https://mkultra.monster/social-media/2025/04/23/the-fediverse-and-influencers.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Does The Fediverse Need Influencers To Survive?" /><published>2025-04-23T05:25:08-04:00</published><updated>2025-04-23T05:25:08-04:00</updated><id>https://mkultra.monster/social-media/2025/04/23/the-fediverse-and-influencers</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://mkultra.monster/social-media/2025/04/23/the-fediverse-and-influencers.html"><![CDATA[<p>Today I’m going to talk about something that someone decided to complain about, on the Fediverse, that <em>most</em> of us on the aforementioned verse are <em>extremely</em> opposed to. But, these kinds of takes were inevitable, since corporate social media is already a thunder-dome of garbage, and <em>of course</em> there are people who want to see Mastodon and other extended ActivityPub apps mirror that. What I’m talking about, this time, though, is “influencers.”</p>

<p>I wrote last year, somewhere along the line, about how the influencer mindset is a disease, and I <em>still</em> hold that position.</p>

<p>Algorithmic feeds have been <em>the worst thing</em> to happen to the social web, because, again and again, the only thing it does is center and reward people who <em>lie, cheat, and scam</em>. Wannabe “influential” people who latch onto a trend, or a brand, and say intentionally disingenuous, or sometimes even <em>nasty</em> things, <em>just to get a reaction.</em> Because that’s what does numbers on algorithmic social media, and that is, in-turn, <em>how they get paid</em>.</p>

<p>ActivityPub and the Fediverse is rightfully attractive to many people. Something that’s hundreds to thousands of people hosting their own version of a piece of software, that anyone can use, so that none of the social network is governed by any single entity, therefore ensuring that the Twitter problem, essentially, <em>never happens</em>. That’s really cool, right?</p>

<p>So, it would make sense, that, in time, it would attract people who think like this:</p>

<blockquote>
"I like that there's no influencers/clout chasers/celebrities on the fediverse"

Ok, but you do realize you're saying you like that people can't make a living here, right? That what happens here can't affect the larger world. That the big closed networks will never be supplanted by this one. You get that, right? 

I mean, this is a communication tool. We're communicating with each other. It's such a small understanding of what that means if it's not to influence the world we live in. 

And, frankly, it's entitled to insist that everyone else should abide by that narrow sensibility.
</blockquote>

<p>Now, I’m not including who said this, because I’m trying to be a little nicer, and to also not look like I’m trying to target anyone. Partially because I’m now a moderator on a community instance, and it’s important that people don’t think I’m some kind of asshole who hates everything and is trying to take people down, but also because <em>I’m not trying to target anyone</em>.</p>

<p>But I <em>do</em> want to talk about this, regardless, because I feel like if people come to the Fediverse with these lines of thinking, and nobody goes, “Hold up, let me tell you why we don’t want this here.” We may just end up with an instance or two full of people trying to exploit others for their own personal gain.</p>

<p>And that’s honestly what an influencer is. Except, I think we need to look at individual points here.</p>

<blockquote>
Ok, but you do realize you're saying you like that people can't make a living here, right? That what happens here can't affect the larger world. That the big closed networks will never be supplanted by this one. You get that, right? 
</blockquote>

<p>First of all, I don’t really know of any studies that have ever been done on influencers, but <em>I’m pretty sure</em> making any kind of a living doing it, is only something that’s afforded to those who are either <em>very lucky</em>, or <em>already rich</em>.</p>

<p>And, saying that … this is bad, because if you can’t make a living and get rich on, say, Mastodon, you’re not affecting the larger world? As if a platform is only important if it’s making someone who posts engagement bait rich, otherwise it’s, what? Trivial? Useless?</p>

<p>The big closed networks being the way that they are, <em>is the reason</em> ActivityPub exists. Apps like Mastodon weren’t developed as a replacement for Twitter. They were developed <em>as an alternative</em> for people who just want a <strong>social</strong> network. That’s a big thing here, because I feel like the social part of being online has been nearly dead for the past 20 years. And, if you want to get an idea of what I’m even talking about, you don’t even have to look at Twitter.</p>

<p>Go open Threads. Post a few times, mingle with the people.</p>

<p>Tell me what it looks like when your social network is nothing but influencers trying to get rich off of engagement.</p>

<p>Once you’ve done that, I want you to tell me if you feel like Threads is useful, and not entirely pointless to regular people.</p>

<blockquote>
I mean, this is a communication tool. We're communicating with each other. It's such a small understanding of what that means if it's not to influence the world we live in. 
</blockquote>

<p>You’re right, disembodied voice of someone dissenting about the theme and point of ActivityPub, it is a <em>communication tool</em>. Communication is not something that influencers engage in.</p>

<p>And I can tell you right now, that ActivityPub and the Fediverse has very much influenced the world, <em>even if</em> grind-set, money-brained (or celebrities, if anyone actually cares about what celebrities think) people refuse to use it. You wouldn’t have posted this diatribe via Mastodon if the network hadn’t influenced you to be there. I know, you’re probably looking at this, and if you know me, you’re going, “Hey, but don’t you sell digital albums and other things?”</p>

<p>Yeah, I do. But we’ll get to that.</p>

<blockquote>
And, frankly, it's entitled to insist that everyone else should abide by that narrow sensibility.
</blockquote>

<p>This is mostly the end of this person’s rant, and there’s really not a whole lot to address here, aside from the fact that … this is a projection. Yes, <em>it is</em> entitled to insist that everyone should abide by your narrow sensibilities. Being as that, you are the only one complaining about this.</p>

<p>Speaking of “making money” on the fediverse, though, I want to share something.</p>

<p><img src="/img/posts/influencer-problem/sales.png" /></p>

<p>These are my all-time sales from Bandcamp, over the course of the past 7 or 8 years. Now, obviously, if you’re a more popular artist, or regularly use algorithmic social media, maybe you’ve made much more than me. That’s not what matters, here, though.</p>

<p>Where do you think a majority of these sales came from? Twitter?</p>

<p>Nah.</p>

<p>Although, these numbers, if you look at them over the span of 7-8 years, really aren’t that huge … but, it’s <em>still pretty huge</em> that I’ve made around 4000 USD in sales, largely from just sharing and talking about my work on Mastodon.</p>

<p>Now, obviously, I’m not rich. Most of, if not all of this money has gone toward life expenses and bills, and absolutely none of that is still in any of my accounts.</p>

<p>But it’s still pretty impressive, at least, if you’re someone who thinks it’s not possible to make money on the Fediverse.</p>

<p>That’s just it though. I’m not <em>on</em> the Fediverse to “make money.” Sure, I share my work and sometimes I make sales, but that’s not the reason I’m there. I don’t view social media and people who follow me as a potential transaction. I don’t view other people as numbers on a spreadsheet, with AI-brainstorming about how I can draw more engagement out of them.</p>

<p>I don’t do <em>any of that shit</em>.</p>

<p>Treating every interaction as a transaction, or the potential for a monetary transaction, is <em>inherently</em> toxic, manipulative, and antithetical to a social web. If this upsets you, and you don’t want to be part of something like this … you don’t have to be! You can go be on Threads, you can go be on Twitter, or, hey, you can go be on Bluesky! Where they’ve just suddenly <a href="https://www.axios.com/2025/04/22/bluesky-verification-blue-check-twitter-x" target="_blank">decided to start giving “notable” users an ego boost</a>.</p>

<p>It’s up to you!</p>

<p>That’s the beauty, or <em>at least was</em>, the beauty of the internet, before it was overtaken by oligarchs and corporations. You could just … <em>do whatever you wanted</em>, and it didn’t have to be for any specific reason other than to meet people and chill. Which is (one of) the whole point of the internet!</p>

<p>Corporatizing ActivityPub would be the beginning of its downfall, and I’m glad that people who think everything should be corporate and influential to grind-set, mindset weirdos, <em>don’t like it.</em> Let’s keep it that way.</p>]]></content><author><name>⸸ commander ░ nova ⸸ :~$</name></author><category term="Social-Media" /><category term="social-media" /><category term="influencers" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today I’m going to talk about something that someone decided to complain about, on the Fediverse, that most of us on the aforementioned verse are extremely opposed to. But, these kinds of takes were inevitable, since corporate social media is already a thunder-dome of garbage, and of course there are people who want to see Mastodon and other extended ActivityPub apps mirror that. What I’m talking about, this time, though, is “influencers.”]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Discord: The Community Killer</title><link href="https://mkultra.monster/social-media/2025/04/21/discord-community-killer.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Discord: The Community Killer" /><published>2025-04-21T19:13:25-04:00</published><updated>2025-04-21T19:13:25-04:00</updated><id>https://mkultra.monster/social-media/2025/04/21/discord-community-killer</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://mkultra.monster/social-media/2025/04/21/discord-community-killer.html"><![CDATA[<p>It’s been a little while since I’ve written on an actual topic. A lot of that has to do with me filling my free time with building a ridiculous world around my base in Minecraft Java (heavily modded), and jumping back into World of Warcraft on my original DeathKnight from … uh, whatever year Wrath of the Lich King released. And that kind of has to do with why I want to write this today. Why I want to write about how Discord, the community chat app, has, and <em>is</em>, killing communities not only around the web, but also within games.</p>

<p>I think I’ve written before about how Discord has almost completely killed usage of internet forums (which is partially why I decided to host <a href="https://forum.mkultra.monster/" target="_blank">my own forum</a>, even if nobody feels like joining it), which is <em>terrible</em> for retention of data online. Especially if you’re someone who uses search engines to find answers to questions, none of the problem solving happening within Discord channels is searchable on Google, and is absolutely <em>not permanent</em>.</p>

<p>And now, that problem will be <em>especially</em> exasperated, as the <a href="https://futurism.com/elon-musk-cuts-funding-for-internet-archive" target="_blank">government defunds grants related to the Internet Archive</a>, one of many horrible moves to erase, destroy, and replace history as we know it.</p>

<p>But … I’m getting a little off-topic.</p>

<p>I wanted to write this today, because this is a problem I’ve seen grow more and more over the years. It’s related to World of Warcraft, Guild Wars 2, or basically any online game where players are supposed to talk with each other <em>within those games</em>.</p>

<p>But that’s not happening, is it?</p>

<p>I log onto World of Warcraft and encounter players in-game. Nobody speaks. I do casual dungeons with random groups. The tank bursts through everything, not even paying even a single bit of attention to the other group members around them. And, once the final boss is beaten, the group disbands, all without anyone ever speaking a word. This was a little bit of an issue ten years ago, and it’s only gotten worse.</p>

<p>I also have personal experience with joining <em>guilds</em>, places that are supposed to be <em>communities</em>, where, instead of any of that, you’re immediately assaulted with Discord links.</p>

<p>“Don’t forget to join our Discord!”</p>

<p>So, instead of people speaking in groups, in guild chat, or in the game <em>at all</em>, communication has moved to the modernized IRC and AOL Instant Messenger merger chat client.</p>

<p>Oh, … great.</p>

<p>So, instead of speaking to you and other members of a guild inside of the actual game, I have to tab out of the game and talk in your closed channels on a proprietary app that has already singlehandedly all but murdered old-net social media?</p>

<p>I even went on the World of Warcraft forums and responded to a thread where someone asks, “How do you meet people in-game?” and I responded, “It’s simple. I don’t.” And someone felt they needed to reply with, “Join Discord servers!”</p>

<p>Look. I think Discord is alright for keeping up with friends and people I know, and there are some uses of servers, like the server I use to connect my Patreon and content I make or write, but also?</p>

<p><strong>Fuck Discord</strong>.</p>

<p>This is <em>also</em> a problem in Second Life, a virtual world that is <em>literally described</em> as a 3D chat application, where, now, <em>almost everyone is exclusively speaking in Discord channels instead of <strong>in</strong> Second Life!</em></p>

<p>How does this kill communities?</p>

<p>Instead of walking around within games and virtual worlds, and meeting people naturally, everyone’s ignoring each other until the off-chance they speak in Discord.</p>

<p>Do I have to detail how this is terrible for the health of communities?</p>

<p>Who wants to play a game filled with millions of people that is now essentially singleplayer until you join the app that’s harvesting all of your data?</p>

<p>But, I understand I’m mostly blowing hot air here. Me posting this won’t stop this from happening, and it’ll probably only get worse and worse. That’s the way of the world nowadays, anyway.</p>

<p>It’s only a matter of time before our actual society mirrors some dystopian depiction of what society might be like if all the wrong things happen and nobody says or does anything.</p>

<p>And I’ve been wondering: Am I just being old, yelling at clouds while new things take over?</p>

<p>20 years ago, old people were yelling about how smartphones wouldn’t improve anything, or in the 90s, about how the internet was a passing fad. But, I think both of these things improved society, even if, 20 years later, both smartphones and the internet are being turned into projections of evil via oligarchs and corporations. And, that’s why I don’t really think this is about just “being old,” and more, I think it’s just about people accepting shit, and consuming shit, because they don’t know any better.</p>]]></content><author><name>⸸ commander ░ nova ⸸ :~$</name></author><category term="Social-Media" /><category term="social-media" /><category term="discord" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[It’s been a little while since I’ve written on an actual topic. A lot of that has to do with me filling my free time with building a ridiculous world around my base in Minecraft Java (heavily modded), and jumping back into World of Warcraft on my original DeathKnight from … uh, whatever year Wrath of the Lich King released. And that kind of has to do with why I want to write this today. Why I want to write about how Discord, the community chat app, has, and is, killing communities not only around the web, but also within games.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">A Deluge Of Sleep And Work</title><link href="https://mkultra.monster/thoughts/2025/04/19/a-deluge-of-sleep-and-work.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A Deluge Of Sleep And Work" /><published>2025-04-19T07:38:25-04:00</published><updated>2025-04-19T07:38:25-04:00</updated><id>https://mkultra.monster/thoughts/2025/04/19/a-deluge-of-sleep-and-work</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://mkultra.monster/thoughts/2025/04/19/a-deluge-of-sleep-and-work.html"><![CDATA[<p>I haven’t really written here all that much in the past couple weeks, and it’s not entirely because I don’t want to, or don’t feel like it. I mean, you can see me posting daily on Akkoma from right here on the site. But, I’m deep into the night shift at work now, and coupled with the ten hour shifts, and the constant overtime … I’m tired?</p>

<p>I have a whole album I need to work on, a book I want to get back to writing, and this website that I want to continue writing on, and I’m going to do all of that. When I can figure out how to rebalance my life so that <em>other things still fit into it</em>.</p>

<p>I kind of feel like a ghost a lot of the time, because I come home, feed my Minecraft addiction, and then sleep, wake up, shower, and head back to work.</p>

<p>It’s taken over so much of my life, that I’m swiping on dating apps <em>while I walk through hallways</em> at work. It’s not that I couldn’t do this at home, but more like I just don’t have the energy for anything right now. And that’s not good. Time is passing us by!</p>

<p>But some of this <em>does</em> have to do with me constantly being in Minecraft. I don’t know. I just feel like building and digging out mines! But, there’s the book in the back of my mind asking me when I’m going to continue writing it. If I’m going to get over the anxiety of the internet being filled with scammers and grifters who want to just steal everything for their own selfish wants. When did the internet get so bad?</p>

<p>Again, I miss the days of Geocities. The age of the 90s when the only thing crawling the internet, <em>was you</em>.</p>

<p>Anyway, that’s what’s going on here. Me, being sleepy.</p>]]></content><author><name>⸸ commander ░ nova ⸸ :~$</name></author><category term="Thoughts" /><category term="thoughts" /><category term="updates" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[I haven’t really written here all that much in the past couple weeks, and it’s not entirely because I don’t want to, or don’t feel like it. I mean, you can see me posting daily on Akkoma from right here on the site. But, I’m deep into the night shift at work now, and coupled with the ten hour shifts, and the constant overtime … I’m tired?]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The Happenings 2: What’s Going On?</title><link href="https://mkultra.monster/thoughts/2025/04/12/the-happenings-2-whats-going-on.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Happenings 2: What’s Going On?" /><published>2025-04-12T14:42:09-04:00</published><updated>2025-04-12T14:42:09-04:00</updated><id>https://mkultra.monster/thoughts/2025/04/12/the-happenings-2-whats-going-on</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://mkultra.monster/thoughts/2025/04/12/the-happenings-2-whats-going-on.html"><![CDATA[<p>It’s been a little bit since I’ve last written directly, here on the site. Most of this has to do with mental burn-out and the current political climate. The rest of it has to do with me being <em>absolutely</em> addicted to Minecraft and the little world I’ve built where I routinely solo-raid the Nether while continually building cobblestone fences around my house. But, I figured I’d write something here before I head off to work for the umpteenth time.</p>

<p>So, first things first, if you missed it, I am now a moderator over at <a href="https://labyrinth.zone">labyrinth.zone</a>, wherein I’ll be working with other moderators handling reports. I threw my hat into the ring with this instance, because it is, quite frankly, one of my favorite places to post. Why not go deeper in that involvement? Hence, here we are.</p>

<p>In other personal updates, I’ve been trying to find a solution to my want for a personal Minecraft Java server, that can be public, and also have some addons, <em>without it costing nearly 60 dollars a month</em>. And it would seem that the only current solution there would potentially be for this, would be to host the server entirely myself, on my <em>own</em> system. Which, I don’t think I’d like to do.</p>

<p>Since I currently pay Linden Labs to have my own personal homestead where I host my store, and some other little things, it wouldn’t currently make sense to suddenly erect a Minecraft server that adds on to those costs.</p>

<p>Everything costs too much in 2025.</p>

<p>In relation to my music, and the ongoing album I’ve been working on, I haven’t had much of a chance to move forward with this yet, but I think it <em>is</em> a good idea to periodically talk about how I’ve decided to drop the “PLEXX” project, and move everything back to <a href="https://eyeshadow2600fm.bandcamp.com" target="_blank">Eyeshadow 2600 FM</a>. As long and as nonsense as the name is for this musical project, I decided that there’s really no reason to abandon pieces of the past, <em>just</em> because I was weird about naming things 8 years ago.</p>

<p>And, as for my book, “Dissolution Protocol,” I haven’t really made a whole lot of progress on this. In fact, as soon as “AI” became a thing, I mostly stopped progressing in writing entirely. Unless, you know, it has to do with writing on my website.</p>

<p>This is still something I’m working through, trying to grasp at reasons to continue, while there are potentially hundreds of thousands of people out there drooling over the chance to rip-off anyone and everything for their own personal gain.</p>

<p>But, that’s mostly it from me in regard to personal updates.</p>

<p>As another reminder, I’m running an old-school kind of bulletin board over at <a href="https://forum.mkultra.monster/" target="_blank">forum.mkultra.monster</a>, where you can sign up, drop a thread, start a conversation, and maybe even contribute to starting up a community! Go on, give it a shot. There’s no downside to setting up an account, and hey, maybe you’ll enjoy this little slice of old-net that I’m propping up for a few bucks a month on a VPS.</p>

<p>And, finally, if you know of a Minecraft Java server solution that doesn’t cost an arm, leg, and an eyeball to put up and run for fun, let me know! My comment section should be working on here, or you can just @ me at <a href="https://labyrinth.zone/daemon_nova" target="_blank">daemon_nova@labyrinth.zone</a>.</p>

<p>Thanks for reading.</p>]]></content><author><name>⸸ commander ░ nova ⸸ :~$</name></author><category term="Thoughts" /><category term="updates" /><category term="thoughts" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[It’s been a little bit since I’ve last written directly, here on the site. Most of this has to do with mental burn-out and the current political climate. The rest of it has to do with me being absolutely addicted to Minecraft and the little world I’ve built where I routinely solo-raid the Nether while continually building cobblestone fences around my house. But, I figured I’d write something here before I head off to work for the umpteenth time.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Inzoi, The Sludge Sim</title><link href="https://mkultra.monster/gaming/2025/04/05/inzoi-the-sludge-sim.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Inzoi, The Sludge Sim" /><published>2025-04-05T06:59:20-04:00</published><updated>2025-04-05T06:59:20-04:00</updated><id>https://mkultra.monster/gaming/2025/04/05/inzoi-the-sludge-sim</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://mkultra.monster/gaming/2025/04/05/inzoi-the-sludge-sim.html"><![CDATA[<p>Just like I thought, the slow-creep of generative AI into gaming continues. Except this time it marches forward with <a href="https://krafton.com/en/more-experience/ai/" target="_blank">Krafton’s enthusiastic destruction of the arts</a> with it’s latest and highly anticipated life-sim, InZoi. Thought to be a “Sims killer,” the game launches as an ultra-realistic sim that <em>immediately</em> shoves generative sludge into your face. Because having artists who make designs for clothing in your game is too hard, and having less ways to get involved in game development is definitely the future we’re all rooting for (sarcasm).</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>Krafton is very open about its pro-AI advocacy – it has a whole section of its website dedicated to its Deep Learning division, which works to use generative AI to “increase game productivity” by generating art, animation, and voices, translating research into real-world tools, creating “Virtual Friends” you can play games with and talk to, virtual influencers that can livestream games, and probably more that isn’t stated on the website.</p>
</blockquote>

<p><em>Quoted from <a href="https://www.thegamer.com/i-have-mixed-feelings-about-inzois-use-of-generative-ai/" target="_blank">thegamer.com</a>.</em></p>

<p>Wow, that’s a lot of horrible things to shotgun all at once!</p>

<p>But, don’t worry, they’re only using things people made for free, or work that they’ve already had done for them by actual artists.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>“All AI features within InZOI utilize proprietary models developed by Krafton and are trained using solely company-owned and copyright issue-free assets and data,” Suri explains. “In addition, inZOI’s AI capabilities are built into the client as on-device solutions and therefore do not make communications online with external servers.”</p>
</blockquote>

<p><em>Quoted from <a href="https://www.pcgamesn.com/inzoi/generative-ai" target="_blank">pcgamesn.com.</a></em></p>

<p>As if it <em>somehow</em> makes it seem better, to announce that you’re outsourcing jobs in your company to an algorithmic machine that’s choking the atmosphere, but with things people didn’t ask for money for, or things you’ve already paid actual human beings to make.</p>

<p>Okay, I get it. I’m cynical, and sick-to-death of talking about this. But, all across social media, or, at least, <em>corporate</em> social media, there are endless people thoughtlessly Ghibli-ifying themselves, or clamoring about how great they think it is to use a hallucinating chatbot as a replacement for critical thinking, and now that same brain-drain garbage is leaking into an art form.</p>

<p>I don’t have much hope for the world. I don’t have much hope for art. I <em>lost</em> hope in most people a long time ago.</p>

<p>But, if you’re like me, and you’re sick of this trash, join my club. The Never-AI-in-My-Damn-Games club, and don’t buy this. Don’t buy anything by any developers or studios who’ve decided that having artists isn’t productive enough, or a waste of money.</p>

<p>Let them burn.</p>]]></content><author><name>⸸ commander ░ nova ⸸ :~$</name></author><category term="Gaming" /><category term="gaming" /><category term="ai" /><category term="inzoi" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Just like I thought, the slow-creep of generative AI into gaming continues. Except this time it marches forward with Krafton’s enthusiastic destruction of the arts with it’s latest and highly anticipated life-sim, InZoi. Thought to be a “Sims killer,” the game launches as an ultra-realistic sim that immediately shoves generative sludge into your face. Because having artists who make designs for clothing in your game is too hard, and having less ways to get involved in game development is definitely the future we’re all rooting for (sarcasm).]]></summary></entry></feed>