<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en-US"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.10.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en-US" /><updated>2024-11-14T21:03:05-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">cmdr-nova@internet:~$</title><subtitle>NOVA PRIME</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Bluesky Reaches 15 Millions, Threads Gains 15 Million More</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/social%20media/2024/11/14/bluesky-reaches-15-millions-threads-gains-15-million-more.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Bluesky Reaches 15 Millions, Threads Gains 15 Million More" /><published>2024-11-14T19:22:00-05:00</published><updated>2024-11-14T19:22:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/social%20media/2024/11/14/bluesky-reaches-15-millions-threads-gains-15-million-more</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/social%20media/2024/11/14/bluesky-reaches-15-millions-threads-gains-15-million-more.html"><![CDATA[<p>Before I have to go to work on a rare overnight shift, I wanted to write about the current social landscape, and less about some kind of perceived competition between Threads and Bluesky, and more about what it means to use these platforms. Obviously, there are reasons to be on Threads, Bluesky, and Mastodon, and for some, it’s a race to the finish line, as to which one “wins” the main-character-social-media-site award.</p>

<p>But I don’t believe either of the three options will ever be the “main-line, main-character” choice. I think people will continue from this point forward, having specific things they want to accomplish and do online, and the place they go will depend on those very things.</p>

<p>Obviously, if you join Threads, you’re probably a fan of Instagram, and you’re looking to connect with, maybe, your audience, or something. And then there’s the ex-Twitter users spilling over, because, it <em>is</em> for sure something <em>like</em> Twitter.</p>

<p>Then you have Bluesky, the site that’s billing itself to be a Twitter replacement, gaining users rapidly, and there are definitely reasons you <em>shouldn’t</em> build a site in order to be the <em>next Twitter</em>. But, there are caveats of Bluesky, in that, you can post your balls and ass, and you won’t get censored. And lots, and <em>lots</em> of people love to do that, on Bluesky, <em>specifically</em>.</p>

<p>And then there’s the community building, the list-making, and the large portion of LGBTQ+ users flocking to the site.</p>

<p>It <em>could</em> contend to be a place that doesn’t suck.</p>

<p>And then you have Mastodon, basically, where <em>everyone</em> else goes. Linux enjoyers, and developers alike, <em>especially</em>. And one of the <em>only</em> social media places on the internet that isn’t run by either a billionaire, or backed by some kind of venture capital.</p>

<p>But what does it mean to use the other two?</p>

<p>Obviously, Zuck is a billionaire, a billionaire who definitely has bad ideas, and bad opinions. On the flipside, like mentioned in one of my recent articles, Bluesky is backed by Bitcoin Capital, run by people who know Steven Bannon intimately. So, are you <em>really</em> ultimately in for <em>anything different</em> than what you were exposed to on Twitter?</p>

<p>Maybe, <em>maybe not</em>.</p>

<p>I do think, though, that it’s becoming kind of muddy to say, “You shouldn’t use this, you should use <em>that</em> instead” because, as I’ve just mentioned, both Threads and Bluesky have issues with influence from … the darker side of politics, and the world.</p>

<p>Notice how I don’t mention Mastodon, or ActivityPub in that, because AP is exactly what you make it. But, if I’ve learned anything, <em>very many</em> people want to sign up on something and then forget about it, <em>forever</em>. Which is not something you do on Mastodon. On Mastodon, you have to be an <em>active</em> participant, almost <em>at all times</em> in order for it to become something that you enjoy. And, let’s face it, if you look at regular, normal users on Threads (for example), there are droves, and droves of people wholly uninterested in social participation, and more interested in a viral post that’ll make them an imaginary millionaire.</p>

<p>At this point, I don’t think it matters too much what you use between the three, and fighting about it is a worthless endeavor. Bluesky and Threads are both connected to ActivityPub in different ways, <em>anyway</em>. So … you could say that Mastodon has already won this metaphorical social media war.</p>

<p>But, again, I don’t think these things matter.</p>

<p>I <em>do</em> think you should consider your environment, and what the people who facilitate it believe, and say, on a regular basis. You <em>should</em> think critically about your participation online, be it via Threads, Bluesky, or <em>even</em> Mastodon.</p>

<p>And you most definitely shouldn’t be on Twitter.</p>]]></content><author><name>𐕣 C M D R ░ NOVA 𐕣</name></author><category term="Social Media" /><category term="social-media" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Before I have to go to work on a rare overnight shift, I wanted to write about the current social landscape, and less about some kind of perceived competition between Threads and Bluesky, and more about what it means to use these platforms. Obviously, there are reasons to be on Threads, Bluesky, and Mastodon, and for some, it’s a race to the finish line, as to which one “wins” the main-character-social-media-site award.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">My Fediverse Starter Pack</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/social%20media/2024/11/13/my-fediverse-starter-pack.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="My Fediverse Starter Pack" /><published>2024-11-13T19:39:00-05:00</published><updated>2024-11-13T19:39:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/social%20media/2024/11/13/my-fediverse-starter-pack</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/social%20media/2024/11/13/my-fediverse-starter-pack.html"><![CDATA[<p>The idea of a “social media starter pack” is nothing new. In the 90s we had webrings with select websites we wanted to connect with, and share with others. In blogging we have “blogrolls,” and on social media we’ve had “follow fridays” for … forever. And, in regards to the fediverse, numerous people have put together lists of users they think others should follow. So, by all means, Bluesky’s version of this is really <em>nothing new</em>, except in that they call follow lists “starter packs.” In that spirit, I’ve made my own, for the fediverse.</p>

<p>You can <a class="page-link" href="/pages/fedi-starter">check out my starter pack</a>, and follow via the little follow button I’ve positioned next to each user’s name (yes, I’ve included myself). And this is by no means an exhaustive and complete list! Currently, I’ve slapped this together in about thirty minutes, after having come home from work, napped, and ate a pizza. The list contains those I enjoy seeing on my timeline, and I <em>fully</em> intend to keep adding to it!</p>

<p>Recently, I wrote about how I felt Bluesky was growing on me a little. Mostly in that, I don’t feel like you need to fully <em>avoid</em> it, and it does have its worth. In comparison to the fediverse though, I think I do still <em>mostly</em> prefer my instance, that I run <em>myself</em>, that I moderate <em>myself</em>, on an open protocol that is entirely run by regular normal people (save from the companies connecting or planning to connect to ActivityPub). And I <em>do</em> still have concerns about Bluesky, like how it recently received funding from a <a href="https://www.socialmediatoday.com/news/bluesky-reaches-13-million-users-announces-funding/730989/#:~:text=On%20that%20front%2C%20Bluesky%20has,able%20to%20continue%20its%20development." target="_blank">crypto company</a>, and it could <em>totally</em> be bought by a billionaire with no morals at <em>any second.</em></p>

<p>It’s for those reasons, I’d like to continue building on the fediverse, and this will eventually also include “building” in regards to my scripting and app development. I don’t want to <em>just</em> have scripts referencing Reddit forever. I’ve mostly used Reddit as a testing ground for ideas.</p>

<p>But, anyway, I hope my starter pack helps you find new people to follow (even though it’s a bit tiny at the moment)!</p>]]></content><author><name>𐕣 C M D R ░ NOVA 𐕣</name></author><category term="Social Media" /><category term="social-media" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[The idea of a “social media starter pack” is nothing new. In the 90s we had webrings with select websites we wanted to connect with, and share with others. In blogging we have “blogrolls,” and on social media we’ve had “follow fridays” for … forever. And, in regards to the fediverse, numerous people have put together lists of users they think others should follow. So, by all means, Bluesky’s version of this is really nothing new, except in that they call follow lists “starter packs.” In that spirit, I’ve made my own, for the fediverse.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">My Joy For Gaming, Replaced By Endless Productivity</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/thoughts/2024/11/12/my-joy-for-gaming-replaced-by-endless-productivity.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="My Joy For Gaming, Replaced By Endless Productivity" /><published>2024-11-12T20:29:00-05:00</published><updated>2024-11-12T20:29:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/thoughts/2024/11/12/my-joy-for-gaming-replaced-by-endless-productivity</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/thoughts/2024/11/12/my-joy-for-gaming-replaced-by-endless-productivity.html"><![CDATA[<p>I don’t know <em>when</em> it happened, or even <em>how</em> it happened. But I know it did. I used to get home from work and spend <em>most</em> of my free time consuming another game. That was in my twenties, mostly, and also in the space of time that I was unemployed and suffering disability-levels of anxiety. But then something changed, and I became a machine.</p>

<p>Most days I come home from work, <em>now</em>, and I immediately load up VS Code and start typing. But before that it was music, and before that it was writing, and my Second Life store, or analyzing social media trying to figure out how to expand my audience. Why? Why do I now suddenly spend maybe five hours a week gaming, and the <em>rest</em> of my time just <em>making</em> things? I mean, I know why.</p>

<p>It’s partially my need, and <em>want</em>, to do something special, to do something people remember, or celebrate. But it’s also my need for self fulfillment. I used to go to work, come home, and just do whatever, and be content with that, and <em>always</em> that. But I’m not content in that anymore.</p>

<p>I went to tech school in the middle of high school to learn to code. I wanted to be a full time web developer. I wanted to be sitting at a computer, analyzing networks, building more efficient web apps, and just … basking in the code. And that was stolen from me. I don’t know if I stole it from myself, or if society pushed me into a place where I subconsciously deemed my lifelong dream career as secondary to what I needed to do in the <em>here</em> and <em>now</em>.</p>

<p>Except, we’re at <em>the now</em>, and even through accomplishment, and self improvement, there’s still just <em>more struggle</em>.</p>

<p>It hardly even bothers me anymore that I might just be single the rest of my life. It bothers me <em>more</em> that I’ve been doing <em>all of these things</em>, and building websites, <em>especially</em>, since 19-frikken-99, and I’m … opening boxes for a retailer? I’m wearing a vest and driving into a big box store, and I’m clocking eight hours, and just going home, and thinking … is this the rest of my life?</p>

<p>I think the switch came on when I realized that it <em>wasn’t</em>.</p>

<p>And now I’m terrified of stagnation.</p>

<p>That’s the post. I don’t really know how to remedy this, short of continuing to submit my resume to places hoping something sticks.</p>]]></content><author><name>𐕣 C M D R ░ NOVA 𐕣</name></author><category term="Thoughts" /><category term="thoughts" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[I don’t know when it happened, or even how it happened. But I know it did. I used to get home from work and spend most of my free time consuming another game. That was in my twenties, mostly, and also in the space of time that I was unemployed and suffering disability-levels of anxiety. But then something changed, and I became a machine.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Ten Months Without Windows</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/linux/2024/11/11/ten-months-without-windows.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Ten Months Without Windows" /><published>2024-11-11T21:16:00-05:00</published><updated>2024-11-11T21:16:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/linux/2024/11/11/ten-months-without-windows</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/linux/2024/11/11/ten-months-without-windows.html"><![CDATA[<p>I’m sitting here a little more tired than I’d like to be, but that’s the life of working a manual labor day job, and code-jacking at night (what the hell is code-jacking). Today I want to sort of look back over the past year, and reflect on what it’s been like to <em>mostly</em> abandon Windows (with a slight hiccup of returning for a week).</p>

<p>A lot of people panicked earlier in the year when <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/6/20/24182350/microsoft-windows-recall-launch-on-arm" target="_blank">Microsoft unveiled its AI powered “recall” feature</a>, that screenshots virtually every single thing you do, and then stores it for uh … recalling later. The scary part is, or was, that you definitely <em>should not</em> trust a mega corporation with that kind of info. <em>Even if they tell you not to worry.</em></p>

<p>And many rightfully made the plunge into Linux, and stayed there.</p>

<p>That’s not why I abandoned Windows, though. I actually left Windows earlier than that, a couple months before the Recall announcement, when I decided that using a laptop for all the resource intensive things I do, … might not be a great idea sometimes.</p>

<p><em>Building a massive song in FL Studio with many, many layers can really lag out a system that isn’t up to spec.</em></p>

<p>See, I have another PC (that’s quite dusty now) that I bought in 2018, that was entirely crowdfunded, so that I could do things I need to do in order to make money (at least at the time), and it was great. It helped me out a lot and I eventually dug myself out of a hole. The thing is … Microsoft is dropping support for Windows 10, <em>next year</em>. And it pissed me off, <em>especially</em>, because the processor in that PC is <em>one generation</em> behind what Windows 11 supports. And, because of that, I would have been stuck on Windows 10, without any security updates, or substantial system updates, <em>forever</em>.</p>

<p>I ultimately decided that this was enough of an insult to literally <em>abandon Windows</em> altogether, and <em>forever</em> (seemingly).</p>

<p>You know, <em>and then</em> they announced Recall, like 2 months later. Two months after I bought a massively powerful Linux PC from <a href="https://system76.com" target="_blank">System 76</a>.</p>

<p>And for <em>months</em> I used it under their flagship operating system, Pop!_OS. I got familiar with VS Code for web development. I moved <em>all</em> of my creative work to Linux, and I even got <em>most</em> of my games that I regularly play working, just fine.</p>

<p>But, like it does with me sometimes, I got this itch. I wanted to play some Call of Duty, and I definitely don’t feel like running a console, when I have a PC with 64 gigs of ram, something like 15 cores, and 8 gigs of videoram. Doesn’t make any sense.</p>

<p>So, I made a split decision, and installed Windows 11. And it was fine … for like a week.</p>

<p>But I noticed, even <em>with</em> all that power, Windows was … somehow laggy, and glitchy. Almost like my PC wasn’t <em>designed</em> for it (or maybe I forgot to download System76 drivers).</p>

<p>Either way, I said, “You know what, this isn’t worth ONE game.” And I then installed one of my favorite Linux distributions, <em>Debian.</em></p>

<p>We’re almost caught up to where I am now.</p>

<p>For about two more weeks, I used Debian, and then I noticed some … weird things, such as games blowing my fans up and my PC sounding like it was taking off into space.</p>

<p>It was <em>then</em> I realized, I need to update my firmware, and have system drivers from System 76.</p>

<p>Which, unfortunately, has almost virtually <em>no</em> existing documentation for Debian.</p>

<p>Enter: Now.</p>

<p>I’m back on Pop!_OS.</p>

<p>What a journey.</p>

<p><img src="/img/posts/pop_os/pop.png" /></p>

<p>The reason I originally <em>didn’t</em> immediately go back to Pop!_OS, was because I’m … kind of unsure of how I’ll react to my Gnome desktop being replaced by whatever it is they give me with COSMIC. But, fear of change aside, this OS is actually, or has actually, <em>really</em> grown on me.</p>

<p>And it’s probably as close to Arch as I’ll ever get (that’s ragebait, Pop!_OS is nothing like Arch).</p>

<p>But, having spent <em>most</em> of the year in Linux, I think I can firmly call this OS my home. It feels natural. I <em>enjoy</em> opening the terminal. I <em>like</em> writing everything in code, even if I don’t have to.</p>

<p>I am become system developer.</p>

<p>Whatever they’re constantly saying on <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/linuxsucks/" target="_blank">/r/linuxsucks</a> is at least, <em>partially</em> untrue (and also, I can’t tell if these people are serious, or shitposting constantly). It’s not as complicated as they make it seem, but it is <em>definitely</em> more challenging than choosing a Mastodon instance.</p>

<p><img src="/img/posts/pop_os/yes.png" /></p>

<p>You don’t <em>need</em> to be a developer to use Linux, but it helps!</p>

<p>You can literally just, make a Debian bootable, or a Mint bootable, and then replace Windows, and continue using your PC like nothing happened. You don’t even <em>have</em> to interact with the terminal. You can just use the graphical package manager that’s standard on, well, at least <em>three</em> Linux distributions I’ve tried (but where’s the fun in that?)</p>

<p>You can install Pop!_OS, and then Steam, and then continue your game in Dwarf Fortress just by switching on a little toggle in Steam user options that enables Proton support across <em>every game you own</em>.</p>

<p>It’s really that simple.</p>

<p>Just don’t expect to play anything with kernel-level anti-cheat.</p>

<p>Which is probably actually a <em>good</em> thing. Why do game developers think they’re allowed to touch the kernel? Who the hell do you think you are? That dude from Scary Movie 2?</p>

<p><img src="/img/posts/pop_os/fingers.jpg" /></p>

<p>Suffice to say, I think Linux is where I’ll stay. As Windows becomes more and more bloated, and far, <em>far</em> away from the nostalgia of its greatness in 1995, Linux easily takes its place.</p>

<p>Now, watch this wholesome Debian presentation I found on Youtube.</p>

<iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/0XhNM_2gYBQ?si=RsT0d-4xvJQlZKms" title="YouTube video player" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>]]></content><author><name>𐕣 C M D R ░ NOVA 𐕣</name></author><category term="Linux" /><category term="linux" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[I’m sitting here a little more tired than I’d like to be, but that’s the life of working a manual labor day job, and code-jacking at night (what the hell is code-jacking). Today I want to sort of look back over the past year, and reflect on what it’s been like to mostly abandon Windows (with a slight hiccup of returning for a week).]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Bluesky Is Growing On Me</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/social%20media/2024/11/10/bluesky-is-growing-on-me.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Bluesky Is Growing On Me" /><published>2024-11-10T19:46:00-05:00</published><updated>2024-11-10T19:46:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/social%20media/2024/11/10/bluesky-is-growing-on-me</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/social%20media/2024/11/10/bluesky-is-growing-on-me.html"><![CDATA[<p>I’ve had some criticisms of Bluesky, <em>ever since</em> it opened. Albeit, I had some <em>bad</em> experiences with some users who seem to have also been chased off of the platform for the way they treat others. But, I also have been skeptical about its mode of decentralization (where is it?), and them being VC backed, and recently funded by a crypto company. But, things are changing …</p>

<p>They’re changing, because the social media landscape is changing. And I don’t mean, “Musk took over Twitter, so we probably have to go somewhere else” in a means of changing, but more like, “All corporate social media with lax moderation methods run by billionaires is probably a good idea to flee from.”</p>

<p>And, for me, personally, looking at potentially <em>everything</em> becoming more expensive, and my bad experiences with being on Mastodon instances that aren’t <em>owned by me personally</em>, I’m looking at what I may need to do in the future.</p>

<p>Don’t get me wrong, I <em>love</em> the fediverse. But I have had to leave at least <em>five</em> different instances due to unjust banning, or extremely overzealous moderators who seek power in a digital space in order to a fill a void where they have none.</p>

<p>And for me, that’s a <em>problem.</em></p>

<p>I’m a creator, I run a website, and now I also run a server with numerous scripts that showcase what I have, and <em>can</em> do. I run a digital “business” in Second Life, and I’m working simultaneously on an album and a novel. I’m a developer, a webmaster, a writer, and a sound designer, and I <em>can’t</em> put my future, and potential future <em>career</em> in the hands of people who could silence me at a moment’s notice, just because I, for example, said “fuck off” to a troll.</p>

<p>Yeah, I’m <em>still</em> talking about the hackers.town incident.</p>

<p>Call me jaded, but I just don’t <em>know</em> if I can trust admins of a fediverse instance to not screw me over, since this is something that has happened to me, <em>over and over</em>.</p>

<p>Now, that’s not to say Bluesky doesn’t have methods of silencing people for no reason. They have public blocklists. But! What these blocklists <em>can’t</em> do, is erase your entire online presence in a matter of minutes.</p>

<p>And that’s where I find myself at a theoretical future crossroads where, suddenly, maybe I can’t pay 40 some dollars a month upkeep on my personal Mastodon instance, and I have to look at the alternatives.</p>

<p>Albeit, Wafrn, and Kitsunes.club are decent enough fediverse servers, and their admins haven’t clobbered me out of existence (which would suck, because I’m <em>also</em> a partial admin/moderator on Wafrn), for one reason or another, they just feel like an <em>extension</em> of my online identity, rather than one that’s central. This isn’t a criticism of either of these places, but more probably just <em>me</em> being … weird. I don’t know. Owning my own Mastodon instance has given me a feeling of <em>real</em> control over how people interact with, and also perceive me online. And on something like Bluesky, I can sort of also achieve that, by forwarding my domain to my username, and redirecting my little bots to separate accounts (which I’ve already done).</p>

<p>The thing is, I’m probably <em>way</em> overthinking all of this, but in this bout of turmoil I’m experiencing, Bluesky <em>has</em> grown on me a bit. I’ve figured out how to use “feeds” to create my own “algorithm” and I’ve setup some placeholder moderation lists, and it feels … okay. It could feel alright, if, for some reason, I suddenly <em>have</em> to move there.</p>

<p>But … maybe I just haven’t given Wafrn or Kitsunes enough of a chance to be central to my online identity.</p>

<p>What I <em>do</em> know, is that it’s important to have control over your identity online, and to own your voice. To give the wrong people power over you in any regard, or facet, would be a <em>mistake</em>.</p>]]></content><author><name>𐕣 C M D R ░ NOVA 𐕣</name></author><category term="Social Media" /><category term="social-media" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[I’ve had some criticisms of Bluesky, ever since it opened. Albeit, I had some bad experiences with some users who seem to have also been chased off of the platform for the way they treat others. But, I also have been skeptical about its mode of decentralization (where is it?), and them being VC backed, and recently funded by a crypto company. But, things are changing …]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">New Shorts Available At [REVOSA]</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/second%20life/2024/11/09/new-shorts-available-at-revosa.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="New Shorts Available At [REVOSA]" /><published>2024-11-09T14:50:00-05:00</published><updated>2024-11-09T14:50:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/second%20life/2024/11/09/new-shorts-available-at-revosa</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/second%20life/2024/11/09/new-shorts-available-at-revosa.html"><![CDATA[<p>It’s becoming kind of a trend, that I make something in my Second Life store, and then drop the whole thing for two to three months while I work on a million other things. Despite all of that, today I decided to put together another pair of shorts for the set I’ve been putting together for … a while. Today, it’s juicy green shorts!</p>

<p><img src="/img/posts/juicy/juicy_ad.png" /></p>

<p>This is the second to last pair of shorts in the <em>Nano Nexus</em> set, and then I move on to … some other piece of clothing! And hopefully end up releasing it in a standard amount of time that is absolutely not equal to an <em>entire year</em>.</p>

<p>You can view them on the <a href="https://marketplace.secondlife.com/p/REVOSA-Nano-Nexus-Juicy-Edition/26578153" target="_blank">digital marketplace</a>, or come and see them <a href="http://maps.secondlife.com/secondlife/Auriga/116/17/2003" target="_blank">in-world at the store</a> itself.</p>

<p>Speaking of <em>millions of other things</em> I work on, in unrelated news, I put together an RSS feed element for my website that reads my Bluesky feed, and then slapped it onto Github for others to check out and potentially use. You can see that <a href="https://github.com/cmdr-nova/bsky-feed" target="_blank">here</a>. Basically, it grabs the RSS feed of your profile (on Bluesky), bounces it off of a proxy so that it doesn’t spit out a ton of CORS errors, and then displays your most recent three posts. And, it updates with each page refresh!</p>

<p>Easy peasy.</p>

<p>I’ve also made it so new posts from this website <em>also</em> go to <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/cmdr-nova.bsky.social" target="_blank">my Bluesky account</a>, and since I haven’t really tested it yet, this post <em>should hopefully</em> get there safely. We’ll see.</p>

<p>But, until my next release, or hacked code update, or random thought, have a good one!</p>]]></content><author><name>𐕣 C M D R ░ NOVA 𐕣</name></author><category term="Second Life" /><category term="second-life" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[It’s becoming kind of a trend, that I make something in my Second Life store, and then drop the whole thing for two to three months while I work on a million other things. Despite all of that, today I decided to put together another pair of shorts for the set I’ve been putting together for … a while. Today, it’s juicy green shorts!]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Making Things and Sipping Juice</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/programming/2024/11/09/making-things-and-sipping-juice.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Making Things and Sipping Juice" /><published>2024-11-09T00:29:00-05:00</published><updated>2024-11-09T00:29:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/programming/2024/11/09/making-things-and-sipping-juice</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/programming/2024/11/09/making-things-and-sipping-juice.html"><![CDATA[<p>The day’s coming to an end (okay, actually, it’s like 12:30 at night, it’s been over), and I’ve done <em>a lot</em>. In my last post I talked about spending all of my free time over the course of 24 hours making a function that pushes my blog posts to Mastodon. Well, after all of that, I went to bed, woke up, and started on something new …</p>

<p>Almost half of my day was spent fixing and upgrading the <a class="page-link" href="/pages/haxpunks/">haxPunks</a> page on this website.</p>

<p>Basically, I noticed that the image modal was not only opening <em>within</em> its parent div (main), but also producing a scrollbar WITHIN that div, and it was very clunky and <em>bad</em> looking. So, the goal was to figure out a better way to do it. And then I stumbled into problems, where I had a position set in one of the CSS elements, and because of that <em>one freakin’ thing</em>, the modal <em>would not stop</em> opening and showing on page load.</p>

<p>This <em>also</em> looked bad.</p>

<p>And it took me HOURS to notice what I did wrong.</p>

<p>But I fixed it.</p>

<p>And I got the modal functioning correctly.</p>

<p>And I formatted it to work nicely on mobile (I think).</p>

<p>Then, it was <em>done</em>.</p>

<p>After that, I took a look at what is now the <a class="page-link" href="/pages/second-life/">Second Life</a> page, and decided to delete everything I’d written in there, and made something new. It showcases my store, and then my land. No big story about where I came from, where I’m going, how things went wrong, and where we’re at now.</p>

<p>Just the stuff that currently exists. Which is good, I think. So people don’t have to read a history book about why I’ve done what I’ve done, and what my goals are.</p>

<p>But I wasn’t finished after that. I <em>needed</em> to do more.</p>

<p>I took to Gimp, opened OBS, and recorded my process of making a haxPunk, and then uploaded the video, plus the result (to the haxPunks page). Yes, you will notice in the video there’s a “generative” layer, and that’s entirely because this is a PSD from when I was still subscribed to Photoshop, and <em>totally</em> innocently looking at what exactly the feature did (lol).</p>

<p>But, here’s that video:</p>

<iframe title="Making Pixels / haxPunks 27" width="560" height="315" src="https://video.infosec.exchange/videos/embed/b8f4feab-2a80-4697-af20-a4b73a62f1f6" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="" sandbox="allow-same-origin allow-scripts allow-popups allow-forms"></iframe>

<p>And here’s the punk:</p>

<p><img src="/img/haxpunks/haxPunks_0027.png" /></p>

<p>As you can probably tell, I’ve modeled this one after the current version of my Second Life avatar, and I think it turned out pretty neat.</p>

<p>I’ve been making these things since <em>before</em> I said, “Wait a minute, NFTs are stupid.” But the thing is, I <em>enjoyed</em> the process of making them so much, that even <em>after</em> exiting the whole “NFT” thing, I wanted to keep making them. I’ve had these going for a <em>long</em> time, and I want to make <em>hundreds</em> of them. Just for fun.</p>

<p>Lately, that’s pretty much the reason I do <em>most</em> things. On my website, on Github, or through Python on my VPS. I just enjoy doing this stuff!</p>

<p>If at some point I happen to get paid to do any of it, hey, that’s awesome (please pay me to do these things at some point oh my god please).</p>

<p>Just kidding</p>

<p>… unless?</p>]]></content><author><name>𐕣 C M D R ░ NOVA 𐕣</name></author><category term="Programming" /><category term="programming" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[The day’s coming to an end (okay, actually, it’s like 12:30 at night, it’s been over), and I’ve done a lot. In my last post I talked about spending all of my free time over the course of 24 hours making a function that pushes my blog posts to Mastodon. Well, after all of that, I went to bed, woke up, and started on something new …]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Jekyll Blog, Post to Mastodon</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/programming/2024/11/07/jekyll-blog-post-to-mastodon.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Jekyll Blog, Post to Mastodon" /><published>2024-11-07T22:28:00-05:00</published><updated>2024-11-07T22:28:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/programming/2024/11/07/jekyll-blog-post-to-mastodon</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/programming/2024/11/07/jekyll-blog-post-to-mastodon.html"><![CDATA[<p>It’s been a hell of a time! Earlier in the week, I suddenly had an issue where I broke my RSS feed bot that posted new feed items from my blog to my Mastodon account. I described this in my last post, but it was entirely because I … edited the XML. So! I spent the last entire day rebuilding a brand new way to do this. By turning VS Code’s “commit” button into a “Post to Mastodon” button. Let me explain.</p>

<p>I’ve been using “Deploy to Neocities” for a while, so I had a basis to work with already. I figured, all I’d have to do … is tell Github to build the site, and then construct the URL from what it would usually be on my website.</p>

<p>The next thing I had to make it do, was SSH into my VPS, because you can’t run Python on Neocities.</p>

<p>My first attempt was to work with a custom Ruby plugin, and have <em>that</em> build the post content, and then send it along with the constructed URL to a Python script on my VPS that would then jumble it all together and post it. But that didn’t work. Because Jekyll apparently does not like custom Rubies … I guess?</p>

<p>Also, if that sounds really convoluted and a round-a-about way of doing things, that’s <em>because it is</em>.</p>

<p>So, I went to sleep, then I went to work. And I mulled it over in my head, “Why not just have the build process construct the URL, look for new posts, and then dump it into the pipeline to your server, where it’s constructed, and posted.”</p>

<p>Behold.</p>

<p><code>
    - name: Check for new posts
      id: check_new_posts
      run: |
        new_post=false
        post_url=""
        current_date=$(TZ=America/New_York date +%Y-%m-%d)
        base_url="https://nova.mkultra.monster"
        echo "Current date: $current_date"
        for file in $(git log --diff-filter=A --name-only HEAD); do
          echo "Checking file: $file"
          if [[ $file == _posts/* ]]; then
            echo "File is in _posts directory"
            post_date=$(basename $file | cut -d'-' -f1-3)
            post_year=$(basename $file | cut -d'-' -f1)
            post_month=$(basename $file | cut -d'-' -f2)
            post_day=$(basename $file | cut -d'-' -f3)
            post_title=$(basename $file | cut -d'-' -f4- | sed 's/\.md$//')
            post_category=$(grep -m 1 '^categories:' $file -A 1 | tail -n 1 | sed 's/- //;s/"//g;s/ //g' | tr '[:upper:]' '[:lower:]')
            echo "Post date: $post_date"
            echo "Post category: $post_category"
            echo "Current date: $current_date"
            if [[ $post_date == $current_date ]]; then
              new_post=true
              post_url="$base_url/$post_category/$post_year/$post_month/$post_day/$post_title.html"
              echo "New post detected: $post_url"
              break
            else
              echo "Post date does not match current date"
            fi
          else
            echo "File is not in _posts directory"
          fi
        done
        echo "new_post=$new_post" &gt;&gt; $GITHUB_ENV
        echo "post_url=$post_url" &gt;&gt; $GITHUB_ENV
        echo "Post URL: $post_url"
</code>
<code>
    - name: Start SSH agent
      uses: webfactory/ssh-agent@v0.5.3
      with:
        ssh-private-key: $
</code>
<code>
    - name: Post to Mastodon
      if: env.new_post == 'true'
      env:
        MASTODON_API_KEY: $
        POST_URL: $
      run: |
        echo "Posting to Mastodon: ${POST_URL}"
        ssh -o StrictHostKeyChecking=no root@my_vps_ip "source ~/masto-poast/masto-poast-env/bin/activate &amp;&amp; MASTODON_API_KEY=$ python3 ~/masto-poast/poast.py '${POST_URL}'"
</code></p>

<p>But wait! THERE’S MORE!</p>

<p><img src="/img/posts/poast/wait.gif" /></p>

<p>The code above is everything Jekyll does by itself on Github until it reaches the point it can do no more, because static sites are a bit limited. But that’s okay! Static sites are great! But … for what we’re doing, we need to connect to my VPS, which is accomplished easily at the end of the build process.</p>

<p>Once connected, it activates the environment, and then runs the Python script, which is as follows.</p>

<p><code>                                                                        
import os
import sys
import requests
from bs4 import BeautifulSoup
</code>
<code>
MASTODON_API_URL = 'https://mkultra.monster/api/v1/statuses'
ACCESS_TOKEN = os.getenv('MASTODON_API_KEY')
POSTED_URLS_FILE = 'posted_urls.txt'
</code>
<code>
def extract_summary_and_tag(post_url):
    response = requests.get(post_url)
    soup = BeautifulSoup(response.content, 'html.parser')
</code>
<code>
    # Extract the second &lt; p &gt; tag within the #main div as a summary
    main_div = soup.find('div', {'id': 'main'})
    if main_div:
        paragraphs = main_div.find_all('p')
        summary = paragraphs[1].get_text() if len(paragraphs) &gt; 1 else "No summary available"
    else:
        summary = "No summary available"
</code>
<code>    
    # Extract the tag from the &lt; span &gt; within the #main div
    tag_span = None
    if main_div:
        for span in main_div.find_all('span'):
            if 'tag:' in span.get_text().lower():
                tag_span = span
                break
</code>
<code>    
    if tag_span:
        tag_link = tag_span.find('a')
        if tag_link:
            tag = tag_link.get_text(strip=True)
            print(f"Extracted tag: {tag}")
        else:
            tag = ""
            print("No &lt; a &gt; tag found within &lt; span &gt;")
    else:
        tag = ""
        print("No &lt; span &gt; tag found with 'tag:' text")
</code>
<code>
    hashtag = f"#{tag.replace(' ', '').lower()}" if tag else ""
</code>
<code>
    return summary, hashtag
</code>
<code>
def post_to_mastodon(content):
    headers = {
        'Authorization': f'Bearer {ACCESS_TOKEN}',
        'Content-Type': 'application/json'
    }
    data = {
        'status': content
    }
    response = requests.post(MASTODON_API_URL, headers=headers, json=data)
    print(f'Request URL: {MASTODON_API_URL}')
    print(f'Request Headers: {headers}')
    print(f'Request Data: {data}')
    print(f'Response Status Code: {response.status_code}')
    print(f'Response Text: {response.text}')
    if response.status_code == 200:
        print('Successfully posted to Mastodon')
    else:
        print(f'Error posting to Mastodon: {response.status_code} - {response.text}')
</code>
<code>
def has_been_posted(post_url):
    if not os.path.exists(POSTED_URLS_FILE):
        return False
    with open(POSTED_URLS_FILE, 'r') as file:
        posted_urls = file.read().splitlines()
    return post_url in posted_urls
</code>
<code>
def mark_as_posted(post_url):
    with open(POSTED_URLS_FILE, 'a') as file:
        file.write(post_url + '\n')
</code>
<code>
if __name__ == '__main__':
    if len(sys.argv) != 2:
        print('Usage: python poast.py "Post URL"')
        sys.exit(1)
    post_url = sys.argv[1]
    print(f'Received post URL: {post_url}')
</code>
<code>    
    if has_been_posted(post_url):
        print(f'Post URL has already been posted: {post_url}')
        sys.exit(0)
</code>
<code>    
    summary, hashtag = extract_summary_and_tag(post_url)
    post_content = f"Today on Nova Prime: {post_url}\n\n{summary}\n\n{hashtag}"
    print(f'Constructed post content: {post_content}')
</code>
<code>    
    post_to_mastodon(post_content)
    mark_as_posted(post_url)
</code></p>

<p>As you can see, all sensitive information is being stored, <em>somewhere else</em>. In Github secrets! Which are injected into the Python script upon connection.</p>

<p>But, what this does, is it basically creates this situation where, now, my blog is kind of, sort of, federated? Not really, but it <em>acts</em> that way. Whenever I write a new post, and hit commit, the site builds, and then my account posts the generated matter. It’s as if my Mastodon account is now inside of VS Code. Which it totally could be! … if I wanted to post everything I write to Mastodon in links to my blog.</p>

<p>I lost a little sleep over this. I went to bed late last night, and then I woke up early to do more troubleshooting, and then I went to work with bags under my eyes, and then I came home, tired as all hell. And I kept going.</p>

<p>And now it’s done</p>

<p>It works.</p>

<p>Enjoy.</p>]]></content><author><name>𐕣 C M D R ░ NOVA 𐕣</name></author><category term="Programming" /><category term="programming" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[It’s been a hell of a time! Earlier in the week, I suddenly had an issue where I broke my RSS feed bot that posted new feed items from my blog to my Mastodon account. I described this in my last post, but it was entirely because I … edited the XML. So! I spent the last entire day rebuilding a brand new way to do this. By turning VS Code’s “commit” button into a “Post to Mastodon” button. Let me explain.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Today I Dropped An Atom Bomb of Posts Onto Mastodon</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/social%20media/2024/11/05/today-i-dropped-an-atom-bomb-of-posts-onto-mastodon.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Today I Dropped An Atom Bomb of Posts Onto Mastodon" /><published>2024-11-05T14:14:00-05:00</published><updated>2024-11-05T14:14:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/social%20media/2024/11/05/today-i-dropped-an-atom-bomb-of-posts-onto-mastodon</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/social%20media/2024/11/05/today-i-dropped-an-atom-bomb-of-posts-onto-mastodon.html"><![CDATA[<p>Today I turned off my GitHub pages mirror of this site, and in doing so, I had to create my own XML feed with its own styling and all. Which … I accomplished, pretty easily! But then my bot that’s supposed to read my feed, and append old items to a file, and <em>only</em> post brand new items, exploded onto Mastodon three times with everything I’ve ever posted on here.</p>

<p>I think I could troubleshoot the issue and fix it, but at this point I don’t think that’s a great idea. But hey! My feed looks REALLY COOL.</p>

<p><a href="https://nova.mkultra.monster/feed.xml">Nova Feed</a></p>

<p>Aside from dropping everything I’ve mostly ever written online, directly onto Mastodon, I also made some updates to the site.</p>

<p>I was struggling with the CORS proxy for about 10 hours, with a break for sleep in-between, and I finally figured it out. Now the Tumblr feed of my bot posting on the left sidebar is working correctly, <em>and</em> updating without the need for the site to be rebuilt.</p>

<p>I’ve also added something pretty neat to the right sidebar, directly under my haxPunks … A list of trending topics from Mastodon! Which, when you click on a topic, you can then view who’s posting about and within that hashtag via your own Mastodon instance.</p>

<p>I may not really be able to figure out how to turn a Jekyll site into something that’s fully federated, but I can make it look like it is!</p>

<p>Aside from all of that, I just wanted to quickly apologize to the people who got slapped hard with all of my posts … three times. My bad.</p>

<p><img src="/img/posts/bomb/fedup.gif" /></p>]]></content><author><name>𐕣 C M D R ░ NOVA 𐕣</name></author><category term="Social Media" /><category term="social-media" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today I turned off my GitHub pages mirror of this site, and in doing so, I had to create my own XML feed with its own styling and all. Which … I accomplished, pretty easily! But then my bot that’s supposed to read my feed, and append old items to a file, and only post brand new items, exploded onto Mastodon three times with everything I’ve ever posted on here.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">CORS Light, The Drink of the API</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/programming/2024/11/05/cors-light-the-drink-of-the-api.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="CORS Light, The Drink of the API" /><published>2024-11-05T00:59:00-05:00</published><updated>2024-11-05T00:59:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/programming/2024/11/05/cors-light-the-drink-of-the-api</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/programming/2024/11/05/cors-light-the-drink-of-the-api.html"><![CDATA[<p>I’m a little bit delirious. Last night I fell asleep on my couch the entire night, and then woke up at 6am to my cat begging for food, and then I stayed up, and went to work. I got home, and yes, instead of watching the new Deadpool, I switch on the code machine and thought, “Why am I routing the Tumblr API through a github secret only to get static results that don’t update unless I push changes to my site? The heck?” And I thought, “What if I just use a proxy server on my VPS that the JavaScript accesses to give a fresh perspective every time someone refreshes my site?” Boy … oh boy.</p>

<p>For all intents and purposes, everything is setup correctly. I have a proxy server running perfectly, and certificates, and nginx blasting on all fours. But then I load the website, I check the developer console and …</p>

<p><strong>YOU HAVE BEEN BLOCKED BY CORS, WHERE THE HEADERS MAN?</strong></p>

<p>And me, crying and screaming, and pounding my fists into a pillow, “THE HEADERS ARE RIGHT THERE IN THE SERVER. THEY’RE RIGHT THERE BRO. WHAT CAN’T YOU READ?”</p>

<p>I don’t think I’ve ever driven myself quite this mad trying to post some dymanic updates from a bot to my website before. But I think it’s definitely because I’m so tired I feel dizzy.</p>

<p>There’s probably a very simple solution, and maybe it’s because I was running a local copy of my website alongside the live version and maybe that was making CORS go “DUDE,” but I think I’ll figure that out later.</p>

<p>I think I’ve had enough of seeing the phrase “CORS.”</p>

<p>I’m never going to drink a certain kind of beer again, at least.</p>

<p>I mean, I really <em>don’t need</em> to have this on my site. In fact, I bet I could find a way to just have the bot post something into a div onto my site with JavaScript and that VPS where I’m running a proxy.</p>

<p>But, uh, I’m just gonna go to sleep.</p>

<p>Thanks for reading my vent.</p>]]></content><author><name>𐕣 C M D R ░ NOVA 𐕣</name></author><category term="Programming" /><category term="programming" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[I’m a little bit delirious. Last night I fell asleep on my couch the entire night, and then woke up at 6am to my cat begging for food, and then I stayed up, and went to work. I got home, and yes, instead of watching the new Deadpool, I switch on the code machine and thought, “Why am I routing the Tumblr API through a github secret only to get static results that don’t update unless I push changes to my site? The heck?” And I thought, “What if I just use a proxy server on my VPS that the JavaScript accesses to give a fresh perspective every time someone refreshes my site?” Boy … oh boy.]]></summary></entry></feed>