<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.5">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2024-09-13T08:00:56-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">cmdr-nova@internet:~$</title><subtitle>NOVA PRIME</subtitle><entry><title type="html">AI Does Not An Author Make</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/tech/2024/09/13/ai-does-not-an-author-make.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="AI Does Not An Author Make" /><published>2024-09-13T07:02:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-09-13T07:02:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/tech/2024/09/13/ai-does-not-an-author-make</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/tech/2024/09/13/ai-does-not-an-author-make.html"><![CDATA[<p>Today I woke up sprawled out on my couch because I once again passed out while watching Youtube. This is a new trend for me as I inch closer and closer to 40. But, I got up, slapped some food into a bowl for my cat, and then turned on the milquetoast social media, and immediately saw more aggravating takes from people who don’t deserve attention, or any money whatsoever. I’m talking about plagiarists who are desperate to be called authors; AI loving losers who think you should definitely expel energy to read things they didn’t even have the energy to write <em>themselves</em>.</p>

<p>This comes on the heel of more irritating news, as <a href="/tech/2024/09/09/tell-mozilla-how-you-feel-about-ai">Mozilla ignores thousands and thousands of their users</a> criticizing their implementation of AI into Firefox (for no verifiable reason whatsoever), because <em>obviously</em> they’re more interested in the destruction of Mozilla, than continuing to be a privacy focused company. I have since moved to <a href="https://vivaldi.net" target="_blank">Vivaldi</a>, a browser by a company that has pledged <em>not</em> to implement AI into their browser.</p>

<p>But, back to the point at-hand, I want to highlight this article specifically, because I can only take <em>so much</em> inauthentic douchebaggery before I have to really express my thoughts. And that’s saying a lot, because <em>most</em> of corporate social media feeds off of being inauthentic and <em>fake</em>.</p>

<center>
<blockquote class="text-post-media" data-text-post-permalink="https://www.threads.net/@theinformation/post/C_yW_-6CJx4" data-text-post-version="0" id="ig-tp-C_yW_-6CJx4" style=" background:#FFF; border-width: 1px; border-style: solid; border-color: #00000026; border-radius: 16px; max-width:540px; margin: 1px; min-width:270px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);"> <a href="https://www.threads.net/@theinformation/post/C_yW_-6CJx4" style=" background:#FFFFFF; line-height:0; padding:0 0; text-align:center; text-decoration:none; width:100%; font-family: -apple-system, BlinkMacSystemFont, sans-serif;" target="_blank"> <div style=" padding: 40px; display: flex; flex-direction: column; align-items: center;"><div style=" display:block; height:32px; width:32px; padding-bottom:20px;"> <svg aria-label="Threads" height="32px" role="img" viewBox="0 0 192 192" width="32px" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg"> <path d="M141.537 88.9883C140.71 88.5919 139.87 88.2104 139.019 87.8451C137.537 60.5382 122.616 44.905 97.5619 44.745C97.4484 44.7443 97.3355 44.7443 97.222 44.7443C82.2364 44.7443 69.7731 51.1409 62.102 62.7807L75.881 72.2328C81.6116 63.5383 90.6052 61.6848 97.2286 61.6848C97.3051 61.6848 97.3819 61.6848 97.4576 61.6855C105.707 61.7381 111.932 64.1366 115.961 68.814C118.893 72.2193 120.854 76.925 121.825 82.8638C114.511 81.6207 106.601 81.2385 98.145 81.7233C74.3247 83.0954 59.0111 96.9879 60.0396 116.292C60.5615 126.084 65.4397 134.508 73.775 140.011C80.8224 144.663 89.899 146.938 99.3323 146.423C111.79 145.74 121.563 140.987 128.381 132.296C133.559 125.696 136.834 117.143 138.28 106.366C144.217 109.949 148.617 114.664 151.047 120.332C155.179 129.967 155.42 145.8 142.501 158.708C131.182 170.016 117.576 174.908 97.0135 175.059C74.2042 174.89 56.9538 167.575 45.7381 153.317C35.2355 139.966 29.8077 120.682 29.6052 96C29.8077 71.3178 35.2355 52.0336 45.7381 38.6827C56.9538 24.4249 74.2039 17.11 97.0132 16.9405C119.988 17.1113 137.539 24.4614 149.184 38.788C154.894 45.8136 159.199 54.6488 162.037 64.9503L178.184 60.6422C174.744 47.9622 169.331 37.0357 161.965 27.974C147.036 9.60668 125.202 0.195148 97.0695 0H96.9569C68.8816 0.19447 47.2921 9.6418 32.7883 28.0793C19.8819 44.4864 13.2244 67.3157 13.0007 95.9325L13 96L13.0007 96.0675C13.2244 124.684 19.8819 147.514 32.7883 163.921C47.2921 182.358 68.8816 191.806 96.9569 192H97.0695C122.03 191.827 139.624 185.292 154.118 170.811C173.081 151.866 172.51 128.119 166.26 113.541C161.776 103.087 153.227 94.5962 141.537 88.9883ZM98.4405 129.507C88.0005 130.095 77.1544 125.409 76.6196 115.372C76.2232 107.93 81.9158 99.626 99.0812 98.6368C101.047 98.5234 102.976 98.468 104.871 98.468C111.106 98.468 116.939 99.0737 122.242 100.233C120.264 124.935 108.662 128.946 98.4405 129.507Z" /></svg></div> <div style=" font-size: 15px; line-height: 21px; color: #999999; font-weight: 400; padding-bottom: 4px; "> Post by @theinformation</div> <div style=" font-size: 15px; line-height: 21px; color: #000000; font-weight: 600; "> View on Threads</div></div></a></blockquote>
<script async="" src="https://www.threads.net/embed.js"></script>
</center>
<p><br />
Opinion: Johnny Silverhand should materialize into the real world and explode AI content farms.</p>

<p>Let’s not even talk about the Threads account of a publication that has such a basic name that it’s gotta be AI generated (we’re … THE INFORMATION), but into the article itself where the featured image, some glossy ai-generated sludge, is attributed to the same guy who’s writing about how great it is to plagiarize actual writers in order to write a book. To add insult to injury, <em>you can’t even read</em> his word-vomit without <em>paying</em> him and/or the website for a subscription. Like the desperation of a teenager right before prom, these complete hacks who think they can technology their way into being a part of the creative world, they’re dead-set <em>determined</em> to make money off of you, somehow, some way.</p>

<p>So, <em>because</em> the article is paywalled and I’m too groggy to sift through their code in order to delete it, we’re just going to talk about the snippet you’re allowed to see before it cuts off and demands … ah, a minimum 300 dollars per year. Yeah, no. Put me in a Saw trap in a dirty bathroom, chained to a wall with a rusty bone saw and I’d sooner remove my own foot than pay you.</p>

<center>
<img src="/img/posts/ai2/monemoney.png" alt="a screenshot from the website the article is hosted on that asks for a minimum 299 per year in order to read their article, which is apparently discounted down from 399 USD." />
</center>
<p><br />
Ripped directly from the RSS feed:</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>Tim Boucher is an artist and technologist who explores the intersection of artificial intelligence and human creativity.</p>
</blockquote>

<blockquote>
  <p>I set up a Google Alert on my name so long ago that I’d almost forgotten about it. It occasionally sends me stories about people in faraway places who share my first and last names. But the alert I received in mid-August was different.</p>
</blockquote>

<blockquote>
  <p>When I opened the email, I realized that this was really about me: My work had been referenced in a class action lawsuit against Anthropic, a leader in generative artificial intelligence. I am not party to the lawsuit, but it claims that my work is not real “writing” (scare quotes and all) and that I am not a real author, because I use generative AI, among other tools, to produce my books. No one involved in the lawsuit reached out to me for more information; I would have been happy to share.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>“Tim Boucher is an artist.” I wouldn’t go that far, insulting artists by giving Tim credibility. But, right from the get-go, this guy is expressing his extreme need to feel important, or like he’s done something, by immediately detailing that he’s setup Google Alerts to let him know when people have mentioned his name online. Tim Boucher, come read what I’ve written about you, you fake piece of crap.</p>

<p>He starts out talking about how he was essentially being sued for using AI to pump out sludge-books. And, to whomever said his writing was not real, I applaud you. You should do it again.</p>

<p>Since that’s around where it cuts off, I’m assuming the article is less about Tim trying to feel validated in being a plagiarist hack, and more him writing a defense he’ll use in the court of law, where he’ll be forever shamed. I’m just going to use this as a jumping off point to share the rest of my feelings on this matter. A matter I wish wasn’t a matter, but we’re living in the worst and also most boring cyberpunk dystopia imaginable.</p>

<p>They’re <em>right</em>, Tim. You are not a real writer, you are not a real author, and you haven’t <em>done</em> anything of note.</p>

<p>Anyone who uses theft-tech to generate words that they can publish for a quick buck <em>is not a damn author</em>. You are no better than Microsoft Tech Support scammers ripping off elderly people of their retirement money. You have done <em>nothing</em>. You did <em>not</em> write anything. You used a machine that has scraped the entire internet of every word an actual human has written, in order to generate a discombobulation of words that you hope someone will think is interesting.</p>

<p>But I’m here to say, <em>fuck you.</em></p>

<p>It’s because of people <em>like you</em> that the world of self published writing will be <em>even worse</em> off, and will be continued to be considered <em>lesser</em> than big house publishing. Because of uncreative, <em>losers</em>, flooding the market, flooding apps with <em>shit</em>. Before, we were only competing with people who refuse to proofread. Now we’re competing with people who refuse to proofread, and <em>also</em> people who refuse to read <em>and</em> write.</p>

<p>I wish I was making this up.</p>

<p>I wish I hadn’t started writing my next book literal <em>months</em> before this started to become a problem. I <em>wish</em> I would’ve written it years ago, so that I could’ve gotten it out, and finished in an era where I could <em>still</em> share snippets and previews online, without needing to worry about machines taking every word and rearranging it for people who should go broke and live in the gutter.</p>

<p>That’s how I feel.</p>

<p>No-holds-barred, if you use AI to generate art and fiction, you deserve <em>the worst</em>. And no less than that.</p>

<p>Fortunately, like NFTs, AI is a bubble, and when it finally pops, the results will be amazing, hilarious, and great. And then the general internet will forget any of this happened three days later.</p>]]></content><author><name>𐕣 C M D R ░ NOVA 𐕣</name></author><category term="Tech" /><category term="tech" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today I woke up sprawled out on my couch because I once again passed out while watching Youtube. This is a new trend for me as I inch closer and closer to 40. But, I got up, slapped some food into a bowl for my cat, and then turned on the milquetoast social media, and immediately saw more aggravating takes from people who don’t deserve attention, or any money whatsoever. I’m talking about plagiarists who are desperate to be called authors; AI loving losers who think you should definitely expel energy to read things they didn’t even have the energy to write themselves.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Illusion Connect Will Return?</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/gaming/2024/09/10/illusion-connect-will-return.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Illusion Connect Will Return?" /><published>2024-09-10T23:34:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-09-10T23:34:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/gaming/2024/09/10/illusion-connect-will-return</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/gaming/2024/09/10/illusion-connect-will-return.html"><![CDATA[<p>It was 2020, my rotation of mobile games included just two of them. I had a phone that could support … maybe three? One of them was the already very well-known Orc game, and the other was a little gacha called Illusion Connect. Okay, so, if you aren’t really interested in gachas, and you think buying stuff in them sucks, this probably isn’t all that interesting to you.</p>

<p>But, today it was revealed, that almost two years after it’s closure, Illusion Connect is returning this winter.</p>

<p><img src="/img/posts/connect/illusion.webp" /></p>

<p>This was my <em>main</em> mobile game for a long time. The thing is, like with most mobile games, I stop playing them for a while, and then I come back and continue. It’s a pattern with me, and not really any inherent issue with mobile games in-general. I treat triple-a desktop games exactly the same way. I’m super into Warframe, but I haven’t opened it in two weeks, because I just … have so much going on in my brain-juice.</p>

<p>So I had that little cooling off period, and after a while, I decided I wanted to open it up again and see how things were going. And then in December, 2022, it abruptly shutdown. Leaving you with nothing but an error screen as if it still exists, it just couldn’t connect to the servers.</p>

<p>Since then, I’ve been kind of meandering through these other gacha games that don’t really capture the same thing, or the same fun I had in my little phone game of anime girls. Albeit, Genshin, ZZZ, Wuthering Waves are all <em>great</em>. There’s just … something <em>also</em> good about a game that isn’t trying to be a huge open-world mega gacha experience. And that’s what Illusion Connect was. A simple thing you logged into, tapped some objectives, collected your stuff, pulled, and then logged off.</p>

<p>I like mobile games like that. Something I can open secretly while I’m walking through the halls at work, click a box, watch it open, and then shove my phone back into my pants.</p>

<p>But <em>anyway</em>, <a href="https://www.taptap.cn/moment/582294702590525813" target="_blank">here’s the announcement</a>.</p>

<p>For those who can’t read Chinese, (like me), here’s the translation:</p>

<center>

<img src="/img/posts/connect/part1.png" />

<img src="/img/posts/connect/part2.png" />

<img src="/img/posts/connect/part3.png" />

</center>

<p><br /></p>

<p>Suffice to say, the developers have apparently been rebuilding the game, and that’s cool! It’s <em>cool</em> when an online game of sorts isn’t just <em>abandoned</em>, and instead worked on, rebuilt, and then relaunched, even <em>after</em> an unfortunate closure. A lot of big studios should take notes here …</p>

<p>Still mad I bought into The Matrix Online two decades ago in order to lose all my stuff, and my character, <em>forever</em>.</p>]]></content><author><name>𐕣 C M D R ░ NOVA 𐕣</name></author><category term="Gaming" /><category term="gaming" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[It was 2020, my rotation of mobile games included just two of them. I had a phone that could support … maybe three? One of them was the already very well-known Orc game, and the other was a little gacha called Illusion Connect. Okay, so, if you aren’t really interested in gachas, and you think buying stuff in them sucks, this probably isn’t all that interesting to you.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Cohost is Shutting Down</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/social%20media/2024/09/10/cohost-is-shutting-down.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Cohost is Shutting Down" /><published>2024-09-10T08:35:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-09-10T08:35:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/social%20media/2024/09/10/cohost-is-shutting-down</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/social%20media/2024/09/10/cohost-is-shutting-down.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="/img/posts/cohost/cohost_logo.png" /></p>

<p>Yesterday, on September 9th, 2024, it came across my timelines that Cohost, one of the few Tumblr alternatives, <a href="https://cohost.org/staff/post/7611443-cohost-to-shut-down" target="_blank">would be shutting its doors</a> at the end of the year, and going read-only on October 1st. I’ve been a <em>huge</em> advocate that people join and use <a href="https://app.wafrn.net" target="_blank">Wafrn</a> as a Tumblr alternative, <em>largely</em> due-in-part to the fact that Wafrn is fediverse connected, and therefore a lot of the stress of server costs are offloaded into that connection. Not only that, but should Wafrn ever close its doors, <em>every single user</em> is fine, since you can <em>just move</em> to another fediverse server, with most of your data in-tact. Despite all of that, it is sad to see something that <em>was</em> pretty cool, go away.</p>

<p>Since the beginning they’ve been proponents of … an isolated social experience, dressed up to look like a website from 1997. Which is cool (the part about looking like it’s from the nineties)! But, like I keep saying in every other post, federated social media controlled by users, and not corporations, <em>is the future</em>. Being regular people who aren’t a corporation who happened to get together as a group of 4, in order to develop a social media website, is pretty <em>neat</em>. I’ll give them that.</p>

<p>But, since the general vibe of Cohost has been to <em>avoid</em> federation, at all costs, and keep users within this walled-garden of sorts … well, I guess all that community building is <em>also</em> finished.</p>

<p>I’m not trying to rub salt in the wounds of people who are upset about this. Cohost was genuinely <em>good</em>. It definitely wasn’t Bluesky, which, since launching, has been nothing but a monster in the room that says and does questionable things, while other people pretend it’s the <em>only</em> choice. And, I actually <em>really</em> wanted to like and use Cohost, but I’m so <em>tied in</em> on federation, that it just made <em>no sense at all</em> to me to really take serious. Just like with SpaceHey, the Myspace revival project … I don’t really have any interest in sharing my thoughts, ideas, and projects on an isolated website, in 2024, just so I can also go share it on the website that <em>isn’t</em> isolated.</p>

<p>Reducing repetitive action is necessary, because, if you’re a creator, <em>you do stuff like this a lot</em>, and time isn’t cheap, and I don’t have a lot of it nowadays.</p>

<p>But, for people who are just online to share thoughts, and didn’t really have any other place they posted them in, I’m sorry. I wish I had a million dollars or two in order to save this website. It <em>really does suck a lot</em> to see the good ones go, when the bad places are still up and running and have yet to die (TWITTER!).</p>

<p>As an alternative action for those who I’ve seen via Cohost talking about how it was, to them, the only safe place online they felt they could express themselves, I <em>urge</em> you to create a website here on Neocities. It doesn’t even have to be professionally designed or <em>perfect</em>, but just make a website. Design it any way you please, and set it up in a way that allows you to speak. I think you’ll find that being able to share you thoughts on something you built, for free, and without threat of any servers dying is pretty fun. And, at the end of the day, everything you create for a website should be backed up on your PC, effectively making it impossible for your data to be destroyed (I also back up my websites in multiple cloud locations, just in case).</p>

<p>Those are my thoughts, though, aside from being confused at how Stripe’s policy change on tipping caused all of this. <em>Surely</em>, you could still offer a site-wide currency in order to generate revenue, and just give people who buy it some kind of fake little digital thing for their blogs so that it’s no longer a payment for what Stripe essentially sees as <em>nothing</em>. I don’t know, maybe the problem runs deeper than that.</p>]]></content><author><name>𐕣 C M D R ░ NOVA 𐕣</name></author><category term="Social Media" /><category term="social-media" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Tell Mozilla How You Feel About AI</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/tech/2024/09/09/tell-mozilla-how-you-feel-about-ai.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Tell Mozilla How You Feel About AI" /><published>2024-09-09T17:03:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-09-09T17:03:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/tech/2024/09/09/tell-mozilla-how-you-feel-about-ai</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/tech/2024/09/09/tell-mozilla-how-you-feel-about-ai.html"><![CDATA[<p>Hey folks! Not a huge update today, but someone on my Mastodon timeline shared a post in regards to Mozilla asking for feedback on their incoming “AI toolbar.”</p>

<iframe src="https://wandering.shop/@Rhube/113109174612343790/embed" width="400" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen" sandbox="allow-scripts allow-same-origin allow-popups allow-popups-to-escape-sandbox allow-forms"></iframe>

<p>I think <em>anyone</em> with an ounce of morals, who know the societal and environmental impacts of AI, should go here and tell Mozilla exactly how you feel about them trying to shove AI into Firefox. Of all the browsers, I <em>never</em> would have expected a so-called privacy focused company to jump onto a trend that’s all about plagiarism and ripping people off. And that’s aside from the detrimental effects that could be caused by allowing space for scrapers <em>in the browser you use</em> on a daily basis.</p>

<p>Stand alongside artists, writers, musicians, and developers, <a href="https://connect.mozilla.org/t5/discussions/share-your-feedback-on-the-ai-services-experiment-in-nightly/m-p/68389" target="_blank">and tell them, <em>“No.”</em></a></p>]]></content><author><name>𐕣 C M D R ░ NOVA 𐕣</name></author><category term="Tech" /><category term="tech" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Hey folks! Not a huge update today, but someone on my Mastodon timeline shared a post in regards to Mozilla asking for feedback on their incoming “AI toolbar.”]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Plant Your Own Garden</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/tech/2024/09/08/plant-your-own-garden.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Plant Your Own Garden" /><published>2024-09-08T19:13:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-09-08T19:13:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/tech/2024/09/08/plant-your-own-garden</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/tech/2024/09/08/plant-your-own-garden.html"><![CDATA[<p>Today, I spent the equivalent of around ten hours of work (on my day off, no less), designing and developing a new kind of “side service” I wanted to offer to people who: Don’t have the time, or don’t <em>want</em> to learn HTML and CSS, and who want to separate themselves from corporate media, <em>just a little bit</em>, even if it’s just to stop paying services like Linktree a monthly fee.</p>

<p>So, today I am unveiling, <a href="/linkgarden/for_you" target="_blank">LinkGarden</a>.</p>

<p>Plant your own garden … of links!</p>

<p><img src="/img/for-you/examples.png" style="align:center;" /></p>

<p>I detail the service on the page, but I’ll write about it here, as well, except, maybe in a more extended fashion. I’m offering this for eighty bucks. You pay me, then contact me, and I’ll get your page together, and even make you a Neocities where it can be hosted (hosted, completely for free). Of course, once I hand over the credentials, you’ll be responsible for changing your password. But, that’s a given!</p>

<p>You <em>can</em> request to use a custom domain, but this is a little more involved, in that, we’ll need to figure out if you’re buying the domain, and if you <em>know</em> how to setup the DNS. If not, I certainly know how to do this, but I <em>also</em> don’t have access to your domain admin panels.</p>

<p>I’m doing this, though, because, I want to show people that they can have all the frills of a Linktree, <em>without</em> a Linktree. I can do it for you, easy-peasy, and in about an hour.</p>

<p>Now, obviously, if you want <em>really</em> extensive, or more complicated stuff (more javascript, animated buttons that do more than just click and highlight, and so on and so forth), that would obviously take <em>more than an hour</em> to setup. Then, yes, we’ll have to negotiate pricing a little bit (right now my day job takes up so much of my time it’s ridiculous). Consider this though, if you currently pay monthly for a Linktree, or some other such service, and you’ve been doing so for a long time, how much have you paid them, in total? Probably less than what it’d cost for me to do this for you, right?</p>

<p>But I’m also doing this, because <em>you should</em> own your own piece of the internet. A place where a bunch of suits <em>aren’t</em> tracking your every move, where people can come and see what you’re all about, quickly, and easily. Maybe sometime in the future I’ll offer to build people entire websites! But, I don’t think that’s a venture I want to spend another ten hours preparing right now (I have some people in VR I want to visit tonight).</p>

<p>Once you have the page, and access to it, if you decide you want things changed, I can <em>also</em> do that. But, I <em>would</em> encourage buyers to look into the code used to build their link pages, and see if you can fiddle with changing things yourself (learning is fun!). I have them all setup with the simplest CSS and HTML possible, and if you use a program like VS Code, switching colors around in a CSS file is <em>even easier</em>. And, if you mess things up, I will have a backup of everything I do right here on my PC.</p>

<p>So, come on over, <em>and plant your own garden</em>.</p>]]></content><author><name>𐕣 C M D R ░ NOVA 𐕣</name></author><category term="Tech" /><category term="tech" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today, I spent the equivalent of around ten hours of work (on my day off, no less), designing and developing a new kind of “side service” I wanted to offer to people who: Don’t have the time, or don’t want to learn HTML and CSS, and who want to separate themselves from corporate media, just a little bit, even if it’s just to stop paying services like Linktree a monthly fee.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">I Gave Buffer a Shot: I Have Thoughts</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/tech/2024/09/07/i-gave-buffer-a-shot-i-have-thoughts.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="I Gave Buffer a Shot: I Have Thoughts" /><published>2024-09-07T21:59:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-09-07T21:59:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/tech/2024/09/07/i-gave-buffer-a-shot-i-have-thoughts</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/tech/2024/09/07/i-gave-buffer-a-shot-i-have-thoughts.html"><![CDATA[<p>A while back, I put up <a href="/social media/2024/07/31/bluesky-part-3-all-your-data-are-belong-to-us">a post about Bluesky</a> announcing their partnership with cross-posting company, “Buffer” (Yes, I’m aware that it’s starting to look like I have multiple topics that are an ongoing series on this website). I also detailed how this was a bad move, because Buffer is using OpenAI tech in their backend, and even though they <em>say</em> it’s just an option you can utilize with writing posts … based on how OpenAI has been conducting themselves, I don’t fully trust <em>any</em> company that thinks it’s a good idea to use their tech. Regardless, since I run a lot of different social media accounts, and I thought it could make things easier for me, like when I write blog posts, or have new music, I decided to give it a whirl!</p>

<p>Here are my thoughts.</p>

<center>
<img src="/img/posts/buffer2/posts.png" alt="screen from the Buffer website, showcasing organized posts I've made across Mastodon on a calendar." />
</center>
<p><br /></p>

<p>The website itself is very well organized, you can connect your socials, and it even has a calendar that displays … <em>everything</em> you’ve ever posted on your connected accounts, chronologically by time and date (which … is actually pretty <em>worrying</em> if you don’t think they’re using that OpenAI tech ethically), and you can do a few other things. Such as, you can create a “start” page, which is just a rip of Link-tree. The downside, is that creating a Buffer version of Link-tree takes up one of your social connections.</p>

<p>But, how <em>many</em> are you allowed to connect on a free account?</p>

<p>Three.</p>

<p>Or, if you want a page with all your links provided by Buffer, essentially, you can connect <em>two</em> accounts.</p>

<p>So, basically, if you’re using the free Buffer plan, you may as well not even be there. If you can’t manage two accounts without the help of some software … geez, dude.</p>

<p>Okay, but how much does it cost to upgrade to have <em>more</em> connections.</p>

<p>Short answer: Way to goddang much.</p>

<p>Long answer:</p>

<p>You can actually opt to start paying them fifteen dollars a month for the three accounts you’ve already connected, and have a few added features. Or, you can connect four accounts for twenty dollars, or five accounts for twenty-five dollars, or … a whopping fifty dollars for ten accounts! For a frame of reference, I have around eleven or twelve accounts I use across different networks, some alts, some not-so-much. They say, on the subscription page, that this is all “the most value for an individual creator …”</p>

<p>An <em>individual</em> creator? Paying, fifty dollars a month for ten accounts, <em>as long as you’re paying on a yearly basis</em>.</p>

<center>
<img src="/img/posts/buffer2/value.png" alt="A screenshot from the Buffer website depicting having to paying 600 dollars total, or 50 dollars a month, for the ability to connect 10 accounts to their service." />
</center>
<p><br /></p>

<p>Bro …</p>

<p>Okay, so <em>obviously</em> this has gotta be some kind of marketing that’s specifically targeting creators who are <em>already</em> making money from what they do online. For fifty dollars a month, if paid yearly, or <em>sixty dollars</em> on a monthly basis, for <em>ten</em> accounts, you could, instead, subscribe to Apple+ and Netflix, and have some entertainment instead. And then just manage your accounts <em>yourself</em>. All with the added benefit of not potentially feeding everything <em>you’ve ever posted</em> into some OpenAI crap.</p>

<p>Which, take a look at this: Are mentioned <em>multiple</em> times on the publishing and scheduling box.</p>

<center>
<img src="/img/posts/buffer2/ai.png" alt="A screenshot from the Buffer website's publishing window, depicting their AI assistant being mentioned twice just pixels away from each other." />
</center>
<p><br />
“Use AI assistant!” Also, did you want help publishing with the “AI Assistant?”</p>

<p>Because <em>everyone on social media knows</em> that using AI to generate your words totally doesn’t make you look like a completely fake tool-bag.</p>

<p>So, instead of using Buffer, I’ve opted to just manage the couple of accounts I use the most … <em>myself</em>. No, you guys aren’t getting fifteen, or twenty, or <em>fifty</em> dollars out of me.</p>

<p>But, I <em>did</em> really like their “start page” link aggregator. And, since they’re so hyper-vigilant about AI generated plagairism, I’m sure they won’t mind if I just … rip out the code of their link page, delete all the link trackers, place the CSS into its own file (because why the hell do you have it on the same page as the content?), rename all the modules to something humorous, enlarge the profile picture, increase the vertical size of the banner gif, change all of the colors, replace their icons with <a href="https://phosphoricons.com" target="_blank">Phosphor</a> icons, and replace their crappy static “update” section that doesn’t even serve clickable links, with … A live feed of my blog’s RSS (courtesy of Brenton Fletcher’s <a href="https://rss.bloople.net" target="_blank">rss.bloople.net</a>)</p>

<p>See it, here: <a href="https://nova.mkultra.monster/linkgarden/" target="_blank">CMDR Nova’s Linkgarden</a>.</p>

<p>Buffer version on the left, my version on the right.</p>

<center>
<img src="/img/posts/buffer2/links.png" alt="A screenshot of Buffer's link page versus my link page, styled similar, but also completely different." />
</center>
<p><br /></p>

<p>But here’s the thing, if you <em>really</em> want, or <em>need</em> a page of all of your links that you can easily just hand to someone like a business card, you can <em>build one yourself</em>, or, if you really don’t have the time, or want to learn HTML and CSS, I can just make it <em>for you</em>. I’m actually going to put together some examples of what a “linkgarden” could look like if I made one, and gave it to someone, and provide information on free hosting. Or, hey, maybe I could set that up for people too?</p>

<p>I don’t know.</p>

<p>What I <em>do</em> know, is that you don’t have to pay companies continuously for something that can be made for you in a couple of hours, or that you can make <em>yourself</em> in a couple of hours, and then have <em>full control over</em>. And if you <em>really</em> need automated control of all of your accounts at once, I’m <em>sure</em> there’s a better way to do it, than paying some company that’s gone all-in on AI, six hundred dollars a mother-frikken <em>year</em>.</p>]]></content><author><name>𐕣 C M D R ░ NOVA 𐕣</name></author><category term="Tech" /><category term="tech" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[A while back, I put up a post about Bluesky announcing their partnership with cross-posting company, “Buffer” (Yes, I’m aware that it’s starting to look like I have multiple topics that are an ongoing series on this website). I also detailed how this was a bad move, because Buffer is using OpenAI tech in their backend, and even though they say it’s just an option you can utilize with writing posts … based on how OpenAI has been conducting themselves, I don’t fully trust any company that thinks it’s a good idea to use their tech. Regardless, since I run a lot of different social media accounts, and I thought it could make things easier for me, like when I write blog posts, or have new music, I decided to give it a whirl!]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Social Media, Empathy, Caring About Other People?</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/social%20media/2024/09/04/social-media-empathy-caring-about-other-people.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Social Media, Empathy, Caring About Other People?" /><published>2024-09-04T15:59:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-09-04T15:59:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/social%20media/2024/09/04/social-media-empathy-caring-about-other-people</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/social%20media/2024/09/04/social-media-empathy-caring-about-other-people.html"><![CDATA[<p>I feel like this is something I want to write about here on the Nova Prime, not because it’s a joyful topic, or something that makes me happy, but because it’s an overall larger issue that I think’s been carried over from a website that’s trained a lot of people to kind of, mentally … disregard others, at all expense, for their own personal gain, or comfort. Am I saying that Twitter has accidentally spawned masses of narcissists? Not really. I don’t think a website and its use for over a decade can alter someone’s brain chemistry. Or … can it?</p>

<p>But this is more about Bluesky, because, yes, again, we are seeing some undue angst and toxicity being slung toward the federated social network revolving around ActivityPub, or more exclusively, Mastodon, <em>because a lot of these people don’t know about</em> and <em>don’t care to</em> discover the rest of it. I’ve seen this happen <em>pretty much</em> every other day since Twitter had its last excursion, and then the more recent Brazilian excursion. People, basically, celebrating what they themselves believe to be a <em>better</em> platform, and for all intents and purposes, they can do that (even if that platform is a corporate owned entity no better than Twitter)! But, for whatever reason, it’s <em>always</em> followed by also dunking on people who are minding their own business on the Fediverse. For …</p>

<p>Reasons!</p>

<p>I want to preface this with something, before I dive into the biggest offenses I’ve seen: I was invited to join Bluesky back when the doors were still closed. Back when it was still an exclusive club, and being more familiar with Mastodon, than Bluesky, I was pretty used to … let’s say, people kinda more actually giving a shit about what they say, when they say it, and how they address others. Much to my dismay, I quickly learned that this is <em>not</em> the average Bluesky experience. Because I didn’t save any screenshots from when it happened, and I don’t feel like reliving every intricacy of what exactly went on, I’ll be brief, and explain as simply as possible what took place.</p>

<p>I started following people in and adjacent to the LGBTQ+ community, and, as you know, some people like to post with complete abandon, and zero regard. A “popular” account, attached to a, then, popular block and mute list creator, used a slur to describe people like her, and people like me, openly, just right on the timeline. Feeling kind of jolted by this, and largely due-in-part to some trauma I’ve had in the past, I asked if it was completely necessary to do that. Or, if some kind of warning could’ve happened (no, I am not talking about the word “Queer”, just so we’re straight on that).</p>

<p>This was, apparently, <em>not the right thing to ask</em>.</p>

<p>It was my first <em>week</em> on Bluesky, and I was dogpiled, I was harassed, I was <em>mocked</em> for being traumatized by past events that I had no control over, because of who I was, and how I presented myself to the world (you know, instances of events where harm did, or could have come upon my person).</p>

<p>I had multiple users jump <em>directly</em> into my notifications to make sure I knew that <em>nobody cares</em> about how I feel, about my <em>feelings</em>, and that my experiences mean nothing. That I am alone, and I have to deal with it myself, while others speak, and do as they please.</p>

<p>As you can probably guess, I was a mess around this point. I was kind of … reeling. Flashbacks, trauma, anxiety; Feeling like I’d just joined a social network absolutely <em>full</em> of sociopaths.</p>

<p>Flash forward a year, and both of those original accounts have been pushed off of the website, because, you guessed it: They’re both abusive people that were given too much benefit of the doubt.</p>

<p><strong>Who could have guessed.</strong></p>

<p>Now: Could I have avoided all of this by just <em>unfollowing</em> the offending account or accounts? Sure. But also I don’t think it’s a lot to ask that people take harmful things, and put them behind a warning. Which is something that usually happens on Mastodon, because, I guess, a larger number of Mastodon users care about other people more than your average Bluesky user?</p>

<p>I don’t know. I don’t know if it’s a good idea to generalize a whole website of people. But! Impressions were made, and <em>set</em>.</p>

<p>Now, here we are today. Another gaggle of people rejoicing at the growth Bluesky is experiencing due to X being banned in Brazil. Which is good! A website that is owned and operated by a corporate entity, and sponsor, <em>needs</em> growth in order to eventually make money. And, like clockwork, with all of that <em>also</em> comes the random dunking of people who use a much older federated network, that’s been around since the internet took off. You already know what I’m talking about, so we’ll just dive right into this, again (I posted about this on my Mastodon account, but I feel like it needed more picking apart).</p>

<center>
<img alt="an image where a Bluesky user asserts that compiling a Linux kernel is easier than joining Mastodon" src="/img/posts/busky3/kernal_hard.png" />
</center>

<p><br /></p>

<p>As a lot of people who read what I write here probably already know, I’m <em>very</em> passionate about the deconstruction of centralized social media, and the corporate internet. So much so, that I have two machines that run Linux, one that runs MacOS, and none that run Windows. Most of my online activity is on some <em>kind</em> of open-source software, and the corporate tech I <em>do</em> interact with is … limited, and usually only for the benefit of what I create, or compose, or make.</p>

<p>Now, I <em>use</em> Linux, and I am by no means a Linux genius, so when I see someone talking about compiling a Linux kernel, I’m not entirely sure how they’d accomplish that. I’ve never done it, nor ever considered it. But! I am under the impression that you <em>need some</em> knowledge of the C programming language, and its compilers.</p>

<p>Imagine saying that you need a degree in computer science to choose a Mastodon instance, and to make sure you’re choosing one with a competent moderation policy, and fully meaning that, wholeheartedly, with a straight face. And to say that in response to someone, <em>basically</em> saying that, your onboarding process for a social network needs to be entirely smooth, without friction, or people will immediately abandon it and just give their data back to their corporate overlords.</p>

<p>I <em>don’t want</em> to believe that a mass majority of people are so intellectually <em>lazy</em> that they’d refuse to spend sixty seconds looking at the splash page of a Mastodon instance and going, “Hmm. Okay, so they ban nazis and they’re okay with gay and trans people, awesome!” I <em>do</em> want to believe that this is just a popular narrative among people who have little specific agendas in mind, but that’s probably too conspiracy theorist to even begin speaking about.</p>

<p>Like I said in my Mastodon post on this topic, <em>leaving Twitter behind</em> is already creating friction in your social media existence. That a little more is too much, is just ridiculous. People are more happy to jump directly into the arms of another corporation, because all they have to do is write down a username and a password and then forget about it?</p>

<p>Nah, you can’t be <em>serious</em>, my guy.</p>

<p>But, this all isn’t even the biggest offense in what’s essentially a huge thread of people dunking on the fediverse, again, <em>for no reason</em> (I would link to it, but I honestly deactivated my mainline Bluesky account after seeing all of this and I have no interest in visiting their domain, again).</p>

<center>
<img alt="an imagine of two Bluesky users sharing the exasperation with ... being expected to care about other people on the fediverse." src="/img/posts/busky3/empathy_hard.png" />
</center>

<p><br /></p>

<p><em>This</em>. This freakin’ attitude again.</p>

<p>“Other people’s feelings aren’t my problem! I don’t care about THEM?! GOD.”</p>

<p>Do you know how difficult it is to push the “CW” button on Mastodon, and then type your post?</p>

<p>It’s not hard.</p>

<p>It’s also not hard to consider other people when you’re going about your daily life and making decisions.</p>

<p><em>It is not hard</em>. You cannot convince me that it is.</p>

<p>All this continued attitude from Bluesky proves to me, is that Mastodon users … somehow care <em>more</em> about the people around them, than <em>maybe</em> your average user on Bluesky. Which is fucked up. Because the Fediverse has its own issues with nazi instances cropping up at random, and abusive people block evading, and so on, and so forth. But to <em>think</em> it’s a DUNK, that on Bluesky, you’re <em>not expected</em> to express empathy for others.</p>

<p>Guys.</p>

<p>Guys, I think I’m gonna barf into my shoes, and then piss my pants.</p>

<p>I’m just <em>utterly</em> confused about how we’ve gotten to this point. <em>to this crossroads</em>, where two different websites are having fights with each other, and one of the <em>main</em> points of argument is that … it’s too hard to care about other people.</p>

<p>I dunno, fellas, maybe I was right in the first paragraph.</p>

<p>Needless to say, I don’t really want much to do with Bluesky, and I’m <em>sure</em> there are perfectly normal and perfectly fine people on the website. But, for the past <strong>year</strong> this has been a trend, an attitude, that I have <em>only seen</em> coming from Bluesky.</p>

<p>That’s a red flag.</p>

<p>A continuous, never-ending red flag, that just keeps waving and waving.</p>

<p>I <em>can’t wait</em> for the “I deleted my Bluesky account today” posts that will inevitably begin cropping up across the Fediverse. Because, federated social media and the federated internet, <em>is the future</em>, whether Jay at BSKY wants to acknowledge it, or not.</p>

<center>
<img alt="the ceo of bluesky explaining how you can use a domain for your username, as if this is a new feature the internet has never seen before" src="/img/posts/busky3/jay.png" />
</center>
<p><br /></p>

<p>Kay, I’m done.</p>]]></content><author><name>𐕣 C M D R ░ NOVA 𐕣</name></author><category term="Social Media" /><category term="social-media" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[I feel like this is something I want to write about here on the Nova Prime, not because it’s a joyful topic, or something that makes me happy, but because it’s an overall larger issue that I think’s been carried over from a website that’s trained a lot of people to kind of, mentally … disregard others, at all expense, for their own personal gain, or comfort. Am I saying that Twitter has accidentally spawned masses of narcissists? Not really. I don’t think a website and its use for over a decade can alter someone’s brain chemistry. Or … can it?]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">So I Beat POOLS</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/gaming/2024/09/03/so-i-beat-pools.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="So I Beat POOLS" /><published>2024-09-03T18:47:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-09-03T18:47:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/gaming/2024/09/03/so-i-beat-pools</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/gaming/2024/09/03/so-i-beat-pools.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="/img/posts/pools2/1.png" alt="image of a pool room with pool slides hanging from the ceiling" /></p>

<p>You remember a while back when <a href="/gaming/2024/05/22/pools">I wrote that post on POOLS</a> about how awesome and good I thought the game was? Well, I got to chapter two around that time, and decided to stop playing for a while. Not because the game was <em>bad</em> or anything, but just because it gets under you skin way too easily. Eventually, though, I <em>had</em> to come back, and I <em>had</em> to complete it.</p>

<p>And that I did.</p>

<p><img src="/img/posts/pools2/2.png" alt="image of another pool room that's shrouded in darkness, with larger than life mannequin heads jutting from the floor, mouths open" /></p>

<p>I’m going to spoil a bunch of stuff here, but I’m assuming that’s okay, because Backrooms related games and media are kinda niche, and when it comes to horror, this is especially niche.</p>

<p>Usually, when I tried to play this game, I would do it late at night, in complete silence … for some <em>reason</em>. And that made it pretty hard to work my way through. Don’t even get me started on The Complex: Expedition. Despite its harmless entity (that I know of), I find that game <em>just</em> as terrifying.</p>

<p>It’s all the low humming, the scratches, the howling of dark wind in an endless tunnel.</p>

<p>But I did it.</p>

<p>I pushed through, with my pinky on the shift key, the entire time.</p>

<p>There were freaky moments. Funny moments. And sometimes, awe-inspiring moments.</p>

<p>And then it came to an end, with the silent protagonist setting their camera down upon a table, mannequins encroaching upon you from one of two paths behind you, and another arm holding a door open. But then the view cuts to a recording, the door shuts, and whoever’s viewing the tape of your actions hits the stop button, and credits roll.</p>

<p>Pretty <em>confusing</em>, right?</p>

<p>I don’t think so.</p>

<p>Throughout POOLS, there is a lot of imagery. It’s, of course, <em>based</em> on the Backrooms. And the pool rooms <em>are</em> a level known in the liminal maze. Some may also know it as Sublimity (you also get a glimpse of the actual Backrooms in POOLS, along with some other pieces of levels dreamed up by the fandom, such as Eternal Suburbia). The developers though, they only say it’s <em>based</em> on the Backrooms, and I think I understand why we’re making that distinction here. Because it <em>is</em> the backrooms, but it’s also something else.</p>

<p>It’s a work of art.</p>

<p>It’s purgatory.</p>

<p><img src="/img/posts/pools2/4.png" alt="image of a hallway that doesn't look at all unlike the actual backrooms" /></p>

<p>It’s an allegory for abuse, and the victim of that abuse <em>fighting to escape it</em>, and <em>failing</em>. Fighting in isolation, and trauma, reminded at every turn what they did to you, and when there’s a light at the end of the tunnel and you think you’re finally out of the never-ending spiral, <em>it goes out</em> and disappears. And then the darkness pulls you back in.</p>

<p>Where does this inkling come from, though? Some have already said that they believe this to be an allegory for such things. That this <em>has</em> to be about abuse, or <em>something</em>. I think someone even mentioned they thought it was about CSA, due to some depictions of a child’s drawings on the walls, big black letters scrawled across a picture that reads, “NOTHING,” a single lonely house that appears to you toward the end, and then endless copies of it, and the appearance of very large mannequins screaming, viewing other mannequins in compromising, embarrassing positions, pointing, staring, mouth-agape in horror.</p>

<p><img src="/img/posts/pools2/3.png" alt="a mannequin sitting on a toilet holding its head in shame in a white tiled environment while another stands upon a balcony overhead and stares" /></p>

<p>Whatever <em>type</em> of abuse it is, I think this game is definitely telling a story, whether real or fiction, and it’s all right in front of you the whole time.</p>

<p>The innocent rubber ducks sitting around in the water that are somehow <em>terrifying</em>. The pool slides that seem to be in random places that beg to be jumped into, as absurd as that is, while you’re lost in a horrifying complex.</p>

<p>The mixture of innocence, and despair.</p>

<p>Of lightheartedness, and terror.</p>

<p><img src="/img/posts/pools2/5.png" alt="image of a lonely house in a room with painted skies and clouds, and a slide attached to its side paneling" /></p>

<p>POOLS takes something that really has no meaning, other than to terrify, and turns it into something that has … a very <em>deep</em> message. Something you have to decode <em>yourself</em>, or not. It’s entirely up to the player, I think. And that’s one more thing that just makes this game <em>so good</em>.</p>

<p>I could be <em>entirely wrong</em>, though, and this could be one of many ways to interpret the game. And that’s okay. Because POOLS isn’t <em>just</em> a game, it’s a work of art, and it asks that you experience it. Nothing more.</p>]]></content><author><name>𐕣 C M D R ░ NOVA 𐕣</name></author><category term="Gaming" /><category term="gaming" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">NaNoWriMo Weaponizes Social Justice Language in Endorsement of AI</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/tech/2024/09/02/nanowrimo-weaponizes-social-justice-language-in-endorsement-of-ai.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="NaNoWriMo Weaponizes Social Justice Language in Endorsement of AI" /><published>2024-09-02T11:32:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-09-02T11:32:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/tech/2024/09/02/nanowrimo-weaponizes-social-justice-language-in-endorsement-of-ai</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/tech/2024/09/02/nanowrimo-weaponizes-social-justice-language-in-endorsement-of-ai.html"><![CDATA[<p>It’s the second day of my little tiny vacation, and I’ve woken up at the bright and early hour of 11 in the morning. I log onto social media to check my notifications and see what’s happening, and … I’m immediately alerted that those behind NaNoWriMo (National Novel Writing Month) <a href="https://nanowrimo.zendesk.com/hc/en-us/articles/29933455931412-What-is-NaNoWriMo-s-position-on-Artificial-Intelligence-AI?ref=404media.co" target="_blank">have endorsed using theft-machines (AI) to generate books and stories</a>, while weaponizing social justice language in order to emotionally manipulate their readers and writers.</p>

<p>404 Media wrote a fairly neutral article on the matter that doesn’t appear to take any position whatsoever, but I’m <a href="https://www.404media.co/nanowrimo-ai-policy-classist-ableist/" target="_blank">linking them here</a> anyway, in order to contextualize <em>who</em> NaNoWriMo was, and is.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>NaNoWriMo started as a group writing project in the ‘90s with the goal of writing a 50,000-word manuscript in one month (November), but in 2005, NaNoWriMo became a nonprofit organization that takes donations and runs fundraising campaigns.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>But, let’s now take a look at their reasoning, and then tear those reasons to shreds. I’ll be calling NaNoWriMo “NNW” from here on out in this post, just because it’s easier to type than an abbreviation with annoying capitalization.</p>

<p>NNW says that condemning AI in writing is classist:</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>Not all writers have the financial ability to hire humans to help at certain phases of their writing. For some writers, the decision to use AI is a practical, not an ideological, one. The financial ability to engage a human for feedback and review assumes a level of privilege that not all community members possess.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>It’s true that, as writers and authors who don’t have access to thousands of dollars, <em>it can be</em> a hard time getting outside opinions and help on your writing. But, here’s the thing: You can still write a story, or a novel, without using machines that rip off <em>other authors</em> in order to edit and proofread (if you can call feeding your work into an LLM “editing” and “proofreading”). As an independent author, myself, I have <em>friends</em>, and sometimes I’ll conscript them to give me some opinions on what I’ve written. I also <em>extensively</em> comb over my writing (now, at least) when I’m putting a book together. Hence the reason it’s been taking me well over a year to make progress on my next book, Dissolution Protocol. I want to make something <em>really good</em>.</p>

<p>And it takes a lot of practice, and time, to become effective at spotting errors and issues in your own writing.</p>

<p>But here’s the thing: That’s fine! What’s the rush? The act of creating art is and always has been a slow-burn process of practicing, learning, and both failure and success. There’s nothing wrong with that! That’s how art <em>is</em>! And introducing AI into the matter <em>cuts that out completely</em>. <em>All of it</em>.</p>

<p>And that’s not to mention all of the other resources available to independent writers and authors. Join a discussion forum of writers and readers! Post snippets! There are so many online avenues you can use to find help with your writing that <em>don’t cost you a dime</em>, and you don’t have to rip off anyone in order to utilize them.</p>

<p>NNW also says that condemning AI in writing is ableist:</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>Not all brains have same abilities and not all writers function at the same level of education or proficiency in the language in which they are writing. Some brains and ability levels require outside help or accommodations to achieve certain goals. The notion that all writers “should“ be able to perform certain functions independently or is a position that we disagree with wholeheartedly. There is a wealth of reasons why individuals can’t “see” the issues in their writing without help.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>In my opinion, this is the part where they get <em>real manipulative</em>, because now we’re using disabled people as our reason for saying it’s totally fine to use these planet-destroying bots to write <em>for you</em> (LLMs are more and more increasingly power hungry, so much so that Microsoft is considering building nuclear reactors to power them, and many current LLMs are burning <em>tons and tons</em> of fossil fuels in order to operate).</p>

<p>Yes, people sometimes need outside accommodations for reading and writing, like <em>screen readers</em>, and special keyboards, and, as I mentioned in my thoughts above, <em>community forums</em> where readers and writers collaborate together to troubleshoot their own work. Saying, “not all brains have the same abilities” in your endorsement of these machines is exactly how a psychopath would attempt to convince you that cutting off your own hand is beneficial to you, <em>somehow</em>.</p>

<p>Now, to be fair, this is what they actually say right at the start of their post on Zendesk:</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>NaNoWriMo does not explicitly support any specific approach to writing, nor does it explicitly condemn any approach, including the use of AI.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>or, “We don’t explicitly support any specific approach to writing, and we don’t condemn any approach, such as AI, but also, here’s why we fully endorse using AI.”</p>

<p>I’m gonna be real with you, chief. I <em>have</em> used text-based AI. I’ve used it like Google to see if it could answer questions <em>better</em> and <em>faster</em> than a Google search would. Because, despite my grievances with most LLMs, and especially the image-generation machines that are completely and entirely based on theft and disenfranchisement, I don’t think these things are going anywhere. I think there are <em>some</em> limited uses for text-based AI. Like, you could open up, let’s say, ChatGPT and say, “Hey, what are some writing prompts that might be interesting?” or, “What are some resources I could use to get outside opinions and help on my writing?”</p>

<p>And sometimes, you do actually get decent answers. <em>I just wouldn’t trust whatever the hell Google’s developing.</em></p>

<p>Now, let’s take a look at their continued opinions in regard to general access issues:</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>All of these considerations exist within a larger system in which writers don’t always have equal access to resources along the chain. For example, underrepresented minorities are less likely to be offered traditional publishing contracts, which places some, by default, into the indie author space, which inequitably creates upfront cost burdens that authors who do not suffer from systemic discrimination may have to incur.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>So, we’re continuing to emotionally manipulate people by, instead of using disabled people this time, we’re going to use marginalized people, such as the LGBTQ+ community.</p>

<p>Yes, yes, finding an agent is hard. Getting a contract is <em>even harder</em>. In the years I’ve been writing fiction (since 2008), I’ve rebuffed the idea <em>completely</em>. <em>Especially</em> after, more recently, seeing <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/byebyejob/comments/1do4w0x/literary_agent_rejects_query_and_asks_someone/" target="_blank">examples of literary agents</a> openly suggesting <em>stealing</em> an author’s query for themselves.</p>

<p>The world is a vampire. A pimple-infested, gout infected, disease ridden, <em>vampire</em>.</p>

<p>But, with this further explanation of their stance, NNW speaks as though being an “indie author” is <em>not desirable</em>, that it’s lesser, and I couldn’t disagree <em>more</em>.</p>

<p>Since I started writing, those who <em>do</em> have contracts, and who <em>do</em> have agents, have always taken to social media to speak like the privileged snobs some of them are. Saying that community-sourced editing and proofreading from authors who take to publishing <em>themselves</em> through avenues like <a href="https://www.smashwords.com/" target="_blank">Smashwords</a>, <em>aren’t as good</em>, or are “lazy.” That you <em>shouldn’t</em> pay any attention to an author’s work, if it isn’t coming out of one of the big six.</p>

<p>And, sadly, authors utilizing AI to write books <em>for them</em> are only going to make independent publishing <em>that much harder</em>, because the optics around self publishing <em>were already</em> dark, and muddy, partially <em>because</em> of the gate-keeper jerks who speak like this.</p>

<p>You can be an independent author, and you can write a <em>decent</em> story, <em>without</em> using machines that not only <em>steal</em> from other writers, but <em>will absolutely</em> vacuum up the work you feed into it, in order to further compound this problem. And I’m going to say that again, so that it’s clear, <em>you should not</em> feed your work into an LLM (an AI), unless you want it <em>stolen</em> from you.</p>

<p>I can only imagine that the reason NNW has taken this stance, is because they <em>must</em> have suddenly received funding from some kind of Silicon Valley venture capital, right?</p>

<p>Right?</p>

<p>Anyway, those are the most important points I wanted to touch on in light of these, frankly, <em>idiotic</em> takes coming from NNW. If you’re going to endorse AI, you can <em>at least</em> do it without speaking to writers and readers like Hannibal-fucking-Lector, manipulating them into sitting down at the dinner table and prepping <em>their own brain</em> for consumption.</p>

<p><strong><em>Update</em></strong>: And here you have it, <a href="https://pivot-to-ai.com/2024/09/02/nanowrimo-gets-ai-sponsor-says-not-writing-your-novel-with-ai-is-classist-and-ableist/" target="_blank">NaNoWriMo is sponsored by a company</a> that utilizes AI.</p>]]></content><author><name>𐕣 C M D R ░ NOVA 𐕣</name></author><category term="Tech" /><category term="tech" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[It’s the second day of my little tiny vacation, and I’ve woken up at the bright and early hour of 11 in the morning. I log onto social media to check my notifications and see what’s happening, and … I’m immediately alerted that those behind NaNoWriMo (National Novel Writing Month) have endorsed using theft-machines (AI) to generate books and stories, while weaponizing social justice language in order to emotionally manipulate their readers and writers.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Embrace, Extend, Extinguish (Repeat)</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/social%20media/2024/09/02/embrace-extend-extinguish-repeat.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Embrace, Extend, Extinguish (Repeat)" /><published>2024-09-02T01:09:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-09-02T01:09:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/social%20media/2024/09/02/embrace-extend-extinguish-repeat</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/social%20media/2024/09/02/embrace-extend-extinguish-repeat.html"><![CDATA[<p>I’ve written on here before about Threads and how:</p>

<ul>
  <li>I think it’s totally fine for people to join if they’re too bamboozled by the process of a picking an instance on Mastodon, or some other piece of ActivityPub software (even though I still can’t really fathom just exactly <em>how</em> it seems hard to some).</li>
  <li>The southern division of public policy has a Project 2025 author on its team, and Meta has yet to even remotely acknowledge this to the public. Just exactly how <em>much</em> influence this living turd has on Threads is questionable. For all I know it could <em>only</em> be Facebook (judging by the way Facebook looks nowadays).</li>
  <li>It’s algorithm is like a drunk person having mood swings, in that, if you even so much as slightly interact with a topic, that’s the only thing you see for the entire next day.</li>
  <li>And that there are groups of instances on the Fediverse extremely dedicated to not only blocking federation from Threads themselves, but essentially utilizing peer pressure as a weapon in order to get others to do so, as well.</li>
</ul>

<p>On that last point, though, I’ve spoken about the little “black list” built by veganism.social that basically lists every federated server they can see, and whether or not they’re blocking Threads (again, peer pressure, and I wish people would stop acting like we’re all mentally still in high school). I find things like this distasteful. Have your opinion, your feelings, and what you think is right, and <em>stop forcing it onto other people</em>, unless of course we’re talking discrimination, hate crimes, or what-have-you … I mean, <em>obviously</em>, you should make sure people know those things are bad.</p>

<p>But Threads?</p>

<p>Right now I’m seeing it as kind of a gray area.</p>

<p>There are people on there I haven’t seen in years, that I was originally following on Twitter. Tons of LGBTQ+ people, and other people I wouldn’t ever call “bad”. And then, you know, the trolls, weirdos, and one-off accounts, and oh yeah, also, the spam accounts intentionally setup to grift engagement.</p>

<p>That’s not what I’m writing this post about, today, though.</p>

<p>Today it’s about the ethos of “embrace, extend, extinguish” that all started with <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/linux/comments/1eykup/google_abandons_open_standards_for_instant/" target="_blank">Google and XMPP</a>. Basically, Google integrated its instant messaging protocol with XMPP, and then decided, like they do with every project that isn’t an immediate groundbreaking successful <em>thing</em>, and backed out. The problem with this, is that Google’s integration was highly anticipated, and this drew a lot <em>more</em> people to XMPP, and then this also essentially “killed it.” I don’t really know if you can say it’s <em>dead</em>, though, because I literally can see people linking to their own usernames for XMPP on their Mastodon profiles, right now, as I’m typing this.</p>

<p>The fear revolving around Threads and federation with ActivityPub, is … uhm, that people might get <em>too excited</em> about this, and everyone might federate with Threads, and then Threads might pull out and <em>extinguish</em> interest in ActivityPub. That, and Meta isn’t so great at moderating Threads. But … I don’t really see how that’s a problem for Mastodon, when as admins and moderators, you can manually silence bad accounts, and <em>you should</em>, regardless of where they’re coming from. An interesting thing I’ve seen on <a href="https://app.wafrn.net" target="_blank">Wafrn</a>, though, is that the federated Tumblr alternative makes federating with Threads an account-level, opt-in, and I think that’s actually <em>really genius</em>. The decision should <em>absolutely</em> be in the hands of the user.</p>

<p>But I have some opinions on XMPP and its eventual perceived crash, and whether Meta is copy/pasting what Google did here.</p>

<p>First of all, as much as I <em>loved</em> Aol Instant Messenger, and instant messaging in the nineties … it’s dead, guys. I don’t know about you, or anyone else, but I can <em>hardly</em> find enough interest in Discord and my Steam friends list to keep up with them enough to actively talk to people for long periods of time. I … kind of just use social media for that. You know, that thing that started with Myspace and only became bigger until it ruled our entire lives?</p>

<p>Nowadays, I kind of don’t really like anyone outside of my family having immediate access to me. I’m reclusive, and I’m battling things in my head that make it hard for me to break out of my own shell, and you think I’m going to go out of my way to actively talk to a bunch of people <em>instantly</em> and <em>all of the time</em>.</p>

<p>Nuh uh.</p>

<p>You see, I mean, <em>sure</em>, Google deciding to graveyard federation with XMPP <em>likely</em> harmed it, even if just a little bit. But I think the overarching problem here is just that, instant messaging isn’t really <em>the thing</em> nowadays, and I think it’s always kind of been on the way out.</p>

<p>Social media, micro-blogging, you think that’d go away on the fediverse on the off-chance that Meta kills Threads, or pulls out of ActivityPub?</p>

<p>AP’s been around since the early 2000s, and yeah, sure, it has this reputation of being a Linux-user’s heaven, and full of dudes who hate people who make things (like music, art, etc), but I don’t think it’s <em>ever</em> going anywhere. At this point, Twitter is <em>basically</em> the only major platform that isn’t federated, or touting decentralization, and <em>it’s dying</em>.</p>

<p>But even in the off-chance that Meta does a select-all and delete on its ActivityPub integration, I think apps like Mastodon would definitely still be standing. Because, as of writing this, plenty of people <em>aren’t even federating</em> with Threads, and most of the people I see and interact with on the fediverse value a user-owned social network more than anything else on the web. Whether Threads is there or not, for many, is purely inconsequential in the grander scheme of things. And a lot of users on <em>Threads</em> don’t even know what the hell Mastodon even <em>is</em>.</p>

<center>
<blockquote class="text-post-media" data-text-post-permalink="https://www.threads.net/@thebrianpenny/post/C_XR5WWxEoj" data-text-post-version="0" id="ig-tp-C_XR5WWxEoj" style=" background:#FFF; border-width: 1px; border-style: solid; border-color: #00000026; border-radius: 16px; max-width:540px; margin: 1px; min-width:270px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);"> <a href="https://www.threads.net/@thebrianpenny/post/C_XR5WWxEoj" style=" background:#FFFFFF; line-height:0; padding:0 0; text-align:center; text-decoration:none; width:100%; font-family: -apple-system, BlinkMacSystemFont, sans-serif;" target="_blank"> <div style=" padding: 40px; display: flex; flex-direction: column; align-items: center;"><div style=" display:block; height:32px; width:32px; padding-bottom:20px;"> <svg aria-label="Threads" height="32px" role="img" viewBox="0 0 192 192" width="32px" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg"> <path d="M141.537 88.9883C140.71 88.5919 139.87 88.2104 139.019 87.8451C137.537 60.5382 122.616 44.905 97.5619 44.745C97.4484 44.7443 97.3355 44.7443 97.222 44.7443C82.2364 44.7443 69.7731 51.1409 62.102 62.7807L75.881 72.2328C81.6116 63.5383 90.6052 61.6848 97.2286 61.6848C97.3051 61.6848 97.3819 61.6848 97.4576 61.6855C105.707 61.7381 111.932 64.1366 115.961 68.814C118.893 72.2193 120.854 76.925 121.825 82.8638C114.511 81.6207 106.601 81.2385 98.145 81.7233C74.3247 83.0954 59.0111 96.9879 60.0396 116.292C60.5615 126.084 65.4397 134.508 73.775 140.011C80.8224 144.663 89.899 146.938 99.3323 146.423C111.79 145.74 121.563 140.987 128.381 132.296C133.559 125.696 136.834 117.143 138.28 106.366C144.217 109.949 148.617 114.664 151.047 120.332C155.179 129.967 155.42 145.8 142.501 158.708C131.182 170.016 117.576 174.908 97.0135 175.059C74.2042 174.89 56.9538 167.575 45.7381 153.317C35.2355 139.966 29.8077 120.682 29.6052 96C29.8077 71.3178 35.2355 52.0336 45.7381 38.6827C56.9538 24.4249 74.2039 17.11 97.0132 16.9405C119.988 17.1113 137.539 24.4614 149.184 38.788C154.894 45.8136 159.199 54.6488 162.037 64.9503L178.184 60.6422C174.744 47.9622 169.331 37.0357 161.965 27.974C147.036 9.60668 125.202 0.195148 97.0695 0H96.9569C68.8816 0.19447 47.2921 9.6418 32.7883 28.0793C19.8819 44.4864 13.2244 67.3157 13.0007 95.9325L13 96L13.0007 96.0675C13.2244 124.684 19.8819 147.514 32.7883 163.921C47.2921 182.358 68.8816 191.806 96.9569 192H97.0695C122.03 191.827 139.624 185.292 154.118 170.811C173.081 151.866 172.51 128.119 166.26 113.541C161.776 103.087 153.227 94.5962 141.537 88.9883ZM98.4405 129.507C88.0005 130.095 77.1544 125.409 76.6196 115.372C76.2232 107.93 81.9158 99.626 99.0812 98.6368C101.047 98.5234 102.976 98.468 104.871 98.468C111.106 98.468 116.939 99.0737 122.242 100.233C120.264 124.935 108.662 128.946 98.4405 129.507Z" /></svg></div> <div style=" font-size: 15px; line-height: 21px; color: #999999; font-weight: 400; padding-bottom: 4px; "> Post by @thebrianpenny</div> <div style=" font-size: 15px; line-height: 21px; color: #000000; font-weight: 600; "> View on Threads</div></div></a></blockquote>
<script async="" src="https://www.threads.net/embed.js"></script>
</center>

<p>I don’t think I have to, but I just want to point out real quick that Mastodon is not a company, and ActivityPub, or, “the fediverse”, as stated before, has existed for decades. That the Bluesky devs suddenly, just two days ago, decided to call the network of keys accessing their servers “the atmosphere” is more or less just another way I feel they’re kind of cherry-picking ideas from a concept that has existed well before they decided they wanted to be Twitter 2.0.</p>

<center>
<blockquote class="bluesky-embed" data-bluesky-uri="at://did:plc:ragtjsm2j2vknwkz3zp4oxrd/app.bsky.feed.post/3l32kiopoay2c" data-bluesky-cid="bafyreiagl2qikdnqra37nsgey7n37hv7vcele6ifmlylgtkp2f2ql5d3me"><p lang="en">We talk about Bluesky getting users, but Bluesky is part of an open social internet called &quot;The Atmosphere&quot; where other people can make their own apps, including their own versions of Bluesky.

Bluesky isn&#x27;t growing; the Atmosphere is! You&#x27;re not &quot;our&quot; users; you&#x27;re a part of a shared place.</p>&mdash; Paul Frazee (<a href="https://bsky.app/profile/did:plc:ragtjsm2j2vknwkz3zp4oxrd?ref_src=embed">@pfrazee.com</a>) <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/did:plc:ragtjsm2j2vknwkz3zp4oxrd/post/3l32kiopoay2c?ref_src=embed">Aug 31, 2024 at 8:43 PM</a></blockquote><script async="" src="https://embed.bsky.app/static/embed.js" charset="utf-8"></script>
</center>

<p>But anyway .. embrace, extend, extinguish, or just fear-mongering, with some legit concerns about corporations, and their goals?</p>

<p>You decide, I suppose.</p>

<p>A lot of what I say about some of these networks might sound negative, or pessimistic, but I really do actually enjoy watching it all shift back and forth. I <em>like</em> that the internet is having a power-struggle to figure out <em>where</em> the “place to be” is now. Because none of them will win. The “place to be” is wherever you <em>want</em>, and it should’ve never been <em>just one</em> website, like I sad in my “blog day” post.</p>]]></content><author><name>𐕣 C M D R ░ NOVA 𐕣</name></author><category term="Social Media" /><category term="social-media" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[I’ve written on here before about Threads and how:]]></summary></entry></feed>