<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/feed-stylesheet.xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>cmdr-nova@internet:~$</title>
    <link>http://localhost:4000</link>
    <description>NOVA PRIME</description>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ten Months Without Windows</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4000/linux/2024/11/11/ten-months-without-windows.html</link>
      <description>I’m sitting here a little more tired than I’d like to be, but that’s the life of working a manual labor day job, and code-jacking at night (what the hell is code-jacking). Today I want to sort of look back over the past year, and reflect on what it’s been like to mostly abandon Windows (with a slight hiccup of returning for a week).

</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Nov 2024 21:16:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>/linux/2024/11/11/ten-months-without-windows</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bluesky Is Growing On Me</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4000/social%20media/2024/11/10/bluesky-is-growing-on-me.html</link>
      <description>I’ve had some criticisms of Bluesky, ever since it opened. Albeit, I had some bad experiences with some users who seem to have also been chased off of the platform for the way they treat others. But, I also have been skeptical about its mode of decentralization (where is it?), and them being VC backed, and recently funded by a crypto company. But, things are changing …

</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Nov 2024 19:46:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>/social%20media/2024/11/10/bluesky-is-growing-on-me</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Shorts Available At [REVOSA]</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4000/second%20life/2024/11/09/new-shorts-available-at-revosa.html</link>
      <description>It’s becoming kind of a trend, that I make something in my Second Life store, and then drop the whole thing for two to three months while I work on a million other things. Despite all of that, today I decided to put together another pair of shorts for the set I’ve been putting together for … a while. Today, it’s juicy green shorts!

</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Nov 2024 14:50:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>/second%20life/2024/11/09/new-shorts-available-at-revosa</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Making Things and Sipping Juice</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4000/programming/2024/11/09/making-things-and-sipping-juice.html</link>
      <description>The day’s coming to an end (okay, actually, it’s like 12:30 at night, it’s been over), and I’ve done a lot. In my last post I talked about spending all of my free time over the course of 24 hours making a function that pushes my blog posts to Mastodon. Well, after all of that, I went to bed, woke up, and started on something new …

</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Nov 2024 00:29:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>/programming/2024/11/09/making-things-and-sipping-juice</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jekyll Blog, Post to Mastodon</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4000/programming/2024/11/07/jekyll-blog-post-to-mastodon.html</link>
      <description>It’s been a hell of a time! Earlier in the week, I suddenly had an issue where I broke my RSS feed bot that posted new feed items from my blog to my Mastodon account. I described this in my last post, but it was entirely because I … edited the XML. So! I spent the last entire day rebuilding a brand new way to do this. By turning VS Code’s “commit” button into a “Post to Mastodon” button. Let me explain.

</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2024 22:28:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>/programming/2024/11/07/jekyll-blog-post-to-mastodon</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Today I Dropped An Atom Bomb of Posts Onto Mastodon</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4000/social%20media/2024/11/05/today-i-dropped-an-atom-bomb-of-posts-onto-mastodon.html</link>
      <description>Today I turned off my GitHub pages mirror of this site, and in doing so, I had to create my own XML feed with its own styling and all. Which … I accomplished, pretty easily! But then my bot that’s supposed to read my feed, and append old items to a file, and only post brand new items, exploded onto Mastodon three times with everything I’ve ever posted on here.

</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2024 14:14:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>/social%20media/2024/11/05/today-i-dropped-an-atom-bomb-of-posts-onto-mastodon</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CORS Light, The Drink of the API</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4000/programming/2024/11/05/cors-light-the-drink-of-the-api.html</link>
      <description>I’m a little bit delirious. Last night I fell asleep on my couch the entire night, and then woke up at 6am to my cat begging for food, and then I stayed up, and went to work. I got home, and yes, instead of watching the new Deadpool, I switch on the code machine and thought, “Why am I routing the Tumblr API through a github secret only to get static results that don’t update unless I push changes to my site? The heck?” And I thought, “What if I just use a proxy server on my VPS that the JavaScript accesses to give a fresh perspective every time someone refreshes my site?” Boy … oh boy.

</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2024 00:59:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>/programming/2024/11/05/cors-light-the-drink-of-the-api</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Work, Sleep, Code, Repeat</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4000/programming/2024/11/04/work-sleep-code-repeat.html</link>
      <description>So, like you do, I got home from work, and immediately dove back into the code machine, i.e., my monstrous PC that I primarily use for writing website stuff, or python scripts, and sometimes playing Dragon Age and Baldur’s Gate.

</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2024 00:09:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>/programming/2024/11/04/work-sleep-code-repeat</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Playing With JavaScript</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4000/programming/2024/11/02/inplaying-with-javascript.html</link>
      <description>Today I got off of work, sat down on my couch, and promptly passed the heck out. Then, I woke up, and ate an italian sub. This was just enough fuel for me to load up VS Code and get back to messing with my website. As you can probably see, if you’re reading this from the page itself, I’ve made some … upgrades.

</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Nov 2024 20:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/programming/2024/11/02/inplaying-with-javascript</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Initial Impressions on Dragon Age: The Veilguard</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4000/gaming/2024/10/31/initial-impressions-on-dragon-age-the-veilguard.html</link>
      <description>It’s been a little while since I’ve written down my impressions of a game. It’s been a little never that I’ve ever written down my initial impressions of a BioWare game. Thinking back, I think the last one that I played all the way through was Andromeda. Which was a good game, despite the meandering open world that took away from the experience. But, now we’re back, with the conclusion (maybe?) of the Inquisition timeline, and everything is purple, and very shiny. These are my thoughts …

</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2024 21:08:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/gaming/2024/10/31/initial-impressions-on-dragon-age-the-veilguard</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Dredge, Again? Rebuilding, Once More</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4000/second%20life/2024/10/29/the-dredge-again-rebuilding-once-more.html</link>
      <description>In the few hours I have to myself tonight, I’d like to update interested peoples and parties on what’s happening with things I’m building in Second Life. As most know, I shut down my city/the homestead a few months back. It’s really hard to justify spending 110+ USD a month on something that’s not making me any returns, and people really only visited on and off in short bursts. No fault of their own, I just mostly always lack the energy for reaching out and building community. But, my Second Life journey is also kind of empty and hollow without owning a piece of land, with things that I’ve built, so …

</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2024 22:22:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/second%20life/2024/10/29/the-dredge-again-rebuilding-once-more</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Guild Wars 2, I&#39;ve Returned!</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4000/gaming/2024/10/28/guild-wars-2-i-ve-returned.html</link>
      <description>It’s been years since I’ve seriously played Guild Wars 2 in a way that constitutes actually completing content, and leveling up. In fact, I haven’t really played it much since the years that I spent outside of the traditional work-force. And that was back around Path of Fire, and now there’s at least three expansions I’ve missed, and need to catch up on. So I logged the heck on.

</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Oct 2024 20:58:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/gaming/2024/10/28/guild-wars-2-i-ve-returned</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Black Ops Zombies: Oh, You Wanted Rewards?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4000/gaming/2024/10/27/black-ops-zombies-oh-you-wanted-rewards.html</link>
      <description>Woohoo! A new Black Ops is out! You know what that means: It’s time to go hunting zombies. Endlessly. Forever. Without pause. No extraction. Keep fighting. Run out of ammo. Die. This is, at least, my experience, in every Black Ops since number two.

</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Oct 2024 20:50:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/gaming/2024/10/27/black-ops-zombies-oh-you-wanted-rewards</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Website, I Command You, Be Responsive!</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4000/programming/2024/10/26/website-i-command-you-be-responsive.html</link>
      <description>Today, I got home from work, and for once wasn’t feeling too tired to even type on my keyboard. So, I logged into Second Life and acquired some land, and noticed I could hold a little more. I shot off a ticket to Linden Labs and asked for some more space, because … I’d like to build things. While I sat waiting for a response to this ticket (which I’m still waiting on) I did what any normal person would do. I fully redesigned the way my website responds to different screens.

</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Oct 2024 22:05:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/programming/2024/10/26/website-i-command-you-be-responsive</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Call of Duty, On Linux?!</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4000/linux/2024/10/24/call-of-duty-on-linux.html</link>
      <description>As some may know, I play Call of Duty sometimes. One of the reasons I briefly switched back to Windows, is because I wanted to do so, and couldn’t on Pop!_OS, despite having purchased pretty much every version of CoD since the original Black Ops 2. But, I ultimately decided that being able to play CoD wasn’t worth the trade-off of … using Windows. That was, until I realized I could play Modern Warfare III, and, presumably, Black Ops 6, on GeForce now. There is … an issue, though.

</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 21:50:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/linux/2024/10/24/call-of-duty-on-linux</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Destroy All Webp Images</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4000/programming/2024/10/24/destroy-all-webp-images.html</link>
      <description>I started learning Python, because I wanted to solve problems, and maybe eventually make a Python game. I haven’t made it to being able to do the latter all that well yet, and maybe sometime here in the near future, we’ll get there. But today, I’m solving a big problem. A problem brought on by Google/Reddit. Or, I should say, I’m destroying all .webp images, once and for all.

</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 06:08:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/programming/2024/10/24/destroy-all-webp-images</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Share Your Wallpaper!</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4000/thoughts/2024/10/23/share-your-wallpaper.html</link>
      <description>I’ve been sitting here listening to Spotify most of the evening, browsing the social fediverse, and kind of thinking about things to write on this blog. Mostly because, I want to keep writing something almost every single day. You know, personal goals and such. And then I remembered old-school forum banter, and forums in-general. I’m currently a member of a few, but I rarely ever post. I guess new age social media has kind of taken my attention away from such things, unfortunately, but do you remember things like, sharing your wallpapers on a weekly basis? People just snapping photos of their desktops and being like, “Check it out dude.” Peppridge Farm remembers.

</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 22:59:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/thoughts/2024/10/23/share-your-wallpaper</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Boo! Revisiting Horrifying Dating Apps</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4000/thoughts/2024/10/21/boo-revisiting-horrifying-dating-apps.html</link>
      <description>Earlier in the year I wrote about the terrible situation that is dating in the post-2020 world. Everything’s a swiper, everyone’s making decisions based on appearances, and nothing else. Most of the accounts on these apps are like, 2% real people, and 98% bots, Instagram account spammers, scammers waiting for you in a motel with a baseball bat and some dude, and couples looking for a unicorn. It’s dire out there, brosefinas.

</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2024 22:01:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/thoughts/2024/10/21/boo-revisiting-horrifying-dating-apps</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using My Time Wisely</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4000/programming/2024/10/20/using-my-time-wisely.html</link>
      <description>So, work has been a pain in the ass lately. And by that, I mean, my offline job. At times, especially the past week, I’ve had a real hard time justifying even getting out of bed in the morning. But, I got out of work last night around 9pm, and I was exploring feed readers, because reading feeds is coming back (via enshitification of everything else). But I didn’t like how most readers are trying to sell monthly subscriptions for features like, being able to make a folder, and storing feeds in them. And then I thought, “I’ll make one.”

</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Oct 2024 18:50:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/programming/2024/10/20/using-my-time-wisely</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Python, Deliver Us the Blue Hellsite</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4000/programming/2024/10/18/python-deliver-us-the-blue-hellsite.html</link>
      <description>Have you ever thought to yourself, “Self, I wish there was more Tumblr on Mastodon?” Well, do I have some freakin’ news for you. In my sickness addled brain, I have slapped together something that will tickle your pickle, or fancy. With a few lines (100 or so) of Python, we can force the Tumblr API to give us whatever it thinks is the top trending image post of the day, and slap that thing onto ActivityPub. Matt might be trying to bury Wordpress in a shallow grave, but maybe we can pretend that Tumblr has ActivityPub integration with some hacks.

</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Oct 2024 19:51:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/programming/2024/10/18/python-deliver-us-the-blue-hellsite</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Pains of Bronchitis? The Flu? Whichever</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4000/thoughts/2024/10/18/the-pains-of-bronchitis-the-flu-whichever.html</link>
      <description>So, much to the dismay of boss/es at the offline job, I’m taking off work today, because going to work feeling every ache and pain in my bones and muscles as this bronchitis, or the flu, ravages my immune system without rest, is just too freakin much. I get fed lines like, “I come to work no matter what unless I’m literally dying.” And, I mean, I guess, hats-off to those of you who wish to die on the job, or collapse in a lesser sense. But that isn’t me.

</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Oct 2024 12:46:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/thoughts/2024/10/18/the-pains-of-bronchitis-the-flu-whichever</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Heavy Metal F.A.K.K.2, Comin&#39; At You?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4000/gaming/2024/10/17/heavy-metal-f-a-k-k-2-comin-at-you.html</link>
      <description>While I’m on this kick of looking back over the years at old games that are still mega-popular, I also want to look at games that maybe nobody remembers, or even knows about. No, I’m not talking about Daikatana. That game is pretty cool, and I’m pretty sure it’s also very well known. I’m talking about Julie and Heavy Metal F.A.K.K.2, a game that came, then said, “Hey!” and subsequently vanished into the ether of game development … seemingly, forever.

</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2024 19:24:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/gaming/2024/10/17/heavy-metal-f-a-k-k-2-comin-at-you</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ExTube: The YouTube Destroyer!</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4000/programming/2024/10/15/extube-the-youtube-destroyer.html</link>
      <description>You remember how Google decided that they were going to disable ad-blockers in their browser, and also make ads on YouTube more intrusive, and more frequent? Well, while I understand there is probably a wealth of YouTube video downloaders out there, I made my own. It runs on Python, it’s just one executable file, and it’s freakin’ sweet looking, bro.

</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2024 18:07:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/programming/2024/10/15/extube-the-youtube-destroyer</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I Can&#39;t Recommend Nekoweb, A Neocities Alternative</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4000/tech/2024/10/15/i-can-t-recommend-nekoweb-a-neocities-alternative.html</link>
      <description>Today I woke up, and, like I do, I checked my “daily report” bot e-mail, and noticed something … strange. According to the Neocities subreddit, the person behind Neocities had written, a year ago, some positive thinking about AI (which, I’m not sure can be fully judged a year later, since it’s only gotten extremely bad, this year). In response, some users were suggesting Nekoweb as an alternative for people who don’t want to be potentially affiliated with someone who endorses Sam Altman. And then I stumbled into an issue, and the strangest people I’ve met this week (so far).

</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2024 07:38:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/tech/2024/10/15/i-can-t-recommend-nekoweb-a-neocities-alternative</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>31 Years Later, Let&#39;s Look At Doom&#39;s Lore (The Original)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4000/gaming/2024/10/13/31-years-later-let-s-look-at-doom-s-lore-the-original.html</link>
      <description>Yesterday, I wrote about Quake and, by extension, Quake 2’s lore. You might think that Doom’s original lore is probably really simple, some kind of, scratches on a paper looking concept, and while it certainly began that way–It also spawned a book. But, one of the reasons I want to visit the lore of the original Dooms, is because the newer Dooms seem … unclear to me, as to where exactly they are in the timeline. Or, if there even is a timeline. Anyway, let’s dive a little deeper into the 1993 classic, DOOM.

</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Oct 2024 22:32:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/gaming/2024/10/13/31-years-later-let-s-look-at-doom-s-lore-the-original</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>28 Years Later, Let&#39;s Look At Quake&#39;s Lore</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4000/gaming/2024/10/13/28-years-later-let-s-look-at-quake-s-lore.html</link>
      <description>So, today, I was playing Quake 1 and 2, and something ocurred to me, that hadn’t ever ocurred to me in the 28 to 30 years that these games have been a thing: I’ve never fully understood what in the hell the story is supposed to be. Obviously, we’re going to skip Quake 3, not because it isn’t good (it’s one of the greatest arena shooters of all time), but because its story is more that of Unreal Tournament. In that, it’s just people from different dimensions fighting in nonstop deathmatch.

</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Oct 2024 16:08:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/gaming/2024/10/13/28-years-later-let-s-look-at-quake-s-lore</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Whoops, Now I&#39;m Sick</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4000/thoughts/2024/10/12/whoops-now-i-m-sick.html</link>
      <description>It’s not every week, or even every month that I have off three days in a row from my offline job. It’s a chance to catch up on projects I’ve been slacking on due to lack of energy, a chance to think of new things I want to put out into the world, and a chance to maybe finally continue the manuscript for my next book. But, like usual, for some reason? I’m sick. I felt it coming when I was on my last day of work for the week, and then I got home, passed out, and woke up yesterday feeling week, and coughing. Yay!

</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Oct 2024 15:45:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/thoughts/2024/10/12/whoops-now-i-m-sick</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I Finally Found A Use For Google Sheets</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4000/programming/2024/10/11/i-finally-found-a-use-for-google-sheets.html</link>
      <description>Do you remember on Twitter, back in the golden days, when the worst part of the website were the people who were addicted to finding things they thought were bad about other people, and then creating dunk posts, and dogpiles? Do you miss that? Oh, yeah, me either. But, the old part of Twitter I’m actually talking about here, are the bots that people used to setup, that read from their tweets, and then shot out a randomized post. I think some of them were called like, “John Reads” or “John Books”, wherein they’d put their name and qualify it with something related to writing or reading. Either way, remember that? Do ya?

</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2024 12:59:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/programming/2024/10/11/i-finally-found-a-use-for-google-sheets</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Turning Windows into a Dev Machine</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4000/tech/2024/10/10/turning-windows-into-a-dev-machine.html</link>
      <description>So, it’s been an interesting week and a half. I started screwing around with Python after spending time casually reading about it, and decided to learn it, hands-on, and I smashed up a slew of interesting things. Then, I started thinking about, despite my love for Linux, and especially Debian, there are some critical things I still don’t have access to while on Linux.

</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Oct 2024 23:05:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/tech/2024/10/10/turning-windows-into-a-dev-machine</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bot, Please Have A Personality</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4000/programming/2024/10/08/bot-please-have-a-personality.html</link>
      <description>Today, it’s my day off, you know. So I spent some time trying to figure out how to make and rebuild Mafia Wars from the ground-up. I achieved … some things, but it’s proving to be something that will take a long time, and I kinda just wanna chill and have some fun? So, I made it so that my Reddit-Bot also posts random status (which are predefined), that are pulled from a json file.

</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2024 16:45:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/programming/2024/10/08/bot-please-have-a-personality</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Python, Serve My RSS Feed For Me</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4000/programming/2024/10/08/python-serve-my-rss-feed-for-me.html</link>
      <description>While the dunces in the room are using AI to paint pictures for them, and make one-bar songs, I’m making little worker bee-bots that aren’t AI at all, but act more like little tiny butlers for me. Butlers that live inside Debian 12 on a VPS.

</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2024 00:28:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/programming/2024/10/08/python-serve-my-rss-feed-for-me</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reddit, Give Me Your Images</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4000/programming/2024/10/06/reddit-give-me-your-images.html</link>
      <description>Because my Mastodon timeline isn’t spicy and chaotic enough, I scraped together pieces of things I’m trying to learn and utilize in Python, and put together a whole entire bot that posts images from a Reddit RSS feed, directly to Mastodon.

</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Oct 2024 22:42:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/programming/2024/10/06/reddit-give-me-your-images</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jump on the Bandwagon!</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4000/social%20media/2024/10/05/jump-on-the-bandwagon.html</link>
      <description>I’m sure there are those who know that Bandcamp was recently bought out by a company called Songtradr, and this came with much dismay, because Bandcamp has been, and has mostly remained, one of the only music platforms where small artists could actually be discovered, heard, and paid. This is incongruent with current trends of the past decade and a half, of the music industry pushing real hard for streaming. Streaming, which pays fractions of a penny of a penny on a dollar, while the rich consume the profits. This has only been exasperated since AI came into the scene, with people absent of talent and inspiration, generating absolute garbage (and this isn’t just a problem in music, it’s everywhere).

</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Oct 2024 21:49:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/social%20media/2024/10/05/jump-on-the-bandwagon</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Crontab, Give Me My Daily Report</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4000/programming/2024/10/04/crontab-give-me-my-daily-report.html</link>
      <description>If you’re like me, and you just can’t find it in yourself to quit the nerd-site, then maybe you should make it easier on yourself, and setup something to just give you a daily report (e-mail) on your favorite subreddits’ top five trending posts.

</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Oct 2024 00:13:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/programming/2024/10/04/crontab-give-me-my-daily-report</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Life Without a Computer?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4000/writing%20prompt/2024/10/03/life-without-a-computer.html</link>
      <description>It’s been at least two months since I’ve done one of Jetpack’s writing prompts. Largely, because, I ditched Wordpress and decided to build something from scratch. It seems, in light of the Wordpress CEO’s recent blunders, it was probably a good idea to abandon Wordpress. But I really only did it because I enjoy writing everything in VS Code, rather than a glitchy editor. Nevertheless, I still have Automattic’s “jetpack” app installed on my phone, and it serves me interesting writing prompts every once in a while, and because I don’t enjoy writing about a crisis every single time I fire up the VSC, I think I’ll snag this one.

</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Oct 2024 22:15:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/writing%20prompt/2024/10/03/life-without-a-computer</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>You Wake Up, And It&#39;s 2012 Again</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4000/thoughts/2024/10/02/you-wake-up-and-it-s-2012-again.html</link>
      <description>I’ve written a lot about how much I miss the 90s, and sometimes pine for an age in the 80s, and, obviously, I’m not talking … politically. But more, a time when things were less chaotic, and we were all kinda just vibing with whatever was happening. Drinking our Ecto-Coolers, slipping on Velcro sneakers, uh, watching Rocko’s Modern Life.

</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Oct 2024 17:11:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/thoughts/2024/10/02/you-wake-up-and-it-s-2012-again</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Progeny Mall, October Shopping Event!</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4000/second%20life/2024/10/01/the-progeny-mall-october-shopping-event.html</link>
      <description>Much like last month, [REVOSA] (my Second Life store), is once again appearing in the Progeny Mall shopping event! This time, for the month of October–the spookiest time of the year! Because my free time is scattered and all over the place, for now, I’m simply discounting a recent, but slightly older item. But! For the first time ever, not only is [REVOSA] part of this event, but so is Ayashi Systems, or AyaSys, my secondary store.

</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 14:09:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/second%20life/2024/10/01/the-progeny-mall-october-shopping-event</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mastodon Has One Thing The Others Don&#39;t</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4000/social%20media/2024/09/29/mastodon-has-one-thing-the-others-don-t.html</link>
      <description>So, I didn’t really try to write a click-baity headline for this post. Partially because, usually, when I share what I write, it doesn’t even show a headline. But, you’re probably wondering, “What could Mastodon/the fediverse possibly have that MySpace doesn’t?”

</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Sep 2024 22:52:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/social%20media/2024/09/29/mastodon-has-one-thing-the-others-don-t</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vivaldi, the Firefox Replacement</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4000/tech/2024/09/28/vivaldi-the-firefox-replacement.html</link>
      <description>It’s been a couple of days since I’ve written anything. Part of that is because my day job highly makes me feel like I don’t want to do anything when I get out of work. The other part of it, is that I spent hours and hours refreshing and updating the look and feel of my site (it’s cooler now). Now that I’ve done that, I’d like to write about Vivaldi.

</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Sep 2024 19:53:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/tech/2024/09/28/vivaldi-the-firefox-replacement</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Released At [REVOSA] Today, The OS95 Shorts!</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4000/second%20life/2024/09/26/released-at-revosa-today-the-os95-shorts.html</link>
      <description>Today, following the end of the month-long shopping event at the Progeny Mall, the Nano Nexus (OS95 Edition) shorts are now available at the store! These shorts continue a bit of a rejuvenated desire to keep my store running, by at least releasing something new once a month. As it turns out, pumping things out every other day was only ever really possible when I was without offline work.

</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2024 14:42:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/second%20life/2024/09/26/released-at-revosa-today-the-os95-shorts</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>One of the World&#39;s Richest Dudes Says Your Work Ain&#39;t Worth a Damn</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4000/tech/2024/09/25/one-of-the-world-s-richest-dudes-says-your-work-ain-t-worth-a-damn.html</link>
      <description>I, regrettably, have to talk about this by quoting from The Verge, but a couple of hours ago they published a talk with the Zuck on Meta’s AI, and the training data associated with it. To say that I’m a bit pissed off is an understatement.

</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2024 16:49:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/tech/2024/09/25/one-of-the-world-s-richest-dudes-says-your-work-ain-t-worth-a-damn</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Social Web Foundation Launches, to Much Confusion</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4000/tech/2024/09/24/the-social-web-foundation-launches-to-much-confusion.html</link>
      <description>Today, kind of just completely out-of-the-blue, this thing called “The Social Web Foundation” launched. Basically, this group of companies and corporations who are banding together to throw their hats together as a supporting web to build up ActivityPub and the Fediverse. Except … It reads and feels a lot like, “We made this.”

</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Sep 2024 22:24:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/tech/2024/09/24/the-social-web-foundation-launches-to-much-confusion</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>You&#39;ve Heard of Misskey, Now Get Ready for Sharks</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4000/social%20media/2024/09/23/you-ve-heard-of-misskey-now-get-ready-for-sharks.html</link>
      <description>For the longest time, I’ve spent most of my fediverse posting hours on the Mastodon software. It’s basically almost all I know. You know, aside from those times I launched a GNU Social instance, and then a very short-lived Pleroma instance. GNU Social is a lot like if someone made an open source Facebook, and Pleroma is okay, but it was originally made by a terrible person (not that this should stop you from doing whatever you want, with your time, and servers).

</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Sep 2024 17:06:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/social%20media/2024/09/23/you-ve-heard-of-misskey-now-get-ready-for-sharks</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scrobbling is My New Favorite Hobby</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4000/tech/2024/09/21/scrobbling-is-my-new-favorite-hobby.html</link>
      <description>Back in 2012, and I don’t even remember how I went about it, I spent enormous amounts of time scrobbling my music listening habits to Last.fm. This lasted into 2014, and I am at least semi certain I started using Spotify for this. How I did before that time … I think I must’ve been using Winamp to track things I was listening to.

</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Sep 2024 11:42:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/tech/2024/09/21/scrobbling-is-my-new-favorite-hobby</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LinkedIn Attempts to Yoink Your Data</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4000/tech/2024/09/19/linkedin-attempts-to-yoink-your-data.html</link>
      <description>If you haven’t heard by now, LinkedIn suddenly implemented a “feature” into their social network that automatically opts you into allowing them to use all of your data for AI training. To top it off, they’ve done this before altering their terms of service. So, technically, nobody’s agreed to this. But! We all know the people behind large learning models absolutely do not know what consent is.

</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Sep 2024 20:23:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/tech/2024/09/19/linkedin-attempts-to-yoink-your-data</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mozilla Sets Their Mastodon Instance on Fire</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4000/tech/2024/09/17/mozilla-sets-their-mastodon-instance-on-fire.html</link>
      <description>Just recently, I wrote about Mozilla proposing their new “AI” features in their nightly builds, and was sharing around the post they made, via another user on the fediverse, calling for all Firefox-enjoyers to run on over and tell them to stop. And thousands upon thousands of people did. It’s one of the largest gatherings of anti-AI force I’ve seen so far, and it was glorious.

</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2024 17:08:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/tech/2024/09/17/mozilla-sets-their-mastodon-instance-on-fire</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Burnout Syndrome, Activate</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4000/thoughts/2024/09/16/burnout-syndrome-activate.html</link>
      <description>It’s been a little while since I’ve written anything relating personally, to myself. I’ve spent a lot of blog posts giving my own opinion on current events, or unfortunate advancements in tech that facilitate mass theft, or rolling my face on the keyboard in my Backrooms obsession. I suppose maybe sometimes it’s harder to write about myself, and what and how I’m feeling about things, because I find it hard to actually want people to know me.

</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Sep 2024 22:28:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/thoughts/2024/09/16/burnout-syndrome-activate</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>You&#39;ve Never Experienced Horror Like Kane Pixels&#39; Backrooms</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4000/media/2024/09/14/you-ve-never-experienced-horror-like-kane-pixels-backrooms.html</link>
      <description>For the better part of a year, I’ve been absolutely raving about the Backrooms. A fixation on a new kind of horror that is both hugely popular, and completely under-the-radar. Something I’ve written about numerous times now, including fictional speculation, and my most recent play-through of the Backrooms inspired Steam game, POOLS: Many have their ideas about the Complex, many people put out amateur content that is in the very least, entertaining. And then Kane Pixels, every so often, drops a nuclear horror bomb that redefines the Backrooms, again.

</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Sep 2024 01:51:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/media/2024/09/14/you-ve-never-experienced-horror-like-kane-pixels-backrooms</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AI Does Not An Author Make</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4000/tech/2024/09/13/ai-does-not-an-author-make.html</link>
      <description>Today I woke up sprawled out on my couch because I once again passed out while watching Youtube. This is a new trend for me as I inch closer and closer to 40. But, I got up, slapped some food into a bowl for my cat, and then turned on the milquetoast social media, and immediately saw more aggravating takes from people who don’t deserve attention, or any money whatsoever. I’m talking about plagiarists who are desperate to be called authors; AI loving losers who think you should definitely expel energy to read things they didn’t even have the energy to write themselves.

</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Sep 2024 07:02:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/tech/2024/09/13/ai-does-not-an-author-make</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Illusion Connect Will Return?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4000/gaming/2024/09/10/illusion-connect-will-return.html</link>
      <description>It was 2020, my rotation of mobile games included just two of them. I had a phone that could support … maybe three? One of them was the already very well-known Orc game, and the other was a little gacha called Illusion Connect. Okay, so, if you aren’t really interested in gachas, and you think buying stuff in them sucks, this probably isn’t all that interesting to you.

</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2024 23:34:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/gaming/2024/09/10/illusion-connect-will-return</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cohost is Shutting Down</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4000/social%20media/2024/09/10/cohost-is-shutting-down.html</link>
      <description>

</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2024 08:35:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/social%20media/2024/09/10/cohost-is-shutting-down</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tell Mozilla How You Feel About AI</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4000/tech/2024/09/09/tell-mozilla-how-you-feel-about-ai.html</link>
      <description>Hey folks! Not a huge update today, but someone on my Mastodon timeline shared a post in regards to Mozilla asking for feedback on their incoming “AI toolbar.”

</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2024 17:03:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/tech/2024/09/09/tell-mozilla-how-you-feel-about-ai</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Plant Your Own Garden</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4000/tech/2024/09/08/plant-your-own-garden.html</link>
      <description>Today, I spent the equivalent of around ten hours of work (on my day off, no less), designing and developing a new kind of “side service” I wanted to offer to people who: Don’t have the time, or don’t want to learn HTML and CSS, and who want to separate themselves from corporate media, just a little bit, even if it’s just to stop paying services like Linktree a monthly fee.

</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Sep 2024 19:13:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/tech/2024/09/08/plant-your-own-garden</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I Gave Buffer a Shot: I Have Thoughts</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4000/tech/2024/09/07/i-gave-buffer-a-shot-i-have-thoughts.html</link>
      <description>A while back, I put up a post about Bluesky announcing their partnership with cross-posting company, “Buffer” (Yes, I’m aware that it’s starting to look like I have multiple topics that are an ongoing series on this website). I also detailed how this was a bad move, because Buffer is using OpenAI tech in their backend, and even though they say it’s just an option you can utilize with writing posts … based on how OpenAI has been conducting themselves, I don’t fully trust any company that thinks it’s a good idea to use their tech. Regardless, since I run a lot of different social media accounts, and I thought it could make things easier for me, like when I write blog posts, or have new music, I decided to give it a whirl!

</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Sep 2024 21:59:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/tech/2024/09/07/i-gave-buffer-a-shot-i-have-thoughts</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Social Media, Empathy, Caring About Other People?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4000/social%20media/2024/09/04/social-media-empathy-caring-about-other-people.html</link>
      <description>I feel like this is something I want to write about here on the Nova Prime, not because it’s a joyful topic, or something that makes me happy, but because it’s an overall larger issue that I think’s been carried over from a website that’s trained a lot of people to kind of, mentally … disregard others, at all expense, for their own personal gain, or comfort. Am I saying that Twitter has accidentally spawned masses of narcissists? Not really. I don’t think a website and its use for over a decade can alter someone’s brain chemistry. Or … can it?

</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Sep 2024 15:59:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/social%20media/2024/09/04/social-media-empathy-caring-about-other-people</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>So I Beat POOLS</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4000/gaming/2024/09/03/so-i-beat-pools.html</link>
      <description>

</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2024 18:47:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/gaming/2024/09/03/so-i-beat-pools</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NaNoWriMo Weaponizes Social Justice Language in Endorsement of AI</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4000/tech/2024/09/02/nanowrimo-weaponizes-social-justice-language-in-endorsement-of-ai.html</link>
      <description>It’s the second day of my little tiny vacation, and I’ve woken up at the bright and early hour of 11 in the morning. I log onto social media to check my notifications and see what’s happening, and … I’m immediately alerted that those behind NaNoWriMo (National Novel Writing Month) have endorsed using theft-machines (AI) to generate books and stories, while weaponizing social justice language in order to emotionally manipulate their readers and writers.

</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2024 11:32:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/tech/2024/09/02/nanowrimo-weaponizes-social-justice-language-in-endorsement-of-ai</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Embrace, Extend, Extinguish (Repeat)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4000/social%20media/2024/09/02/embrace-extend-extinguish-repeat.html</link>
      <description>I’ve written on here before about Threads and how:

</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2024 01:09:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/social%20media/2024/09/02/embrace-extend-extinguish-repeat</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Available Today at the Progeny Mall Event!</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4000/second%20life/2024/09/01/available-today-at-the-progeny-mall-event.html</link>
      <description>

</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 08:42:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/second%20life/2024/09/01/available-today-at-the-progeny-mall-event</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is Today Blog Day?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4000/thoughts/2024/08/31/is-today-blog-day.html</link>
      <description>I shouldn’t even really ask the question, “Is today blog day?” Because the day has passed us by. It is now 11pm. So, if today was a blog day, I’ve mostly missed it, but that’s only because I was at work the whole time. Though, I did look at some sources to see if it really is, or was, blog day, on this here August 31st, and the results are … confusing?

</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Aug 2024 23:01:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/thoughts/2024/08/31/is-today-blog-day</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Neo Machina Goes Offline</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4000/second%20life/2024/08/30/neo-machina-goes-offline.html</link>
      <description>It’s hard to believe I built a city in Second Life, and spent months, and months, and months putting together one of my biggest projects, ever. And then it stood for a year and eight months. It was my virtual home, my little piece of metaverse space with which I could do whatever I pleased. It wasn’t just some copy of the older version of Neo Machina that was built by someone else, it was it’s own thing. And I enjoyed spending time in it.

</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Aug 2024 00:47:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/second%20life/2024/08/30/neo-machina-goes-offline</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tumblr to Move to Wordpress</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4000/social%20media/2024/08/28/tumblr-to-move-to-wordpress.html</link>
      <description>

</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Aug 2024 23:12:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/social%20media/2024/08/28/tumblr-to-move-to-wordpress</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Overwatch Doomed Us All</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4000/gaming/2024/08/28/overwatch-doomed-us-all.html</link>
      <description>This is probably going to be an unpopular opinion, but: I really don’t like “hero shooters”, especially as live-service games. From Overwatch, to whatever that failed hero-shooter was at Amazon (I forget the name), to Concord, and Deadlock. There’s just, to me, absolutely nothing fun about having to fight with other people to choose the character you want to play (everything does in fact not have to be a MOBA!), and then also compete in linear game-styles against other players where you’re doing less shooting and racking up kills, and more … escorting payloads and camping on a point.

</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Aug 2024 09:37:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/gaming/2024/08/28/overwatch-doomed-us-all</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Now available at [REVOSA], Nano Nexus (McFly Edition) Shorts!</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4000/second%20life/2024/08/26/now-available-at-revosa-nano-nexus-mcfly-edition-shorts.html</link>
      <description>

</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2024 19:56:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/second%20life/2024/08/26/now-available-at-revosa-nano-nexus-mcfly-edition-shorts</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>mkultra.monster, Your Tri-Monthly Update</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4000/mastodon/2024/08/26/mkultra-monster-your-tri-monthly-update.html</link>
      <description>It’s time for the tri-monthly update on the Mastodon instance I run, mkultra.monster (no, it’s not hosted on this website or its server, but it is using the same domain)! Queue me trying to figure out if it really has been three months since I posted anything about my instance.

</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2024 16:33:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/mastodon/2024/08/26/mkultra-monster-your-tri-monthly-update</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[REVOSA] Saved from the Brink of Death</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4000/second%20life/2024/08/25/revosa-saved-from-the-brink-of-death.html</link>
      <description>It was a little over a week ago now that I got hit with some pretty hefty charges for automotive repair offline, you know, in the real world. I’ve been trying to raise a little bit of money in order to soften the impact of this a bit, and you can totally read more about that here.

</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Aug 2024 19:24:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/second%20life/2024/08/25/revosa-saved-from-the-brink-of-death</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lost in the Complex</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4000/thoughts/2024/08/24/lost-in-the-complex.html</link>
      <description>I’ve been having this issue since I started going hard on developing this website into something that’s strange, or interesting, or maybe even fun to visit. I’ve embedded a small little box to the right where you can leave messages, I made a todo list that details what I plan to do next in regards to the website, I have another box to the right that shows a live feed of my posts over on Mastodon, and I even put a little radio underneath all that which plays the ambient drone sound from the now closed city I built in Second Life.

</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Aug 2024 23:08:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/thoughts/2024/08/24/lost-in-the-complex</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Yesterday&#39;s Websites, Today</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4000/tech/2024/08/23/yesterday-s-websites-today.html</link>
      <description>You’ve heard of the old-web revival lurking in the underground of the furthest reaches of internet-space, now get ready for: Actual Geocities pages, archived in an easy to navigate interface! I’ve been lurking the Melonland forums, and searching around websites people have built, and one of the main complaints, or issues I see, is people are using Gifcities to kind of “gamble” their way into finding actual cool gifs, blinkers, badges, and banners. And, while this might be effective sometimes, I’d like to direct people interested in collecting old-net artifacts, or those who’d just like a little bit of nostalgia, to Restoritaveland. This comes complete with Geocities neighborhood navigation, and although I don’t think it has every site ever made on Geocities … it’s possible, you might just find something you’ve made, if you’re as old as me.

</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Aug 2024 00:39:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/tech/2024/08/23/yesterday-s-websites-today</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Worlds Chat to Worlds Online</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4000/gaming/2024/08/20/worlds-chat-to-worlds-online.html</link>
      <description>


</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Aug 2024 22:38:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/gaming/2024/08/20/worlds-chat-to-worlds-online</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rebuilding in VR Chat</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4000/gaming/2024/08/19/rebuilding-in-vr-chat.html</link>
      <description>

</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Aug 2024 15:58:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/gaming/2024/08/19/rebuilding-in-vr-chat</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>You Should Always Go Full ActivityPub</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4000/tech/2024/08/18/you-should-always-go-full-activitypub.html</link>
      <description>Hello good people of the indie-web, and shout-out to the fediverse! Why am I shouting out the fediverse? Surely they can’t see what I’m typing here, right now? Oh, but what if they could? What if, after I share this update via my own Mastodon account, all replies to that post came directly to this post, here, on my website. Well, buddy, ol’ pal. That’s exactly what happens now.

</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Aug 2024 15:35:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/tech/2024/08/18/you-should-always-go-full-activitypub</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Urgent Financial Help Needed</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4000/fundraiser/2024/08/17/urgent-financial-help-needed.html</link>
      <description>So, yesterday, I basically shuttered my Second Life store in order to, pretty much immediately stop paying Linden Labs any money whatsoever in order to have land, and access to group space needed for both hosting my store in-world, and maintaining groups for promotion. As of right now, my little venture in Second Life is pretty much over.

</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Aug 2024 09:03:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/fundraiser/2024/08/17/urgent-financial-help-needed</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[REVOSA] Shuttered into Cryo-Stasis</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4000/second%20life/2024/08/16/revosa-shuttered-into-cryo-stasis.html</link>
      <description>I knew someday this day would come. When my ambitions of starting a store out of desperation, in need of an income of sorts, of any, would eventually come to an end. Sometimes it’s a molehill, and sometimes it’s a mountain.

</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Aug 2024 16:20:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/second%20life/2024/08/16/revosa-shuttered-into-cryo-stasis</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VR Chat: Second Life For People Who Have a Meta Quest</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4000/gaming/2024/08/15/vr-chat-second-life-for-people-who-have-a-meta-quest.html</link>
      <description>Lately, or, for the past few days, I’ve been messing around in VR Chat, the virtual world that aims to be Second Life, but with a strict, “Keep the NSFW stuff in private” sort of … uh, place.

</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Aug 2024 23:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/gaming/2024/08/15/vr-chat-second-life-for-people-who-have-a-meta-quest</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Github Explodes</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4000/tech/2024/08/14/github-explodes.html</link>
      <description>Today, for … uhm, whatever reason? Github went plop. It fell down. It shat itself. Its servers went down completely and totally. And I didn’t even really notice until hours, and hours after they’d already started investigating. And then … it came back!

</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Aug 2024 22:19:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/tech/2024/08/14/github-explodes</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Twitter is Viable, and Bicycles Are Boats</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4000/social%20media/2024/08/13/twitter-is-viable-and-bicycles-are-boats.html</link>
      <description>I was talking to someone on Threads, whose name I won’t mention, because I do think she actually believes Twitter is still the only real place to be. But it brought up some thoughts, and interesting points. There are some people who refuse to abandon Twitter. Sex workers, parts of the LGBTQ+ community, and so on. Despite being an attack vector for everyone who hates the aforementioned with every fiber of their being, some of these people still resume their patronage to the Musk-site, hotbed of misinformation and algorithmic content scraping.

</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Aug 2024 11:26:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/social%20media/2024/08/13/twitter-is-viable-and-bicycles-are-boats</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[REVOSA] moved, Patreon &amp; Apple, &amp; Other Updates</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4000/updates/2024/08/13/revosa-moved-patreon-apple-other-updates.html</link>
      <description>Now playing : Eclipse - Perturbator

</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Aug 2024 00:20:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/updates/2024/08/13/revosa-moved-patreon-apple-other-updates</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Neo Machina &amp; Other Changes in Second Life</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4000/second%20life/2024/08/10/neo-machina-other-changes-in-second-life.html</link>
      <description>Ever since I started a store in Second Life, I’ve always wanted to own my own full sim. There were reasons that wasn’t possible in the past, and reasons that became possible in the now, or, at least, around the beginning of 2023. It was quite the chunk of money to maintain, but I built by hand my own rendition of a sci-fi/cyberpunk city I used to visit in my earlier days. This is one of the reasons I have had such a hard time shutting it down, and saving my money. To … stop paying one hundred dollars a month for something people really only pass through in seconds and minutes.

</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2024 23:52:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/second%20life/2024/08/10/neo-machina-other-changes-in-second-life</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The AI Bubble is About to Pop, But the Delusions Continue</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4000/tech/2024/08/10/the-ai-bubble-is-about-to-pop-but-the-delusions-continue.html</link>
      <description>

</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2024 10:29:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/tech/2024/08/10/the-ai-bubble-is-about-to-pop-but-the-delusions-continue</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Warframe, Revisited: Again</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4000/gaming/2024/08/06/warframe-revisited-again.html</link>
      <description>

</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Aug 2024 22:37:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/gaming/2024/08/06/warframe-revisited-again</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Criticism Doesn&#39;t Exist if You Don&#39;t Look At It</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4000/social%20media/2024/08/05/criticism-doesn-t-exist-if-you-don-t-look-at-it.html</link>
      <description>Over the past year, since I’ve started writing much more heavily online, and established a website (despite said website changing at least five times), I’ve written about quite a few controversies. Like how Microsoft is developing AI-fueled spyware, Reddit is copy/pasting Musk’s behavior in their structural decision making, Bluesky is partnering with a company that utilizes OpenAI, and Threads’ new public policy director is an entire fascist. There’s just one problem with all of this, and it’s not only a problem you see with corporations and billionaires, but something that’s been happening more and more as we inch closer to the middle of the 2020s.

</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2024 19:08:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/social%20media/2024/08/05/criticism-doesn-t-exist-if-you-don-t-look-at-it</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Game Informer Found Dead, Gamestop Top Suspect</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4000/media/2024/08/03/game-informer-found-dead-gamestop-top-suspect.html</link>
      <description>

</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Aug 2024 20:27:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/media/2024/08/03/game-informer-found-dead-gamestop-top-suspect</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MMOs in the Era of Subscription Everything</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4000/gaming/2024/08/01/mmos-in-the-era-of-subscription-everything.html</link>
      <description>

</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 20:43:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/gaming/2024/08/01/mmos-in-the-era-of-subscription-everything</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bluesky Part 3: All Your Data Are Belong to Us</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4000/social%20media/2024/07/31/bluesky-part-3-all-your-data-are-belong-to-us.html</link>
      <description>

</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2024 16:51:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/social%20media/2024/07/31/bluesky-part-3-all-your-data-are-belong-to-us</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Threads &amp; Project 2025</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4000/social%20media/2024/07/30/threads-project-2025.html</link>
      <description>

</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jul 2024 14:59:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/social%20media/2024/07/30/threads-project-2025</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Merge Complete</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4000/updates/2024/07/29/merge-complete.html</link>
      <description>Today was a … day, at work. I mean, it’s always a day of sorts, but work is always, you know, work. But I got out, I drove, I arrived, I shoved food into my gullet, and then I sat down to reformat the front matter of over one hundred different old posts from my numerous blogs I’ve had over the years (some of which were abandoned to time for a very long … time).

</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jul 2024 21:46:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/updates/2024/07/29/merge-complete</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Fediverse, For Those Who&#39;ve Never Used It</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4000/social%20media/2024/07/28/the-fediverse.html</link>
      <description>

</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jul 2024 19:13:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/social%20media/2024/07/28/the-fediverse</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nova Prime, Initiated!</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4000/updates/2024/07/27/prime-initiated.html</link>
      <description>What do you do when you have a day off from work? Do you play some viddygames? Do you go outside and roll around in the grass, praying you don’t accidentally slob around in some poopoo? Well, that’s not what I do. Today, I sat down in front of my computer screen, chugged an energy drink as my heart screamed at me “Please, for the love of pizza and beer, stop the caffeine!” and I said, “What if I filled out every single link in the nav section?”

</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jul 2024 15:38:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/updates/2024/07/27/prime-initiated</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Another day, More Content</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4000/updates/2024/07/26/another-day-more-content.html</link>
      <description>Today, I struggled with myself to push through my final day of work for the week, so that I can come home to my one day off until I go back to work on Sunday! But, with the prospect of having a little bit of extended time to myself, I dedicated an entire evening, and partial late-night into adding mountains of content, and placeholders for content to this website. If you look to the top right, whether you’re on mobile or desktop, you’ll notice the navigation bar has become a constant hamburger menu. This is the way it should be, as I have many, many links. And the only way it could possibly break and not be a hamburger, is if you’re using a massive resolution scale on desktop, and … at that point. I dunno, brother.

</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jul 2024 23:31:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/updates/2024/07/26/another-day-more-content</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Days Later, But With More Stress</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4000/updates/2024/07/25/days-later.html</link>
      <description>So it’s been a few days since I’ve posted here on the new site, and there’s a really great reason for that! I was having a huge error with pagination. Or, to be more specific, the deprecated paginator plugin for Github’s Jekyll. I think I must’ve gone through about forty different arrangements of code, and also deletion of code, and edited code, and re-edited code, and then complete deletion. I was pulling out my hair, I was crying and shidding into my pillow … I was swearing and cursing up and down in commit comments and in a help request on the official Jekyll repo.

</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jul 2024 22:07:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/updates/2024/07/25/days-later</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Moving Forward</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4000/updates/2024/07/23/moving-forward.html</link>
      <description>For about four or five months, I’ve been using Wordpress to push out all my larger thoughts, ideas, and musings. I have to admit, Wordpress is pretty simple, and very convenient. It requires a whole lot of just … typing what you want, and then slapping post, and nothing else! Unfortunately, after some careful consideration, I decided that I kind of missed hacking into code. So, I moved some repos around, switched branches, and launched a new version of my website via Github in Ruby, i.e., Jekyll.

</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jul 2024 21:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/updates/2024/07/23/moving-forward</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mastodon: Become Immortal, the Logical Next Step in Federated Social Media</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4000/social%20media/2024/07/21/mastodon-immortal.html</link>
      <description>

</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jul 2024 22:40:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/social%20media/2024/07/21/mastodon-immortal</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wuthering Waves: Genshin Impact, But For Adults</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4000/gaming/2024/07/19/wuthering-waves-genshin-impact-but-for-adults.html</link>
      <description>Wuthering Waves is another mobile game that crosses the boundaries between your phone, your console, and your PC. Much like the games that came before it via MiHoYo, it proves that a gacha can be so much more than a slot machine rewarding you with anime girls. For years and years, I would’ve never considered a phone a thing with actual good games, and I’m slowly but surely being proven wrong.

</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jul 2024 19:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/gaming/2024/07/19/wuthering-waves-genshin-impact-but-for-adults</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The First Descendant: Bunnies &amp; Guns Edition</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4000/gaming/2024/07/16/the-first-descendant.html</link>
      <description>Over the past week, I’ve spent a little time here and there checking out the latest game out of grindy, microtransaction game maker, Nexon. This is what I think about it.

</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2024 23:55:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/gaming/2024/07/16/the-first-descendant</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why Bluesky Will Probably Never Be It</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4000/social%20media/2024/07/16/why-bluesky-will-probably-never-be-it.html</link>
      <description>This is going to be a sort of long one (or maybe it won’t?), because I have a lot of thoughts as a tech and social media enthusiast, and some of those thoughts have to do with how I feel about the direction that social media is moving in. How I feel about Mastodon, and Nostr, side-by-side, and what the biggest problems with Bluesky are.

</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2024 15:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/social%20media/2024/07/16/why-bluesky-will-probably-never-be-it</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nostr, the Strangest and Clunkiest Twitter Replacement</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4000/social%20media/2024/07/11/nostr-the-strangest-and-clunkiest-twitter-replacement.html</link>
      <description>Nostr, the name of a social network that I really can’t pinpoint the theme of. Like something a disgruntled Twitter developer came up with after trying Mastodon, and thought, “Hey, there aren’t enough opportunities to pay for this?” And then there’s the name, like it was definitely something thought up by a hipster sitting in a corporate lounge.

</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jul 2024 20:11:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/social%20media/2024/07/11/nostr-the-strangest-and-clunkiest-twitter-replacement</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Two-for-One Threads.net Sale! Transphobia and LLMs, Oh My!</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4000/social%20media/2024/07/09/a-two-for-one-threads-net-sale-transphobia-and-llms-oh-my.html</link>
      <description>
I woke up on my day off like I usually do, basically just procrastinating for hours and hours. And then I logged onto Mastodon, and then Threads. I like to start off my day by doing some posting, like you do. And then I saw that, uh, well, the official Threads account is attempting to commit career unaliving.


</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jul 2024 17:28:27 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/social%20media/2024/07/09/a-two-for-one-threads-net-sale-transphobia-and-llms-oh-my</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Let&#39;s Talk About Zenless Zone Zero</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4000/gaming/2024/07/09/zenless-zone-zero.html</link>
      <description>No, I’m not being paid by MiHoYo to write about, or stream Zenless Zone Zero (or ZZZ). I felt like I wanted to write about it, because, as an adult who has to work, a lot, and is always out and about with less time at home in front of my PC than I am wandering the world: Mobile games have kind of become a staple in how I find a little enjoyment in the day-to-day usual activities.

</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jul 2024 04:11:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/gaming/2024/07/09/zenless-zone-zero</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Threads vs. Twitter (the eX), One Year Later</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4000/social%20media/2024/07/06/threads-vs-twitter.html</link>
      <description>As someone who is very much into Linux and open source software, and therefore by extension, the fediverse (Mastodon, Wafrn, etc), you might think it&#39;s weird that I&#39;d write up an article about how I feel Threads is doing versus Twitter. Thing is, I understand there are people out there who ... let&#39;s just say, need to be on corporate social media. It&#39;s the only thing they can envision themselves being part of. Like someone who always buys the expensive purified Smart™ water instead of just grabbing one of the Great Value brand bottles, because they somehow think it&#39;s healthier. Or more ... watererer.

</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Jul 2024 05:03:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/social%20media/2024/07/06/threads-vs-twitter</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SerenityOS and LadyBirds: Because These Things Shouldn&#39;t Hide in Closed Git Conversations</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4000/tech/2024/07/03/serenityos-and-ladybird.html</link>
      <description>

</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jul 2024 17:34:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/tech/2024/07/03/serenityos-and-ladybird</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Corporate Social Media &amp; Engagement Farming: Extended Special Edition Max</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4000/social%20media/2024/07/02/corporate-social-media-engagement-farming-extended-special-edition-max.html</link>
      <description>
I wrote sort of recently about engagement farming, and how ridiculous, annoying, and bad it is. How there are people out there who will post things, not because they believe in it, think it, or like it, but because it&#39;s what will get them the most clicks and views. Either because they believe it&#39;ll bring in monetary gain, or because they have a severe addiction to the serotonin pump of getting likes in their notifications. And that, at the end of the day, it&#39;s money, and lack thereof in our current society, that likely drives people to waste their time on the internet in this way.


</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2024 15:31:49 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/social%20media/2024/07/02/corporate-social-media-engagement-farming-extended-special-edition-max</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prompt: Have I Had Surgery?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4000/writing%20prompts/2024/06/30/prompt-have-i-had-surgery.html</link>
      <description>
Have you ever had surgery? What for?


</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jun 2024 04:15:17 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/writing%20prompts/2024/06/30/prompt-have-i-had-surgery</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Closet Redditors: Stigmatizing Not Being Famous</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4000/thoughts/2024/06/27/closet-redditors.html</link>
      <description>
I remember when I first discovered Reddit back in 2010, and spent hours and hours basically living there reading things constantly. I also remember when I started wanting to find places to share my work as an author, and then suddenly finding out that largely, Reddit as a whole, is extremely hostile to people who want to share what they do, unless they&#39;re already famous. In order to share your work as an independent artist, writer, or musician on Reddit, your work needs to already be known by the masses. Else you will be harassed, you will be moderated, deleted, and banned.


</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2024 22:45:29 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/thoughts/2024/06/27/closet-redditors</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Threads vs. Mastodon: The Trilogy</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4000/social%20media/2024/06/27/threads-vs-mastodon-the-trilogy.html</link>
      <description>
Just recently, Threads initiated phase two of their federation with the fediverse. Now, users on Threads can finally see posts from those replying to them from, say, a Mastodon account. For the longest time, you were simply sending your Threads posts to the Fediverse, and never seeing much info about who was interacting with you. Like firing a gun at a wall and hoping you hit your targets.


</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2024 03:02:17 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/social%20media/2024/06/27/threads-vs-mastodon-the-trilogy</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Saga of the Dr. Disrespect Twitch Ban</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4000/controversy/2024/06/25/dr-disrespect-twitch-ban.html</link>
      <description>

</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jun 2024 22:32:47 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/controversy/2024/06/25/dr-disrespect-twitch-ban</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prompt: My Biggest Time Wasters</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4000/writing%20prompts/2024/06/23/prompt-my-biggest-time-wasters.html</link>
      <description>
How do you waste the most time every day?


</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jun 2024 20:07:25 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/writing%20prompts/2024/06/23/prompt-my-biggest-time-wasters</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Life of a Content Creator</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4000/thoughts/2024/06/22/the-life-of-a-content-creator.html</link>
      <description>
I actually really dislike the phrase, &quot;content creator.&quot; It sounds like a bleached version of things creative people produce, made more easily digestible for the masses. But! That is the world and future we now live in, where everything is watered down in content, and also in language.


</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Jun 2024 02:51:56 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/thoughts/2024/06/22/the-life-of-a-content-creator</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prompt: My First Crush</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4000/writing%20prompts/2024/06/19/prompt-my-first-crush.html</link>
      <description>
Write about your first crush.


</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jun 2024 15:59:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/writing%20prompts/2024/06/19/prompt-my-first-crush</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Embracer Group: Embrace, Destroy, Repeat</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4000/gaming/2024/06/17/embracer-group-embrace-destroy-repeat.html</link>
      <description>
I&#39;m sure most people didn&#39;t really know who Embracer Group was until they acquired Tomb Raider from Square Enix in 2022. And, although they have a long history, in the past three to four years, they only seem to be acquiring studios, and also killing studios.


</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jun 2024 14:45:33 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/gaming/2024/06/17/embracer-group-embrace-destroy-repeat</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prompt: How Would I Retire?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4000/writing%20prompts/2024/06/16/prompt-how-would-i-retire.html</link>
      <description>
How do you want to retire?


</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Jun 2024 17:45:34 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/writing%20prompts/2024/06/16/prompt-how-would-i-retire</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>It&#39;s C O M P L E X, on Spotify &amp; Apple Music</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4000/music/2024/06/15/its-c-o-m-p-l-e-x-on-spotify-apple-music.html</link>
      <description>
After confirming, and redoing some track art (I realized I uploaded it with the album art work instead of something custom for the track itself), c o m p l e x is out on the streaming platforms.


</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Jun 2024 03:00:13 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/music/2024/06/15/its-c-o-m-p-l-e-x-on-spotify-apple-music</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hey It&#39;s Maven! Who&#39;s Maven?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4000/tech/2024/06/13/hey-its-maven-whos-maven.html</link>
      <description>
So you&#39;re posting on Mastodon, enjoying your digital life away from most of the tech blunders of integrating AI into everything for no reason. Your words are your own, you&#39;ve got your robots.txt files organized nicely in your root directories, and everything is peaceful.


</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jun 2024 00:03:29 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/tech/2024/06/13/hey-its-maven-whos-maven</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tipping Bad, Gifting Bad, Say Corporations Who Intend to Control Everyone&#39;s Money</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4000/thoughts/2024/06/12/tipping-bad-gifting-bad-say-corporations-who-intend-to-control-everyones-money.html</link>
      <description>
Amidst payment platforms such as Cashapp stating that their app is a bank, and not a platform for tipping, or gifting money (I actually can&#39;t remember where I read this, but I believe they said it on a social media platform), more and more are setting down restrictions on how you use their services with money you give to other people. Today&#39;s post is about Stripe. The next corporation in-line to commit a corporate self-own, or as the gamers would say, an Epic Gamer Move.


</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jun 2024 20:58:23 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/thoughts/2024/06/12/tipping-bad-gifting-bad-say-corporations-who-intend-to-control-everyones-money</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Neo Machina [02]: Updates from the Highrise</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4000/second%20life/2024/06/12/neo-machina-02-updates-from-the-highrise.html</link>
      <description>
Hello everyone! Today I&#39;m putting out chronicle number two on my city in Second Life, Neo Machina. I don&#39;t have a whole lot to talk about, as updates and other things have been a bit slow due to my day job (it&#39;s always eating up all of my energy), but I still do have some news.


</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jun 2024 11:07:20 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/second%20life/2024/06/12/neo-machina-02-updates-from-the-highrise</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PLEXX - c o m p l e x</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4000/music/2024/06/09/plexx-c-o-m-p-l-e-x.html</link>
      <description>

https://youtu.be/mtBtu4ZZLvk?si=JliNmiu8osDMIkMU
The debut track for my new music project, PLEXX.

</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Jun 2024 22:23:43 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/music/2024/06/09/plexx-c-o-m-p-l-e-x</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Does Kink Belong at Pride?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4000/lgbtq+/2024/06/09/does-kink-belong-at-pride.html</link>
      <description>
A topic that shouldn&#39;t be all that controversial, but is, anyway. The topic of whether the act of having kinks, or sharing them in an event typically revolving around the LGBTQ+ community (that is going to be shamed and persecuted no matter what, anyway, until our society gets to grips with the fact that people are unique), is good or bad. A lot of talking points that sound like common sense on the surface, but are really just the talking points of people who would seek to eradicate the aforementioned community, at all costs.


</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Jun 2024 20:35:26 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/lgbtq+/2024/06/09/does-kink-belong-at-pride</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PLEXX, A New Direction</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4000/music/2024/06/07/plexx-a-new-direction.html</link>
      <description>
The other day, I wrote about how I&#39;d thought of changing my name in music altogether, and starting over, fresh. How I wasn&#39;t sure if I really wanted to do that. Well, instead of wiping the slate clean, I&#39;ve decided to simply make a secondary project, under the name PLEXX.


</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jun 2024 17:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/music/2024/06/07/plexx-a-new-direction</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spotify Threatens Price Hike While Continuing to Pay Nothing for Music They Use</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4000/media/2024/06/06/spotify-threatens-price-hike.html</link>
      <description>
I&#39;m sure most people are aware that Spotify is a streaming giant, and maybe even to some people, you&#39;re confused about this, right? iTunes came way before Spotify&#39;s rise, and it even offered a way to buy your music, and back it up. And then there was the whole iPod craze.


</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2024 11:51:05 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/media/2024/06/06/spotify-threatens-price-hike</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Eyeshadow 2600 FM, the Legacy, and Now</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4000/thoughts/2024/06/05/eyeshadow-2600-fm-the-legacy-and-now.html</link>
      <description>
I&#39;m writing this post about the music I&#39;ve made and have been making since 2017, because it&#39;s been a journey. A journey of learning, mastering my style and skill, and even continuing to learn (you never stop doing that). It&#39;s also been a journey of loss, and hate, and sometimes anger, and after coming out the other side, it all continued.


</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jun 2024 16:15:15 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/thoughts/2024/06/05/eyeshadow-2600-fm-the-legacy-and-now</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ActivityPub, Peertube, &amp; the Meta</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4000/tech/2024/06/04/activitypub-peertube-the-meta.html</link>
      <description>
Today was the first day of a three-day off period I took from work as a late birthday ... thing, for myself. But, the first thing I did when I woke up, was I jumped onto my PC and started writing a guide to ActivityPub. Why did I do this? Well ...


</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jun 2024 22:05:51 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/tech/2024/06/04/activitypub-peertube-the-meta</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Unknown One</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4000/thoughts/2024/06/03/the-unknown-one.html</link>
      <description>
What fears have you overcome and how?


</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2024 01:21:30 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/thoughts/2024/06/03/the-unknown-one</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hustle Culture: 21st Century Self Harm</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4000/thoughts/2024/05/31/hustle-culture-21st-century-self-harm.html</link>
      <description>
You&#39;ve seen it, you&#39;ve read it, and maybe you&#39;ve even heard it. The dude on Twitter/Threads/Mastodon who posts forty-seven automated tweets/threads/toots per day about how you just need to push yourself a little harder, dude. Take your free time and turn it into passive income, bro! Follow these seventy-seven easy steps to financial independence!


</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 May 2024 21:45:33 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/thoughts/2024/05/31/hustle-culture-21st-century-self-harm</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Jobs I&#39;ve Done</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4000/writing%20prompts/2024/05/30/jobs-ive-done.html</link>
      <description>
What jobs have you had?


</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 May 2024 02:26:24 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/writing%20prompts/2024/05/30/jobs-ive-done</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>You&amp;#8217;re Too Old to Game, and Other Things Killjoys Want You to Believe</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4000/thoughts/2024/05/28/youre-too-old-to-game-and-other-things-killjoys-want-you-to-believe.html</link>
      <description>
For as long as I can remember, probably at least since I turned 23, there&#39;s always been this march of people younger and older who have framed themselves as the deciders of what is or isn&#39;t cool for you to do or participate in depending on your age. Some things I can understand, you know, like, okay, you probably shouldn&#39;t be chilling outside the high school at 42. Why are you doing that? Put the cigarette out, it&#39;s 2024, and go to the mall or something (that is, if you&#39;re fortunate enough to still have malls where you live).


</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2024 22:16:51 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/thoughts/2024/05/28/youre-too-old-to-game-and-other-things-killjoys-want-you-to-believe</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Life Before the Internet</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4000/thoughts/2024/05/27/life-before-the-internet.html</link>
      <description>
Do you remember life before the internet?


</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 May 2024 23:04:48 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/thoughts/2024/05/27/life-before-the-internet</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Corporations Chase Scams, While Users Chase Scraps of the Old Internet</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4000/tech/2024/05/25/corporations-lie-to-themselves.html</link>
      <description>
Corporations chasing scams, what could I mean by that ... maybe, language learning model, or, non-fungible token?


</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 May 2024 19:49:12 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/tech/2024/05/25/corporations-lie-to-themselves</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Beetlejuice, Beetlejuice, Beetlejuice</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4000/media/2024/05/23/beetlejuice-beetlejuice.html</link>
      <description>
Beetlejuice Beetlejuice finally has a trailer (did I say Beetlejuice enough times?) and I feel it looks interesting, maybe pretty cool, but where are the Maitlands?


</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 May 2024 22:11:46 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/media/2024/05/23/beetlejuice-beetlejuice</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pools</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4000/gaming/2024/05/22/pools.html</link>
      <description>
You wake up just like before. Maybe you passed out, maybe you fell through reality, or no-clipped as they like to say. But this time it isn&#39;t yellow wallpaper and damp carpet. It&#39;s white tiling, and rooms with oddly shaped pools, steel railings, and slide tubes.


</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 May 2024 03:36:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/gaming/2024/05/22/pools</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WAFRN, the Federated Tumblr Alternative</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4000/social%20media/2024/05/21/wafrn-its-kinda-tumblr.html</link>
      <description>
WAFRN, it sounds like waffles, but it&#39;s not, or is it? I&#39;m not sure. I don&#39;t know what it stands for! But I&#39;m not here to talk possible acronyms, or words I&#39;m unfamiliar with. I just wanted to write about this Tumblr alternative that is ... uh, actually pretty cool?


</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 May 2024 02:36:26 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/social%20media/2024/05/21/wafrn-its-kinda-tumblr</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gofundme: The Vets Who Slammed Me With Years of Debt</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4000/fundraisers/2024/05/20/gofundme-debt-relief.html</link>
      <description>
You probably read that title and thought,&quot;Dang, what did veterans do?&quot; But actually, I&#39;m talking about vets, animal vets. Veterinarians. You know, those places you go with your pet when you&#39;ve got no choice, and you don&#39;t want your cat or dog to stay sick, or worse, pass away. At least, that was my line of thinking when I took my old cat, Dora, to the emergency vet twenty minutes from here.


</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 May 2024 04:03:11 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/fundraisers/2024/05/20/gofundme-debt-relief</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prompt: Maintaining a Healthy Work and Life Balance</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4000/writing%20prompts/2024/05/19/prompt-work-life.html</link>
      <description>
How do you balance work and home life?


</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 May 2024 00:48:40 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/writing%20prompts/2024/05/19/prompt-work-life</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft Desperately Scrambles to Figure Out a Way to Power Tech Nobody Asked For</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4000/tech/2024/05/18/microsoft-desperately-scrambles-to-figure-out-a-way-to-power-tech-nobody-asked-for.html</link>
      <description>
Microsoft, founded in 1975, rushing to the death of its operating system with more bloat than me after a gallon of water and salty French fries, and also making sure we never have a winter with snow, ever again. It’s a tale as old as time: Plucky young lad builds a computer in Daddy’s garage, and then forty years later decides to be a supervillain, holding the entire world hostage demanding that his graphics card farms receive more power, or he’ll shoot the icecaps in the face.


</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 May 2024 00:15:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/tech/2024/05/18/microsoft-desperately-scrambles-to-figure-out-a-way-to-power-tech-nobody-asked-for</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reddit, Following in Twitter&amp;#8217;s Footsteps Like a Lost Puppy</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4000/social%20media/2024/05/17/reddit-following-in-twitters-footsteps-like-a-lost-puppy.html</link>
      <description>
Earlier last year, when Musk restricted access to Twitter&#39;s API (see: X) and started charging for access to it, Reddit&#39;s team, and likely also the CEO, Steve Huffman, decided that this was a way cool and awesome idea. And, just like the nonstop shoehorning of AI into literally everything, most people were disgusted by the move. A move that also destroyed third party Reddit apps.


</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 May 2024 18:12:26 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/social%20media/2024/05/17/reddit-following-in-twitters-footsteps-like-a-lost-puppy</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Community Moderation, The Bad Place, and Doing the Work Yourself</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4000/social%20media/2024/05/16/community-moderation-the-bad-place-and-doing-the-work-yourself.html</link>
      <description>
I&#39;m kind of a weirdo. I have an account on numerous ActivityPub instances ranging from Mastodon, to Misskey, to a rather new one that replaces Tumblr, called Wafrn. And I&#39;m writing this post today, because of something that I was made aware of via that new Tumblr replacement, AP connected instance: People are still sharing blocklists across the fediverse (see: activitypub, mastodon), but this time in a slightly more sophisticated manner via an app called The Bad Space, and one of its biggest contributors is mastodon.art.


</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 May 2024 11:21:06 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/social%20media/2024/05/16/community-moderation-the-bad-place-and-doing-the-work-yourself</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Engagement Farming: A Disease of the Modern Internet</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4000/thoughts/2024/05/15/engagement-farming-a-disease-of-the-modern-internet.html</link>
      <description>

</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 May 2024 20:07:36 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/thoughts/2024/05/15/engagement-farming-a-disease-of-the-modern-internet</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prompt: An Ode to Ed</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4000/writing%20prompts/2024/05/13/prompt-an-ode-to-ed.html</link>
      <description>
Share a story about someone who had a positive impact on your life.


</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 May 2024 01:09:27 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/writing%20prompts/2024/05/13/prompt-an-ode-to-ed</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prompt: Adapting, Post Covid-19</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4000/writing%20prompts/2024/05/12/prompt-adapting-post-covid-19.html</link>
      <description>
How have you adapted to the changes brought on by the Covid-19 pandemic?


</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 May 2024 01:21:18 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/writing%20prompts/2024/05/12/prompt-adapting-post-covid-19</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>mkultra.monster, a Mastodon Instance</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4000/social%20media/2024/05/10/mkultra-monster-a-mastodon-instance.html</link>
      <description>
If you&#39;re seeing this from the Fediverse, it&#39;s because I have my self-hosted Wordpress blog using plugins that connect it directly via something of a pseudo instance. Each post on my blog is also a post on the Fediverse, and although I can follow users from Wordpress, it&#39;s not exactly bug free, in that I can&#39;t turn off e-mail updates that rip and tear at my daily mail limits on SendGrid.


</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2024 21:17:13 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/social%20media/2024/05/10/mkultra-monster-a-mastodon-instance</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prompt: Public Figures &amp;amp; the AI Lie</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4000/writing%20prompts/2024/05/10/prompt-public-figures.html</link>
      <description>
What public figure do you disagree with the most?


</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2024 14:45:16 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/writing%20prompts/2024/05/10/prompt-public-figures</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Neo Machina [01]: From the Dredges</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4000/second%20life/2024/05/07/neo-machina-01-from-the-dredges.html</link>
      <description>
I&#39;ve decided to start this kind of chronicle. Not really &quot;news articles,&quot; or a magazine, but since I am now, once again, running the city Neo Machina in Second Life, and at a rate that is more affordable, I think it&#39;d be neat to write about it. To write about the happenings, updates, what&#39;s going on, or what-have-you.


</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2024 15:45:29 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/second%20life/2024/05/07/neo-machina-01-from-the-dredges</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello, Dexter Morgan: The Show that Came, Went, and Came Back Again</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4000/media/2024/05/02/hello-dexter-morgan-the-show-that-came-went-and-came-back-again.html</link>
      <description>
Major spoilers ahead for both Dexter and Dexter: New Blood, for those who still haven&#39;t watched either of them.


</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2024 22:47:23 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/media/2024/05/02/hello-dexter-morgan-the-show-that-came-went-and-came-back-again</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Anti-Social Media: Corporations Just Don&amp;#8217;t Get it</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4000/thoughts/2024/04/29/anti-social-media-corporations-just-dont-get-it.html</link>
      <description>
I keep trying to like Threads. I know, I know, this is a massively unpopular thing to do on the fediverse, but I tend not to do what other people want me to do until I&#39;ve come to concrete decisions and ideas on my own, through my own experience. There&#39;s a lot of the internet, and on social media in-general where I think people just make snap decisions based on things other people say, without research, or experience, and I think that&#39;s bad.


</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Apr 2024 21:44:10 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/thoughts/2024/04/29/anti-social-media-corporations-just-dont-get-it</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Initiate the Protocol: Nova Online Now Federating!</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4000/updates/2024/04/22/initiate-the-protocol-nova-online-now-federating.html</link>
      <description>
Over the past couple of months, or, since the beginning of the year, I&#39;ve been tinkering around with moving, completely, toward ActivityPub. From taking my Twitter activity and killing it in its entirety so that I can run my instance at mkultra, to replacing Instagram with my Pixelfed, to replacing Youtube with my Peertube, and also now, my blog!


</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2024 12:10:18 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/updates/2024/04/22/initiate-the-protocol-nova-online-now-federating</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>You&#39;ve Been Severed</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4000/media/2024/04/19/youve-been-severed.html</link>
      <description>
Sometimes I struggle to think of topics to write about on my blog, and as anyone reading might see, the topics are all over the place. In order to continue that tradition, but to keep it in the same kind of theme I&#39;ve been rolling with lately: Liminality.


</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2024 23:53:51 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/media/2024/04/19/youve-been-severed</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New at AyaSys: The Howler!</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4000/second%20life/2024/04/18/new-at-ayasys-the-howler.html</link>
      <description>
For years, and years, I&#39;ve had a secondary store in Second Life. It was first named Horcrux Business Solutions, when its only products were some adboards and an online indicator. Sometime a few years ago, I noticed that, although small, and mostly unknown, it does make sales here and there. So, I decided it should have a new name, and a rebranding.


</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2024 20:50:42 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/second%20life/2024/04/18/new-at-ayasys-the-howler</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New at [REVOSA]: Nano Nexus (Void Edition)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4000/second%20life/2024/04/17/new-at-revosa-nano-nexus-void-edition.html</link>
      <description>
Brand new at [REVOSA] (my Second Life store), and after quite a bit of time, the Nano Nexus line of shorts has received a &quot;void&quot; edition! Like previous shorts, this is fit for legacy, reborn, and maitreya, and is colored in ALL BLACK!


</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2024 15:39:46 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/second%20life/2024/04/17/new-at-revosa-nano-nexus-void-edition</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Toll it Takes: Isolation, Transness, &amp;amp; the Disappointment That Are Other People</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4000/thoughts/2024/04/17/the-toll-it-takes-isolation-transness-the-disappointment-that-are-other-people.html</link>
      <description>
I wanted to write a story here, in as much a condensed manner as I can, about things I&#39;ve grappled with, and had going on years ago, and am dealing with the fallout from, even today. But it&#39;s complicated, it&#39;s messy, it&#39;s not fun or happy; it&#39;s not a road I&#39;ve gone down in a cohesive way in a single blog post.


</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2024 12:53:06 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/thoughts/2024/04/17/the-toll-it-takes-isolation-transness-the-disappointment-that-are-other-people</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Backrooms: Fact, or Fiction?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4000/thoughts/2024/04/12/the-backrooms-fact-or-fiction.html</link>
      <description>
We&#39;ve all been there. The gas station on the side of the road in the middle of the night, the mall near closing time, your own living space at three in the morning. Liminal spaces. A concept that was a sensation on Tumblr years, and years ago. And then it became something bigger, burst straight from the chest of 4chan.


</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2024 23:10:41 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/thoughts/2024/04/12/the-backrooms-fact-or-fiction</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prompt: What’d You Learn in High School?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4000/writing%20prompts/2024/04/12/prompt-whatd-you-learn-in-high-school.html</link>
      <description>
Describe something you learned in high school.


</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2024 04:21:50 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/writing%20prompts/2024/04/12/prompt-whatd-you-learn-in-high-school</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Protocol, in the Works</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4000/thoughts/2024/04/10/a-protocol-in-the-works.html</link>
      <description>
Before I switched positions and location at my offline job, I was pretty heavily into writing this book. I&#39;m not sure why I&#39;ve been on a cooling-off period for a couple of months in regard to writing it, but that&#39;s how it&#39;s been my whole life. Took me three years to finish the full manuscript of my first book, and looking back at it ten years later after publishing, I don&#39;t even really feel like I would have published it now, had it taken me this long to finish (my tastes and ideas have radically changed since then).


</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Apr 2024 20:14:55 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/thoughts/2024/04/10/a-protocol-in-the-works</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Neo Machina, Offline, for Now</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4000/second%20life/2024/04/08/neo-machina-offline-for-now.html</link>
      <description>
So this has been a thing since the beginning of the year. I had planned to bring it down, but couldn&#39;t really stomach it and decided not to. But another month or so of the server bills came in, and it&#39;s got me feeling very tight on cash. Especially with having switched job locations and needing to put gas in my tank a bit more often.


</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Apr 2024 23:34:01 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/second%20life/2024/04/08/neo-machina-offline-for-now</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>As Google Increases Predatory Practices, Should You Switch to Peertube?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4000/tech/2024/04/06/as-google-increases-predatory-practices-should-you-switch-to-peertube.html</link>
      <description>
If you&#39;ve been on the internet for the past five years, or even the past ten years, you might remember that moment on Twitter where someone noted that the people at Google&#39;s headquarters in California took down their &quot;Don&#39;t be evil&quot; sign and/or removed it from their CoC, as if they were cartoon villains getting ready to do something nefarious. And nefarious things they did do, and are preparing to do more of.


</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Apr 2024 02:12:47 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/tech/2024/04/06/as-google-increases-predatory-practices-should-you-switch-to-peertube</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Strings of Strangeness, a Mastodon Odyssey</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4000/thoughts/2024/04/02/strings-of-strangeness-a-mastodon-odyssey.html</link>
      <description>
This has sort of been a thing since I first relaunched an instance on the ActivityPub network in my efforts to govern my own space, and also get away from bad administration and moderation on past instances (hackers.town to name one, forever banned for telling a bully to shut his face, literally).


</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2024 17:37:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/thoughts/2024/04/02/strings-of-strangeness-a-mastodon-odyssey</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prompt: What’s Your Morning Ritual?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4000/writing%20prompts/2024/04/01/prompt-whats-your-morning-ritual.html</link>
      <description>
What are your morning rituals? What does the first hour of your day look like?


</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 14:44:15 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/writing%20prompts/2024/04/01/prompt-whats-your-morning-ritual</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>*hacker voice* I&#39;m In, the XZ Fiasco</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4000/tech/2024/03/29/hacker-voice-im-in-the-xz-fiasco.html</link>
      <description>
As some who visit this blog, and also my Patreon, may know, for the past month or so, I&#39;ve gone headfirst completely into Linux leaving Windows in the dust like the roadrunner escaping the coyote. This was largely due-in-part to Microsoft&#39;s forced &quot;artificial intelligence&quot; injections into every single piece of its software (and possible subscription requirements in future versions of Windows).


</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2024 18:00:10 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/tech/2024/03/29/hacker-voice-im-in-the-xz-fiasco</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Year is 1995</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4000/thoughts/2024/03/29/the-year-is-1995.html</link>
      <description>
You&#39;re sitting at a wooden desk in front of a mammoth of a PC tower. It&#39;s beige and blocky; the buttons are chunky. Its idling sounds like the low hum of an aircraft taking off, and the hard drive clicks like a woodpecker having a seizure. 


</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2024 01:51:40 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/thoughts/2024/03/29/the-year-is-1995</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prompt: Comprehension, and Einstein&amp;#8217;s Theory of Relativity</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4000/writing%20prompts/2024/03/27/prompt-comprehension-and-einsteins-theory-of-relativity.html</link>
      <description>
What’s something most people don’t understand?


</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2024 22:55:11 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/writing%20prompts/2024/03/27/prompt-comprehension-and-einsteins-theory-of-relativity</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prompt: Just Say No</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4000/writing%20prompts/2024/03/25/prompt-just-say-no.html</link>
      <description>
How often do you say “no” to things that would interfere with your goals?


</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2024 01:40:16 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/writing%20prompts/2024/03/25/prompt-just-say-no</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Create a Bootable Debian Flash Drive</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4000/linux/2024/03/17/create-a-bootable-debian-flash-drive.html</link>
      <description>
In my last post, I suggested you, the reader, abandon Windows, jump ship, get out while you still can, and dive directly into Debian. What I didn&#39;t talk about, was how to create a bootable flash drive so that you can install it! This is, of course, sparsely detailed on the Debian Wiki itself, and maybe across many different websites.


</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Mar 2024 02:15:52 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/linux/2024/03/17/create-a-bootable-debian-flash-drive</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prompt: Failure and Success</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4000/writing%20prompts/2024/03/05/prompt-failure-and-success.html</link>
      <description>
How has a failure, or apparent failure, set you up for later success?


</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2024 09:14:09 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>/writing%20prompts/2024/03/05/prompt-failure-and-success</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prompt: Is fate real?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4000/writing%20prompts/2024/03/01/prompt-is-fate-real.html</link>
      <description>
Do you believe in fate/destiny?


</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 17:57:05 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>/writing%20prompts/2024/03/01/prompt-is-fate-real</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The True Era of Open Source</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4000/thoughts/2024/02/28/the-true-era-of-open-source.html</link>
      <description>
If you&#39;re a user of Windows, and have been for a large portion of your life, you&#39;re probably astounded that, via Windows 11, Microsoft is both trying to mimic Apple, and embedding information theft directly into your desktop. What do I mean? I mean, Apple does Apple better than Microsoft, and the inaccurately named &quot;AI&quot; that every billion dollar company is jumping on, is now also a part of your Windows desktop.


</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2024 00:54:47 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>/thoughts/2024/02/28/the-true-era-of-open-source</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prompt: My most ambitious project</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4000/thoughts/2024/02/26/prompt-my-most-ambitious-project.html</link>
      <description>
Describe the most ambitious DIY project you&#39;ve ever taken on.


</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Feb 2024 21:46:17 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>/thoughts/2024/02/26/prompt-my-most-ambitious-project</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prompt: Would you ban a word?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4000/writing%20prompts/2024/02/25/prompt-would-you-ban-a-word.html</link>
      <description>
If you could permanently ban a word from general usage, which one would it be? Why?


</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Feb 2024 10:25:54 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>/writing%20prompts/2024/02/25/prompt-would-you-ban-a-word</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Challenges</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4000/writing%20prompts/2024/02/24/challenges.html</link>
      <description>
What is the biggest challenge you will face in the next six months?


</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Feb 2024 21:23:09 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>/writing%20prompts/2024/02/24/challenges</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Parcels for rent at Neo Machina!</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4000/second%20life/2024/02/24/parcels-for-rent-at-neo-machina.html</link>
      <description>
Hello, and good day to the denizens of the world, and also, the virtual world, Second Life! Today I&#39;m writing to make available some information about what&#39;s going on at Neo Machina, my future-city sim within the virtual world.


</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Feb 2024 11:21:10 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>/second%20life/2024/02/24/parcels-for-rent-at-neo-machina</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Call to Action: Help my brother out</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4000/fundraisers/2024/02/13/call-to-action-help-my-brother-out.html</link>
      <description>
This isn&#39;t going to be a very long post, as I don&#39;t feel it&#39;s a good idea to delve too much into the details of the inner-workings of my brother&#39;s relationship, or lack-thereof with his wife, soon to be ex. But I want to put this out there as a call-to-action, why?


</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Feb 2024 19:29:11 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>/fundraisers/2024/02/13/call-to-action-help-my-brother-out</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New @ [REVOSA] / / Nano Nexus (Fade Edition)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4000/second%20life/2024/01/31/new-revosa-nano-nexus-fade-edition.html</link>
      <description>
Next up in my virtual world product line of cyberpunk inspired gym shorts, is the &quot;Fade Edition.&quot; Made in fully yellow with two black stripes and a band around the wearers waist that reads, &quot;Never Fade Away.&quot;


</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2024 11:33:10 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>/second%20life/2024/01/31/new-revosa-nano-nexus-fade-edition</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New @ [REVOSA] / / the Nano Nexus Gym Shorts!</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4000/second%20life/2024/01/28/new-revosa-the-nano-nexus-gym-shorts.html</link>
      <description>
It&#39;s been a while, or maybe a long time (months, and months at this point), since I&#39;ve released a really in-depth sort of product in my Second Life store. From a time, way back when in the early days of 2015, when I used to post a new product every other day, non-stop, constantly, to now, where just making the product takes me days, weeks of time. And then posting it? Hours of time.


</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jan 2024 14:15:31 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>/second%20life/2024/01/28/new-revosa-the-nano-nexus-gym-shorts</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Story Behind [REVOSA]</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4000/second%20life/2024/01/20/the-story-behind-revosa.html</link>
      <description>
One day back in late 2014, I had just lost my job. There is a whole entire story behind this with years worth of history connected to it, but for now, and today, this story is about the store I started and still run in Second Life.


</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jan 2024 21:43:28 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>/second%20life/2024/01/20/the-story-behind-revosa</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why it Matters to Oppose AI</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4000/thoughts/2024/01/19/why-it-matters-to-oppose-ai.html</link>
      <description>
We&#39;ve all been there. You&#39;re trying to figure out what direction to take next in your book, or what stroke to make next on the canvas, and undecided, you put it down for four months. It happens. Whaddya gonna do about it?


</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jan 2024 21:48:48 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>/thoughts/2024/01/19/why-it-matters-to-oppose-ai</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Tragedy of Modern Dating Apps</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4000/thoughts/2024/01/19/the-tragedy-of-modern-dating-apps.html</link>
      <description>
This is going to make me sound old, and maybe rightfully so. There are good things about the new age, the new landscape in which the way the world works, but there are also a lot of bad things. Bad things, like mass-disinformation in the form of short video content, sludge-video content (multiple videos side-by-side in the same post i.e., Tik Tok), splintered social media that is almost entirely just people lying, or saying fake things they don&#39;t actually believe in order to do the numbers (most of the time for no reason other than to feel like a celebrity)...


</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jan 2024 11:41:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>/thoughts/2024/01/19/the-tragedy-of-modern-dating-apps</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TERMINUS, the album to end all albums (Get it?)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4000/updates/2019/07/28/terminus-the-album-to-end-all-albums-get-it.html</link>
      <description>
Or not, because this definitely is not my last album.


</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jul 2019 19:19:07 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/updates/2019/07/28/terminus-the-album-to-end-all-albums-get-it</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#TheSims4: VampHouse Challenge</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4000/gaming/2019/07/28/thesims4-vamphouse-challenge.html</link>
      <description>
A lot of the times, at least when I&#39;m in Sims 4, I have a tendency to start new games over and over again, without any clear goals as to what I want to do. Not even most of the challenges can make it easy for me to finally just stick with something. Part of this is due to the fact that my original game was awesome, but I messed it up with too much modding and game-altering with things like MCCC (a mod I would highly recommend for story progression, and especially this challenge, at least, if you want your offspring to make their own lives without your intervention).


</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jul 2019 15:58:04 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/gaming/2019/07/28/thesims4-vamphouse-challenge</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Throne of the Forsaken, and the Start of Something New</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4000/updates/2019/05/28/throne-of-the-forsaken-and-the-start-of-something-new.html</link>
      <description>
TotF: The Shattering


</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2019 16:05:43 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/updates/2019/05/28/throne-of-the-forsaken-and-the-start-of-something-new</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>REVOSA Long Sleeve [Imperial]</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4000/second%20life/2016/01/13/revosa-long-sleeve-imperial.html</link>
      <description>

Need a break from looking for droids? Want to show your Galactic Empire pride? Now you can with this long sleeve lady’s top!

This package comes with a regular shirt layer and a Maitreya applier HUD and is the first of a few, I think.

Available on the marketplace here, or you can stop by inworld to check it out and maybe even slap that Midnight Mania!
</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jan 2016 12:52:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>/second%20life/2016/01/13/revosa-long-sleeve-imperial</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 6 &amp;#8220;Bloodlust&amp;#8221; complete</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4000/fiction/2016/01/05/chapter-6-bloodlust-complete.html</link>
      <description>Alright, so this latest chapter sees the end of an important figure, or someone who has been relatively important throughout the entire series so far, and then we’re introduced to something familiar, yet maybe strange for such a setting that I have developed here.

Nonetheless, I hope the reception of this particular aspect of the story is received well, because I can, and am going to have a lot of fun in developing it.

I am of course talking about vampirism, and although it isn’t directly named or mentioned as such, that is exactly what it is. I used to have lots and lots of fun roleplaying in vampire settings in a modern sort of way, and I had a lot of ideas and character progression that I think kicked tons of ass. But, being as this was a simple roleplay setting, that work that I did would never really see the light of day in actual storytelling.

Well, until now at least.

To reach chapter 6, or any other chapters, click here and follow the link to the NETHERBOUND serial index page. And remember to share/reblog if you enjoy what you read!
</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jan 2016 13:37:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>/fiction/2016/01/05/chapter-6-bloodlust-complete</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 5 &amp;#8220;Jack of Spades&amp;#8221; Complete!</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4000/fiction/2016/01/02/chapter-5-jack-of-spades-complete.html</link>
      <description>After some time and some interruptions for other things that needed to happen, including the holiday season and some new games that are pretty cool, I got back to chapter five and finished it today!

In chapter five, instead of having the Tredecim’s ship AI just talk for a whole chapter about how and why everyone on the vessel is dead, I decided to do something a little different and take the reader through the perspective of one of the biggest antagonists in the series, Jack Marcellus.

He’s violent, he’s bad. There isn’t a single redeeming quality left in this man, but it was essential for establish what happens next, in chapter six, “Bloodlust.”

I’ve made a few new decisions about what’s going to happen next in this book, and what I’m going to do with these characters. It might actually come out looking controversial but it’s something I’ve always wanted to do in fiction and I figured, why not do it now?

Until then, click here and head on over to the Tumblr index page and check out chapter five! Or, if you haven’t read any of it yet, start from the beginning. Just be forewarned that anything written on Tumblr is considered rough draft material and completely subject to changes once the initial first draft is completed.

Here’s hoping everyone had a wonderful holiday and a bright beginning to a new year!
</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2016 16:01:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>/fiction/2016/01/02/chapter-5-jack-of-spades-complete</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>REVOSA Masquerade Red Set</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4000/second%20life/2015/12/30/revosa-masquerade-red-set.html</link>
      <description>

Now available at REVOSA, the Masquerade Red set, panties and optional bra! Comes with a Maitreya applier HUD (with both options), two tattoo layers (for optional on and off bra) or a regular undershirt and underwear layer!

As always, remember to stop by the store today for Midnight Mania and grab a free car at midnight tonight! (inworld link) and the lucky chairs are always here for your enjoyment.

Happy holidays!
</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Dec 2015 15:02:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>/second%20life/2015/12/30/revosa-masquerade-red-set</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>REVOSA Love Bites Chest Tattoo</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4000/second%20life/2015/12/22/revosa-love-bites-chest-tattoo.html</link>
      <description>
&amp;nbsp;



MarketplaceInworld

</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Dec 2015 13:43:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>/second%20life/2015/12/22/revosa-love-bites-chest-tattoo</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>REVOSA Pris Facepaint</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4000/second%20life/2015/12/21/revosa-pris-facepaint.html</link>
      <description>

New today is a facepaint reminiscent of the eighties, if you catch my drift! I am remaining on the side of not mentioning popular media that some of my stuff is inspired by because Linden Labs has stalked my marketplace in the past and deleted things for literally no reason.

This comes with a tattoo layer, a notecard with some quick information and my signature free drink!
</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Dec 2015 13:23:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>/second%20life/2015/12/21/revosa-pris-facepaint</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>REVOSA M66 XS Full Perm rifle!</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4000/second%20life/2015/12/20/revosa-m66-xs-full-perm-rifle.html</link>
      <description>

Just released is this brand new REVOSA M66 XS rifle! This weapon comes with specular, normal and diffuse textures that are also full perm.

Terms of use are included here on the marketplace page, so please read them before you make your purchasing decision!

Originally, this rifle was meant to be scripted for CCS, but due to the gigantic restraints that the script developers put on weapon developers, I’ve decided the best option would be to simply sell my weapons (this being the first of many) full perm to those who have the patience and know-how (I’m not all that great at script management anyway).

Also, don’t forget to stop by the REVOSA mainstore for the Midnight Mania and lucky chairs!
</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Dec 2015 13:26:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>/second%20life/2015/12/20/revosa-m66-xs-full-perm-rifle</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>REVOSA Fishnet Lingerie Set!</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4000/second%20life/2015/12/15/revosa-fishnet-lingerie-set.html</link>
      <description>

REVOSA returns after a bit of a break for Fallout 4 (and other things) with a brand new system and applier fishnet lingerie set!

Comes with top, undies, gloves, socks and a Maitreya Lara applier hud!

Check it out on the marketplace and if you’re in Second Life, come on over to the store and hit up the Midnight Mania board, or grab a free drink while you wait for the lucky chairs to spin around and land on you!
</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Dec 2015 17:37:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>/second%20life/2015/12/15/revosa-fishnet-lingerie-set</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 4 rough draft completed!</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4000/updates/2015/12/14/chapter-4-rough-draft-completed.html</link>
      <description>I know, I know. It’s been a little bit of a long time coming, but I have an explanation. There are explanations for everything. While I was in the middle of writing chapter four, Fallout 4 released! This was pretty awesome, because the game is amazing. But I won’t go into detail about that because it isn’t entirely important to this update, nor is the fact that I also went through most of the main campaign in New Vegas, started playing Elder Scrolls Online (Add @paxcorpus if you like) again and am slowly working my way through Alien: Isolation (An amazing entry into the franchise).

Having burned myself out from 3D modeling, I decided to take a little break, and now that my head is sort of in the right place, I’ve finished chapter four of NETHERBOUND and am preparing to head into chapter five, rightly titled Jack of Spades.

Chapter four details a death-defying space walk within the already mentioned black hole where our ship, the Tredecim is hanging, suspended in hyperspace. You can read the whole chapter, and the rest of the rough draft chapters here, through the index page.

Chapter five, though, is going to be a bit different than anything I’ve done in my previous books. Instead of having the ship’s artificial intelligence spend an entire chapter simply talking to the reader, we’re going to literally jump into the mind of Jack Marcellus, which will detail certain unrevealed things and lead up to the beginning of NETHERBOUND, at which point the story will continue, mostly uninterrupted from any further gazing into the past.

Way back when I originally started writing this book, the beginning was very, very different. With those ideas from the first incarnation in mind, I’ll be using them to detail in a much shorter fashion the how and why. For months I struggled with wanting to write that particular story, but also wanting to move forward to what I had planned next. Although I have explained my reasons for doing all that I’ve done, this is another reason I decided to start with what I wanted to do next, and gently inject the original story into this new form the story has taken.

But hey, that’s all for now. I hope you enjoy reading what I’ve got so far for the rough draft, and look forward to what’s to come. The pacing may be a bit slower, but that’s how rollercoasters work, right?
</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Dec 2015 13:24:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>/updates/2015/12/14/chapter-4-rough-draft-completed</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NETHERBOUND Chapter 3 &amp;#8220;Transmission From Hell&amp;#8221; Complete</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4000/fiction/2015/11/06/netherbound-chapter-3-transmission-from-hell-complete.html</link>
      <description>

That’s right! Another chapter is finished! In this chapter we come back to reality, whatever that means when you’re trapped inside of a place where the laws physics mean nothing, and we learn even more new things.

Back in the seventies a signal was discovered in a pocket of dark space, no planets, no stars, nothing. This signal came to be named the “Wow!” signal and is a real thing you can listen to on youtube, here.

As Jennfier, the ships A.I. intercepts a strange signal that is assumed to have slipped over the event horizon, she discovers that this signal was being broadcast at 1420 megahertz, and that not only is it a distress signal, but likely the same signal that was discovered in the seventies, way back on Earth before everything died.

How?

You tell me.

Come check out the new NETHERBOUND index page here on Tumblr where you can easily select chapters to read, including the newly released and finished chapter, “Transmission From Hell.”
</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Nov 2015 16:26:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>/fiction/2015/11/06/netherbound-chapter-3-transmission-from-hell-complete</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NETHERBOUND Chapter 2 &amp;#8220;There But For The Grace of God&amp;#8221; Completed</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4000/fiction/2015/11/05/netherbound-chapter-2-there-but-for-the-grace-of-god-completed.html</link>
      <description>

That’s right! I spent most of the day pounding out the second chapter of NETHERBOUND. It’s a little shorter but it explains a lot. We start from the point at which Escape Velocity (the previous novel) ended and we skew it, we warp it and we connect it in fragmented shards that tell little significant details about what exactly happened.

He’s awoken 223 years into the future, but this fact is not mentioned, yet.

He’s incarcerated and blamed for wiping out most of humanity

He escapes prison, regardless and reunites with a mysterious and unexplained version of Meryl SinGarda, and then we find out that he is no longer he, or Dante.

This chapter is where I tie the two books together, provide some closure for the extremely anticlimactic end to Escape Velocity and provide the framework for the rest of NETHERBOUD. So if you’ve read Escape Velocity and you’re dying to know just what the hell happens next, you can now not only find out where we are in the story, but how (sort of) we got there.

Stay tuned for chapter 3, “Transmission From Hell.”

Click here to start at the beginning of chapter 2, or here to start from chapter 1.
</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Nov 2015 16:44:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>/fiction/2015/11/05/netherbound-chapter-2-there-but-for-the-grace-of-god-completed</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NETHERBOUND Chapter One Completed!</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4000/fiction/2015/11/04/netherbound-chapter-one-completed.html</link>
      <description>

As of today, the rough draft for chapter one in the explosive, dark and moody sequel to Escape Velocity is complete! As I’ve mentioned before, I’m doing what I’m calling a “live rough drafting” of the story over on Tumblr for all to read as it happens.

If you haven’t seen any of it yet, or aren’t sure how to get to the beginning of the story, click this link to start from the beginning. Each section of chapter one has links at the top and the bottom for chapter navigation, should you get lost, or need to go backward. I’m sure Morgan wishes she could!

So far, as the story goes, we’ve met a brand new character in #thepaxseries (or so you think), trapped on a ship named the Tredecim (latin for the number thirteen). As she learns that the situation is less than beneficial to her survival, she sets out to not only figure out what happened, why everyone is dead, but to find the passcode that she needs in order to force the ship out of hyperspace.

Hyperspace, which she discovers to be the depths of a black hole.

Stay tuned for more! 


</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Nov 2015 13:55:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>/fiction/2015/11/04/netherbound-chapter-one-completed</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#thepaxseries returns!</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4000/fiction/2015/11/02/thepaxseries-returns.html</link>
      <description>

Hello everybody! It’s Meryl S. Kavanagh, author of PaxCorpus and Escape Velocity! I have returned from the darkness to bring to you the most concrete evidence that I am still alive! I know some of you may have read Escape Velocity and are probably going nuts wondering what in the hell happens next, right? So instead of making people wait even longer (since I’ve had so many hiccups and issues over 2015) I’m writing the sequel to Escape Velocity live on Tumblr.

I’m callling it a live serial drafting, so basically you can read the rough draft as I write it, in small “bite” sized pieces that are easier to digest than having a full novel chapter shoved at you.

You can find the NETHERBOUND serial project here on its Tumblr blog (if you’re uncertain how to find the installments, click the NB Serial link at the top of the page), where you can read character profiles, look over my previous books and read each chapter as they’re written! Currently there is a small piece of the first chapter on display and ready to read. “The End of Everything” chapter 1.2 is coming soon as a continuation to the beginning of the novel that will redefine #thepaxseries in every possible way.

Leave comments, tell me what you think and most importantly, enjoy!
</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Nov 2015 17:47:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>/fiction/2015/11/02/thepaxseries-returns</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>REVOSA Dark Fairy Eyeshadow</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4000/second%20life/2015/10/30/revosa-dark-fairy-eyeshadow.html</link>
      <description>
&amp;nbsp;



Marketplace: https://marketplace.secondlife.com/p/REVOSA-Dark-Fairy-Eyeshadow/7974626



Inworld:&amp;nbsp; http://maps.secondlife.com/secondlife/Pisces/172/239/29

</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Oct 2015 14:40:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/second%20life/2015/10/30/revosa-dark-fairy-eyeshadow</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[NEW] REVOSA Boomers by Lula</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4000/second%20life/2015/10/29/new-revosa-boomers-by-lula.html</link>
      <description>

Today I bring you a pair of 100% mesh headphones for your head! These are non-rigged and they come with an easy peasy color change HUD.

This particular item was made for the November Firestorm free hunt thing but as usual with applying to be part of something dominated by super big-time developers, I heard nothing in return. Therefore I’m selling them!

They’re also a cool 1 land impact for those who might want to use them as desk props or whatever without worrying about it swallowing up your entire parcel!

Marketplace: https://marketplace.secondlife.com/p/REVOSA-Boomers-by-Lula/7969244

Inworld: http://maps.secondlife.com/secondlife/Pisces/172/239/29
</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Oct 2015 10:37:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/second%20life/2015/10/29/new-revosa-boomers-by-lula</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[NEW] REVOSA Energized Lipstick [FatPack]</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4000/second%20life/2015/10/26/new-revosa-energized-lipstick-fatpack.html</link>
      <description>

Getting burned out chugging all the different flavors of the REVOSA Energy and Soft Drink line? Well now you can simply wear the fruity flavors on your lips! (This excludes the Fizzy Coke and Diet Fizzy Coke flavors, as their colors were too bland for a lipstick).

Comes with a Nyam Nyam applier HUD and classic tattoo layers for each lipstick shade.

As usual you can find this on my marketplace store or inworld!
</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Oct 2015 15:52:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/second%20life/2015/10/26/new-revosa-energized-lipstick-fatpack</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Seven new flavors added to the REVOSA Energy Vending Machine!</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4000/second%20life/2015/10/22/seven-new-flavors-added-to-the-revosa-energy-vending-machine.html</link>
      <description>

So today I spent most of my time creating seven more flavors of my infamous energy drink line-up and then I stuffed them into my vending machine and released an update.

Now, along with the initial atomic grape, you can have 5 loko, blueberry blast, citrus burst, fizzy cola, orange splash, spilled blood (a vampire variety cherry blood mix) and diet fizzy cola!

Each can is texture with a dark and dirty looking sort of theme and includes ambient occlusion for ultimate realism. Yes, they look like they all rolled through a gutter before they made it into my machine, and ultimately, your hands, but hey, they taste great! Just be wary of that 5 loko, I hear it’s banned in a few systems.

You can grab the vending machine here or come see it (and taste the flavors) inworld here!
</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Oct 2015 15:06:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/second%20life/2015/10/22/seven-new-flavors-added-to-the-revosa-energy-vending-machine</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>REVOSA Small Round Table</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4000/second%20life/2015/10/21/revosa-small-round-table.html</link>
      <description>


Marketplace: https://marketplace.secondlife.com/p/REVOSA-Small-Round-Table/7930381

Inworld: http://maps.secondlife.com/secondlife/Pisces/187/236/27
</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Oct 2015 23:42:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/second%20life/2015/10/21/revosa-small-round-table</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[NEW] REVOSA Blood Queen Shadow</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4000/second%20life/2015/10/21/new-revosa-blood-queen-shadow.html</link>
      <description>

You know, I was sitting here like, I just don’t have enough blood happening with my makeup. Well, now you can you look totally fierce with the blood of your enemies… on your FACE!

Why? Because why not! This makeup comes in a single tattoo layer for your face and includes my famous totally free energy drink, now in atomic grape flavor!

Check out the eye shadow on the marketplace and inworld.

Shirt: REVOSA Be Anything VneckLips: Nyam Nyam
Hair: lamb. the big doll house
Lipstick: REVOSA Venomous Lipstick
Skin: Pink Fuel Vamp
Eyeshadow: REVOSA Blood Queen Shadow
Tattoo: REVOSA Winged Skull Chest tat
Piercings: REVOSA Facial Piercings Set
Eyes: The Addy Style Avery
</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Oct 2015 21:42:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/second%20life/2015/10/21/new-revosa-blood-queen-shadow</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[NEW] REVOSA Be Anything Vneck</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4000/second%20life/2015/10/21/new-revosa-be-anything-vneck.html</link>
      <description>


Marketplace: https://marketplace.secondlife.com/p/REVOSA-Be-Anything-Vneck-Maitreya-Add-me/7927362

Inworld: http://maps.secondlife.com/secondlife/Pisces/172/239/29
</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Oct 2015 13:33:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/second%20life/2015/10/21/new-revosa-be-anything-vneck</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[NEW] REVOSA Sick Sad World Open Hoodie</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4000/second%20life/2015/10/21/new-revosa-sick-sad-world-open-hoodie.html</link>
      <description>

It’s a sick sad world! Especially when you’re wearing this hoodie! Bringing back the 90s one piece of clothing at a time.

As with the other hoodie, this one comes in five sizes and includes two alphas for different sizes.

If you have any issues with fitting please contact me ASAPple.

Hoodie is available on the marketplace and at my store inworld. A demo for the hoodie is currently in the works and will be available soon.
</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Oct 2015 08:11:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/second%20life/2015/10/21/new-revosa-sick-sad-world-open-hoodie</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[NEW] REVOSA Spoopy Polish &amp;#8211; Maitreya Nails</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4000/second%20life/2015/10/20/new-revosa-spoopy-polish-maitreya-nails.html</link>
      <description>


Marketplace: https://marketplace.secondlife.com/p/REVOSA-Spoopy-Polish-Maitreya-Applier/7923276

Inworld: http://maps.secondlife.com/secondlife/Pisces/172/239/29
</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Oct 2015 19:04:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/second%20life/2015/10/20/new-revosa-spoopy-polish-maitreya-nails</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[NEW] REVOSA Energy Vending Machine</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4000/second%20life/2015/10/18/new-revosa-energy-vending-machine.html</link>
      <description>

Way back like almost a year ago, when I was still under the company name “Full Carbon” I had created an energy drink named “Moxie Energy” which became a drift race team name and signature drink of the aforementioned business.

Upon the split with my previous business partner and the rights loss to Full Carbon, I also lost the work I’d done on my first energy drink. So as a response to that seven months ago when I started this business, I made an energy drink called “REVosa Energy” which was actually part of how I even named my new business, and since have included a free copy of the drink with nearly every single product listed in my store.

Now, after all this time, I’ve decided to update the drink with brand new mesh and high resolution 


textures. Not only that, but when attached to your avatar it plays a snap and fizz sound, at which your avatar will sip the drink for two minutes before it automatically detaches! To go alone with this, I made a vending machine by hand (that’s only one land impact!) and loaded up with an infinite amount of my signature drink.

The vending machine itself plays a low humming ambient sound for realism and when clicked it plays a scifi-esque sound that can only be described as a beaming of sorts, as if it’s beaming the drink into your pocket! And now, for 79 linden, you can have this vending machine all to yourself (marketplace link)! Put it in your club, your bar, your hangout, your home, wherever! Your day hasn’t started until you’ve had your caffeine, and now you can have it right at your fingertips.

I will also be including the new and improved drink with every product I make from this point forward, as usual.

And if you’re reading this, don’t forget to stop by the store today and slap the MM board! Your ride is right here. Have a wonderful Sunday.
</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Oct 2015 11:54:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/second%20life/2015/10/18/new-revosa-energy-vending-machine</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[NEW] REVOSA Venomous Lipstick (Nyam Nyam applier)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4000/second%20life/2015/10/17/new-revosa-venomous-lipstick-nyam-nyam-applier.html</link>
      <description>

Now available at REVOSA, another elegant and gothy lipstick that resembles blood, a sadistic and passionate color for your Nyam Nyam lips or regular system lips! (tattoo layer included)

Head to the marketplace to check them out, or inworld for that matter. And if you stop by the store, don’t forget to slap the Midnight Madness board and check out the lucky chairs, because it might just be your lucky day! ♥

Have a wonderful weekend everyone!
</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Oct 2015 12:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/second%20life/2015/10/17/new-revosa-venomous-lipstick-nyam-nyam-applier</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>REVOSA Cyberlegs Demo!</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4000/second%20life/2015/10/17/revosa-cyberlegs-demo.html</link>
      <description>

Have you been on the brink of purchasing these cybernetic legs but were totally uncertain if they’d fit you? Well now you can try a demo!

Along with the demo, please feel free to send me an IM inworld with questions about the product and issues you might be having with fitting. I am usually pretty busy but I will do my best to help you.

The demo is freely available on the marketplace or on any of my vendors!

Marketplace link: https://marketplace.secondlife.com/p/REVOSA-Cyberlegs-Demo/7898864
</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Oct 2015 11:17:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/second%20life/2015/10/17/revosa-cyberlegs-demo</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[NEW] REVOSA Black Sheer Panties</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4000/second%20life/2015/10/16/new-revosa-black-sheer-panties.html</link>
      <description>


Marketplace: https://marketplace.secondlife.com/merchants/3025076/store/products

Inworld: http://maps.secondlife.com/secondlife/Pisces/203/233/27
</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Oct 2015 17:20:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/second%20life/2015/10/16/new-revosa-black-sheer-panties</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[NEW] REVOSA Midnight Candy Lipstick [Nyam Nyam]</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4000/second%20life/2015/10/15/new-revosa-midnight-candy-lipstick-nyam-nyam.html</link>
      <description>

Have you ever found yourself on one of those days where you’re wearing your black lipstick cause you’re feeling super cool or whatever and you’re eating all the purple skittles out of a bag. Later you find yourself brushing your teeth and notice you’ve got purple smeared all over the black of your lips and you’re thinking, “Dang that should be a lipstick!”

Well now it is!

Check it out here: https://marketplace.secondlife.com/p/REVOSA-Midnight-Candy-Lipstick-Nyam-Nyam/7886495
</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Oct 2015 11:41:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/second%20life/2015/10/15/new-revosa-midnight-candy-lipstick-nyam-nyam</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>REVOSA Pink Frosted Lipstick</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4000/second%20life/2015/10/14/revosa-pink-frosted-lipstick.html</link>
      <description>


Marketplace: https://marketplace.secondlife.com/p/REVOSA-Frosted-Pink-Lipstick/7883696

Inworld: http://maps.secondlife.com/secondlife/Pisces/195/218/27
</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Oct 2015 19:35:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/second%20life/2015/10/14/revosa-pink-frosted-lipstick</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[NEW] REVOSA Natural Eyeliner</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4000/second%20life/2015/10/14/new-revosa-natural-eyeliner.html</link>
      <description>

New from REVOSA, the first product in our line of facial cosmetics, natural eyeliner!

Liner comes in 4 different version, all with a little bit of shadow. Colors are black, white, black &amp;amp; white and red.

You may have noticed that the face is different, and this is because I’ve decided to return to using a system body head. One, because I want to do a product line of different types of facial cosmetics and two, because the TMP head just isn’t allowing for the customization I’m used to (and in 2 and a half weeks, I haven’t heard back from their team about appliers/installers).

Marketplace: https://marketplace.secondlife.com/p/REVOSA-Natural-Eyeliner/7882406

Inworld: http://maps.secondlife.com/secondlife/Pisces/201/208/27
</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Oct 2015 16:06:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/second%20life/2015/10/14/new-revosa-natural-eyeliner</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[NEW] REVOSA Goat Skull Tramp Stamp</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4000/second%20life/2015/10/13/new-revosa-goat-skull-tramp-stamp.html</link>
      <description>

Brand new from REVOSA, the goat skull tramp stamp! Now you can have evil really close to your butt!

This package, as with all of my other tattoos, comes with a default system layer tattoo and a Maitreya applier HUD.

Don’t forget that I also take custom requests for tattoos! Come visit my store inworld here and hit that box below my tattoo vendors and we’ll work something out just for you.

See the marketplace listing here.
</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Oct 2015 16:41:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/second%20life/2015/10/13/new-revosa-goat-skull-tramp-stamp</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[NEW] REVOSA Chainmail</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4000/second%20life/2015/10/11/new-revosa-chainmail.html</link>
      <description>
&amp;nbsp;



Marketplace: https://marketplace.secondlife.com/p/REVOSA-Chainmail-with-Maitreya-applier-HUD/7867659



Inworld:&amp;nbsp; http://maps.secondlife.com/secondlife/Pisces/172/239/29

</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Oct 2015 17:32:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/second%20life/2015/10/11/new-revosa-chainmail</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[NEW] REVOSA Parental Advisory Sundress</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4000/second%20life/2015/10/11/new-revosa-parental-advisory-sundress.html</link>
      <description>

Bright and early release at REVOSA! This “Parental Advisory” sundress comes in 5 sizes and includes an alpha for system layer bodies.

Bring back 90s goth one dress, shirt, jacket, hoodie or tank top at a time!

Come see the dress inworld for a demo of this and the rest of my clothing, and of course, so much more.



Marketplace: https://marketplace.secondlife.com/p/REVOSA-Parental-Advisory-Sundress/7865273

Inworld: http://maps.secondlife.com/secondlife/Pisces/172/239/29
</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Oct 2015 07:50:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/second%20life/2015/10/11/new-revosa-parental-advisory-sundress</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[NEW] REVOSA Elf Ears!</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4000/second%20life/2015/10/10/new-revosa-elf-ears.html</link>
      <description>

Brand new in the “body mods” section of the REVOSA store, elven ears!

These ears are handcrafted 100% original mesh. The pack comes with a regular version and 3 version that include separately pierced ears and then a version with both ears pierced. Product also includes a color picker HUD in order to help match your skin, although the product is copy/mod so it may be resized, moved and even retextured if you please.

Available on the marketplace and inworld!
</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Oct 2015 15:59:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/second%20life/2015/10/10/new-revosa-elf-ears</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[NEW] REVOSA Charcoal &amp;#038; Wine Open Hoodie</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4000/second%20life/2015/10/09/new-revosa-charcoal-wine-open-hoodie.html</link>
      <description>

Brand new from REVOSA, this mesh open hoodie comes in 5 sizes, has two alphas (the alternative for the bigger sizes) and includes a color changing HUD for the inner-shirt.

Later versions are planned to have texture shirts and possibly a “Daria” colored tribute.

Hoodie is available at the same low price as all of my rigged mesh clothing and a demo is in the works!


Marketplace listing: https://marketplace.secondlife.com/p/REVOSA-Charcoal-Wine-Open-Hoodie/7858050

Inworld store: http://maps.secondlife.com/secondlife/Pisces/172/239/29
</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Oct 2015 13:27:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/second%20life/2015/10/09/new-revosa-charcoal-wine-open-hoodie</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Waiting Game</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4000/second%20life/2015/10/08/the-waiting-game.html</link>
      <description>So today I’m not really doing any work, you know, aside from the “Miami beach” themed photoshoot I did for a little promotion on Flickr (view that album here: Miami). Why, though, am I not working? For one, I sent in a process credit on my Second Life account on Saturday and it’s being stalled four days later for unscheduled maintenance on the entire billing system, which also means any sales I could be making are currently not happening.

I also applied for the TMP dev kit earlier last week and am currently waiting to receive the email and the kit so that I can get to work on lipstick, eyeshadow, liner and more. But, as it always goes, this is a waiting game, and since I’ve signed up with them for exclusive makeup, I can’t exactly go and make a bunch of system layer makeup (which I’d have to convert later anyway).

And then I’m also waiting on the Maitreya dev kit so that I can perfect system layer clothing, and maybe create specialized versions of all my mesh clothing specifically for Maitreya.



What this means is, basically, my production is halted while I simply wait. On everything. But maybe it’s best I take a day and focus on some other things.

One good thing has come of all of this though! Just a few hours ago I decided to sponsor Making Strides Against Breast Cancer at my inworld store with a donation kiosk, a promise desk, and a cheap little hunt item that, for twenty linden, will give you my newest “Pink Explosion” nails (for Maitreya)! Proceeds, of course, go directly toward the fundraiser. Stop by my store here and check it out!

With all of that aside, I really have no idea what I’d like to work on today besides maybe relaxing a little bit… or maybe the cybernetic arms I plan to release for the holiday season? We’ll see!
</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Oct 2015 14:04:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/second%20life/2015/10/08/the-waiting-game</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>REVOSA Pink Explosion Polish</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4000/second%20life/2015/10/07/revosa-pink-explosion-polish.html</link>
      <description>


Marketplace: https://marketplace.secondlife.com/p/REVOSA-Pink-Explosion-Polish-Maitreya-Applier/7851561

Inworld: http://maps.secondlife.com/secondlife/Pisces/203/211/27
</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Oct 2015 18:05:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/second%20life/2015/10/07/revosa-pink-explosion-polish</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>REVOSA Fear the Living Sundress</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4000/second%20life/2015/10/07/revosa-fear-the-living-sundress.html</link>
      <description>


Marketplace listing: https://marketplace.secondlife.com/p/REVOSA-Fear-the-Living-Sundress/7850422

Inworld: http://maps.secondlife.com/secondlife/Pisces/199/239/27
</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Oct 2015 14:10:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/second%20life/2015/10/07/revosa-fear-the-living-sundress</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[NEW] REVOSA Fear the Living Vneck</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4000/second%20life/2015/10/07/new-revosa-fear-the-living-vneck.html</link>
      <description>

The end is here, the dead walk the Earth, but the least of your worries are the shambling corpses…

Now available at the REVOSA mainstore and marketplace, “FEAR THE LIVING” vneck system layer and Maitreya applier shirt!

Great for Halloween or just spreading awareness of the real threat in the end of the world zombie apocalypse…



Marketplace listing: https://marketplace.secondlife.com/p/REVOSA-Fear-the-Living-Vneck-Maitreya-Applier/7850181

Inworld: http://maps.secondlife.com/secondlife/Pisces/203/237/27
</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Oct 2015 12:24:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/second%20life/2015/10/07/new-revosa-fear-the-living-vneck</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[NEW] Hello Kitty Panties &amp;#8211; Maitreya Applier</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4000/second%20life/2015/10/06/new-hello-kitty-panties-maitreya-applier.html</link>
      <description>


Marketplace: https://marketplace.secondlife.com/p/REVOSA-Hello-Kitty-Cotton-Panties-Maitreya/7847865

Inworld: http://maps.secondlife.com/secondlife/Pisces/172/239/29
</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2015 21:25:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/second%20life/2015/10/06/new-hello-kitty-panties-maitreya-applier</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>REVOSA Eat Flesh Tshirt</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4000/second%20life/2015/10/06/revosa-eat-flesh-tshirt.html</link>
      <description>


Marketplace: https://marketplace.secondlife.com/p/REVOSA-Eat-Flesh-Tshirt/7847557

Inworld Demo: http://maps.secondlife.com/secondlife/Pisces/198/238/27
</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2015 18:45:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/second%20life/2015/10/06/revosa-eat-flesh-tshirt</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[NEW] REVOSA Pentagram Sundress</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4000/second%20life/2015/10/06/new-revosa-pentagram-sundress.html</link>
      <description>

Today I’m starting (and maybe ending for the day lol) with a brand new mesh garment and one of the first dresses I’ve ever made!

This one in-particular is shaded black with a pentagram printed across the front. Many different variations are planned, as well. This pack includes 5 sizes that fit most average shapes, but it also includes an alpha.

Come try a demo inworld with the link below!

Marketplace listing: https://marketplace.secondlife.com/p/REVOSA-Pentagram-Sundress/7846872

Demo location: http://maps.secondlife.com/secondlife/Pisces/199/242/27
</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2015 15:43:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/second%20life/2015/10/06/new-revosa-pentagram-sundress</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>REVOSA Spoopy Pumpkin Tee</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4000/second%20life/2015/10/06/revosa-spoopy-pumpkin-tee.html</link>
      <description>
&amp;nbsp;



Marketplace listing: https://marketplace.secondlife.com/p/REVOSA-Spoopy-Pumpkin-Tee-Maitreya/7844606



Inworld store:&amp;nbsp; http://maps.secondlife.com/secondlife/Pisces/172/239/29

</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2015 01:24:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/second%20life/2015/10/06/revosa-spoopy-pumpkin-tee</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>REVOSA Cthulhu Thigh Tattoo!</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4000/second%20life/2015/10/05/revosa-cthulhu-thigh-tattoo.html</link>
      <description>
&amp;nbsp;



Marketplace listing: https://marketplace.secondlife.com/p/REVOSA-Cthulhu-Thigh-Tattoo-Maitreya/7842727



Inworld store:&amp;nbsp; http://maps.secondlife.com/secondlife/Pisces/192/238/27

</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Oct 2015 15:51:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/second%20life/2015/10/05/revosa-cthulhu-thigh-tattoo</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[NEW] REVOSA Vest Top</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4000/second%20life/2015/10/05/new-revosa-vest-top.html</link>
      <description>

A simple system layer/Maitreya applier vest top to go with your darker lifestyle, or such and such.

Top comes with the usual system layer shirt, an applier exclusive to Maitreya and a free energy drink!

Next up on my list, I think, are more tattoos. Speaking of which, I am open to commission for custom tattoos! Just find me at my store, or the call box beneath the tattoo wall and give me a shout! My prices are reasonable, and I’m sure I can do whatever it is that you want.

Marketplace listing: https://marketplace.secondlife.com/p/REVOSA-Vest-Top-Maitreya/7841942

Inworld store: http://maps.secondlife.com/secondlife/Pisces/172/239/29
</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Oct 2015 12:22:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/second%20life/2015/10/05/new-revosa-vest-top</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>REVOSA Blood Spatter Polish &amp;#8211; Maitreya</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4000/second%20life/2015/10/04/revosa-blood-spatter-polish-maitreya.html</link>
      <description>
&amp;nbsp;



Marketplace: https://marketplace.secondlife.com/p/REVOSA-Blood-Spatter-Polish-Maitreya/7838287



Inworld:&amp;nbsp; http://maps.secondlife.com/secondlife/Pisces/172/239/29

</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Oct 2015 18:23:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/second%20life/2015/10/04/revosa-blood-spatter-polish-maitreya</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[Updated] REVOSA Dexter Cami</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4000/second%20life/2015/10/04/updated-revosa-dexter-cami.html</link>
      <description>

After finishing the last two products that I made today, I remembered that I had an old system layer camisole on my marketplace store, something I’d made way, way back when I started REVOSA (6 months ago).

So with my current ability, I took that cami and updated it with a Maitreya applier HUD, and now it is once again a viable purchase! (lol)

I think this may be the last old product that I update, although there was one other shirt, which was my very first product, before I even had a Second Life business… but we’ll see about that.

Marketplace listing: https://marketplace.secondlife.com/p/REVOSA-Dexter-Cami-20-Maitreya-Applier/7837482

Inworld store: http://maps.secondlife.com/secondlife/Pisces/172/239/29
</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Oct 2015 15:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/second%20life/2015/10/04/updated-revosa-dexter-cami</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>REVOSA Ice Truck Killer Polish</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4000/second%20life/2015/10/04/revosa-ice-truck-killer-polish.html</link>
      <description>

Also released today, a special kind of nail polish. Is this good for Halloween? Probably.

Not so good if you’re an amputee, or the mother of a serial killer!

Ice Truck Killer nail polish package comes with Maitreya applier HUD, notecard and a free energy drink as always.

Being a giant fan of Dexter, this was a pleasure to make, and won’t be the last I do either!


Marketplace listing: https://marketplace.secondlife.com/p/REVOSA-Ice-Truck-Killer-Polish-Maitreya/7837272

Inworld store: http://maps.secondlife.com/secondlife/Pisces/172/239/29
</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Oct 2015 14:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/second%20life/2015/10/04/revosa-ice-truck-killer-polish</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[NEW] REVOSA Sheer Black Stockings [Bloody}</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4000/second%20life/2015/10/04/new-revosa-sheer-black-stockings-bloody.html</link>
      <description>

Just released, this delicious pair of sheer black stockings! Although, I guess someone forgot to wash them after their recent feeding ritual or something, I don’t know. It works though!

I think.

This pack comes with a Maitreya applier HUD, a system layer tattoo, the typical notecard and my signature REVOSA Energy Drink, all at 79 linden!


Marketplace listing: https://marketplace.secondlife.com/p/REVOSA-Sheer-Black-Stockings-Bloody-Maitreya/7836660

Inworld store: http://maps.secondlife.com/secondlife/Pisces/199/234/27
</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Oct 2015 12:46:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/second%20life/2015/10/04/new-revosa-sheer-black-stockings-bloody</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>REVOSA Cross Polish &amp;#8211; Are they inverted? You decide!</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4000/second%20life/2015/10/03/revosa-cross-polish-are-they-inverted-you-decide.html</link>
      <description>


Marketplace listing: https://marketplace.secondlife.com/p/REVOSA-Cross-Polish-Maitreya-Applier-HUD/7832753

Inworld store: http://maps.secondlife.com/secondlife/Pisces/172/239/29
</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Oct 2015 19:21:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/second%20life/2015/10/03/revosa-cross-polish-are-they-inverted-you-decide</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>REVOSA Loveless and Winged Skull Combo Tat! (Maitreya)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4000/second%20life/2015/10/03/revosa-loveless-and-winged-skull-combo-tat-maitreya.html</link>
      <description>

Also now you can buy both of my previous tattoos in one applier and on one layer!

Not only is this the cheapest deal, if you of course want to wear both, but also removes the hassle of masking and mixing layers!

Next up I will likely do leg tattoos, or maybe even a butt today (lol).

As soon as TMP responds to my request, I’ll also being doing what I called “bloody frosted” lipstick. But, you know, it’s a waiting game.

Marketplace listing: https://marketplace.secondlife.com/p/REVOSA-Loveless-and-Winged-Skull-Combo-Tat-Maitreya/7832170

Inworld store: http://maps.secondlife.com/secondlife/Pisces/172/239/29
</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Oct 2015 16:43:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/second%20life/2015/10/03/revosa-loveless-and-winged-skull-combo-tat-maitreya</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[NEW] REVOSA Winged Skull Chest Tattoo!</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4000/second%20life/2015/10/03/new-revosa-winged-skull-chest-tattoo.html</link>
      <description>

New today, the REVOSA Winged Skull Chest tattoo! Perfect for those who enjoy the darker side of life, or feel as though they’re constantly balancing good and evil! But that’s subjective anyway, right?

Included in the pack is a classic tattoo layer and a Maitreya applier HUD.

Next on my list is to make this chest tattoo and the recent sleeves that I did combined, so that you don’t have to fiddle with multiple layers and masking issues on your avatar. Enjoy!

Marketplace listing: https://marketplace.secondlife.com/p/REVOSA-Winged-Skull-Chest-Tat-Maitreya-Applier-HUD/7831876

Inworld store: http://maps.secondlife.com/secondlife/Pisces/172/239/29
</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Oct 2015 15:38:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/second%20life/2015/10/03/new-revosa-winged-skull-chest-tattoo</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[Free Gift!] REVOSA Spooky Green Nail Polish</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4000/second%20life/2015/10/03/free-gift-revosa-spooky-green-nail-polish.html</link>
      <description>

This just in! Spooky Green nail polish (for Maitreya) now available at the REVOSA mainstore, right next to the rest of the group gifts!

Come on down to the store, make sure you have the group Maitreya Gifts, Sales &amp;amp; News active (can be grabbed from the wall next to the entrance if you don’t have that group) and then simply click the black box!

Grab your ride below ♥


REVOSA Mainstore: http://maps.secondlife.com/secondlife/Pisces/172/238/27
</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Oct 2015 00:07:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/second%20life/2015/10/03/free-gift-revosa-spooky-green-nail-polish</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[NEW] REVOSA Tainted Nail Polish (Maitreya Lara Nails)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4000/second%20life/2015/10/02/new-revosa-tainted-nail-polish-maitreya-lara-nails.html</link>
      <description>

Brand new to REVOSA is the start of the Maitreya nail polish accessory line!

This particular iteration of nail polish is pastel pink with one nail on each hand and foot appearing black, thus the name “tainted.”

Along with nail polish, I’ll also be doing lipstick… As soon as TMP gets back to me about my creator application and the dev kit I need in order to make lipstick installers. Assuming they accept me, I’ll also do lipstick, eyeliner and eyeshadow. But we’ll see how that goes!

Marketplace listing: https://marketplace.secondlife.com/p/REVOSA-Tainted-Nail-Polish-Maitreya-Appliers/7828436

Inworld store: http://maps.secondlife.com/secondlife/Pisces/172/239/29
</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Oct 2015 21:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/second%20life/2015/10/02/new-revosa-tainted-nail-polish-maitreya-lara-nails</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>REVOSA Knit Sweater [Ankh]</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4000/second%20life/2015/10/02/revosa-knit-sweater-ankh.html</link>
      <description>

First new product today is another applier garment, a kind of warm knit “sweater” with an ankh sewn into the fabric!

Following this product I’ll be doing two more before I return to finishing up the mesh part of my first clothing line, and then will likely move onto cybernetic arms.

The package for this sweater includes a tattoo layer and the usual Maitreya applier HUD.


Marketplace listing: https://marketplace.secondlife.com/p/REVOSA-Knit-Sweater-Ankh-Maitreya-applier-HUD/7827376

Inworld store: http://maps.secondlife.com/secondlife/Pisces/172/239/29
</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Oct 2015 16:43:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/second%20life/2015/10/02/revosa-knit-sweater-ankh</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>REVOSA Spoopy Tee &amp;#8211; Be spoopy this Halloween!</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4000/second%20life/2015/10/02/revosa-spoopy-tee-be-spoopy-this-halloween.html</link>
      <description>
&amp;nbsp;



Marketplace listing: https://marketplace.secondlife.com/p/REVOSA-Spoopy-Tee-Maitreya-Lara-Applier-HUD/7825811



Inworld store:&amp;nbsp; http://maps.secondlife.com/secondlife/Pisces/172/239/29

</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Oct 2015 02:27:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/second%20life/2015/10/02/revosa-spoopy-tee-be-spoopy-this-halloween</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>REVOSA Skeleton Hands Bra</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4000/second%20life/2015/10/01/revosa-skeleton-hands-bra.html</link>
      <description>

Another piece of clothing from REVOSA just in time for the holiday season. What holiday? Halloween!

Grab this spooky (or spoopy) bra before the best season of the year is over! Cause you’re sure going to look awkward standing around a turkey with skeleton hands across your breasts.

Or would you?

Nevertheless, stay tuned for more totally sweet mesh and applier clothing!

Marketplace listing: https://marketplace.secondlife.com/p/REVOSA-Skeleton-Hands-Bra-Maitreya-Lara-applier-HUD/7823833

Inworld store: http://maps.secondlife.com/secondlife/Pisces/172/239/29
</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2015 20:22:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/second%20life/2015/10/01/revosa-skeleton-hands-bra</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[NEW} REVOSA Loveless Tattoo Sleeve</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4000/second%20life/2015/10/01/new-revosa-loveless-tattoo-sleeve.html</link>
      <description>

For my first release today is another (yes, another!) first in the REVOSA clothing, tattoo and makeup line, an awesome set of tattoo sleeves that I’ve dubbed “loveless.”

You might notice the Maitreya Lara logo on this ad, and that’s because with Omega, I noticed I was only making appliers for Maitreya, so I figured, why not just go grab the official Maitreya dev kit and eliminate a step from putting on your stuff?

And, I have to say, the Maitreya appliers are even easier to work with.

Marketplace listing: https://marketplace.secondlife.com/p/REVOSA-Loveless-Tat-Sleeve-Maitreya-Lara-Applier-HUD/7823205

Inworld store: http://maps.secondlife.com/secondlife/Pisces/172/239/29
</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2015 18:18:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/second%20life/2015/10/01/new-revosa-loveless-tattoo-sleeve</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>REVOSA Black/White Cotton G-String [Penta]</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4000/second%20life/2015/10/01/revosa-black-white-cotton-g-string-penta.html</link>
      <description>
&amp;nbsp;



Marketplace listing: https://marketplace.secondlife.com/p/REVOSA-BlackWhite-Cotton-G-String-Penta/7821263



Inworld store:&amp;nbsp; http://maps.secondlife.com/secondlife/Pisces/172/239/29

</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2015 04:03:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/second%20life/2015/10/01/revosa-black-white-cotton-g-string-penta</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[NEW] REVOSA Fishnet Stockings [Inverted Crosses]</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4000/second%20life/2015/09/30/new-revosa-fishnet-stockings-inverted-crosses.html</link>
      <description>

Brand new in the REVOSA clothing line are these fishnet stockings! Comes in a pack with classic layer stocking tattoo and Omega appliers for Maitreya Lara.

I think it’s safe to say that REVOSA is now selling pretty much everything!

Besides shoes, I guess. But that’s another area I’ll be delving into once I feel that my base clothing line is complete. Come check them out inworld are right on the marketplace.

Marketplace listing: https://marketplace.secondlife.com/p/REVOSA-Fishnet-Stockings-Inverted-Crosses/7819931

Inworld store:  http://maps.secondlife.com/secondlife/Pisces/172/239/29
</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2015 21:58:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/second%20life/2015/09/30/new-revosa-fishnet-stockings-inverted-crosses</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[NEW] REVOSA Inverted Cross Tshirt</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4000/second%20life/2015/09/30/new-revosa-inverted-cross-tshirt.html</link>
      <description>


Marketplace listing: https://marketplace.secondlife.com/p/REVOSA-Inverted-Cross-Tshirt/7816140

Inworld store: http://maps.secondlife.com/secondlife/Pisces/172/239/29
</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2015 02:01:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/second%20life/2015/09/30/new-revosa-inverted-cross-tshirt</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[NEW] REVOSA Energy Zip-up Jacket! Delicious!</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4000/second%20life/2015/09/29/new-revosa-energy-zip-up-jacket-delicious.html</link>
      <description>

Since the inception of REVOSA and with just about every single product I’ve sold, I’ve also given away a free energy drink with all packages.

I have no idea how many people have purchased items from me, but I assume that very many people have at least one REVOSA Energy Drink stashed in their inventory.

So, today, I decided to make a jacket very much in the style of other energy drink product jackets, and now you can represent the tangy sweet drink and get a caffeine high! Of course, it comes in 5 sizes, includes an alpha, and if you have any fitting issues, I am here to help!

You might be wondering if I’ll ever make men’s themed clothes, and I would like to, maybe, at some point, although I lack an adequate man avatar, along with dude sizes for my Blender projects. Plus, being heavily female oriented as I am (bisexual leaning lesbian), I’m not really losing any sleep over making clothing that mostly caters to women. Sorry guys!

I do want to learn how to make appliers, because I have some nifty ideas for tattoos and stockings, but have no idea how appliers work. But anyway…

Marketplace listing: https://marketplace.secondlife.com/p/REVOSA-Energy-Zip-up-Jacket/7813930

Inworld store: http://maps.secondlife.com/secondlife/Pisces/172/239/29
</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Sep 2015 18:16:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/second%20life/2015/09/29/new-revosa-energy-zip-up-jacket-delicious</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[NEW] REVOSA Black Tank Top</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4000/second%20life/2015/09/28/new-revosa-black-tank-top.html</link>
      <description>

My second release for today, and at a much more “natural” time, is the “black” tank top.

Tired of other colors usurping the heir to the throne of darkness? Now you can tell the world how you feel about that with this lady’s tank top!

This top, like my others, comes in six sizes! Extra extra small, extra small, small, medium, large and extra large. If for some reason none of these fit you, I would be more than happy to help out! My customer’s happiness is important, afterall.

Marketplace listing: https://marketplace.secondlife.com/p/REVOSA-Black-Tank-Top/7809868

Inworld store: http://maps.secondlife.com/secondlife/Pisces/172/239/29
</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Sep 2015 17:41:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/second%20life/2015/09/28/new-revosa-black-tank-top</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[NEW] REVOSA Tacos Tank Top (super late/early morning release! x_x)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4000/second%20life/2015/09/28/new-revosa-tacos-tank-top-super-late-early-morning-release-x_x.html</link>
      <description>
&amp;nbsp;



Marketplace listing: https://marketplace.secondlife.com/p/REVOSA-Tacos-Tank-Top/7808191



Inworld store:&amp;nbsp; http://maps.secondlife.com/secondlife/Pisces/172/239/29

</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Sep 2015 07:33:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/second%20life/2015/09/28/new-revosa-tacos-tank-top-super-late-early-morning-release-x_x</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[NEW] REVOSA Black Pleated Skirt</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4000/second%20life/2015/09/27/new-revosa-black-pleated-skirt.html</link>
      <description>

Today I’ve released the very first skirt in the REVOSA clothing line! This particular skirt is black-ish, comes in five the the typical sizes (which were tested on very classic shapes, Maitreya and TMP) and of course, includes an alpha.

Also worn in the photo is my other recent release, the REVOSA Middle Fingers Tank Top, which is a favorite among most of the clothing I’ve made so far!

Stay tuned for more clothing, maybe a dress? We’ll see!

Marketplace listing: https://marketplace.secondlife.com/p/REVOSA-Black-Pleated-Skirt/7805895

Inworld store: http://maps.secondlife.com/secondlife/Pisces/172/239/29
</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Sep 2015 18:39:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/second%20life/2015/09/27/new-revosa-black-pleated-skirt</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>REVOSA Neko Ears! Be cute!</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4000/second%20life/2015/09/26/revosa-neko-ears-be-cute.html</link>
      <description>
&amp;nbsp;



Marketplace listing: https://marketplace.secondlife.com/p/REVOSA-Neko-Ears/7801359



Inworld store:&amp;nbsp; http://maps.secondlife.com/secondlife/Pisces/172/239/29

</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Sep 2015 20:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/second%20life/2015/09/26/revosa-neko-ears-be-cute</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[NEW] REVOSA Middle Fingers Tank Top</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4000/second%20life/2015/09/26/new-revosa-middle-fingers-tank-top.html</link>
      <description>

Now you can tell the world just exactly how you feel with this “middle fingers” tank top.

This top comes in five sizes and includes an alpha. The text across the front reads “I WASN’T BORN WITH ENOUGH MIDDLE FINGERS” and is placed atop a goathead pentagram.

For the goth in you that you never let go of, another fantastic addition to the REVOSA clothing line. Tank top is 125 linden, copy, no mod and no trans.

Worn items in photo:
REVOSA Middle Fingers Tank Top
Blueberry Letia (Stoned)
REVOSA CyberLegs
REVOSA Blood Vial Earrings
REVOSA Facial Piercings Set
TRUTH HAIR Tymber
Head - TMP Fierce
Body - Maitreya Lara

Marketplace listing: https://marketplace.secondlife.com/p/REVOSA-Middle-Fingers-Tank-Top/7799317

Inworld store: http://maps.secondlife.com/secondlife/Pisces/172/239/29
</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Sep 2015 16:18:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/second%20life/2015/09/26/new-revosa-middle-fingers-tank-top</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[NEW] REVOSA Kitty Zip-up Jacket</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4000/second%20life/2015/09/26/new-revosa-kitty-zip-up-jacket.html</link>
      <description>
&amp;nbsp;



Marketplace listing: https://marketplace.secondlife.com/p/REVOSA-Kitty-Zip-up-Jacket/7796058



Inworld store: http://maps.secondlife.com/secondlife/Pisces/172/239/29

</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Sep 2015 02:32:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/second%20life/2015/09/26/new-revosa-kitty-zip-up-jacket</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[NEW] REVOSA Skulls Zip-up Jacket (Perfect for Halloween!)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4000/second%20life/2015/09/25/new-revosa-skulls-zip-up-jacket-perfect-for-halloween.html</link>
      <description>

Just in time for Halloween (only a little over a month away, I know!) is the REVOSA Skulls Zip-up Jacket.

This comes in five classic sizes with an included alpha and has been tested on a wide variety of classic sizes and an average sized Maitreya mesh body.

I strayed away from doing fitted mesh for this one because of numerous issues it was producing, although I’m sure there’s at least one size in here that will fit you. If not, give me an IM and I will personally fit a jacket to your body.

Marketplace listing: https://marketplace.secondlife.com/p/REVOSA-Skulls-Zip-up-Jacket/7795030

Inworld store: http://maps.secondlife.com/secondlife/Pisces/172/239/29
</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Sep 2015 22:25:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/second%20life/2015/09/25/new-revosa-skulls-zip-up-jacket-perfect-for-halloween</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Celebrating 6 months of REVOSA [Free poster pack]</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4000/revosa/second%20life/2015/09/24/celebrating-6-months-of-revosa-free-poster-pack.html</link>
      <description>

So today I decided to put together some of my best photos and advertisements for REVOSA, slap them on some prims and add a shadow map for added quality. Why? Because it’s been six months since I started REVOSA, which, as mentioned before, started as a very tiny operation out of a virtual garage and grew into something much, much larger.

You can grab the poster pack here, on the marketplace, or by visiting my inworld mainstore and grabbing it from one of my vendors across the great wall of stuff!

Included in this poster pack are two REVOSA advertisements, a photo of Lula not looking at an explosion and a bonus explicit photo taken during Crystal Falls roleplay, which, sadly, no longer exists, aside from within my Flickr album memorial. That particular album can be viewed here.

Today is also a “break” day for me, so I’ll be releasing no new products until tomorrow, stay tuned, and REV it up!
</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Sep 2015 19:36:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/revosa/second%20life/2015/09/24/celebrating-6-months-of-revosa-free-poster-pack</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[NEW] REVOSA Police Box</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4000/second%20life/2015/09/24/new-revosa-police-box.html</link>
      <description>
&amp;nbsp;



Marketplace listing: https://marketplace.secondlife.com/p/REVOSA-Police-Box/7786272



Inworld store:&amp;nbsp; http://maps.secondlife.com/secondlife/Pisces/172/239/29

</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Sep 2015 02:46:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/second%20life/2015/09/24/new-revosa-police-box</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[NEW] REVPRO Charged!</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4000/second%20life/2015/09/23/new-revpro-charged.html</link>
      <description>

Today we have a car that I was building as a custom tuner (looks a lot like a Dodge Charger) for my original first customer from way back a year or so ago when my business was called “greasfox.” This is your standard muscle car, modified for precision drifting and, with the right settings, grip. What’s drift? Find me inworld and I’ll show you.

This may or may not be the last vehicle I release. Since REVOSA began, I’ve slowly moved from building vehicles to creating things from scratch in Blender, things that range from technology all the way to pizza! It would be fair to say that I’m a bit burned out on car building and tuning.

Nevertheless, this vehicle is just as cool as my previous five releases!

Marketplace: https://marketplace.secondlife.com/p/REVPRO-Charged/7785541

Inworld store: http://maps.secondlife.com/secondlife/Pisces/172/239/29
</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Sep 2015 23:05:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/second%20life/2015/09/23/new-revpro-charged</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>REVOSA: A 6 Month Milestone (Taking a look back)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4000/second%20life/2015/09/22/revosa-a-6-month-milestone-taking-a-look-back.html</link>
      <description>Today, since I created a simpler product that didn’t take me eight hours to complete (lol), I wanted to post here on my blog a written history of where my Second Life business REVOSA originally started, and how I got to the point of selling nearly over a hundred different products in a myriad of categories, a three story mainstore on my own land and franchises all over the grid in a period of six months.



Back toward the middle and end of 2014, when I was still super active in the furry community and sporting a fennec avatar, all under the name of FoxyMeryl, I was an avid club-goer, dancer and club host for ::FRISSON:: with a house in the sky that I paid for mostly out-of-pocket. During this time, I had no idea that I could really make any kind of actual money in Second Life. For me it was just something to do in my free time to, you know, kill time.

That was until I was forced to stop hosting due to unfortunate circumstances, but one day when I was exploring one of the many furry sims, I saw a store and an ad for “custom tuners” and I was intrigued. Up until that point, I hadn’t heard of anything like this in Second Life.

So of course I ordered myself a custom car, and met the person who was building. We grew close to 


each other and eventually ended up in a Second Life relationship, which is right around the time that I made myself a little company called “Greasfox,” where I took empty car shells and built them into tuners (as I learned how to do so, in-part to my partner at the time and her help) and then sold them on the marketplace.

Occasionally, I’d get custom car requests. This made me a small amount of money on a weekly basis. We’re talking small amount of lindens, and then what I made I spent on clothing or furry stuff. 

Greasfox moved from a parcel and a cheap garage to my partner’s Homestead sim where I setup shop, but Greasfox only lasted for about a month or so, before my partner and I decided to merge our existing businesses into one that would be called Full Carbon.



Full Carbon started in the same way that both of our businesses were being run. We built cars from empty shells and took custom requests, eventually moving from the homestead to a private parcel with a house and a garage.

This particular phase lasted for a month or so while we made a little more money than, at least, I was used to making.

I think this was around the time that I saw the real potential that Second Life had, and what I could possibly do in order to support myself and my real life endeavors.

Having made enough money to move from our cheaper place, we bought a third of a sim and built a space station that became quite popular among the drift (a form of racing) team we’d started, which is called Moxie Drift Team, still, to this day (as is Full Carbon, a now registered trademark).

The idea was that we’d build cars on this station where we’d setup a mainstore and a scifi roleplay hangout area. We attracted more visitors than we were used to, but this was lucrative for our business at the time.

The station, though, the Infinitum SR2, this was something that I held dearly (and am tentatively rebuilding on my own to sell as a mesh skybox). It was my dream in Second Life, at that moment in time, to virtually live on a station in space and run my own roleplay community. Unfortunately though, like many things, this station’s life came to an eventual end, as did my relationship with my partner after six months, a third iteration of the space station itself and an attempt to fix what we had, which was far beyond repair. As it turns out, mixing business and romance is a recipe for disaster.



On the days that followed the end of our relationship, I lost my ties to Full Carbon, Full Carbon Auto and Moxie Drift Team altogether, but that’s okay, because I was starting something new, anyway.

After revamping my marketplace store to be less reflective of the previous business I’d been involved with and something new that I was cooking up, I rented a small parcel and setup a garage type loft apartment. Here I began work on, once again, custom tuner cars that I would slap inside of boxes and sell on a table outside of my apartment (which I also listed in the SL search database haha).

This business of mine came to be called REVosa, which was around the same point in time that I abandoned the idea of using furry avatars and silently removed myself from that community (mostly, besides the friends that I still have within it) due to many different personal reasons.

As I built my new business, which would only have direct ties to myself (in order to ensure that I 


would never lose the rights to my work again), I met a new friend (wink, wink) who would help me both with my personal parcel and a fledgling mainstore in the Pisces region (where it still exists today). Getting quite exhausted with making cars, I opened up Blender one day earlier this year and began to screw around with shapes, which morphed into a month of teaching myself (with a little help from friends) how to use this particular 3D modeling software and what I could do with it.

From that point in May, 2015, up to where we are now, I filled my store with many different nick-nacks and fun little things, learned how to design clothing and learned how to weight paint and rig clothing for Second Life.

By the time we hit September 2015, I’d have sold enough products to fund my shop without real world influence (besides my skill in Blender and my aforementioned friend, now also business partner) and have managed to seed many very small shops in the name of my business, through 40% profit affiliate vendors. I even have my own streaming radio spot running! (Listen here: https://soundcloud.com/lulavauss/revosa-ad1)

It’s been six months since I started REVOSA, and although my shop, my business aren’t as big as some of the others out there that have been running for a much longer period of time, I know that REVOSA will lead the way. What an interesting time it’s been in what, only a year ago, was what I considered to be a pretty dull virtual world without much in the way of things to do (I was wrong, very wrong).

And, even though the Infinitum SR2 and SR3 are gone, for now, there’s always Afterlife, club, bar and hangout, a brand new place that I manage (and am currently attempting to drive traffic into).

But that’s it for now. REV it up, baby.

-ℒula ℒaValette  (merylimperil)

Marketplace store: https://marketplace.secondlife.com/stores/165186

Inworld store: http://maps.secondlife.com/secondlife/Pisces/172/239/29

</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Sep 2015 20:22:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/second%20life/2015/09/22/revosa-a-6-month-milestone-taking-a-look-back</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[NEW] REVOSA GIVE BLOOD Tshirt</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4000/second%20life/2015/09/22/new-revosa-give-blood-tshirt.html</link>
      <description>
&amp;nbsp;



Marketplace listing: https://marketplace.secondlife.com/p/REVOSA-GIVE-BLOOD-Tshirt-4-sizes/7779387Inworld store: http://maps.secondlife.com/secondlife/Pisces/172/239/29 

</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Sep 2015 18:16:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/second%20life/2015/09/22/new-revosa-give-blood-tshirt</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[NEW] REVOSA Cybernetic Carapace</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4000/second%20life/2015/09/21/new-revosa-cybernetic-carapace.html</link>
      <description>
&amp;nbsp;


Marketplace listing: https://marketplace.secondlife.com/p/REVOSA-Cybernetic-Carapace-Standard-Stained-Metal-Carbon/7775335

Inworld store: http://maps.secondlife.com/secondlife/Pisces/172/239/29
</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Sep 2015 22:47:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/second%20life/2015/09/21/new-revosa-cybernetic-carapace</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>REVOSA CyberLegs</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4000/second%20life/2015/09/20/revosa-cyberlegs.html</link>
      <description>
&amp;nbsp;



Marketplace listing: https://marketplace.secondlife.com/p/REVOSA-CyberLegs-v12-Carbon-Honeycomb-Metal/7770195

Inworld store: http://maps.secondlife.com/secondlife/Pisces/172/239/29 

</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Sep 2015 22:52:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/second%20life/2015/09/20/revosa-cyberlegs</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[WIP] REVOSA CyberLegs</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4000/second%20life/2015/09/20/wip-revosa-cyberlegs.html</link>
      <description>

Some might ask, “What’s Lula working on today?” Well, if you’re one of those people, you might like this new product I’m working on that has been a long time in the making, and quite secret as well.

In testing right now are a pair of cybernetic legs, rigged and ready to go. All I’ve left to do is apply three or four textures and…figure out how to make a texture changing HUD! Because that’s something I’ve never been able to do before (didn’t know how), but for a product like this I believe it is totally necessary to have options.

The legs, of course, will be low-leg oriented and most likely priced around the range of 500 linden or so. My avatar is a Maitreya body, and as you can see from the photo, they mostly fit perfectly. I assume this means they’ll work with TMP and Slink, but I’ll have to make sure before I put the finishing touches on them.

That’s it for now! I’ll return later with, hopefully, a finishing product!

Inworld store: http://maps.secondlife.com/secondlife/Pisces/172/239/29
Marketplace store: https://marketplace.secondlife.com/stores/165186
</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Sep 2015 16:56:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/second%20life/2015/09/20/wip-revosa-cyberlegs</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stop by the REVOSA mainstore and check out the new Gatcha!</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4000/second%20life/2015/09/20/stop-by-the-revosa-mainstore-and-check-out-the-new-gatcha.html</link>
      <description>
&amp;nbsp;



Find the source for REVOSA gatcha only at the mainstore: REVOSA Mainstore and Blood Bank

</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Sep 2015 03:19:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/second%20life/2015/09/20/stop-by-the-revosa-mainstore-and-check-out-the-new-gatcha</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>REVOSA Cardigan Jacket [Black Fabric]</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4000/second%20life/2015/09/19/revosa-cardigan-jacket-black-fabric.html</link>
      <description>
&amp;nbsp;


Marketplace listing: REVOSA Cardigan Jacket [Black Fabric]
Inworld store: REVOSA Mainstore and Blood Bank
</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Sep 2015 00:55:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/second%20life/2015/09/19/revosa-cardigan-jacket-black-fabric</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[WIP] REVOSA Cardigan/Jacket</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4000/second%20life/2015/09/18/wip-revosa-cardigan-jacket.html</link>
      <description>

So for the past day and a quarter now I’ve been working on my first serious piece of clothing for my store. It’s been a lot of re-topology, a lot of mesh cleanup, a lot of screwing around with frustrating UV maps and now I’m attempting to size it correctly.

Since this is my first attempt at actually making something wearable, it’ll likely be priced on the low-end of the average clothing scale, and as I gain experience, prices will likely increase by a small margin.

As you can see, the mesh itself looks pretty clean, but if you bring up the wiremesh, it’s sort of messy. I’ve done what I believe I can do in order to clean it up as much as possible.

The next step I have to work through is resizing parts of the jacket itself, since, for some weird 


reason, it no longer fits the average avatar. The backside clips into the butt and the arms are too long, therefore cutting into the hands. The arms themselves clip into the avatar’s skin, but I’ll be creating an alpha to fix that problem.

Since I use the Maitreya body on my avatar, I’ll be working to fit it best around this template, even though the Maitreya creators have yet to respond to my requests for the templates they use. So it’s basically guess work and lots of mesh stretching.

As for making clothing in general, since, at the moment, it’s a pretty long process for me, I’ll probably be building a clothing line rather slowly. I actually have a full line of things I was making in the past, but my biggest hurdle has always been weight painting. In theory, I don’t have to create anything else from scratch for a while, if I should go back and fix the twenty some outfits I’ve made!

That’s it for now though, aside from another product I’m working on which is much simpler than clothing… A vampire turning altar. This item is projected to be low land impact, but since I haven’t started much of it yet, I don’t have anything to show in regards to that product.

But as always, thank you for reading!

Marketplace store: REVOSA Sex, Mesh, Murder
Inworld store. REVOSA Mainstore and Blood bank
</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Sep 2015 18:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/second%20life/2015/09/18/wip-revosa-cardigan-jacket</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing REVOSA</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4000/second%20life/2015/09/17/introducing-revosa.html</link>
      <description>Welcome to the brand new REVOSA blog! REVOSA is a Second Life based business that specializes in scifi, fantasy, modern and vampire themed accessories, furniture, homes, vehicles and much more!

Since this is my first post here on the REVOSA blog, I’m going to talk about all of the products I’ve 


done this week, starting with the Bleeding Rose.

This Bleeding Rose is a 100% original mesh home decor accessory with a land impact of only one. The blood drip particle animation is also simple, and extremely low lag. You can check for yourself! This should be a good addition to any vampire’s home, or otherwise anyone who enjoys the darker side of life, or second life, for that matter.

The marketplace listing for this item can be found here.



Which brings us to my next, not-so-bloody product, a transgender pride bracelet. I made this as a way to show my support for the transgender community, and to raise awareness for the plight of equal rights in the United States. As it stands today, the transgender community is currently, and still, one of the most marginalized communities in the world.

If you view the product page, there you can find even more information about the struggles that face the average transgender person. Show your support! At a cool 50 linden, it’s a steal anyway!
Marketplace listing for the trans pride bracelet can be found here.

Next up is one of my favorite products that I’ve done yet! This is dubbed “Tome of the Damned,” with an obvious vampire theme. The book, which is 100% original mesh, comes in its package with 


three different versions. The first version is a simple prop, the book, which you can place anywhere that you please. The second version is a wearable book that your avatar will hug is if it were a cuddly teddy bear. And then the final version of this product comes with a bonus lectern stand with the book already attached! All versions of this product are only one land impact.

This product is one of many in a long line of vampire themed accessories I would like to make (including an entire turning altar). 

Marketplace listing for the Tome of the Damned is here.



Second to last on the list is another favorite product of mine, a remake of the very first item I ever made in Second life, the Kill Trophy Box. Although, the first version of this was made entirely out of prims and added up to about seven land impact (lol!), the new and improved version, celebrating 8 months of REVOSA, is only two land impact. Not only that, it comes with a low-lag open and close script. Simply click the lid and it will either open, or close depending on what state the box is currently in.

Being a big fan of the television show, Dexter, this was really fun to make, and I was surprised at what the final product came out as. The Kill Trophy Box can be found here.

Last on this week’s list (or at least, so far) is a simple candelabra that I decided to make, which fits in quite well with the Tome of the Damned and Lectern. Alternatively, this would likely fit well in any


vampire or dark fantasy setting. As with all of my items (or mostly all of them) this product is copy and modifiable. At a land impact of 6 this should be fine just about anywhere.

The flickering particle flames adorned at the top of each candle can be toggled on and off with a simple click of your mouse.

REVOSA Candelabra is available for 75 linden here.

And that just about wraps up my first post for this blog! Later I plan on writing another significantly large post about exactly how REVOSA came to be, where it started and where the exclusive Second Life business is now. As always, thank you for your interest in my products! Rev it up baby!

Inworld store: REVOSA Mainstore and Blood Bank
Marketplace store: REVOSA Sex, Mesh, Murder
</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Sep 2015 20:43:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/second%20life/2015/09/17/introducing-revosa</guid>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>