<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en-US"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.10.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en-US" /><updated>2025-01-09T23:10:15-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">cmdr-nova@internet:~$</title><subtitle>cmdr-nova&apos;s personal blog and home on the indie-web.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Second Life: No, You Don’t Get to Dictate What Creators Do</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/second-life/2025/01/09/second-life-no-you-don-t-get-to-dictate-what-creators-do.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Second Life: No, You Don’t Get to Dictate What Creators Do" /><published>2025-01-09T22:11:00-05:00</published><updated>2025-01-09T22:11:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/second-life/2025/01/09/second-life-no-you-don-t-get-to-dictate-what-creators-do</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/second-life/2025/01/09/second-life-no-you-don-t-get-to-dictate-what-creators-do.html"><![CDATA[<p>In Second Life, anyone can be a creator, and make their creations available to the virtual world for purchase, and some have found major success with this. Others, it exists, maybe, as more of a hobby. For me, that’s mostly what it is, for now. But this all comes with a downside, because, like in the real world, the customer sometimes thinks they know best, and if you’ve ever worked retail, you know how very wrong that is.</p>

<p>I touched on this topic a little bit via Mastodon while I was on break at work, but I wanted to break it down in more detail, because this is a problem I see a lot of in Second Life. I’m not saying this is <em>every person in the virtual world who buys things</em>, but it is more or less, a pretty pervasive idea that I don’t think gets challenged enough. But, to break <em>that</em> down, basically, when people sell things in Second Life, you can sell it with permissions that allow a buyer to modify your content to their liking. You can <em>also</em> choose not to do this, in order to keep your work the way it is when it’s sold (especially if you want to sell different variations, which is, again, entirely up to the creator). Some people have a <em>very big problem</em> with the latter …</p>

<p><img src="/img/posts/sl-stores/IMG_8137.jpg" /></p>

<p>This is a screenshot of a Reddit post that got a lot of traction … a lot of people in agreement, and because Reddit is a place where dissenting opinions get buried and heckled, I felt it a good idea to write it all up here. So, let’s tear this apart, shall we?</p>

<blockquote>
As I'm customising my avatar more and getting more creative. I'm realising that there's no good reason for 99% of clothing to be non mod Perm (especially if it's a fatpack).
</blockquote>

<p>A lot of this language will probably be pretty alien to people who don’t peruse Second Life, so … “fatpack” is something creators make that contain all variations of a certain product, such as a shirt. We’ll go with that. So, a creator makes a black shirt, and a white shirt, and then maybe five other colors, and they sell them all individually. Then, what they’ll do, is they’ll make a pack that contains all of them together, along with, maybe, a couple bonuses for buying that pack, i.e., a “fatpack.”</p>

<p>I don’t see any real problem with this, but we’ll get into that when I’m done here.</p>

<p>This Redditor believes there’s “no good reason” for most clothing to not to be modifiable by the buyer. And I say, there is a good reason! If a creator <em>wants</em> to sell their virtual clothing in specific colors, patterns and textures, and not allow people to change this, that’s up to them! You are <em>not</em> the person running the store. You are not the person <em>creating</em> these things. And <em>most of it</em> is sold for prices <em>below</em> 2000 linden.</p>

<p>A fatpack will usually run anywhere between 600 to 1200 linden. And maybe you’re thinking, “Whoa, is that expensive?”</p>

<p>No.</p>

<p>Some people look at that pricing, <em>within</em> Second Life, and they’ll call it expensive. They always do. But why don’t we look at the actual exchange rate.</p>

<p><img src="/img/posts/sl-stores/Screenshot from 2025-01-09 22-29-48.png" /></p>

<p>So … for less than a value meal at McDonalds, or a cup of coffee at Starbucks, you can buy an entire set of clothing? For a little bit less than 5 dollars USD?</p>

<p>Another way to look at this, is that people are spending <em>hours</em> and <em>hours</em> on making clothing and accessories for people to buy, to customize their avatars, and to spice up their little virtual lives, <em>for almost nothing</em>. For less than a Fiverr gig. When, in the real world, if I were making you a custom 3D modeled product for a <em>game</em>, with complete textures, UV mapping, skeleton rigging, and weight painting … I would charge you <em>at least 500 dollars</em>.</p>

<p>Fortunately, we’re talking about Second Life, where all of that work is done behind-the-scenes, and people sell things at prices that are easily digestible to the masses, which, I think <em>is beyond fair.</em> It’s almost highway robbery.</p>

<blockquote>
Removing hidden faces, unliking and linking items is a must. Especially because you often start running against attachment limits.
</blockquote>

<p>We step into the next point of this user’s argument, in that, their perceived issue, is that clothing in link-sets should be able to be de-linked, because sometimes you run into an issue where your avatar has <em>too many attachments</em>, and you can’t wear something that you want. And, a linkset, is basically just <em>gluing</em> different items together so that they count more as one, but, even in doing that, they still cost server resources.</p>

<p>So you can only attach so many resources to your avatar until you hit that limit, you know, so that you don’t become a walking DDoS.</p>

<p>But … what’s the attachment limit in 2025, for a Second Life avatar?</p>

<p>Quoted directly from the <a href="https://wiki.secondlife.com/wiki/Limits#:~:text=general%20inworld%20experience.-,Avatar,and%20choosing%20Edit%20My%20Outfit." target="_blank">Second Life Wiki</a>, “Max. # of attachments - 38 combined HUD and body attachments.”</p>

<p>An outfit someone might wear, will usually consist of a top, a bottom, and maybe shoes. So we’re talking … three to four attachment points. But then, of course, you have to account for your body, whether the hands and feet are separate, your hair, maybe custom eyes, and even fingernails.</p>

<p>So what would that run you?</p>

<p>To be generous, we’ll just say … 15. Even though that’s more than what I’ve listed, we’ll go with 15, to be fair to the original quoted post.</p>

<p>You’ve <em>still got 23 additional attachment points</em>.</p>

<p>Now, some people like to wear HUDs, like body HUDs that make hiding texture faces on your body easier (although, I’m not sure why you would wear this at all times), or gaming HUDs, like a system that makes it so your avatar is a vampire, or sexual HUDs that make your virtual life a little more … spicy. And, of course, you probably walk around with the HUD for your head on, at least, <em>sometimes</em>, so that you can control your eye and mouth movements.</p>

<p>But … that’s like, maybe 3 to 5 more attachment points.</p>

<p>You’ve still got a lot to go.</p>

<p>I can’t remember if server weight is counted in addition to attachment points, but we’ll just say, <em>it is</em>, and some of these attachments are taking up multiple points. Odds are, you’ve still got room to put more stuff on your avatar.</p>

<p>My point here, is that, <em>in most cases</em>, this is a complete non-issue, and it’s an excuse being made in order to aid the original argument. That creator’s should do what non-creator’s say, or else. And maybe you’re thinking, “Wh … what do you mean by that?”</p>

<p>Just wait.</p>

<blockquote>
When you're new, you don't care and I think it's a bit cash grabby to sell non mod Items with shiny branding pages and stores.
<br /><br />
There are so many stores that are less shiny on the outside but their stuff is amazing and mod Perm.
</blockquote>

<p>I’m going to tackle both of these points together, because this is already pretty long. So. This kind of circles back to my point on pricing, and how <em>utterly entitled it is</em> to say that creators in Second Life are pushing out “cash grabs” when they decide they want to sell specific colors and designs, that you can’t rip out and replace with … whatever.</p>

<p>That sounds, not just entitled, but … and this is a little ironic, but <em>greedy</em>.</p>

<p>I’m not sure what being “new” has to do with this.</p>

<p>But then in their continued final point, basically, stores that aren’t flashy and less established are, apparently, more inclined to sell their products with the ability to tear things apart, and do with them whatever a customer pleases. And hey, that’s also fine! If someone wants to sell their products in a way that makes it so customers can do whatever they want, go ahead!</p>

<p>There is no wrong way to be a creator in Second Life, and you can do whatever you want, <em>because it is your work.</em></p>

<p>And now, we’re going to circle back to my comment that hinted at an ultimatum …</p>

<p><img src="/img/posts/sl-stores/Screenshot from 2025-01-09 22-56-08.png" /></p>

<p>So, and this is also a point I’ve seen come up elsewhere, in that, and I’m going to be blunt, these <em>entitled as all hell people</em>, are trying to say that if a creator sells their work in a way that you can’t modify it, this <em>incentivizes</em> people to steal. To use ToS breaking scripts to rip your work out of Second Life, and to then re-upload it so that anything they want to do with it, can be done, for <em>free</em>.</p>

<p>It’s no secret that there are unscrupulous, grifting, uncreative, jerks out there in the world. We know this, <em>especially now</em>, because of generative AI. But to say that creators should let you tear their work apart, or have it stolen … That’s just ridiculous. It’s <em>especially</em> ridiculous, when you realize that there <em>are</em> people stealing work in Second Life, that costs, <em>most of the time</em>, less than five dollars to have.</p>

<p>When I say, there are some petty, entitled people in Second Life, <strong>I mean it</strong>.</p>

<p><em>A large majority of work sold on the Second Life marketplace goes for less than even a dollar, sometimes 30 to 50 cents!</em></p>

<p>And there are people <em>threatening to steal the work of these creators</em>, because they want to color the shirt you made baby-puke green.</p>

<p>I have enjoyed running a store in Second Life for 10 years, and I’ll continue to do so, in exactly the way that I want, with complete disregard for what people like this think. Because they need hobbies. They need things to occupy themselves.</p>

<p>They remind me of the people who walk into Walmarts with shitty attitudes, who yell at staff about pricing, and about item availability, and then stomp their feet and whine like a baby.</p>

<p>Because that’s what they are.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Second-Life" /><category term="secondlife" /><category term="metaverse" /><category term="creators" /><category term="stores" /><category term="virtualworld" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[In Second Life, anyone can be a creator, and make their creations available to the virtual world for purchase, and some have found major success with this. Others, it exists, maybe, as more of a hobby. For me, that’s mostly what it is, for now. But this all comes with a downside, because, like in the real world, the customer sometimes thinks they know best, and if you’ve ever worked retail, you know how very wrong that is.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">MKMO (mkultra.monster) Now Blocks Federation with Threads, Once, and For All</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/social-media/2025/01/07/mkmo-mkultra-monster-now-blocks-federation-with-threads-once-and-for-all.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="MKMO (mkultra.monster) Now Blocks Federation with Threads, Once, and For All" /><published>2025-01-07T13:21:00-05:00</published><updated>2025-01-07T13:21:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/social-media/2025/01/07/mkmo-mkultra-monster-now-blocks-federation-with-threads-once-and-for-all</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/social-media/2025/01/07/mkmo-mkultra-monster-now-blocks-federation-with-threads-once-and-for-all.html"><![CDATA[<p>As per <a class="pages-link" href="https://nova.mkultra.monster/social-media/2025/01/07/meta-to-end-fact-checking-to-become-twitter-2-or-3">my last post</a> this morning (in regard to Meta’s loosening of moderation, as if it wasn’t already loose enough), I, as the admin of <a href="https://mkultra.monster" target="_blank">mkultra.monster</a>, will be blocking federation with Threads. For a long period of time, I hadn’t been doing this, partially because I don’t like bandwagons, and also because there are <em>regular, decent</em> people on Threads that I personally wanted to see. But, now it’s a bit more than a lost cause, and the social network is nothing <em>but</em> a detriment to the open social web.</p>

<p>The people I liked seeing updates from will just have to move to Mastodon, or some other fediverse software.</p>

<p>But, the other reason I wanted to post this, is because there are a lot of people who trot out their reasoning, or why they’ve blocked them from the start. Whether it’s performative or not, I remained skeptical for a long period of time. Skeptical, because I have experience from within the fediverse of numerous people, moderators, and admins saying one thing, or that they <em>stand</em> for one thing, and then they do the opposite.</p>

<p>And this has made me <em>more</em> critical, <em>more</em> skeptical, and <em>more</em> distrusting of others.</p>

<p>Yes, I have spoken about this before, but since it’s been about a year or so (or more?) since this all happened, I want to <em>again</em> bring light to the actions of the administrator and moderation team behind the Mastodon instance … hackers.town.</p>

<p>It was some time around August 25th of 2023, that I was posting on my timeline over at HT about … I don’t know, something to do with how resilient my Macbook was. I was kind of stanning Apple real hard around that time, just because I enjoyed/liked their hardware. Never-the-less, a user by the name of 0xSH00T (who now, at least, appears to be banned and erased, over a <em>year</em> later) jumped in to make some vitriolic remarks about myself, my having posted on the timeline, and my choice in hardware.</p>

<p>It was a <em>stupid</em> thing to get angry about, and it was a <em>stupid</em> thing to troll someone over.</p>

<p>He escalated, <em>I</em> escalated, and I don’t claim to be of perfect cognitive or mental health. <em>I have my issues</em>, and I deal with them.</p>

<p>I told him, and I quote, “Go fuck yourself, eat a pile of dicks and delete your goddamn account.”</p>

<p>Yes, this is kind of … haha, ANGRY.</p>

<p>And I had every right to be.</p>

<p>In a direct message that no longer contains the originating message from the admin (@thegibson), I responded, “I’m here minding my own business mostly just talking to myself, and this person comes into my mentions swinging, I’m not tolerating any both sides-ing bullshit. Delete the instigator or I’m out.”</p>

<p>Because, he and his mod-team, very much <em>were</em> playing the “both sides” card. In response to a troll, who was, in fact, instigating a fight.</p>

<p>I didn’t really <em>want</em> to leave hackers.town (and I wouldn’t have, anyway, I just wanted the troll to, at minimum, be moderated). I was in a blood-haze, and kind of spiraling a bit. Just like when it happened on the instance over at deadinsi.de, where just about the same things had gone on, and the admin and moderator team had a lapse in judgment. That’s … that’s what we’ll call it, I guess.</p>

<p>I made an off-the-cuff post about PTSD, I told Gibson again something like, “either you ban this asshole, or you ban me” and rather than doing any real moderation work, I was, of course, banned.</p>

<p>This was not the outcome I <em>thought</em> would take place. At least not at the time.</p>

<p>Again, I was spiraling. I was in a much worse mental place than I am now.</p>

<p><em>Of course</em>, I shouldn’t have been banned. If someone is having a break in mental health, and spiraling out (crashing out, as the zoomers would say) over being harassed over and over, as a responsible administrator, or moderator, <em>you take action against the instigator, no matter the personal relationship you hold with them.</em></p>

<p>Over this <em>tiny</em>, insignificant instance of abuse, I lost <em>years</em> of my presence on the fediverse, <em>indefinitely</em>. There were never any talks or apologies once the dust had settled. There was never any further action taken, appeals never read, never looked at, never considered. And yet, for <em>whatever reason</em>, my account still stands, frozen in time (suspended, but viewable), and now linking to my account on my own instance … <em>where this type of thing will never happen</em>.</p>

<p>You cannot call yourself an instance, a server, that is tolerant, and forward-thinking, and “for the people,” if your personal relationships come first. Especially if those personal relationships are with instigative assholes who shouldn’t exist on your platform. This is going to sound really self-absorbed, but <em>I am a better administrator and moderator than anyone at hackers.town by 1000 miles,</em> and I will stand by that, into the future. Because I will never let this happen.</p>

<p>Even if my server is only ever myself, and one other person, trolls will never gain the upper-hand, because I will never make excuses for anyone who’s being a shit.</p>

<p>And that’s why, when people start posting on the federated timeline, about how bad you are if you don’t, or haven’t had Threads blocked, I have to stop and question: Is there an ulterior motive here? Should I <em>care</em> what any of these people think? What have they done in their positions that they likely haven’t answered for?</p>

<p>And, thankfully, in a lot of instances, none of this applies. They’re just thoughts … most of the time.</p>

<p>But there are people out there in the fediverse who are <em>just as bad</em> as the people you’d hope to escape by leaving Twitter, or Threads, and I think it’s important to realize that no place is perfect. The open social web, Mastodon, and ActivityPub is something I will continue to, and <em>always</em> support. But … it’s important to know that it’s not all just roses and candy.</p>

<p>Jerks, and people not fit to moderate, exist, <em>everywhere</em>.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Social-Media" /><category term="mastodon" /><category term="fediverse" /><category term="meta" /><category term="threads" /><category term="facebook" /><category term="instagram" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[As per my last post this morning (in regard to Meta’s loosening of moderation, as if it wasn’t already loose enough), I, as the admin of mkultra.monster, will be blocking federation with Threads. For a long period of time, I hadn’t been doing this, partially because I don’t like bandwagons, and also because there are regular, decent people on Threads that I personally wanted to see. But, now it’s a bit more than a lost cause, and the social network is nothing but a detriment to the open social web.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Meta to End Fact-Checking to Become Twitter 2, or 3?</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/social-media/2025/01/07/meta-to-end-fact-checking-to-become-twitter-2-or-3.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Meta to End Fact-Checking to Become Twitter 2, or 3?" /><published>2025-01-07T10:37:00-05:00</published><updated>2025-01-07T10:37:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/social-media/2025/01/07/meta-to-end-fact-checking-to-become-twitter-2-or-3</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/social-media/2025/01/07/meta-to-end-fact-checking-to-become-twitter-2-or-3.html"><![CDATA[<p>We all (or most of us) remember when Musk took over Twitter. People got fired, the website became increasingly unstable, the algorithm got tweaked to be less “biased” toward fascist propaganda, lies, and hate, and then everyone left in droves. Then, in response to this, Meta launched Threads, a Twitter alternative. And it was actually <em>nice</em> … for a time. About a year ago. But then Trump got elected, and like billionaires do, Marky Knuckleburger decided that it was time to pander, by eliminating safe-guards against the exact same things that turned Twitter into 4chan 2.</p>

<div class="threads-container">
<blockquote class="text-post-media" data-text-post-permalink="https://www.threads.net/@zuck/post/DEhgZJYJu5D" data-text-post-version="0" id="ig-tp-DEhgZJYJu5D" style=" background:#FFF; border-width: 1px; border-style: solid; border-color: #00000026; border-radius: 16px; max-width:540px; margin: 1px; min-width:270px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);"> <a href="https://www.threads.net/@zuck/post/DEhgZJYJu5D" style=" background:#FFFFFF; line-height:0; padding:0 0; text-align:center; text-decoration:none; width:100%; font-family: -apple-system, BlinkMacSystemFont, sans-serif;" target="_blank"> <div style=" padding: 40px; display: flex; flex-direction: column; align-items: center;"><div style=" display:block; height:32px; width:32px; padding-bottom:20px;"> <svg aria-label="Threads" height="32px" role="img" viewBox="0 0 192 192" width="32px" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg"> <path d="M141.537 88.9883C140.71 88.5919 139.87 88.2104 139.019 87.8451C137.537 60.5382 122.616 44.905 97.5619 44.745C97.4484 44.7443 97.3355 44.7443 97.222 44.7443C82.2364 44.7443 69.7731 51.1409 62.102 62.7807L75.881 72.2328C81.6116 63.5383 90.6052 61.6848 97.2286 61.6848C97.3051 61.6848 97.3819 61.6848 97.4576 61.6855C105.707 61.7381 111.932 64.1366 115.961 68.814C118.893 72.2193 120.854 76.925 121.825 82.8638C114.511 81.6207 106.601 81.2385 98.145 81.7233C74.3247 83.0954 59.0111 96.9879 60.0396 116.292C60.5615 126.084 65.4397 134.508 73.775 140.011C80.8224 144.663 89.899 146.938 99.3323 146.423C111.79 145.74 121.563 140.987 128.381 132.296C133.559 125.696 136.834 117.143 138.28 106.366C144.217 109.949 148.617 114.664 151.047 120.332C155.179 129.967 155.42 145.8 142.501 158.708C131.182 170.016 117.576 174.908 97.0135 175.059C74.2042 174.89 56.9538 167.575 45.7381 153.317C35.2355 139.966 29.8077 120.682 29.6052 96C29.8077 71.3178 35.2355 52.0336 45.7381 38.6827C56.9538 24.4249 74.2039 17.11 97.0132 16.9405C119.988 17.1113 137.539 24.4614 149.184 38.788C154.894 45.8136 159.199 54.6488 162.037 64.9503L178.184 60.6422C174.744 47.9622 169.331 37.0357 161.965 27.974C147.036 9.60668 125.202 0.195148 97.0695 0H96.9569C68.8816 0.19447 47.2921 9.6418 32.7883 28.0793C19.8819 44.4864 13.2244 67.3157 13.0007 95.9325L13 96L13.0007 96.0675C13.2244 124.684 19.8819 147.514 32.7883 163.921C47.2921 182.358 68.8816 191.806 96.9569 192H97.0695C122.03 191.827 139.624 185.292 154.118 170.811C173.081 151.866 172.51 128.119 166.26 113.541C161.776 103.087 153.227 94.5962 141.537 88.9883ZM98.4405 129.507C88.0005 130.095 77.1544 125.409 76.6196 115.372C76.2232 107.93 81.9158 99.626 99.0812 98.6368C101.047 98.5234 102.976 98.468 104.871 98.468C111.106 98.468 116.939 99.0737 122.242 100.233C120.264 124.935 108.662 128.946 98.4405 129.507Z" /></svg></div><div style=" font-size: 15px; line-height: 21px; color: #000000; font-weight: 600; "> View on Threads</div></div></a></blockquote>
<script async="" src="https://www.threads.net/embed.js"></script>
</div>

<p>I’m not saying that community notes on Twitter have been a <em>bad thing</em>, because they’ve actually been pretty funny when its been used against liars and people who fabricate situations in order to embolden hate. But, it’s the context, and the reasons you have to look at. Mack Fucklenarg has never been genuine or progressively-inclined about anything he’s ever done. From building The Facebook, which was originally <a href="https://www.eviemagazine.com/post/before-facebook-zuckerberg-created-a-girl-rating-site-facemash" target="_blank">a website used to rate the “hotness” of girls in college</a>, to seemingly condemning the acts of the January 6th terrorists.</p>

<p><img src="/img/posts/meta-censors/jan6.jpg" /></p>

<p>This was, and you guessed it, manipulative pandering to the incoming administration.</p>

<p>Fark Bafflenard doesn’t have <em>any core beliefs</em>. Like all billionaires, he follows the money, and he follows his own interests in not wanting to be potentially arrested and imprisoned by the currently incoming administration. It is only a complete coincidence if your beliefs and your virtues <em>ever</em> line up with what Mark Zugzugsomethingneeddoing is currently doing, or saying.</p>

<p>Right now, those actions are lining up with the same criminals and potential mass shooters that Twitter harbors. And that’s a bad thing. A bad thing for people who enjoy posting within a civilized atmosphere that at least attempts to pretend that we’re living in 2025, and not 1825.</p>

<p>If, in 4 years, a straight-up communist is somehow elected, I’m almost entirely <em>sure</em> that Marky-Mark would make statements on how Meta and its properties will release control of its production means to its users.</p>

<p>It’s just as pathetic as Diamond-Mine Musk using memes from 15 years ago in an attempt to impress neo nazis who are in their 40s and 50s.</p>

<p>Men who go through life believing in nothing, who hold insurmountable amounts of power over mass amounts of people, will be the downfall of civilized society.</p>

<p>But, despite all of Meta’s mistakes, its family of apps hold more than <a href="https://variety.com/2024/digital/news/meta-q4-2023-earnings-record-revenue-monthly-users-1235894587/" target="_blank">3.98 billion users</a> (as of February 1st, 2024), and that’s a staggering amount of people. That’s about half of the entire world’s popu-frikken-lation. And while I’ve seen the usual round of people promising they’re moving to Bluesky (which is honestly not even much better of a platform), I don’t think there is <em>any way</em> in any shape or form, that you will <em>ever</em> convince half the world’s population to join Mastodon, or even the Twitter-carbon-copy, Bluesky.</p>

<p>Like with most things, the average user only cares about ease of use, and if you can sign up for Threads by already having an Instagram account, that eliminates the process of even just setting up an account. You’re already there! An advantage that Meta has over <em>all other platforms</em>. And this is why I think it is incredibly important that Mastodon, and other ActivityPub apps and projects, work toward simplifying the onboarding process even more than they already have.</p>

<p>It is imperative to get as many people off of propaganda platforms as humanly possible, because, the annoying people from 2017 Tumblr … were correct, after-all.</p>

<p><img src="/img/posts/meta-censors/propaganda.png" /></p>]]></content><author><name>𐕣 C M D R ░ NOVA 𐕣</name></author><category term="Social-Media" /><category term="meta" /><category term="threads" /><category term="facebook" /><category term="instagram" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[We all (or most of us) remember when Musk took over Twitter. People got fired, the website became increasingly unstable, the algorithm got tweaked to be less “biased” toward fascist propaganda, lies, and hate, and then everyone left in droves. Then, in response to this, Meta launched Threads, a Twitter alternative. And it was actually nice … for a time. About a year ago. But then Trump got elected, and like billionaires do, Marky Knuckleburger decided that it was time to pander, by eliminating safe-guards against the exact same things that turned Twitter into 4chan 2.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Second Life: [REVOSA] Has Moved!</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/second-life/2025/01/06/irsecond-life-revosa-has-moved.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Second Life: [REVOSA] Has Moved!" /><published>2025-01-06T13:18:00-05:00</published><updated>2025-01-06T13:18:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/second-life/2025/01/06/irsecond-life-revosa-has-moved</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/second-life/2025/01/06/irsecond-life-revosa-has-moved.html"><![CDATA[<p>Keeping up with my finnicky tradition of always moving my store around in Second Life about once every six months (at this point), I’ve transferred land ownership back to the account that <em>actually runs the store</em>, and moved to a better parcel! This comes, after realizing I made a huge mistake with my finances in relation to Linden Labs, and being someone who uses <em>multiple accounts</em>. That’s a big oof on my part.</p>

<p>Still with all the same products, and room to add more, you can now find my Second Life store, in-world, <a href="http://maps.secondlife.com/secondlife/Necrotee/218/233/3551" target="_blank">here</a>.</p>

<p>I made this move, because I wasn’t too happy with the tiny amount of space I had in the old spot, and I was shuffling around expenses and found out … I’ve been paying Linden Labs for a large amount of land for probably <em>well over a year</em>, unknowingly. Being that, I somehow <em>forgot</em> that I was doing this. So, I moved everything around, found a new location, put the store online <em>in that new location</em>, and then turned off all transactions on my alt account.</p>

<p>Now … the only account paying for anything, <em>should be the account running the store!</em></p>

<p>Whew.</p>

<p>Anyway, on-wards and forwards into the new year!</p>]]></content><author><name>𐕣 C M D R ░ NOVA 𐕣</name></author><category term="Second-Life" /><category term="secondlife" /><category term="revosa" /><category term="metaverse" /><category term="virtualworld" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Keeping up with my finnicky tradition of always moving my store around in Second Life about once every six months (at this point), I’ve transferred land ownership back to the account that actually runs the store, and moved to a better parcel! This comes, after realizing I made a huge mistake with my finances in relation to Linden Labs, and being someone who uses multiple accounts. That’s a big oof on my part.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Ironic Use of AI Just Means You’re Not Funny</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/tech/2025/01/06/ironic-use-of-ai-just-means-you-re-not-funny.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Ironic Use of AI Just Means You’re Not Funny" /><published>2025-01-06T09:32:00-05:00</published><updated>2025-01-06T09:32:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/tech/2025/01/06/ironic-use-of-ai-just-means-you-re-not-funny</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/tech/2025/01/06/ironic-use-of-ai-just-means-you-re-not-funny.html"><![CDATA[<p>We’ve all seen it at this point: Chronic shitposters (largely coming from Bluesky) using AI generated imagery to poke fun at the incoming administration, or <em>generative slop users themselves</em>. And, every single time, I imagine these people think they’re doing something productive, or revolutionary, or funny. But here’s the news flash: You’re not. If you wouldn’t use blockchain tech, or buy NFTs in 2022, then you shouldn’t be generating sludge as a joke, either.</p>

<p>Situations like this remind of me old Mastodon instances in the pre-2020 era of the fediverse, that were erected solely for “shitposting.” They start out funny, or mildly annoying (because, let’s face it, if the only thing you ever post is incoherent jokes, you become tiring after about a day), and usually mostly politically left-leaning. Then, the jokes get worse, and worse. And suddenly, the instance is being flooded with neo nazis and predators, because you decided that ironic fascist jokes weren’t over-the-line. And now you’re just no different than them.</p>

<p>I can just vaguely recall Mastodon instances that were shutdown within months of opening, such as bofa.lol, kazink, and so on. And shitposters.club, a currently active server that is instance-blocked by <em>most</em> instances across the fediverse. <em>All guilty of exactly the same things</em>.</p>

<p>Why do I bring up this comparison?</p>

<p>Partially, because I have a personal grudge against people whose entire personality is shitty jokes (see: the monumentally huge amount of harassment I’ve received on Bluesky for practically no reason at all, from people who have bad taste in humor and politics). But also, because this is an extremely predictable pipeline that <em>always leads to opening the door for undesirables (fascists, crypto-brained losers, sludge-enjoyers)</em>.</p>

<p>This isn’t even the only reason you shouldn’t do this, though! Making yourself indistinguishable from people who have no qualms with the destruction of human creativity, and art is, <em>bad enough</em>, but then you also have to take into account the harm you’re causing the <em>actual literal planet every single time you make a prompt</em>.</p>

<p>Quote from <a href="https://www.watertechnologies.com/blog/artificial-intelligence-using-ton-water-heres-how-be-more-resourceful" target="_blank">watertech.com</a>:</p>

<blockquote>
Artificial intelligence (AI) quickly went from a neat parlor trick to a business imperative. IBM reports that 82% of large enterprises have either deployed AI or are experimenting with doing so. Unlike other technology innovations like smartphones or WiFi networks, AI isn’t a one-time integration. The technology is constantly evolving with new models and capabilities.
<br />
<br />
Each time these AI tools are prompted, there’s a cost that few consider. Researchers believe that each string of prompts uses roughly 16 ounces of water at data centers that house these AI systems. Extrapolate AI use globally, and it’s clear how water systems are taxed. Microsoft’s latest environmental report shows its water consumption jumped 34% from 2021 to 2022, reaching nearly 1.7 billion gallons. Google reports its water consumption went up nearly 22% over the same period to a staggering 5.56 billion gallons, about 800 times as big as The Lincoln Memorial reflecting pool.
</blockquote>

<p>And that doesn’t even mention the carbon dioxide generated from the fossil-fuel powered electricity that we use, that <em>has already been melting the ice caps for about fifty to sixty years, or more</em>.</p>

<p>Some of these people might argue that you do the same amount of harm by charging your smartphone, or running a microwave. But, if that’s true (and those were just crude examples), why in the world would you feel it necessary to <em>double</em> the harm you’re doing by generating some uncanny-valley sludge in response to racist propaganda?</p>

<blockquote class="bluesky-embed" data-bluesky-uri="at://did:plc:pga3jfwjqmilx3od5hsjccty/app.bsky.feed.post/3lf23bad6g222" data-bluesky-cid="bafyreiexgtfgdwrtsr2bddhdk6eby3p3hnafe2qqr2tehhw5bvyyfy4ehm"><p lang="en">OK, it&#x27;s AI...but much truer than Haitians eating your dogs and cats!<br /><br /><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/did:plc:pga3jfwjqmilx3od5hsjccty/post/3lf23bad6g222?ref_src=embed">[image or embed]</a></p>&mdash; eugene (<a href="https://bsky.app/profile/did:plc:pga3jfwjqmilx3od5hsjccty?ref_src=embed">@eugene290390.bsky.social</a>) <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/did:plc:pga3jfwjqmilx3od5hsjccty/post/3lf23bad6g222?ref_src=embed">January 5, 2025 at 9:22 PM</a></blockquote>
<script async="" src="https://embed.bsky.app/static/embed.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>Oh, I see, it’s <em>funny</em>, because Donald Trump is just a drooling baby and Elon Musk is the actual sitting president. Ah.</p>

<p>And you couldn’t have dictated your little joke with <em>words</em>, and a little bit of stock footage? Or, remembered that Joe Biden is still currently in the White House (as of posting this)?</p>

<p>To give some closing perspective, here are some websites and communities that have been willingly (by their creators) destroyed by generative AI.</p>

<ul>
  <li>
    <p><a href="https://www.deviantart.com/tag/ai" target="_blank">DeviantArt</a>: Once a place for artists to share their work, and even sell it, now overrun by inauthentic slop.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p><a href="https://www.etsy.com/seller-handbook/article/1275449912004" target="_blank">Etsy</a>: Once a place for creatives to make money off of the things they make, and do, now a place where you can use algorithmically stolen work, that <em>can’t legally even be copyrighted</em> to make money off the backs of those <em>same exact people</em>.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p><a href="https://www.wired.com/story/nanowrimo-organizers-classist-and-ableist-to-condemn-ai/" target="_blank">NaNoWriMo</a>: Once a fun community event about writing for yourself a 50,000 word novel in the month of November, now fully endorses plagiarism bots. And this is a <em>special</em> case, because they <em>originally</em> called those who are against AI <em>ableist</em>, for not wanting plagiarism and creative theft in writing spaces. And then they doubled back and deleted that statement, and edited it to talk down to those critical of AI as if they’re our angry parents.</p>
  </li>
</ul>

<p>And that’s just to name a few. There are many more spaces and communities that either have already been destroyed by the continuing enshitification of anything good that’s left in the world, by big tech companies, or those that are currently being targeted. This is why <em>so many people</em> have been fleeing corporate social media. And the <em>last</em> thing you should do, is bring it with you, in the form of bad jokes and a vitriolic personality, <em>just to be ironic</em> on Bluesky, or even <em>Mastodon</em>.</p>

<p>Don’t be <em>that</em> douche.</p>]]></content><author><name>𐕣 C M D R ░ NOVA 𐕣</name></author><category term="Tech" /><category term="ai" /><category term="tech" /><category term="bluesky" /><category term="mastodon" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[We’ve all seen it at this point: Chronic shitposters (largely coming from Bluesky) using AI generated imagery to poke fun at the incoming administration, or generative slop users themselves. And, every single time, I imagine these people think they’re doing something productive, or revolutionary, or funny. But here’s the news flash: You’re not. If you wouldn’t use blockchain tech, or buy NFTs in 2022, then you shouldn’t be generating sludge as a joke, either.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Meta Experiments with Digital Blackface</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/social-media/2025/01/04/meta-experiments-with-digital-blackface.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Meta Experiments with Digital Blackface" /><published>2025-01-04T09:52:00-05:00</published><updated>2025-01-04T09:52:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/social-media/2025/01/04/meta-experiments-with-digital-blackface</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/social-media/2025/01/04/meta-experiments-with-digital-blackface.html"><![CDATA[<p>So, last week, I wrote about <a href="/tech/2024/12/30/the-dead-internet-comes-to-life.html">Meta inadvertently planning to confirm the “Dead Internet Theory,”</a> with cringy fake people (AI bots), and how enthusiastic the Zuck was about all of this, despite there being no value, or any verifiable <em>reason</em> for it all to exist. And, almost <em>immediately</em> afterward, scores of people began planning their move away from Threads across the platform (post-2023 social media is just a game of digital hot potato). Other users scoured Instagram and Facebook to find a slew of 20 some bots … including a fake black woman pretending to have a family, and culture.</p>

<p><img src="/img/posts/meta-dead/liv.png" /></p>

<p>As it turns out, these weren’t actually the bots that Meta was planning to implement, rather, they were experiments from over a year ago that nobody noticed and/or completely ignored, until Mark started to bring attention to his next, biggest, worst decision. These profiles are now deleted, as complaints were made against the accounts … <em>because you couldn’t block them</em>, and due to major backlash, in-general.</p>

<p>Via <a href="https://www.404media.co/metas-ai-profiles-are-indistinguishable-from-terrible-spam-that-took-over-facebook/" target="_blank">404 Media</a>:</p>

<blockquote>
"There is confusion: the recent Financial Times article was about our vision for AI characters existing on our platforms over time, not announcing any new product," Sweeney said. "The accounts referenced are from a test we launched at Connect in 2023. These were managed by humans and were part of an early experiment we did with AI characters. We identified the bug that was impacting the ability for people to block those AIs and are removing those accounts to fix the issue.” 
</blockquote>

<p>But, the aforementioned “Liv” wasn’t Meta’s only experiment with making racist caricatures, as Threads user krenaep details, with a completely different, and also now deleted account, named “Jade.”</p>

<div class="threads-container">
<blockquote class="text-post-media" data-text-post-permalink="https://www.threads.net/@krenaep/post/DEYPd_qvd69" data-text-post-version="0" id="ig-tp-DEYPd_qvd69" style=" background:#FFF; border-width: 1px; border-style: solid; border-color: #00000026; border-radius: 16px; max-width:540px; margin: 1px; min-width:270px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);"> <a href="https://www.threads.net/@krenaep/post/DEYPd_qvd69" style=" background:#FFFFFF; line-height:0; padding:0 0; text-align:center; text-decoration:none; width:100%; font-family: -apple-system, BlinkMacSystemFont, sans-serif;" target="_blank"> <div style=" padding: 40px; display: flex; flex-direction: column; align-items: center;"><div style=" display:block; height:32px; width:32px; padding-bottom:20px;"> <svg aria-label="Threads" height="32px" role="img" viewBox="0 0 192 192" width="32px" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg"> <path d="M141.537 88.9883C140.71 88.5919 139.87 88.2104 139.019 87.8451C137.537 60.5382 122.616 44.905 97.5619 44.745C97.4484 44.7443 97.3355 44.7443 97.222 44.7443C82.2364 44.7443 69.7731 51.1409 62.102 62.7807L75.881 72.2328C81.6116 63.5383 90.6052 61.6848 97.2286 61.6848C97.3051 61.6848 97.3819 61.6848 97.4576 61.6855C105.707 61.7381 111.932 64.1366 115.961 68.814C118.893 72.2193 120.854 76.925 121.825 82.8638C114.511 81.6207 106.601 81.2385 98.145 81.7233C74.3247 83.0954 59.0111 96.9879 60.0396 116.292C60.5615 126.084 65.4397 134.508 73.775 140.011C80.8224 144.663 89.899 146.938 99.3323 146.423C111.79 145.74 121.563 140.987 128.381 132.296C133.559 125.696 136.834 117.143 138.28 106.366C144.217 109.949 148.617 114.664 151.047 120.332C155.179 129.967 155.42 145.8 142.501 158.708C131.182 170.016 117.576 174.908 97.0135 175.059C74.2042 174.89 56.9538 167.575 45.7381 153.317C35.2355 139.966 29.8077 120.682 29.6052 96C29.8077 71.3178 35.2355 52.0336 45.7381 38.6827C56.9538 24.4249 74.2039 17.11 97.0132 16.9405C119.988 17.1113 137.539 24.4614 149.184 38.788C154.894 45.8136 159.199 54.6488 162.037 64.9503L178.184 60.6422C174.744 47.9622 169.331 37.0357 161.965 27.974C147.036 9.60668 125.202 0.195148 97.0695 0H96.9569C68.8816 0.19447 47.2921 9.6418 32.7883 28.0793C19.8819 44.4864 13.2244 67.3157 13.0007 95.9325L13 96L13.0007 96.0675C13.2244 124.684 19.8819 147.514 32.7883 163.921C47.2921 182.358 68.8816 191.806 96.9569 192H97.0695C122.03 191.827 139.624 185.292 154.118 170.811C173.081 151.866 172.51 128.119 166.26 113.541C161.776 103.087 153.227 94.5962 141.537 88.9883ZM98.4405 129.507C88.0005 130.095 77.1544 125.409 76.6196 115.372C76.2232 107.93 81.9158 99.626 99.0812 98.6368C101.047 98.5234 102.976 98.468 104.871 98.468C111.106 98.468 116.939 99.0737 122.242 100.233C120.264 124.935 108.662 128.946 98.4405 129.507Z" /></svg></div><div style=" font-size: 15px; line-height: 21px; color: #000000; font-weight: 600; "> View on Threads</div></div></a></blockquote>
<script async="" src="https://www.threads.net/embed.js"></script>
</div>

<p>It seems these bots were completely willing to de-mask their creators, showing us that both of these accounts, and the others, were all constructed by a team of mostly white guys. Which, and I’m not a genius or anything, but, looks <em>real</em> bad, chief. But it <em>does</em> further the conversation as to <em>what exactly</em> the goal was, or <em>is</em> with these things. Some have said the the goal is to “drive engagement,” but, to what end, and how? You going to use AI to boost real human beings?</p>

<p>Or, you’re going to ask content creators to use your AI tools in order to develop caricatures of themselves that can interact with people <em>for them</em>, thereby discouraging human interaction on a social media platform. Because if there’s anything billionaires hate more than losing a single cent to paying their <em>goddamn taxes</em>, it’s regular, <em>real</em> human beings, who still have functioning frontal lobes. And the assumption, is, I guess, that <em>everyone else must be like this, too</em>.</p>

<p><img src="/img/posts/meta-dead/tools.png" /></p>

<p>In the age of tomfoolery, and fuckery, and generative slop that guzzles gallons of fresh water <em>every single time</em> you make a prompt, I think it’s important to <em>begin</em> the move away from corporate social media. If you can. Albeit, I do exist on Meta social media, and that’s entirely for my own reasons–I’m conflicted, and I have work that I’d like to reach more than a few handfuls of people with, because I don’t want to work retail for the rest of my natural life, until I’m replaced by an AI bot that will inevitably hallucinate that I was <em>never actually born</em>.</p>

<p>But, this is your regular reminder that user-owned social media exists, and you have full control over the things you see, and interact with online … even if Meta will never truly delete or relinquish your data, no matter <em>what</em> you do with your accounts. And if we can get people en-masse to move to the protocol mentioned below, then maybe even <em>more</em> people will feel like they don’t have to keep one foot in the digital hell, and the other in the place where they actually want to be.</p>

<p>Ways to join Mastodon:</p>

<ul>
  <li>
    <p>Check out <a href="https://mastodon.social" target="_blank">mastodon.social</a>, the flagship instance that has the <em>most</em> people on it. This is good for people who don’t want to bother looking through different servers and simply want to give the place a try.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Check out <a href="https://mkultra.monster" target="_blank">my instance</a>, and submit a join request (please type a legible reason for joining with your request, so that I can distinguish you from bots).</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Or, <a href="https://jointhefediverse.net/?lang=en-us" target="_blank">surf through numerous different ActivityPub instances</a> that span even more than just Mastodon.</p>
  </li>
</ul>]]></content><author><name>𐕣 C M D R ░ NOVA 𐕣</name></author><category term="Social-media" /><category term="meta" /><category term="threads" /><category term="instagram" /><category term="facebook" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[So, last week, I wrote about Meta inadvertently planning to confirm the “Dead Internet Theory,” with cringy fake people (AI bots), and how enthusiastic the Zuck was about all of this, despite there being no value, or any verifiable reason for it all to exist. And, almost immediately afterward, scores of people began planning their move away from Threads across the platform (post-2023 social media is just a game of digital hot potato). Other users scoured Instagram and Facebook to find a slew of 20 some bots … including a fake black woman pretending to have a family, and culture.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The Year Was 2025</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/thoughts/2025/01/01/the-year-was-2025.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Year Was 2025" /><published>2025-01-01T17:46:00-05:00</published><updated>2025-01-01T17:46:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/thoughts/2025/01/01/the-year-was-2025</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/thoughts/2025/01/01/the-year-was-2025.html"><![CDATA[<p>Happy new year, everyone! I don’t know that I have any resolutions this time. I have … goals! Goals I would like to actually meet this year. I want to pay down this debt that I incurred from veterinarians more than three years ago now. I want to … find work in a tech field! Even if that may be <em>even more</em> impossible than it was six months ago. And, most of all, I want to revitalize my Patreon. Here’s why …</p>

<p>I’ve been running <a href="https://www.patreon.com/c/cmdr_nova" target="_blank">my Patreon</a> since October 2014. It has been … <em>a very long time</em>. Ten years! And in that time, I’ve posted downloadable releases of my <em>very first book</em> I ever self published, and then <em>two more</em> that came after. I have over twenty musical releases up, that I’ve posted about over the years, and you can download <em>all of them</em> (as a paid member). I have posts containing spotlights and information about nearly <em>everything I’ve ever</em> put into my Second Life store, and then I also have regular updates that include my blog posts (which have been on <em>multiple websites since then</em>).</p>

<p>There was a time when my paid subscribers reached the height of <em>thirty active subs</em>, and then, over time, I lost focus, bad things happened in the synthwave scene, and a lot of them left.</p>

<p>I’m going to put this out there, though: I appreciate <em>every single person</em> who has been on my Patreon, is there, and/or is even just <em>following</em> for free (except for Czarina, she was only subscribed for selfish reasons that she could later hold over my head in the midst of her retaliation to my outspoken views on the transphobia within the synthwave scene).</p>

<p>On the topic of my Patreon, though, I <em>did</em> sort of stop updating it for a little bit of 2024. I thought I could move to Ko-fi, or other sites like it, because for a while <em>it did</em> feel easier to provide updates on things I’ve been doing, and creating. But … most of the sites that are <em>like</em> Patreon, are kind of also missing a lot of the features Patreon has. And … why abandon something I’ve been using <em>for ten years</em>?</p>

<p>It may as well be an archive of everything I’ve ever done, right?</p>

<p>I currently have a Python script running on a remote server that posts a snippet of information about my Patreon to my Mastodon account once daily, and I wanted to write this post, as well, to give a little bit of deeper insight. One of the things I was doing, that got me to where I used to be (before I returned to the offline work-world), was that I <em>shared</em> what I do, and what I create, <em>on a daily basis</em>. Sometimes <em>multiple</em> times a day.</p>

<p>Since I returned to offline work, I’ve really slacked on actually sharing what I do, and I feel like that’s a big contributor as to why, <em>even with having a bestselling darksynth album</em>, I’ve kind of sifted into the background noise a bit.</p>

<p>But, you should sign up to: support what I do, help me get out of this friggin’ debt, and, also? Help me <em>leave retail work once and for all</em>.</p>

<p>That’s it. That’s the goal.</p>]]></content><author><name>𐕣 C M D R ░ NOVA 𐕣</name></author><category term="Thoughts" /><category term="blogging" /><category term="thoughts" /><category term="newyear" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Happy new year, everyone! I don’t know that I have any resolutions this time. I have … goals! Goals I would like to actually meet this year. I want to pay down this debt that I incurred from veterinarians more than three years ago now. I want to … find work in a tech field! Even if that may be even more impossible than it was six months ago. And, most of all, I want to revitalize my Patreon. Here’s why …]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Second Life to Introduce Fake Friends</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/second-life/2024/12/31/second-life-to-introduce-fake-friends.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Second Life to Introduce Fake Friends" /><published>2024-12-31T08:04:00-05:00</published><updated>2024-12-31T08:04:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/second-life/2024/12/31/second-life-to-introduce-fake-friends</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/second-life/2024/12/31/second-life-to-introduce-fake-friends.html"><![CDATA[<p>If you’ve spent any time in Second Life over the course of the last decade or so, you’ve probably definitely noticed that more and more people are agoraphobic. Many stay in their homes idling by themselves, or atop “platforms” 3000 meters up in the air, only socializing with one or two people they know personally. The virtual world has never been more disconnected as a social platform, for reasons … uh, that I’m not quite sure of. But, no need to fear! Linden Labs is alpha testing an AI character creator so that your friends can be as fake as your imagination!</p>

<p><img src="/img/posts/sl-ai/creator.png" /></p>

<p>Pictured in the screenshot is a dialogue that says, “Your own personal bot intended to accompany you as you explore the world, bond with you, and interact mostly or only with you.” Because, it’s not like Second Life was, and has always been, a 3D virtual chat application. A place where you’re supposed to meet people, form friendships, and build together. <em>No, absolutely not.</em> This is a single-player virtual world, where the bonds you form are as contrived, meaningless, and embarrassing as asking Google’s Gemini if it loves you.</p>

<p>Introduced by Darcy Linden via an <a href="https://community.secondlife.com/blogs/entry/15954-introducing-the-character-designer-alpha/" target="_blank">official blog post</a>:</p>

<blockquote>
Developed in collaboration with Convai, the Character Designer empowers you to craft, customize, and animate virtual characters within Second Life. This tool is intended for developers, community builders, roleplay enthusiasts, and anyone looking to enhance their inworld experiences through dynamic characters. 
</blockquote>

<p>Roleplay enthusiasts! Now you don’t have to stand around in a group of five people in a city crafted by the hands of creators, writing ten paragraph long scenes for each other to immerse yourselves within while you create stories. Now, you’ll be able to replace all of those people and unique moments with plagiarism bots! <strong><em>OH BOY</em></strong>.</p>

<p>Just like with any other company that has suddenly decided to force AI into their products, we can only assume that this is happening because the CEO behind Linden Labs has demanded it. And, also, in every circumstance that this has happened within in the past year, I’ll ask the same question: Can we fire whoever’s responsible for this? Before it becomes the nail in the coffin that completely ruins what has been a place of discovery and friendship for <em>decades</em>?</p>

<p>Linden Labs: You want to bolster the community, reinvigorate the userbase? Take notes from VR Chat. Make creation and building <em>easier</em>. Realize that not <em>everything</em> should require a user whip out their wallet, and give new users <em>something actually cool</em>. Lower the cost of hosting your own server from 250 USD per month, to something more within the realm of sanity, at, say, 14.99 a month.</p>

<p>Or, go the desperate CEO route, and inject generative slop into Second Life. Watch it finally die, so that every person on Reddit who asks, “Isn’t Second Life dead?” can finally be correct.</p>]]></content><author><name>𐕣 C M D R ░ NOVA 𐕣</name></author><category term="Second-Life" /><category term="secondlife" /><category term="ai" /><category term="lindenlabs" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[If you’ve spent any time in Second Life over the course of the last decade or so, you’ve probably definitely noticed that more and more people are agoraphobic. Many stay in their homes idling by themselves, or atop “platforms” 3000 meters up in the air, only socializing with one or two people they know personally. The virtual world has never been more disconnected as a social platform, for reasons … uh, that I’m not quite sure of. But, no need to fear! Linden Labs is alpha testing an AI character creator so that your friends can be as fake as your imagination!]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The Dead Internet Comes to Life</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/tech/2024/12/30/the-dead-internet-comes-to-life.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Dead Internet Comes to Life" /><published>2024-12-30T22:28:00-05:00</published><updated>2024-12-30T22:28:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/tech/2024/12/30/the-dead-internet-comes-to-life</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/tech/2024/12/30/the-dead-internet-comes-to-life.html"><![CDATA[<p>We’ve all recently come to the conclusion that billionaires and CEOs don’t really care what you think of them, or what they do. And Mark Zuckerberg continues to provide glaring examples of why that’s true. From his sanitized Second Life clone, Horizons, to the present day, with AI generated social media users. It’s not just a question of, “Who the hell asked for this?” But also a question of, “What in the world is the point of filling social media with fake people who don’t exist that reply to things without logical reasoning?” Well … uh, we’re all asking that question.</p>

<div class="threads-container">
<blockquote class="text-post-media" data-text-post-permalink="https://www.threads.net/@timeforainews/post/DEH3aIroPor" data-text-post-version="0" id="ig-tp-DEH3aIroPor" style=" background:#FFF; border-width: 1px; border-style: solid; border-color: #00000026; border-radius: 16px; max-width:540px; margin: 1px; min-width:270px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);"> <a href="https://www.threads.net/@timeforainews/post/DEH3aIroPor" style=" background:#FFFFFF; line-height:0; padding:0 0; text-align:center; text-decoration:none; width:100%; font-family: -apple-system, BlinkMacSystemFont, sans-serif;" target="_blank"> <div style=" padding: 40px; display: flex; flex-direction: column; align-items: center;"><div style=" display:block; height:32px; width:32px; padding-bottom:20px;"> <svg aria-label="Threads" height="32px" role="img" viewBox="0 0 192 192" width="32px" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg"> <path d="M141.537 88.9883C140.71 88.5919 139.87 88.2104 139.019 87.8451C137.537 60.5382 122.616 44.905 97.5619 44.745C97.4484 44.7443 97.3355 44.7443 97.222 44.7443C82.2364 44.7443 69.7731 51.1409 62.102 62.7807L75.881 72.2328C81.6116 63.5383 90.6052 61.6848 97.2286 61.6848C97.3051 61.6848 97.3819 61.6848 97.4576 61.6855C105.707 61.7381 111.932 64.1366 115.961 68.814C118.893 72.2193 120.854 76.925 121.825 82.8638C114.511 81.6207 106.601 81.2385 98.145 81.7233C74.3247 83.0954 59.0111 96.9879 60.0396 116.292C60.5615 126.084 65.4397 134.508 73.775 140.011C80.8224 144.663 89.899 146.938 99.3323 146.423C111.79 145.74 121.563 140.987 128.381 132.296C133.559 125.696 136.834 117.143 138.28 106.366C144.217 109.949 148.617 114.664 151.047 120.332C155.179 129.967 155.42 145.8 142.501 158.708C131.182 170.016 117.576 174.908 97.0135 175.059C74.2042 174.89 56.9538 167.575 45.7381 153.317C35.2355 139.966 29.8077 120.682 29.6052 96C29.8077 71.3178 35.2355 52.0336 45.7381 38.6827C56.9538 24.4249 74.2039 17.11 97.0132 16.9405C119.988 17.1113 137.539 24.4614 149.184 38.788C154.894 45.8136 159.199 54.6488 162.037 64.9503L178.184 60.6422C174.744 47.9622 169.331 37.0357 161.965 27.974C147.036 9.60668 125.202 0.195148 97.0695 0H96.9569C68.8816 0.19447 47.2921 9.6418 32.7883 28.0793C19.8819 44.4864 13.2244 67.3157 13.0007 95.9325L13 96L13.0007 96.0675C13.2244 124.684 19.8819 147.514 32.7883 163.921C47.2921 182.358 68.8816 191.806 96.9569 192H97.0695C122.03 191.827 139.624 185.292 154.118 170.811C173.081 151.866 172.51 128.119 166.26 113.541C161.776 103.087 153.227 94.5962 141.537 88.9883ZM98.4405 129.507C88.0005 130.095 77.1544 125.409 76.6196 115.372C76.2232 107.93 81.9158 99.626 99.0812 98.6368C101.047 98.5234 102.976 98.468 104.871 98.468C111.106 98.468 116.939 99.0737 122.242 100.233C120.264 124.935 108.662 128.946 98.4405 129.507Z" /></svg></div><div style=" font-size: 15px; line-height: 21px; color: #000000; font-weight: 600; "> View on Threads</div></div></a></blockquote>
<script async="" src="https://www.threads.net/embed.js"></script>
</div>

<p>I have a complicated relationship with Meta. Like I spoke about before, in a previous post, I’ve had a Facebook account since it was brand new, and even if I were to delete it, <em>they have everything about me, ever, and they’ll likely never relinquish that information.</em> And, at the same time, I do tend to enjoy some mindless scrolling on Reels, or pretending that I’m a regular normal social media user on Threads, as I watch Zuck make the worst decisions possible to impress people who he has imagined in his own mind. And yes, I own a Meta Quest 2, which has been gathering dust in a drawer for about three months (VR Chat has slipped out of my zone of interest).</p>

<p>This also probably sounds extremely contrary, or in opposition to my hefty support of ActivityPub, and Mastodon, especially because I <a href="https://mkultra.monster" target="_blank"><em>run my own instance</em></a>. But, as a creator of <em>things</em>, and if you create things as well (art, fiction, etc), you already know, that you <em>must</em> maintain a presence in as many places as possible. It’s part of the game. And it’s a shitty game, that I do not enjoy.</p>

<p>But, to bring the topic back to the embedded Threads post, Zuckerberg imagines a social media where there are millions and billions of AI agents, i.e., fake people. To no one’s surprise, just about <em>every single person</em> learning of this news is asking, “What in the hell is this good for?”</p>

<p>Taken from an annoyingly milquetoast article over at <a href="https://www.rollingstone.com/culture/culture-news/meta-ai-users-facebook-instagram-1235221430/" target="_blank">Rolling Stone</a>:</p>

<blockquote>
 The prospect seems an unusual one for websites predicated on the idea of human-to-human interaction. While Meta’s other AI offerings, including photo-editing tools, a ChatGPT-like text bot, and forthcoming software for producing AI-generated video, have more readily obvious appeal, it’s far from certain that an Instagram or Facebook populated by virtual apparitions would prove enticing to newcomers or satisfying for long-time users. Meta revealed to FT that users have created “hundreds of thousands of characters” since AI Studio launched in July, but that most of them remain private. The company declined to comment further to Rolling Stone. 
</blockquote>

<p>The question remains: What <em>value</em> does this provide? You’re melting the ice caps in order to put fake people on social media, that you’re <em>already aware people don’t like</em>, for <strong>what reason</strong>? Are you going to sell people AI blocking software as a solution to a problem that you yourselves have created? Is that the end goal here?</p>

<p>You see, I come from the 90s. And in the 90s, we had very, <em>very</em> primitive chatbots. Chatbots that responded to trigger words with predefined text. This is something that you can now build by yourself with like 5 minutes of Python. Hardly anyone thought it was cool then, and it definitely isn’t cool now.</p>

<p>It’s not cool, because <em>most people</em> are online and on social media, to meet, and talk to <em>real</em> people. To make friends. To make connections. <em>What</em> connection are you making with an AI ghost on Facebook?</p>

<p>Am I missing a piece of the human genome that makes something like this exciting?</p>

<p>I must be.</p>

<p>You can go and see one of these “characters” on Facebook, now. And, if you’re feeling extra funny, you can use Facebook’s <em>own reporting tools</em> to report the entire account for being a <strong>fake person</strong>. It’s literally there, in the reporting dialogue.</p>

<iframe src="https://www.facebook.com/plugins/post.php?href=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.facebook.com%2Fhellograndpabrian%2Fposts%2Fpfbid025EzMnV8ZnS9cVBEpuMeYE9hRYJED52XcenSN1Ao1t1w4sX1PQ4Zqx99d1robKuakl&amp;show_text=true&amp;width=500" width="500" height="687" style="border:none;overflow:hidden; background-color: #fff" scrolling="no" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="true" allow="autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; picture-in-picture; web-share"></iframe>

<p>This is, at least, a great reason to entice regular people to <em>finally</em>, <em>please</em> for the love of god, <a href="https://jointhefediverse.net/?lang=en-us" target="_blank">join a fediverse instance</a>. If we can move the digital world to ActivityPub, on user-owned servers, then maybe artists, and writers, and musicians can feel like they don’t have to be on these data farms anymore, just to gamble and get a 10% boost in exposure while bots are scraping everything they say so that AI generated Jimmy Carter can say, “Hey John, did you buy that Apple Watch you were talking about yesterday?”</p>]]></content><author><name>𐕣 C M D R ░ NOVA 𐕣</name></author><category term="Tech" /><category term="socialmedia" /><category term="tech" /><category term="meta" /><category term="ai" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[We’ve all recently come to the conclusion that billionaires and CEOs don’t really care what you think of them, or what they do. And Mark Zuckerberg continues to provide glaring examples of why that’s true. From his sanitized Second Life clone, Horizons, to the present day, with AI generated social media users. It’s not just a question of, “Who the hell asked for this?” But also a question of, “What in the world is the point of filling social media with fake people who don’t exist that reply to things without logical reasoning?” Well … uh, we’re all asking that question.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The Bechdel Test, and Why It’s Tainted</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/lgbtq/2024/12/29/the-bechdel-test-and-why-it-s-tainted.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Bechdel Test, and Why It’s Tainted" /><published>2024-12-29T21:11:00-05:00</published><updated>2024-12-29T21:11:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/lgbtq/2024/12/29/the-bechdel-test-and-why-it-s-tainted</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/lgbtq/2024/12/29/the-bechdel-test-and-why-it-s-tainted.html"><![CDATA[<p>A long time ago, in an age far, far away … Ten years ago, to be exact. And, keeping within the theme of traveling back in time to the world of Tumblr fandoms and Gamergate, it’s time we switched gears to the once growing “trans exclusionary radical feminist” movement, and the spectrum of hate and transphobia that came with it. Today, we’re talking about a book that was published in 2014, called <em>Adam</em>.</p>

<p><img src="/img/posts/bechdel/adam.jpg" /></p>

<p>The synopsis is as follows:</p>

<blockquote>
When Adam Freedman — a skinny, awkward, inexperienced teenager from Piedmont, California — goes to stay with his older sister Casey in New York City, he is hopeful that his life is about to change. And it sure does.<br /><br />

It is the summer of 2006. Gay marriage and transgender rights are in the air, and Casey has thrust herself into a wild lesbian subculture. Soon Adam is tagging along to underground clubs, where there are hot older women everywhere he turns. It takes some time for him to realize that many in this new crowd assume he is trans—a boy who was born a girl. Why else would this baby-faced guy always be around?<br /><br />

Then Adam meets Gillian, the girl of his dreams — but she couldn’t possibly be interested in him. Unless passing as a trans guy might actually work in his favor . . .<br /><br />

Ariel Schrag’s scathingly funny and poignant debut novel puts a fresh spin on questions of love, attraction, self-definition, and what it takes to be at home in your own skin.
</blockquote>

<p>This had a movie accompanying it that released in 2019, wherein the <em>extremely flawed</em> premise of a guy pretending to be trans in order to sleep with a lesbian caught fire like a volcano on Twitter (and you may also note, the premise describes Adam as a <em>teenager</em>).</p>

<p>And then it was summarily forgotten in about a week.</p>

<p>These themes and premises <em>also</em> align with things TERFs believe, or talk about. But, it’s been so long since these types have really seen the light of day, at least, in the way they <em>did</em> back in 2014 across the earlier versions of the sites we’re all stuck on (well, maybe not stuck). You can read more about who they are and what they believe, <a href="https://nwlc.org/happy-pride-dont-be-a-terf/" target="_blank">here</a>.</p>

<p>And, <em>maybe</em> this book isn’t exclusively anything to <em>do</em> with trans exclusionary radfems, but it’s definitely in the spaces of something that sits in the same arena as, “men wearing dresses pretending to be women entering spaces where they don’t belong,” except, in this instance, the role is reversed. The role is reversed, and it places transgender men in a light wherein they <em>have something in common with lesbians</em>, therein aligning them as <em>women who look and act like men.</em></p>

<p>Obviously, this isn’t <em>good</em>, or excusable, to write a story where something like this is painted as fun, uplifting, and “liberating.” Transphobia is literally the gasoline that’s fueling the modern fascist movement. And pretending that trans men are just women, whom’st lesbians can be interested in, romantically and sexually involved with, <em>is both transphobic and homophobic.</em> At least … if you actually align yourself with transgender people, in that they are who they say they are.</p>

<p>Now, stay with me here, what’s that quote at the top of the book’s cover read? Did you see that?</p>

<blockquote>
"The sexual revolution is finally over, and Ariel Schrag has won." - Alison Bechdel
</blockquote>

<p>Who’s <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Alison_Bechdel" target="_blank">Alison Bechdel</a>, though?</p>

<p>During the emergence of Gamergate, there was also a lot of talk about representation in gaming and other media, specifically about how women are represented and written. In that, they’re usually written <em>badly</em>, and usually to the benefit of a male character, for the male reader’s personal sexual “gaze” or enjoyment.</p>

<p>If you’re an older netizen like myself, you may remember Anita Sarkeesian and the extreme amount of vitriol she faced <em>whenever she talked about these things</em>, usually, specifically, in relation to gaming. You may also remember Zoe Quinn, whom is thought to be where, why, and <em>how</em> Gamergate “started,” i.e., in backlash <em>against her.</em> You can read much more about all of that <a href="https://www.npr.org/sections/alltechconsidered/2014/09/24/349835297/-gamergate-controversy-fuels-debate-on-women-and-video-games" target="_blank">here</a>.</p>

<p>But then, there also emerged a guideline of sorts that served and <em>still serves</em> as a litmus test for gauging old, new, and upcoming media for their literacy in representing women.</p>

<p>This test is known as <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bechdel_test" target="_blank">The Bechdel Test</a>.</p>

<blockquote>
The Bechdel test (/ˈbɛkdəl/ BEK-dəl),[1] also known as the Bechdel-Wallace test, is a measure of the representation of women in film and other fiction. The test asks whether a work features at least two female characters who have a conversation about something other than a man. Some versions of the test also require that those two female characters have names.
</blockquote>

<p>Now, I’m not saying this “test” of sorts doesn’t have any merit. There is <em>a lot</em> of merit in gauging these things, and determining if media is <em>actually good</em>, especially in this day and age, where Bad Things are getting <em>more bad</em>. But, I can’t quite put my finger on why someone who gave such an endorsement, to such a terrible piece of media, that <em>absolutely betrays her own test</em>, women, and the entire trans community, and was so proud of it, that it was <strong>featured on the front of the book</strong> … is still being celebrated.</p>

<p>And I wanted to <em>finally</em> bring a more permanent light to this, because I’ve been talking about it <em>for a decade</em>, to an internet that forgets everything it thinks it cares about faster than the speed of light, and I’ve been doing that on social media websites like, Twitter, Bluesky, Tumblr, <em>all this time</em>. And, whether you think I belong to any community or not doesn’t matter. It matters that critical thinking doesn’t die, and it matters more that we consider those we’re promoting and uplifting.</p>

<p>Alison Bechdel isn’t special. She’s just as flawed as any of us, and maybe she’s not <a href="https://rationalwiki.org/wiki/Cathy_Brennan" target="_blank">Cathy Brennan</a>, but <em>maybe we can think of a new name for litmus testing media for actual interesting female characters</em>, that doesn’t involve the name of someone who endorsed media where a man pretends to be transgender in order to sleep with a lesbian.</p>]]></content><author><name>𐕣 C M D R ░ NOVA 𐕣</name></author><category term="LGBTQ" /><category term="bechdel" /><category term="bechdeltest" /><category term="lgbtq" /><category term="gamergate" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[A long time ago, in an age far, far away … Ten years ago, to be exact. And, keeping within the theme of traveling back in time to the world of Tumblr fandoms and Gamergate, it’s time we switched gears to the once growing “trans exclusionary radical feminist” movement, and the spectrum of hate and transphobia that came with it. Today, we’re talking about a book that was published in 2014, called Adam.]]></summary></entry></feed>