<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en-US"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.10.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en-US" /><updated>2025-01-29T13:33:14-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">cmdr-nova@internet:~$</title><subtitle>cmdr-nova&apos;s personal blog and home on the indie-web.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Migrating Across the Fediverse: Nova Edition</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/socialmedia/2025/01/29/migrating-across-the-fediverse-nova-edition.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Migrating Across the Fediverse: Nova Edition" /><published>2025-01-29T13:24:00-05:00</published><updated>2025-01-29T13:24:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/socialmedia/2025/01/29/migrating-across-the-fediverse-nova-edition</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/socialmedia/2025/01/29/migrating-across-the-fediverse-nova-edition.html"><![CDATA[<p>So, last night I was poking around in my VPS billing reports, and I was going over some things. Basically, I have <em>plenty</em> of bandwidth for the mass of incoming media across the fediverse on my Mastodon instance … <em>but</em>, all the things I have running, in order to keep it operating smoothly, are costing me nearly 70-80 USD a month, <strong>and</strong> my instance is beginning to experience slow-down. This is not good. If I felt more secure in my current job, and wanted to keep spending that much, maybe this wouldn’t be an issue. But, for now, it kinda is. Therefore, I’m migrating away from hosting my own instance, for now.</p>

<p>As of now, and as my account migrates in this exact moment, I’ve moved over to labyrinth.zone, on the account <a href="https://labyrinth.zone/daemon_nova" target="_blank">@daemon_nova</a>.</p>

<p>The good news is, I’m still able to maintain a feed of my posts on this site, and <em>also</em> fediverse comments beneath my posts (although, once I shut-off the instance, old ones will obviously be broken). The down-side, is that I haven’t quite work out some of the kinks, because comments from <em>myself</em> show up as unidentified in the “instance” field of a comment.</p>

<p>Since I’m not sure how to extract a user ID number from Akkoma, this will just have to be like that for now.</p>

<p>The feed, on the other-hand, was just a quick simple RSS feed hack that took me 10 minutes to setup.</p>

<p>But, the bad news is, since I’m not sure you can setup API keys on an Akkoma account, I’ll have to share my posts <em>manually</em>, for now. Which is kinda okay? It’s an alright trade-off for saving myself 70 USD a month.</p>

<p>Plus, copy / pasting isn’t that hard. I only automated this because I can be overwhelmed sometimes.</p>

<p>Either way, the migration process was <em>sort of</em> smooth. I think I briefly nearly crashed the instance (my bad) due to the amount of follows I have. And, if you’re following me, and notice that I’m not, it’s not because I unfollowed you! It’s because the Mastodon &gt; Akkoma follow transfer didn’t go through 100%, so I unfortunately will have to refollow some people, <em>as I notice them</em>.</p>

<p>Thanks for coming along in my fediverse journey. We’ll see where it goes from here! I’m mainly doing this, <em>also</em>, because I wanted to focus more on maintaining my website, rather than doing that, <em>plus</em> being the full-time admin of my own Mastodon instance.</p>

<p>So, I think things will only get cooler from here.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="SocialMedia" /><category term="fediverse" /><category term="akkoma" /><category term="migration" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[So, last night I was poking around in my VPS billing reports, and I was going over some things. Basically, I have plenty of bandwidth for the mass of incoming media across the fediverse on my Mastodon instance … but, all the things I have running, in order to keep it operating smoothly, are costing me nearly 70-80 USD a month, and my instance is beginning to experience slow-down. This is not good. If I felt more secure in my current job, and wanted to keep spending that much, maybe this wouldn’t be an issue. But, for now, it kinda is. Therefore, I’m migrating away from hosting my own instance, for now.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Sims 4: New Template &amp;amp; Resurrection of the VampHouse Challenge</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/gaming/2025/01/28/sims-4-new-template-resurrection-of-the-vamphouse-challenge.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Sims 4: New Template &amp;amp; Resurrection of the VampHouse Challenge" /><published>2025-01-28T16:07:00-05:00</published><updated>2025-01-28T16:07:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/gaming/2025/01/28/sims-4-new-template-resurrection-of-the-vamphouse-challenge</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/gaming/2025/01/28/sims-4-new-template-resurrection-of-the-vamphouse-challenge.html"><![CDATA[<p>So, I was thinking today, “Hey, my old website used to have a section dedicated to The Sims 4 where I hosted a downloadable version of my game template.” And, after some consideration, I decided to put it back! Although, as of posting this, EA released an update to Sims 4 that <em>somehow</em> completely broke their servers, and now you can’t launch the game … at all. Which means, I can’t finish editing my new 2025 Sims 4 world template. Thanks EA! But, that’s not the only thing I’ve added to the site.</p>

<p>The template <a href="/pages/thesims/">will be here</a>, once they fix what they broke.</p>

<p>But, back in 2019, I was <em>really</em> into doing Sims 4 challenges. I was still out-of-work, so I spent most of the time that I wasn’t working on personal projects, playing The Sims 4.</p>

<p>I enjoyed the Legacy Challenge the most, because it involved starting with <em>nothing</em>, and then building up a massive family legacy over numerous generations of sims. I could never really make it past the first generation, though, because, like in all of my save files, I find it hard to let go of the originals. Never-the-less, I thought it would be cool to make <em>my own</em> version of the Legacy Challenge.</p>

<p>So, I wrote something, and hosted it on Google Sheets, so that people could connect to and read it. And then some years passed, and it vanished, along with the website where I originally posted it. And, for the longest time, I thought it was just gone, completely.</p>

<p>But, much like my Second Life guide, <em>nothing is ever gone, forever</em>.</p>

<p>Now, if you navigate to the right (or from the pop-out menu at the top, if you’re on mobile), you’ll find my original VampHouse Challenge recovered and preserved on its own page, <a href="/sims4/vamphouse">right here</a> on my website!</p>

<p>My head hurts a little bit right now, so I haven’t jumped into re-reading the whole thing, but, basically, it’s a challenge that revolves around the idea of the original save file I had way, <em>way</em> back, when I first started playing The Sims 4. I had my own sim, and I moved her into a house. Eventually, she got married and had a child to another sim. Then, someone who will not be named (cause she’s a jerk), from Mastodon, bought me the Vampire pack, and, well, I <em>had</em> to play with it, right?</p>

<p>So I made a new sim, a vampire, and I moved her in down the street from the family I started.</p>

<p>I became <em>so engrossed</em> with this sim, that I ended up moving her into my main house.</p>

<p>And then, one thing led to another, and the vampire, and my original main sim, became romantically involved, and then had a huge family of children. This grew into a massive household, and sims that branched out across the 4 different worlds that there were in the game, at the time. Which, after digging up the save file, and incorporating aspects of it into a world template, I thought, “This should be a challenge people can do themselves.”</p>

<p>So now it is.</p>

<p>If you feel up to it, and partake in this years-old challenge, upload the family you create to the Sims 4 gallery, and use the hashtag #vamphousechallenge. Maybe I’ll check them out, and maybe I’ll use them in my own world!</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Gaming" /><category term="gamingnews" /><category term="sims4" /><category term="gaming" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[So, I was thinking today, “Hey, my old website used to have a section dedicated to The Sims 4 where I hosted a downloadable version of my game template.” And, after some consideration, I decided to put it back! Although, as of posting this, EA released an update to Sims 4 that somehow completely broke their servers, and now you can’t launch the game … at all. Which means, I can’t finish editing my new 2025 Sims 4 world template. Thanks EA! But, that’s not the only thing I’ve added to the site.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Nvidia Will Have To Go Back To Selling Videocards At Normal Human Prices</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/tech/2025/01/27/nvidia-will-have-to-go-back-to-selling-videocards-at-normal-human-prices.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Nvidia Will Have To Go Back To Selling Videocards At Normal Human Prices" /><published>2025-01-27T22:37:00-05:00</published><updated>2025-01-27T22:37:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/tech/2025/01/27/nvidia-will-have-to-go-back-to-selling-videocards-at-normal-human-prices</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/tech/2025/01/27/nvidia-will-have-to-go-back-to-selling-videocards-at-normal-human-prices.html"><![CDATA[<p>It’s been a hell of a week. Work has been busy. I’ve been tentatively trying to get back to finding new work as a web developer, because that’s the career I should’ve been in twenty some odd years ago, and by golly gee whiz, I’m going to get it. But that’s not why I’m writing you today, Mr. Internet. I’m writing, because the AI bubble is having a giant shit, and it’s popping, and Nvidia is tanking. Thank the all mighty Flying Spaghetti Monster, and Venus’ molten atmosphere: AI might be finished, or, at least, seriously diminished to the point that it’s no longer a fad that annoying bastards on public social media timelines spam you about all day.</p>

<p><img src="/img/posts/nvidia/07fbb834c5ac2bb1.png" /></p>

<p>Drink it in. Greedy, unoriginal, plagiarism loving fucks, are having themselves a cry. And the juice couldn’t be more delicious.</p>

<p>Why’s this happening, though?</p>

<p>China, somehow, someway, <a href="https://www.cbsnews.com/news/what-is-deepseek-ai-china-stock-nvidia-nvda-asml/" target="_blank">figured out how to do AI for pocket change</a>, compared to what American billionaires are spending, and that’s <em>hilarious</em>. And I can only hope this takes a chunk out of Meta, out of Twitter, and most importantly, out of Sam Altman’s mega-grift of stealing the entire internet to power his wrong-answer machine.</p>

<p>Albeit, AI should go away, <em>completely</em>. But if I have to settle for China doing it slightly better, and crashing the entire stock market. Well. I’ll take it.</p>

<p>Thanks, China.</p>

<p>As I dump year old malt liquor into my Dr. Pepper, I sit and reflect on two years of bullshit. Dudes with no imagination telling you, “This is inevitable.” And corporations ignoring your consent in order to use everything you’ve ever typed, online, to fuel these things: Potentially becoming worthless e-waste.</p>

<p>Man, that’s the JUICE.</p>

<p>Anyway, I’m gonna go run around in Pandora for 14 hours while I have time to myself.</p>

<iframe title="Avatar: Frontiers of Pandora | Escape to Pandora" width="560" height="315" src="https://video.infosec.exchange/videos/embed/47b127f3-2965-40d2-a5ad-705a16de5b90" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="" sandbox="allow-same-origin allow-scripts allow-popups allow-forms"></iframe>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Tech" /><category term="ai" /><category term="tech" /><category term="nvidia" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[It’s been a hell of a week. Work has been busy. I’ve been tentatively trying to get back to finding new work as a web developer, because that’s the career I should’ve been in twenty some odd years ago, and by golly gee whiz, I’m going to get it. But that’s not why I’m writing you today, Mr. Internet. I’m writing, because the AI bubble is having a giant shit, and it’s popping, and Nvidia is tanking. Thank the all mighty Flying Spaghetti Monster, and Venus’ molten atmosphere: AI might be finished, or, at least, seriously diminished to the point that it’s no longer a fad that annoying bastards on public social media timelines spam you about all day.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">There is No Snow in Alaska; But AI Must Continue</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/tech/2025/01/26/there-is-no-snow-in-alaska-but-ai-must-continue.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="There is No Snow in Alaska; But AI Must Continue" /><published>2025-01-26T03:48:00-05:00</published><updated>2025-01-26T03:48:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/tech/2025/01/26/there-is-no-snow-in-alaska-but-ai-must-continue</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/tech/2025/01/26/there-is-no-snow-in-alaska-but-ai-must-continue.html"><![CDATA[<p>It’s a pretty widely known fact, at this point, that the development and continued use of AI is <a href="https://www.unep.org/news-and-stories/story/ai-has-environmental-problem-heres-what-world-can-do-about" target="_blank">killing the planet</a>. It’s killing the planet at an even more accelerated rate than the world’s richest people and their corporations were, already. And yet, you can log onto Twitter (if you dare), Threads, Bluesky, and even Mastodon, and see tech-hype-brained, uncritical idiots (for lack of a better term), celebrating the thought of the expansion of LLMs to the point where we’re now apparently even talking of wasting the potential of Linux-based operating systems on our phones, on its continued development and use.</p>

<blockquote class="mastodon-embed" data-embed-url="https://mastodon.social/@one_with_linux/113891469603965665/embed" style="background: #FCF8FF; border-radius: 8px; border: 1px solid #C9C4DA; margin: 0; max-width: 540px; min-width: 270px; overflow: hidden; padding: 0;"> <a href="https://mastodon.social/@one_with_linux/113891469603965665" target="_blank" style="align-items: center; color: #1C1A25; display: flex; flex-direction: column; font-family: system-ui, -apple-system, BlinkMacSystemFont, 'Segoe UI', Oxygen, Ubuntu, Cantarell, 'Fira Sans', 'Droid Sans', 'Helvetica Neue', Roboto, sans-serif; font-size: 14px; justify-content: center; letter-spacing: 0.25px; line-height: 20px; padding: 24px; text-decoration: none;"> <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" width="32" height="32" viewBox="0 0 79 75"><path d="M74.7135 16.6043C73.6199 8.54587 66.5351 2.19527 58.1366 0.964691C56.7196 0.756754 51.351 0 38.9148 0H38.822C26.3824 0 23.7135 0.756754 22.2966 0.964691C14.1319 2.16118 6.67571 7.86752 4.86669 16.0214C3.99657 20.0369 3.90371 24.4888 4.06535 28.5726C4.29578 34.4289 4.34049 40.275 4.877 46.1075C5.24791 49.9817 5.89495 53.8251 6.81328 57.6088C8.53288 64.5968 15.4938 70.4122 22.3138 72.7848C29.6155 75.259 37.468 75.6697 44.9919 73.971C45.8196 73.7801 46.6381 73.5586 47.4475 73.3063C49.2737 72.7302 51.4164 72.086 52.9915 70.9542C53.0131 70.9384 53.0308 70.9178 53.0433 70.8942C53.0558 70.8706 53.0628 70.8445 53.0637 70.8179V65.1661C53.0634 65.1412 53.0574 65.1167 53.0462 65.0944C53.035 65.0721 53.0189 65.0525 52.9992 65.0371C52.9794 65.0218 52.9564 65.011 52.9318 65.0056C52.9073 65.0002 52.8819 65.0003 52.8574 65.0059C48.0369 66.1472 43.0971 66.7193 38.141 66.7103C29.6118 66.7103 27.3178 62.6981 26.6609 61.0278C26.1329 59.5842 25.7976 58.0784 25.6636 56.5486C25.6622 56.5229 25.667 56.4973 25.6775 56.4738C25.688 56.4502 25.7039 56.4295 25.724 56.4132C25.7441 56.397 25.7678 56.3856 25.7931 56.3801C25.8185 56.3746 25.8448 56.3751 25.8699 56.3816C30.6101 57.5151 35.4693 58.0873 40.3455 58.086C41.5183 58.086 42.6876 58.086 43.8604 58.0553C48.7647 57.919 53.9339 57.6701 58.7591 56.7361C58.8794 56.7123 58.9998 56.6918 59.103 56.6611C66.7139 55.2124 73.9569 50.665 74.6929 39.1501C74.7204 38.6967 74.7892 34.4016 74.7892 33.9312C74.7926 32.3325 75.3085 22.5901 74.7135 16.6043ZM62.9996 45.3371H54.9966V25.9069C54.9966 21.8163 53.277 19.7302 49.7793 19.7302C45.9343 19.7302 44.0083 22.1981 44.0083 27.0727V37.7082H36.0534V27.0727C36.0534 22.1981 34.124 19.7302 30.279 19.7302C26.8019 19.7302 25.0651 21.8163 25.0617 25.9069V45.3371H17.0656V25.3172C17.0656 21.2266 18.1191 17.9769 20.2262 15.568C22.3998 13.1648 25.2509 11.9308 28.7898 11.9308C32.8859 11.9308 35.9812 13.492 38.0447 16.6111L40.036 19.9245L42.0308 16.6111C44.0943 13.492 47.1896 11.9308 51.2788 11.9308C54.8143 11.9308 57.6654 13.1648 59.8459 15.568C61.9529 17.9746 63.0065 21.2243 63.0065 25.3172L62.9996 45.3371Z" fill="currentColor" /></svg> <div style="color: #787588; margin-top: 16px;">Post by @one_with_linux@mastodon.social</div> <div style="font-weight: 500;">View on Mastodon</div> </a> </blockquote>
<script data-allowed-prefixes="https://mastodon.social/" async="" src="https://mastodon.social/embed.js"></script>

<p>“Who made <em>you</em> the arbiter of what people do with their own hardware?!” An apologist of planet-crushing autocorrect, might ask.</p>

<p>To which I say, “Me, asshole. Just me.”</p>

<p>When I moved to Linux, it was partially because of Microsoft and their bad decisions in regard to booting anyone with slightly out-of-date processors to the curb (welcome to Windows 10, say goodbye to security updates). The other half of it, was the eventual announcement of their “AI powered” <a href="/linux/2024/11/11/ten-months-without-windows.html">privacy invasion software</a>, labeled “Recall.” You know, along with the ads, the popups, and the <em>other</em> AI garbage, embedded directly into your desktop.</p>

<p>I moved to Linux, because, you can do pretty much whatever you want with the software, and it is <em>extremely secure</em>, and privacy focused.</p>

<p>Unfortunately, people with no imagination, and no respect for themselves, the environment, or the Linux operating system, have decided that “anything” can also mean, developing and/or using water-guzzling, ice-cap melting, plagiarism machines.</p>

<p>And when I think of Linux, but on a phone, I think: Security, privacy, endless customization, and how cool it would be if we still had snow on Christmas in Pennsylvania.</p>

<p>When these fartbags think of Linux, but on a phone, they think: Of how great it would be if the entire human population were wiped out by 2042.</p>

<blockquote class="mastodon-embed" data-embed-url="https://alaskan.social/@Ghostsheetz/113892118620430992/embed" style="background: #FCF8FF; border-radius: 8px; border: 1px solid #C9C4DA; margin: 0; max-width: 540px; min-width: 270px; overflow: hidden; padding: 0;"> <a href="https://alaskan.social/@Ghostsheetz/113892118620430992" target="_blank" style="align-items: center; color: #1C1A25; display: flex; flex-direction: column; font-family: system-ui, -apple-system, BlinkMacSystemFont, 'Segoe UI', Oxygen, Ubuntu, Cantarell, 'Fira Sans', 'Droid Sans', 'Helvetica Neue', Roboto, sans-serif; font-size: 14px; justify-content: center; letter-spacing: 0.25px; line-height: 20px; padding: 24px; text-decoration: none;"> <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" width="32" height="32" viewBox="0 0 79 75"><path d="M74.7135 16.6043C73.6199 8.54587 66.5351 2.19527 58.1366 0.964691C56.7196 0.756754 51.351 0 38.9148 0H38.822C26.3824 0 23.7135 0.756754 22.2966 0.964691C14.1319 2.16118 6.67571 7.86752 4.86669 16.0214C3.99657 20.0369 3.90371 24.4888 4.06535 28.5726C4.29578 34.4289 4.34049 40.275 4.877 46.1075C5.24791 49.9817 5.89495 53.8251 6.81328 57.6088C8.53288 64.5968 15.4938 70.4122 22.3138 72.7848C29.6155 75.259 37.468 75.6697 44.9919 73.971C45.8196 73.7801 46.6381 73.5586 47.4475 73.3063C49.2737 72.7302 51.4164 72.086 52.9915 70.9542C53.0131 70.9384 53.0308 70.9178 53.0433 70.8942C53.0558 70.8706 53.0628 70.8445 53.0637 70.8179V65.1661C53.0634 65.1412 53.0574 65.1167 53.0462 65.0944C53.035 65.0721 53.0189 65.0525 52.9992 65.0371C52.9794 65.0218 52.9564 65.011 52.9318 65.0056C52.9073 65.0002 52.8819 65.0003 52.8574 65.0059C48.0369 66.1472 43.0971 66.7193 38.141 66.7103C29.6118 66.7103 27.3178 62.6981 26.6609 61.0278C26.1329 59.5842 25.7976 58.0784 25.6636 56.5486C25.6622 56.5229 25.667 56.4973 25.6775 56.4738C25.688 56.4502 25.7039 56.4295 25.724 56.4132C25.7441 56.397 25.7678 56.3856 25.7931 56.3801C25.8185 56.3746 25.8448 56.3751 25.8699 56.3816C30.6101 57.5151 35.4693 58.0873 40.3455 58.086C41.5183 58.086 42.6876 58.086 43.8604 58.0553C48.7647 57.919 53.9339 57.6701 58.7591 56.7361C58.8794 56.7123 58.9998 56.6918 59.103 56.6611C66.7139 55.2124 73.9569 50.665 74.6929 39.1501C74.7204 38.6967 74.7892 34.4016 74.7892 33.9312C74.7926 32.3325 75.3085 22.5901 74.7135 16.6043ZM62.9996 45.3371H54.9966V25.9069C54.9966 21.8163 53.277 19.7302 49.7793 19.7302C45.9343 19.7302 44.0083 22.1981 44.0083 27.0727V37.7082H36.0534V27.0727C36.0534 22.1981 34.124 19.7302 30.279 19.7302C26.8019 19.7302 25.0651 21.8163 25.0617 25.9069V45.3371H17.0656V25.3172C17.0656 21.2266 18.1191 17.9769 20.2262 15.568C22.3998 13.1648 25.2509 11.9308 28.7898 11.9308C32.8859 11.9308 35.9812 13.492 38.0447 16.6111L40.036 19.9245L42.0308 16.6111C44.0943 13.492 47.1896 11.9308 51.2788 11.9308C54.8143 11.9308 57.6654 13.1648 59.8459 15.568C61.9529 17.9746 63.0065 21.2243 63.0065 25.3172L62.9996 45.3371Z" fill="currentColor" /></svg> <div style="color: #787588; margin-top: 16px;">Post by @Ghostsheetz@alaskan.social</div> <div style="font-weight: 500;">View on Mastodon</div> </a> </blockquote>
<script data-allowed-prefixes="https://alaskan.social/" async="" src="https://alaskan.social/embed.js"></script>

<p>As an iPhone user, I’ve already had AI shoved in my face–Just as much as I have in using Microsoft products that I’m forced to interface with at my job, or the endless droves of creatively bankrupt drones on corporate social media who post slop, ad infinitum, and for the pleasure of no one but themselves.</p>

<p>And maybe you’re thinking, “Pfft, so you’re almost 40, I bet you’re just yelling angrily at a cloud, afraid to embrace new things!”</p>

<p>No, see. <em>I have used AI,</em> and even <em>without</em> the extreme environmental impact, it sucks nards and ass.</p>

<p><img src="/img/posts/nosnow/Screenshot from 2025-01-26 17-12-33.png" /></p>

<p>AI has a massive propensity to simply <em>guess</em> things if it doesn’t immediately know the answer. Which, in the least, is a bunch of crap. You mean to tell me you think Jupiter is closer to Saturn than it is to Earth? Are you serious?</p>

<p>And, at worst, it’s an efficient propaganda machine that could easily fuel misinformation campaigns.</p>

<p>These trillion dollar companies have scraped the entire internet, and the creativity of real human beings, in order to … <em>give you incorrect information</em>.</p>

<p>And yet, these tech bros will talk to you and say things like, “It’s inevitable dude, may as well jump on board!”</p>

<p><img src="/img/posts/nosnow/Screenshot from 2025-01-26 04-27-03.png" /></p>

<p>Yeah, AI is inevitable. Inevitable to either aid and abet Elon Musk and Mark Zuckerberg in killing everyone on the planet, or popping like a saturated bubble in the same way NFTs did.</p>

<p>Either way, if you’re using Linux to interface with a plagiarism bot, please just go back to Windows. Windows was <em>built for you</em>. You can revel in your contribution to the destruction of our home <em>without</em> tainting the Linux operating system for something you’re going to be embarrassed about if you happen to live long enough to retire.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Tech" /><category term="ai" /><category term="linux" /><category term="climatechange" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[It’s a pretty widely known fact, at this point, that the development and continued use of AI is killing the planet. It’s killing the planet at an even more accelerated rate than the world’s richest people and their corporations were, already. And yet, you can log onto Twitter (if you dare), Threads, Bluesky, and even Mastodon, and see tech-hype-brained, uncritical idiots (for lack of a better term), celebrating the thought of the expansion of LLMs to the point where we’re now apparently even talking of wasting the potential of Linux-based operating systems on our phones, on its continued development and use.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Sleeper Hits: Games With No Ad Revenue</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/gaming/2025/01/24/sleeper-hits-games-with-no-ad-revenue.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Sleeper Hits: Games With No Ad Revenue" /><published>2025-01-24T21:43:00-05:00</published><updated>2025-01-24T21:43:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/gaming/2025/01/24/sleeper-hits-games-with-no-ad-revenue</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/gaming/2025/01/24/sleeper-hits-games-with-no-ad-revenue.html"><![CDATA[<p>Today, I wanted to write about some games that I enjoy that also appear to have no advertising, <em>ever</em>, for one reason or another. Either the studio just doesn’t spend any money on ads, or they have no money to spend. In the past, I firmly believe this has been the reason games like Wildstar were eventually shutdown. You probably heard of that MMO, and also probably its demise, but had you seen any advertisements for or about it years after its launch? Probably not. Or, with how Second Life has been running for over 20 years, and there are virtually no and/or never any advertising campaigns about it. Yet, somehow, it thrives based on word-of-mouth, <em>alone</em>.</p>

<p>If you’ve read my blog here and there over the past year, you might remember when I wrote about the game POOLS, which I believed to be a liminal horror walking simulator that stands as an allegory to abuse. Or, any of the other <em>more traditional</em> Backrooms related games, that come, go, and never get talked about.</p>

<p>One of them, being, <em>The Complex: Expedition</em>.</p>

<p><img src="/img/posts/sleepers/Screenshot from 2025-01-24 21-48-57.png" /></p>

<p>If you’re familiar with the Kane Pixels’ Youtube series of Backrooms content, diving into this game will feel like the same territory. And, although, it’s <em>not</em> directly based on Kane’s work, it is very much obviously inspired by it.</p>

<p><img src="/img/posts/sleepers/Screenshot from 2025-01-24 22-09-05.png" /></p>

<p>In an almost frighteningly real looking excursion into the Backrooms, as one of the hazmat-suit-wearing researchers, you crawl beneath a crevice, and while <em>within the complex itself</em>, you slip through a null zone and sink further into it. Effectively cutting you off from your team. Hence begins your expedition, a personal walk around the actual Backrooms.</p>

<p>Another game that I’ve been enjoying lately, along with a few others from the publisher and studios that are currently undergoing a possible acquisition, i.e., <a href="https://www.euronews.com/business/2025/01/10/ubisoft-appoints-advisors-to-explore-strategic-options-for-a-potential-buyout" target="_blank">Ubisoft</a>, is Avatar: Frontiers of Pandora.</p>

<p><img src="/img/posts/sleepers/Screenshot from 2025-01-24 22-19-10.png" /></p>

<p>Firstly, it’s really no surprise that Ubisoft is about to be bought out by a larger company (like Tencent), after one of their executives fumbled its customer relations so <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/ubisoft-exec-says-gamers-need-to-get-comfortable-not-owning-their-games-for-subscriptions-to-take-off" target="_blank">disturbingly badly</a>.</p>

<p>But, as we all know, studios within a publishing house don’t really always reflect the opinions of out-of-touch stock-jockeys.</p>

<p>So, we enter the world of Pandora, not through the eyes of one of the humans attempting to colonize and exploit the planet, and not even through the eyes of one of the human freedom fighters, but through a native of the planet itself. Which is really cool.</p>

<p>Think: Farcry meets Avatar.</p>

<p>You’ve got a massively expansive world to explore, places to liberate from human exploitation, and a crafting system that involves foraging and looting in a way that fits well within the nature-bound lifestyle of the Na’vi.</p>

<p><img src="/img/posts/sleepers/Screenshot from 2025-01-24 20-28-21.png" /></p>

<p>And, like the previous game I mentioned, AFOP has next to none, or <em>absolutely</em> no advertising, whatsoever. Which is <em>especially</em> strange, since it appears to have multiple expansions. Not to mention, the backing of three movies that cost more than potentially buying the city of New York for your personal amusement.</p>

<p>Third on my list, is a Call of Duty clone by Ukrainian developers, Alfa Bravo Inc, that is originally a mobile game, but <em>entirely functional on Linux</em>, with zero intrusive kernel-level anti-cheat.</p>

<p><img src="/img/posts/sleepers/Screenshot from 2025-01-24 22-26-52.png" /></p>

<p>The game plays like a slightly fumbly-ish Call of Duty Modern Warfare, except it’s not being replaced every 6 months with another 200 gig iteration. In fact, the game only takes up around about a single gigabyte of storage.</p>

<p>“WHAT?!” You say.</p>

<p>Yes.</p>

<p><img src="/img/posts/sleepers/20250124223011_1.jpg" /></p>

<p>It’s great for blowing off some steam, and especially for scratching that itch you may be missing having abandoned Windows. Which, <em>you should</em>, because <em>fuck</em> Microsoft.</p>

<p>When I say “fumbly,” though, I mean, it could do with a bit more polish in the area of character movement. It doesn’t feel <em>as tight</em> as it would in Call of Duty. You sometimes feel like a piece of jello bouncing around. But, other than that, it’s great! And it’s not at all like its polar opposite, which also works on Linux, Counterstrike.</p>

<p>Personally, I’ve had so much time in CS:GO, that it’s virtually uninteresting to me in 2025. I was playing that game in … frikken, uh, 2002 (the original CS, obviously)?</p>

<p>And, like the others, you’ve probably never heard of this game before.</p>

<p>But that’s just three of the sleepers I wanted to mention. Honestly, this post could go on and on for hours about numerous games that I think are really cool, that nobody ever talks about, that you never even see on milquetoast social media adverts (I don’t even really look at that stuff anymore, anyway). I could write detailed information on Sacred 2 Gold, an <em>extremely old</em> action RPG, Grim Dawn, another ARPG, or even, something way out of left field, Quake Champions!</p>

<p>Although … Quake Champions is kind of a … lukewarm re-imagining of the classic arena shooter, that I honestly think is not that popular, solely because they tried to reinvent something that didn’t need reinventing, with … hero classes.</p>

<p>But anyway, I’m not writing this post to talk about why I think Quake Champions is never talked about or even mentioned, <em>anywhere</em>.</p>

<p>No matter if you’re a fan of liminal horror, Farcry, or shooters, I’m sure everyone reading this will find something they enjoy about at least <em>one</em> of the three titles I’ve mentioned.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Gaming" /><category term="gamingnews" /><category term="gaming" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today, I wanted to write about some games that I enjoy that also appear to have no advertising, ever, for one reason or another. Either the studio just doesn’t spend any money on ads, or they have no money to spend. In the past, I firmly believe this has been the reason games like Wildstar were eventually shutdown. You probably heard of that MMO, and also probably its demise, but had you seen any advertisements for or about it years after its launch? Probably not. Or, with how Second Life has been running for over 20 years, and there are virtually no and/or never any advertising campaigns about it. Yet, somehow, it thrives based on word-of-mouth, alone.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Fun Things To Do in Your Linux Terminal</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/linux/2025/01/21/fun-things-to-do-in-your-linux-terminal.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Fun Things To Do in Your Linux Terminal" /><published>2025-01-21T17:17:00-05:00</published><updated>2025-01-21T17:17:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/linux/2025/01/21/fun-things-to-do-in-your-linux-terminal</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/linux/2025/01/21/fun-things-to-do-in-your-linux-terminal.html"><![CDATA[<p>I’m still sort of sick, but also actively participating in going to work (because I don’t have sick time to use right now), but! I wanted to write something on the blog here, despite being tired, and stuffy, and having pains in my body, and so I thought, “What about neat things you can do in your Linux terminal that some might not be aware of?” I know, yes. This is a very nerdy thing to think about, or even do, and I’m sure the Windows-holdouts are giving this paragraph the stink-eye. Never-you-mind them, though. Let’s open up that terminal.</p>

<p>First, let’s do a ‘sudo apt install cowsay’, and then once it’s finished, type in something like,</p>

<div class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge"><div class="highlight"><pre class="highlight"><code>cowsay 'At the stripted club, jorkin my peanits'
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>And enjoy the result:</p>

<p><img src="/img/posts/funlinux/Screenshot from 2025-01-21 17-21-32.png" /></p>

<p>Or, maybe you want to generate some quick ascii text for your blog header, or social profile? Easy peasy, dude. First, make sure you have figlet installed, by typing, ‘sudo apt install figlet’, and then go ahead and do something like this:</p>

<div class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge"><div class="highlight"><pre class="highlight"><code>figlet cmdr nova
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>Example result:</p>

<p><img src="/img/posts/funlinux/Screenshot from 2025-01-21 17-28-34.png" /></p>

<p>Our next little easter-egg-ish thing (depending on whether it’s already installed on your system or not) is more just kind of neat. Just in case, since not all systems will have this, type in ‘sudo apt install sl’, and then run this:</p>

<div class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge"><div class="highlight"><pre class="highlight"><code>sl
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>(No, it won’t delete your entire hdd)</p>

<p>Or, maybe you want to do something a little more complicated, but fun, nonetheless. If you’re a 90s baby, or even a mid-80s baby, this will suddenly feel like, <em>maybe</em>, you’re being warped back in time a bit. Type ‘sudo apt install sudoku’ into your terminal, and then run it with:</p>

<div class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge"><div class="highlight"><pre class="highlight"><code>sudoku
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>And enjoy:</p>

<p><img src="/img/posts/funlinux/Screenshot from 2025-01-21 17-33-11.png" /></p>

<p>Perhaps you want something a bit more complex, so let’s install NetHack, and become a Wizard!</p>

<div class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge"><div class="highlight"><pre class="highlight"><code>sudo apt install nethack-console
</code></pre></div></div>
<p>and then run:</p>
<div class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge"><div class="highlight"><pre class="highlight"><code>nethack
</code></pre></div></div>

<p><img src="/img/posts/funlinux/Screenshot from 2025-01-21 17-40-45.png" /></p>

<p>But, maybe this is too complicated, and you’re looking for something … a bit more straight-forward, and maybe even <em>retro</em>? I got you.</p>

<p>Do this:</p>
<div class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge"><div class="highlight"><pre class="highlight"><code>sudo apt install colossal-cave-adventure
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>And then, in any terminal, just type in ‘adventure.’</p>

<p><img src="/img/posts/funlinux/Screenshot from 2025-01-21 18-35-10.png" /></p>

<p>Okay, so, obviously, we went a little bit further here than just playing with random little quirky things in a Linux terminal, but I wanted to showcase how, even if you don’t want to install Steam, even if you mainly use your Linux computer for work, or productivity, and there really aren’t any games, or fun things on it … you can just <em>do</em> things, in the Terminal, and this is just the beginning.</p>

<p>An entire era of lost art, and a type of gaming, living freely in your Linux terminal, rather than a DOS machine from 1985.</p>

<p>One thing I <em>do</em> remember from those times, is a text adventure Twilight Zone game, and I would <em>very much</em> like to find it again, or, to be more specific, <em>find it</em>, and then load it up in the terminal and play it that way. I’m pretty sure it’s easily available on DOSbox somewhere. But, you know, I have a terminal. Let me play it like that. The way it was <em>meant to be played</em>. If you’ve done this, or can point me in the right direction: Let me know!</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Linux" /><category term="linux" /><category term="terminal" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[I’m still sort of sick, but also actively participating in going to work (because I don’t have sick time to use right now), but! I wanted to write something on the blog here, despite being tired, and stuffy, and having pains in my body, and so I thought, “What about neat things you can do in your Linux terminal that some might not be aware of?” I know, yes. This is a very nerdy thing to think about, or even do, and I’m sure the Windows-holdouts are giving this paragraph the stink-eye. Never-you-mind them, though. Let’s open up that terminal.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Tik Tok, Popular Sludge Content Platform: Banned</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/social-media/2025/01/19/tik-tok-popular-sludge-content-platform-banned.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Tik Tok, Popular Sludge Content Platform: Banned" /><published>2025-01-19T11:48:00-05:00</published><updated>2025-01-19T11:48:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/social-media/2025/01/19/tik-tok-popular-sludge-content-platform-banned</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/social-media/2025/01/19/tik-tok-popular-sludge-content-platform-banned.html"><![CDATA[<p>Yes, yes. It is absolutely a travesty and a violation of the first amendment for the government to ban a platform that the public uses to speak, and express themselves. Does that mean it was a perfect, and good platform? No. Just like Facebook, Instagram, Threads, and Twitter, there are, or have been, surface-level good things, with extremely very not good things just centimeters beneath the surface. From sludge that’s made to maintain a viewer’s attention for as long as possible, to manipulative content that pushes falsehoods and lies for engagement, to ByteDance’s own AI crawler that’s been scraping the entire internet for use in their image and video filters, <em>for years</em>. You definitely should not shed any tears.</p>

<p>“But what about the content creators who were making thousands of dollars off of engagement bait? The NPC actors making millions of dollars in a year?!” You might ask, and I’ll begrudgingly respond: I’m sure Instagram will welcome them with open arms.</p>

<p>You see, there <em>were</em> good things about Tik Tok, and I know it’s probably not gone forever, but I personally feel like the platform has been a net negative for the human population, overall, and I also realize that this makes it sound like I <em>agree</em> with the government. I do not.</p>

<p>I do not believe that the Chinese government gives two flying ballsacks what a random American person is doing on an app where people shovel food in their mouths and try not to puke, in hopes they get forty five million views and a 5000 dollar paycheck. I feel like, if the president and corporations don’t want our information being sold to China, they should first <em>stop</em> allowing Elon Musk and Mark Zuckerberg to do so.</p>

<p>With that out of the way, <em>fuck Tik Tok</em>.</p>

<p>From <a href="https://www.haproxy.com/blog/nearly-90-of-our-ai-crawler-traffic-is-from-tiktok-parent-bytedance-lessons-learned" target="_blank">an article</a> written in October 2024,</p>

<blockquote>
This month, Fortune.com reported that TikTok’s web scraper — known as Bytespider — is aggressively sucking up content to fuel generative AI models. We noticed the same thing when looking at bot management analytics produced by HAProxy Edge — our global network that we ourselves use to serve traffic for haproxy.com. Some of the numbers we are seeing are fairly shocking, so let’s review the traffic sources and where they originate.
</blockquote>

<p>Out of the slew of bots I have to block on both my website, and also my Mastodon instance, I’m praying that their bot gets shutdown. Just so that I can count on one less DDOS scraper violating my consent.</p>

<p>But, I’m also aware that Tik Tok is a staple of generation Z social networking. Like, it’s their monument, or whatever. It is to Gen Z, what MySpace is to Millennials. And while MySpace had the superficial “top 8” and spam in your inbox, I don’t recall an algorithm that <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2023/apr/04/how-tiktoks-algorithm-exploits-the-vulnerability-of-children" target="_blank">intentionally exploited children</a> in order to promote addiction.</p>

<p>This also has a lot to do with parents not properly reviewing what their kids are doing online, whether it be scrolling sludge for 6 hours, or screaming at adults in Call of Duty. I can’t really speak <em>too badly</em> about parents in this day and age though, because I’m sure <em>many</em> millennials were doing things online that they shouldn’t have been doing, as well.</p>

<p>Never-the-less, there is a bit of an influx of people from Tik Tok, to Mastodon, and ActivityPub, which is surprising. I’m not sure what characteristics of written social media Tik Tok users would enjoy. Either way, there’s always <a href="https://pixelfed.org/how-to-join" target="_blank">Pixelfed</a> and the upcoming <a href="https://loops.video" target="_blank">Loops.video</a> to replace predatory algorithm apps, and I hope they take off just the same way these scummy corporate apps have.</p>

<p>At the end of the day, remember: Tik Tok, Threads, Twitter, Instagram, and even Bluesky: These apps and websites can be banned. All of them. But you can’t ban ActivityPub, not unless you’re going to expend billions in resources to track down thousands to hundreds of thousands of apps and servers.</p>

<p>Welcome to the future.</p>

<p>(My thoughts throughout this blog post may seem disjointed and frayed, and that’s because I’m at home with the flu, and a fever right now)</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Social-Media" /><category term="tiktokban" /><category term="socialmedia" /><category term="tik tok" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Yes, yes. It is absolutely a travesty and a violation of the first amendment for the government to ban a platform that the public uses to speak, and express themselves. Does that mean it was a perfect, and good platform? No. Just like Facebook, Instagram, Threads, and Twitter, there are, or have been, surface-level good things, with extremely very not good things just centimeters beneath the surface. From sludge that’s made to maintain a viewer’s attention for as long as possible, to manipulative content that pushes falsehoods and lies for engagement, to ByteDance’s own AI crawler that’s been scraping the entire internet for use in their image and video filters, for years. You definitely should not shed any tears.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">MKULTRA GAMING NEWS: Brought to You By Python</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/development/2025/01/17/mkultra-gaming-news-brought-to-you-by-python.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="MKULTRA GAMING NEWS: Brought to You By Python" /><published>2025-01-17T09:04:00-05:00</published><updated>2025-01-17T09:04:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/development/2025/01/17/mkultra-gaming-news-brought-to-you-by-python</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/development/2025/01/17/mkultra-gaming-news-brought-to-you-by-python.html"><![CDATA[<p>Today, I’m feeling a bit under-the-weather. I’ve got the aches, the pains, and the coughing fits. Never-the-less, I wanted to do something, <em>regardless</em>, and I thought to myself, “You know, there are a few gaming news related bots on the fediverse, and most of them kinda suck, because they have no regard for people’s timelines.” In that, I mean, a lot of bots I’ve seen will pump a handful of rounds of feed items into a shotgun, and blast them all over your timeline in extremely short time spans. This sucks, because attempting to read your timeline while a bot spams it, is annoying! So, I solved the problem.</p>

<p>What sparked me wanting to do this, was me, suddenly remembering how I asked one of the gaming news bot curators if he could … you know, put some kind of limit or interval on posts that his bot shares, or curate it in a way that it doesn’t share the same news ten times in five minutes.</p>

<p>I remember him saying something like, “Well, I don’t know how to do that.”</p>

<p>Being me, and knowing how to use a cronjob, I did it myself, with my own Python code, and my own bot. You can follow that bot <a href="https://mkultra.monster/@mkultra_gaming" target="_blank">here</a>, from my Mastodon instance.</p>

<p>Here’s how it’s done.</p>

<div class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge"><div class="highlight"><pre class="highlight"><code>import feedparser
import random
from mastodon import Mastodon
import time

# List of RSS feed URLs
rss_feeds = [
    'https://www.polygon.com/rss/index.xml',
    'https://www.dualshockers.com/feed/',
    'https://kotaku.com/rss',
    'https://www.vg247.com/feed/',
    'https://toucharcade.com/feed/',
    'https://www.gamespot.com/feeds/mashup',
    'https://www.ign.com/rss/articles/feed?tags=games',
    'https://www.gematsu.com/feed',
    'https://www.destructoid.com/feed/',
    'https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/feed',
    'https://www.siliconera.com/feed/',
    'https://nichegamer.com/feed/',
    'https://massivelyop.com/feed/',
    'https://www.gamingonlinux.com/article_rss.php',
    'https://www.tabletopgamingnews.com/feed/'
]

# Grab the latest item from a feed, and use retry logic, just in case a feed is dead
def get_latest_item(feed_url, retries=3):
    for attempt in range(retries):
        try:
            feed = feedparser.parse(feed_url)
            if feed.entries:
                return feed.entries[0]
        except Exception as e:
            print(f"Error fetching {feed_url}: {e}")
            if attempt &lt; retries - 1:
                time.sleep(2)  # Wait before retrying
            else:
                return None
    return None

# Look at all feeds
latest_items = []
for feed in rss_feeds:
    item = get_latest_item(feed)
    if item:
        latest_items.append(item)

# Select one at random
if latest_items:
    selected_item = random.choice(latest_items)

    # Custom text
    custom_text = "The latest gaming news! Brought to you and personally curated by cmdr_nova:\n\n"

    # Mastodon credentials
    mastodon = Mastodon(
        access_token='an_access_token_from_mastodon',
        api_base_url='https://mkultra.monster'
    )

    # Post that shit, bro!
    status = f"{custom_text}[{selected_item.title}]\n\n{selected_item.link}"
    mastodon.toot(status)
else:
    print("No items to share.")
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>Here are your requirements:</p>

<div class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge"><div class="highlight"><pre class="highlight"><code>feedparser==6.0.10
Mastodon.py==1.5.1
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>And here’s a cronjob using a shell script so that it can activate an environment, execute the script, and then close the environment.</p>

<p>Shell script:</p>
<div class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge"><div class="highlight"><pre class="highlight"><code>#!/bin/bash
cd folder_location_of_script
source environment_name/bin/activate
python3 mkultra-gaming.py
deactivate
</code></pre></div></div>
<p>Cronjob:</p>
<div class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge"><div class="highlight"><pre class="highlight"><code>0 * * * * folder_location_of_script/gaming.sh
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>And you’re good to go! This shares once an hour, from a feed, at random, and has retry logic just in case a feed doesn’t work, or blocks scripts, or whatever.</p>

<p>Voila.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Development" /><category term="gamingnews" /><category term="programming" /><category term="bots" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today, I’m feeling a bit under-the-weather. I’ve got the aches, the pains, and the coughing fits. Never-the-less, I wanted to do something, regardless, and I thought to myself, “You know, there are a few gaming news related bots on the fediverse, and most of them kinda suck, because they have no regard for people’s timelines.” In that, I mean, a lot of bots I’ve seen will pump a handful of rounds of feed items into a shotgun, and blast them all over your timeline in extremely short time spans. This sucks, because attempting to read your timeline while a bot spams it, is annoying! So, I solved the problem.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">So, It’s Been Over 20 Years</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/thoughts/2025/01/16/so-it-s-been-over-20-years.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="So, It’s Been Over 20 Years" /><published>2025-01-16T22:30:00-05:00</published><updated>2025-01-16T22:30:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/thoughts/2025/01/16/so-it-s-been-over-20-years</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/thoughts/2025/01/16/so-it-s-been-over-20-years.html"><![CDATA[<p>It’s not a secret that I turn 40 in May. Not a secret, because I can’t stop talking about how conflicted and melancholy this makes me feel. It forces me to look back into the past, twenty some years ago when life was completely different. When things were simpler, and I was simultaneously more comfortable, and less worried, but angsty, and angry all of the time. Back when I lived in a most definitely haunted house, that still stands to this day. That I’ve promised to myself, that if ever I can afford to buy a house: That’s the one I’ll buy.</p>

<p>Thinking back 23 to 24 years ago, the memories in my head feel like … like something from another dimension. Something that wraps me in a lukewarm blanket of black and white, in the midst of Fall, and the silence of my bedroom where I once slept. Where I smoked cigarettes out the side-window, and sat at my 486 computer and waited for hours, <em>everyday</em>, for my internet girlfriends to log on AOL Instant Messenger. Where I spent most of my time trying to decide on the coolest anime wallpaper for my desktop, or prattling on and on about meaningless things on the message board, <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20030207160624/http://animeboards.com/" target="_blank">animeboards.com</a>. Where I decorated my room with goth and death inspired candles, and incense, and listened to KoRn and Marilyn Manson for hours and hours on infinite repeat.</p>

<p>The distant past feels like a place I could visit, if only I tried hard enough.</p>

<p>Yesterday, I pulled up my ex-girlfriend from the end of my high school years, on Facebook, and I sent her a semi-heartfelt message. I spoke about the reasons I broke up with her in 2004, what I really thought the future might’ve been months before I made that decision, in that time and period. And the things I didn’t express, such as how I wish I would’ve made different decisions. Wish I would’ve had my head on straight.</p>

<p>I miss it all.</p>

<p>I miss having all that energy. I miss not knowing what the future might be. I miss playing The Sims and torturing the Goth family while I renovated their house to be a castle of death.</p>

<p>I miss all the stupid things I said and did that ultimately ended up being experiences I would never forget.</p>

<p>I miss all the friends I had, and even the girl who only dated me for a week, in high school, only to ditch me for some other dude in a matter of minutes.</p>

<p>I miss not feeling like my entire life is bound to be owned by a corporation, where I’ll do nothing but work and pay bills until the end of days.</p>

<p>But I think about all of these things and how, you know? I don’t <em>have</em> to be totally confined, a loner, a shut-in. I could get back out there, and do <em>new</em> things, make new memories, and <em>new</em> experiences. The problem is, I don’t know where to start anymore. Don’t know where to go, what to do.</p>

<p>I do know, that something’s gotta change. In the immediate future.</p>

<p>Because your whole life can’t just be a cascade of thoughts that all start with, “You know, I miss …”</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Thoughts" /><category term="blogging" /><category term="thoughts" /><category term="aging" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[It’s not a secret that I turn 40 in May. Not a secret, because I can’t stop talking about how conflicted and melancholy this makes me feel. It forces me to look back into the past, twenty some years ago when life was completely different. When things were simpler, and I was simultaneously more comfortable, and less worried, but angsty, and angry all of the time. Back when I lived in a most definitely haunted house, that still stands to this day. That I’ve promised to myself, that if ever I can afford to buy a house: That’s the one I’ll buy.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">To Build A Website, and Remain Invested</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/webdev/2025/01/15/to-build-a-website-and-remain-invested.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="To Build A Website, and Remain Invested" /><published>2025-01-15T23:49:00-05:00</published><updated>2025-01-15T23:49:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/webdev/2025/01/15/to-build-a-website-and-remain-invested</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/webdev/2025/01/15/to-build-a-website-and-remain-invested.html"><![CDATA[<p>I was surfing the <a href="https://forum.melonland.net" target="_blank">MelonLand forums</a>, looking for interesting topics to read, or even reply to, and then I noticed one I had once replied to late last year, where a user was asking how to stay invested in their own website. And I posted in reply, where I talked about how I was extending my website to make calls to a VPS in order to utilize Python to make it less “static.” But, that’s not really <em>the best</em> way to stay invested in maintaining your own personal website. You should stay invested, because, at the end of it all, and everything, and the oligarch-tech-complex that looms overhead, <em>it could end up being the only place where you’re able to speak.</em></p>

<p>Sure, your provider, be it Github Pages, or some VPS maintainer, they could just … pull the rug and offline your site in the blink of an eye. But, guess what! You’re smart. You build your website on your local machine, and then upload it to your server. So, you didn’t lose anything. You won’t <em>lose anything, ever</em>.</p>

<p>Think about how Twitter was overtaken, and maybe you said goodbye, and you deleted your account. A decade of your internet history, wiped clean from the internet. Think about going to Threads, and finding out Zuck is <em>even more of an asshole than you thought he was,</em> and so you left. Now you’ve joined Bluesky, or Mastodon. On Bluesky, what if some control-freak crypto-company buys the app, and then wipes your data? Or, something to that effect? What if you’re on Mastodon, and you take a break from social media, and then return, and the server you were on is gone?</p>

<p>Well, so’s your data, and your internet history, and all the work you’ve done.</p>

<p>This is not a criticism of ActivityPub, by the way. Maintaining community owned social media comes with some risks, and you should be prepared, <em>by having the bulk of your work, and words, and thoughts</em>, on a website of your own.</p>

<p>It doesn’t have to be flashy. It doesn’t have to look like it was developed by some 50-years-of-experience web developer. It just has to be <em>yours</em>.</p>

<p>Build, <em>something</em>, and then start jotting down your thoughts. Put up <a href="https://slashpages.net" target="_blank">slashpages</a>, and share your work, share your interests, share, <em>yourself</em>. And when you’re done doing all of that, <em>keep on writing.</em> Make new posts, put them in their own pages, share those pages to Mastodon, or Bluesky, or, wherever you are.</p>

<p>Speak your mind, and say whatever-the-fuck you want, because if you own the slate, it cannot be smashed by adult toddlers who want to take away everyone’s toys.</p>

<p>You want to know <em>how</em> to stay invested in maintaining your own website?</p>

<p><strong>Make your website the central communication and sharing platform, that’s all about you, that you own.</strong></p>

<p>You do that, and you’ll never stop messing with it.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Webdev" /><category term="webdev" /><category term="indieweb" /><category term="webmaster" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[I was surfing the MelonLand forums, looking for interesting topics to read, or even reply to, and then I noticed one I had once replied to late last year, where a user was asking how to stay invested in their own website. And I posted in reply, where I talked about how I was extending my website to make calls to a VPS in order to utilize Python to make it less “static.” But, that’s not really the best way to stay invested in maintaining your own personal website. You should stay invested, because, at the end of it all, and everything, and the oligarch-tech-complex that looms overhead, it could end up being the only place where you’re able to speak.]]></summary></entry></feed>